<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>daniil.bazhenov on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/daniil.bazhenov/</link><description>Recent content in daniil.bazhenov on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 14:54:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/daniil.bazhenov/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to contribute Dashboards to PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 14:54:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</guid><description>Have you already contributed to Percona’s open-source products or perhaps you wanted to try doing so?
I will tell you how to become a contributor to the popular open-source product from Percona in just a few hours. You don&amp;rsquo;t need any serious developer skills.
We earlier explained how to contribute to PMM documentation in our last post. Now we will contribute to PMM itself, namely to Dashboards. Dashboards are an important part of PMM, they are seen and used by thousands of users, so your contribution may be of benefit to many others.</description></item><item><title>Our Offer to Online Meetups and Community Leaders</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/07/our-offer-to-online-meetups-and-community-leaders/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 10:52:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/07/our-offer-to-online-meetups-and-community-leaders/</guid><description>Percona’s Community team organizes our speakers at in-person events around the world, such as Percona Live, Percona University, and events sponsored by other organizations. However, like everyone else around the world, all our plans are on hold due to the Coronavirus pandemic.
Perhaps you, like many others, are organizing online events, such as virtual meetups on Meetup.com. We can help you by making Percona’s team of experienced and well-known speakers available for your event.</description></item><item><title>How To Contribute to PMM Documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 16:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;d love to see more contributions towards the development and improvement of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM), one of Percona&amp;rsquo;s most valued projects. Like all of Percona&amp;rsquo;s software, PMM is free and open-source. An area where we&amp;rsquo;d dearly love to see some community provided enhancement is in its documentation. In future blog posts, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide some insight on how to contribute to our software but&amp;hellip; the beauty of documentation is that it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to maintain, and you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to be a programmer to be able to provide valuable corrections and enhancements.</description></item></channel></rss>