<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Run Percona: Embrace Open on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Run Percona: Embrace Open on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Kubernetes Operators</title><link>https://percona.community/projects/operators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/projects/operators/</guid><description>If you are using Kubernetes, you might have wondered how to best deal with database clusters. This is done by controllers in Kubernetes configuration files - our Kubernetes Operators allow you to easily manage complex deployments by extending the Kubernetes API with custom resources.
For instructions on how to use, check out the Percona Distribution for MySQL Operator documentation or the GitHub repository.
For instructions on how to use, check out the Percona Distribution for MongoDB Operator documentation or the GitHub repository.</description></item><item><title>Percona Toolkit</title><link>https://percona.community/projects/toolkit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/projects/toolkit/</guid><description>With Percona Toolkit you can focus on planning, designing, and deploying new architectures instead of routine tasks in your database setup.
Percona Toolkit is a collection of advanced open source command-line tools and includes several tasks for MySQL as well as MongoDB deployments. Check out the Percona Toolkit documentation for more details on which tools are included in the toolkit and how to best use them.
⤓ Download Percona Toolkit</description></item><item><title>PMM - Percona Monitoring and Management</title><link>https://percona.community/projects/pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/projects/pmm/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) has a demo website which allows you to quickly check out what it&amp;rsquo;s all about. If you prefer text instead, here&amp;rsquo;s quick list of what you can do with PMM:
Query Analytics (intuitive interface enabling you to quickly analyze and optimize your queries) Metrics Monitor (historical view of metrics that are critical to your database server) Security Threat Tool (quickly find and fix common data security issues across all your open source databases) &amp;hellip;and much more If you&amp;rsquo;ve checked out the demo and are ready to give it a try, you can read more about how to set it up in our installation documentation.</description></item></channel></rss>