<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Run Percona: Embrace Open on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Run Percona: Embrace Open on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Distribution for Kubernetes Operators</title><link>https://percona.community/projects/operators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/projects/operators/</guid><description>How can you help?
Download, Try, Give Feedback, &amp;amp; Enhance Welcome to Percona’s Community Page for Kubernetes Operators! The Percona Kubernetes Operators automate the creation, alteration, or deletion of members in your Percona Distribution for MySQL, MongoDB, or PostgreSQL environments. We would love your help in contributing to those projects and driving them forward. How can you do that? It could be very simple. Give us your feedback, submit bug reports, create content, or contribute code.</description></item><item><title>Percona Toolkit</title><link>https://percona.community/projects/toolkit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/projects/toolkit/</guid><description>How can you help?
Download, Try, Give Feedback, &amp;amp; Enhance Percona Toolkit is a collection of advanced open source command-line tools, developed and used by the Percona technical staff, that are engineered to perform a variety of MySQL®, MariaDB®, MongoDB®, and PostgreSQL server and system tasks that are too difficult or complex to perform manually. We would love for you to try it out, give us feedback, or contribute.
Looking to submit a PR, contribute code, or submit a bug?</description></item><item><title>PMM - Percona Monitoring and Management</title><link>https://percona.community/projects/pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/projects/pmm/</guid><description>How can you help?
Download, Try, Give Feedback, &amp;amp; Enhance Need to easily monitor and troubleshoot your databases? PMM is the solution we highly encourage you to try to and give feedback on. It is free, open-source and supports various databases (MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MariaDB), and allows you to view and monitor all of your open source databases easily in one place. Give it a try and help us improve it with your feedback!</description></item></channel></rss>