<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ClickHouse on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/clickhouse/</link><description>Recent content in ClickHouse on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/clickhouse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trino on Ice: Using Iceberg To Replace the Hive Table Format</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/10/</guid><description>Brian Olsen - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
Trino (formerly PrestoSQL) is a ludicrously fast query engine that evolved from the need to replace the slow query turnaround speeds of the Hive engine. Trino grew in popularity under the label of Presto for years as an interactive query engine that lives over your data lake. While this operation was certainly a step away from the initial big data days of waiting hours to days for queries to complete, there were still many tedious rules engineers had to follow in order to correctly create, manage, and use their data in the datalake due to the Hive table format.</description></item><item><title>Fun and Games: Why We Picked ClickHouse To Drive Gaming Analytics at GiG</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/9/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/9/</guid><description>Stephen Borg - Matthew Formosa - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
With such a saturated market for the iGaming industry, many technology providers are reviewing their architecture to provide a leaner, more sustainable platform. Complex architectures that involve heavy license and high maintenance costs were two of the rules to avoid when GiG kicked o R&amp;amp;D on what technology to choose at the heart of GiG Data. Tied with the necessity of good governance whilst empowering stakeholders needing real-time data, the list of databases became shorter and shorter.</description></item><item><title>I’ve Got a Fever and the Only Prescription is Apache Druid</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/8/</guid><description>Rachel Pedreschi - Imply - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
Digital transformation initiatives have unlocked large and fast-moving data sets including clickstreams, network telemetry, application monitoring and IoT devices. Analytics architectures have not kept pace, with most data still being run through existing “cold analytics” systems and tools designed for smaller and less time-sensitive workloads. “Hot analytics” denotes workloads where the responsiveness of the system is instantaneous and can support self-service data exploration, and where the data is extremely fresh, allowing for more informed decision-making.</description></item><item><title>DuckDB: Embedded Analytics with Parallel/Vector/Columnar Performance</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/7/</guid><description>Jim Tommaney - Databricks - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
DuckDB is a project coming out of CWI in the Netherlands that combines vector, columnar, and parallel capabilities.
Highlights:
Great performance for analytic queries Fast batch load Near linear scaling Near-zero administration DuckDB is a SQLite replacement for analytics.
In this session you will learn about:
What is different about Embedded/Serverless data engines? Current performance and features of DuckDB Best practices using DuckDB</description></item><item><title>WarpSQL – A Distribution of MySQL 8 With Columnar Storage, Bitmap Indexing, and Parallel Query Execution</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/6/</guid><description>Justin Swanhart - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
WarpSQL is a distribution of MySQL 8 which includes the WARP storage engine and has parallel query execution features for queries that use WARP tables. The WARP storage engine features automatic creation of compressed bitmap indexes, which can be used to eciently execute complex queries that can not be executed eciently using traditional btree indexes, even over very large amounts of data.</description></item><item><title>A Tale of Two Communities: How Open Source, ClickHouse and Superset Help Visualize Your Data</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/5/</guid><description>Robert Hodges (Altinity) and Srini Kadamati (Preset.io) - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
This talk consists of live lab exercises for the ClickHouse Developer Tutorial, Part 1. Please attend that talk and then join us for fun using ClickHouse. We have some puzzles for you to try that will test your ClickHouse knowledge. You can run all queries straight from your web browser, so there&amp;rsquo;s no preparation required. Join us for the fun!</description></item><item><title>ClickHouse Developer Tutorial, Part 2 - Lab Exercises</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/4/</guid><description>Robert Hodges and Alexander Zaitsev - Altinity - Altinity Community Track
This talk consists of live lab exercises for the ClickHouse Developer Tutorial, Part 1. Please attend that talk and then join us for fun using ClickHouse. We have some puzzles for you to try that will test your ClickHouse knowledge. You can run all queries straight from your web browser, so there&amp;rsquo;s no preparation required. Join us for the fun!</description></item><item><title>ClickHouse Developer Tutorial, Part 1 - Intro to ClickHouse</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/3/</guid><description>Robert Hodges and Alexander Zaitsev - Intro to ClickHouse - Altinity Community Track
Heard about ClickHouse and been itching to try it out? This talk is for you! It&amp;rsquo;s a tutorial to get new ClickHouse developers up and running quickly. We&amp;rsquo;ll begin by summarizing practical differences between ClickHouse and row stores like MySQL or PostgreSQL. Next, we&amp;rsquo;ll show how to install ClickHouse and connect to it with popular client tools. We&amp;rsquo;ll then teach basics of ClickHouse SQL, focusing on commands to build reports and dashboards.</description></item><item><title>ClickHouse 2021: New Features and Roadmap</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/2/</guid><description>Alexey Milovidov - Yandex - Percona Live ONLINE 2021 - Altinity Community Track
In 2021 the ClickHouse community is shipping the features that you probably always dreamed of. We are eliminating previously known limitations of ClickHouse. I will tell you and show demos about: replication without ZooKeeper; semistructured data; processing of frequent small INSERTs; support for transactions; window functions and projections and more and more&amp;hellip; We&amp;rsquo;re really excited about these features and hope they will make ClickHouse even better for your analytic applications.</description></item><item><title>Projections in ClickHouse</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/1/</guid><description>Amos Bird - kuaishou.com - Percona Live - Altinity Community Track
Projections are collections of table columns with different physical layout to speed up queries. They are the main constructs of Vertica. At kuaishou.com we have implemented PROJECTIONs support for ClickHouse. It boosts our OLAP analytic capabilities by an order of magnitude. This talk will highlight the design considerations, some implementation details, how it is integrated into ClickHouse design. Examples and demo of the feature will be shown</description></item><item><title>IIoT platform databases - How Mail.ru Cloud Solutions deals with petabytes of data coming from a multitude of devices</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:11:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</guid><description>Hello, my name is Andrey Sergeyev and I work as a Head of IoT Solution Development at Mail.ru Cloud Solutions. We all know there is no such thing as a universal database. Especially when the task is to build an IoT platform that would be capable of processing millions of events from various sensors in near real-time.
Our product Mail.ru IoT Platform started as a Tarantool-based prototype. I’m going to tell you about our journey, the problems we faced and the solutions we found.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: ClickHouse at Messagebird: Analysing Billions of Events in Real-Time*</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/29/clickhouse-at-messagebird-analysing-billions-of-events-in-real-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 17:28:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/29/clickhouse-at-messagebird-analysing-billions-of-events-in-real-time/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll look into how Clickhouse allows us to ingest a large amount of data and run complex analytical interactive queries at MessageBird. We also present the business needs that brought ClickHouse to our attention and detail the journey to its deployment. We cover the problems we faced, and how we dealt with them. We talk about our current Cloud production setup and how we deployed and use it.</description></item><item><title>Easy and Effective Way of Building External Dictionaries for ClickHouse with Pentaho Data Integration Tool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</guid><description>In this post, I provide an illustration of how to use Pentaho Data Integration (PDI) tool to set up external dictionaries in MySQL to support ClickHouse. Although I use MySQL in this example, you can use any PDI supported source.
ClickHouse ClickHouse is an open-source column-oriented DBMS (columnar database management system) for online analytical processing. Source: wiki.
Pentaho Data Integration Information from the Pentaho wiki: Pentaho Data Integration (PDI, also called Kettle) is the component of Pentaho responsible for the Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) processes.</description></item></channel></rss>