<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tools on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/tools/</link><description>Recent content in tools on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:33:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Embracing the Stream</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/10/embracing-the-stream/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/10/embracing-the-stream/</guid><description>So this happened: CentOS Project shifts focus to CentOS Stream
The future of the CentOS Project is CentOS Stream, and over the next year we’ll be shifting focus from CentOS Linux, the rebuild of Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), to CentOS Stream, which tracks just ahead of a current RHEL release. CentOS Linux 8, as a rebuild of RHEL 8, will end at the end of 2021. CentOS Stream continues after that date, serving as the upstream (development) branch of Red Hat Enterprise Linux.</description></item><item><title>Not JOINing on PERFORMANCE_SCHEMA</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/01/not-joining-on-performance_schema/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 19:22:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/01/not-joining-on-performance_schema/</guid><description>The tables in PERFORMANCE_SCHEMA (P_S) are not actually tables. You should not think of them as tables, even if your SQL works on them. You should not JOIN them, and you should not GROUP or ORDER BY them.
Unlocked memory buffers without indexes The stuff in P_S has been created with “keep the impact on production small” in mind. That is, from a users point of view, you can think of them as unlocked memory buffers - the values in there change as you look at them, and there are precisely zero stability guarantees.</description></item><item><title>On the Observability of Outliers</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/11/23/on-the-observability-of-outliers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 17:41:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/11/23/on-the-observability-of-outliers/</guid><description>At work, I am in an ongoing discussion with a number of people on the Observability of Outliers. It started with the age-old question “How do I find slow queries in my application?” aka “What would I want from tooling to get that data and where should that tooling sit?”
As a developer, I just want to automatically identify and isolate slow queries!
Where I work, we do have SolarWinds Database Performance Monitor aka Vividcortex to find slow queries, so that helps.</description></item><item><title>How to build a high-performance application on Tarantool from scratch</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</guid><description>I came to Mail.ru Group in 2013, and I required a queue for one task. First of all, I decided to check what the company had already got. They told me they had this Tarantool product, and I checked how it worked and decided that adding a queue broker to it could work perfectly well. I contacted Kostja Osipov, the senior expert in Tarantool, and the next day he gave me a 250-string script that was capable of managing almost everything I needed.</description></item><item><title>Zero downtime schema change with Liquibase &amp; Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/26/zero-downtime-schema-change-with-liquibase-percona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 14:14:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/26/zero-downtime-schema-change-with-liquibase-percona/</guid><description>I am always surprised to learn something new whenever I talk to a member of the open-source community. No matter how much I think I have heard of every use case there is for Liquibase (and database change management in general), I always hear something that makes this space still feel new. There’s always something left to discover.
Today, that new something is the problem of how to perform large batches of changes with SQL ALTER TABLE statements.</description></item><item><title>Mayastor: Lightning Fast Storage for Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/23/mayastor-lightning-fast-storage-for-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 14:03:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/23/mayastor-lightning-fast-storage-for-kubernetes/</guid><description>At MayaData we like new tech. Tech that makes our databases perform better. Tech like lockless ring buffers, NVMe-oF, and Kubernetes. In this blog post we’re going to see those technologies at work to give us awesome block storage performance with flexibility and simple operations.
Mayastor + SPDK + NVMe = fast databases Mayastor is new tech, it’s fast, and it’s based on SPDK. Why is SPDK exciting? It’s a new generation in storage software, designed for super high speed low latency NVMe devices.</description></item><item><title>The State of ProxySQL, 2020 Edition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/16/the-state-of-proxysql-2020-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 20:08:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/16/the-state-of-proxysql-2020-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 7:30 a.m. • London 12:30 p.m. • New Delhi 5:00 p.m. • Singapore 7:30 p.m.
Abstract ProxySQL is a high performance, high available, protocol aware proxy for MySQL. 2.0 has been GA for some time now, and there have been a lot of changes that come in point releases as well, such that you can benefit from them. Listen to René, the founder of ProxySQL, take you through some of the new features in 2.</description></item><item><title>Database Schema Management Via Liquibase</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 22:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</guid><description>Creating the database for an application is simple and easy. However, database script management gets complicated in a hurry when you need to support multiple versions, work with multiple teams, and apply the same changes to multiple types of databases. One open-source tool that helps teams track, version, and deploy database schema changes is Liquibase. It executes database scripts sequentially, allows for the automatic creation and execution of rollback scripts for failed updates, and provides an easy way to use the same scripts and apply them to different types of databases.</description></item><item><title>How to Write Your Index in Tarantool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 17:23:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</guid><description>Tarantool is an application server and a database. The server part is written in C, and the user is provided with a Lua interface to use it. Then, Tarantool is an open-source product with its source code in open access, and anyone can develop and distribute Tarantool-based software freely.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you about an attempt to write my own data structure for the search (the Z-order curve) and build it into the Tarantool ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code Refactor PMM Framework Project with Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:08:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</guid><description>I am Meet Patel, 2nd year undergraduate at DAIICT, Gandhinagar, India; pursuing a bachelor’s degree in Information and Communication Technology with a minor in Computational Science.
I am proud to be selected for the Google Summer of Code program under an open source organization as big and impactful as Percona. As we head towards the end of this amazing program, I’ll try to share a general overview of what and how all of it has been implemented.</description></item><item><title>IoT Performance Bottlenecks &amp; Open Source Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</guid><description>The Internet of Things (IoT), in essence, is all about everyday devices that are readable, recognizable, trackable, and/or controllable via the Internet, regardless of the communication means — RFID, wireless LAN, and so on. The total installed base of IoT connected devices is projected to amount to 21.5 billion units worldwide by 2025. Thanks to IoT, the proliferation of data can be quite daunting. Hence, businesses should effectively organize and work with this enormous amount of valuable data.</description></item><item><title>IIoT platform databases - How Mail.ru Cloud Solutions deals with petabytes of data coming from a multitude of devices</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:11:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</guid><description>Hello, my name is Andrey Sergeyev and I work as a Head of IoT Solution Development at Mail.ru Cloud Solutions. We all know there is no such thing as a universal database. Especially when the task is to build an IoT platform that would be capable of processing millions of events from various sensors in near real-time.
Our product Mail.ru IoT Platform started as a Tarantool-based prototype. I’m going to tell you about our journey, the problems we faced and the solutions we found.</description></item><item><title>Cassandra Where and How by John Schulz</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</guid><description>If Percona Live ONLINE had graded its talks by skill level this year, John Schulz’s talk would have been essential viewing in the Beginners track. (You can watch all the event’s presentations now on Percona’s YouTube channel.) This talk was a good overview and meant for anyone who had heard of the Apache Cassandra distributed database but wasn’t sure whether it would be suitable for their project or not.
Database-veteran, John Schulz has been tinkering with Cassandra for about a decade and to help anyone get started he gave a whistle-stop tour of the Cassandra ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Making a Tarantool-Based Investment Business Core for Alfa-Bank</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/19/making-a-tarantool-based-investment-business-core-for-alfa-bank/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 13:23:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/19/making-a-tarantool-based-investment-business-core-for-alfa-bank/</guid><description>A still from &amp;ldquo;Our Secret Universe: The Hidden Life of the Cell&amp;rdquo;
Investment business is one of the most complex domains in the banking world. It&amp;rsquo;s about not just credits, loans, and deposits — there are also securities, currencies, commodities, derivatives, and all kinds of complex stuff like structured products.
Recently, people have become increasingly aware of their finances. More and more get involved in securities trading. Individual investment accounts have emerged not so long ago.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE: Anti-cheating tools for massive multiplayer games using Amazon Aurora and Amazon ML services</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/11/percona-live-online-anti-cheating-tools-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 14:21:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/11/percona-live-online-anti-cheating-tools-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services/</guid><description>Would you play a multiplayer game if you discovered other people are cheating? According to a survey by Irdeto, 60% of online games were negatively impacted by cheaters, and 77% of players said they would stop playing a multiplayer game if they think opponents are cheating. Player churn grows as cheating grows.
Stopping this is therefore essential if you want to build and develop your community, which is essential to success for today’s gaming companies.</description></item><item><title>Percona Projects for Google Summer of Code - 2020</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that Percona was selected as a participating organization for the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2020 program, this is our second year as a participating org with the GSoC program.
GSoC is a great program to involve young student developers in open source projects. We participated in the program in 2019 for the first time and we were really happy and satisfied with the results.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Enhancing MySQL security at LinkedIn by Karthik Appigatla</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/01/percona-live-online-talk-enhancing-mysql-security-at-linkedin-by-karthik-appigatla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 08:01:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/01/percona-live-online-talk-enhancing-mysql-security-at-linkedin-by-karthik-appigatla/</guid><description>MySQL, arguably the most popular relational database, is used pretty extensively at the popular professional social network LinkedIn. At Percona Live ONLINE 2020, the company’s flagship event held online for the first time due to the Covid-19 pandemic, Karthik Appigatla from LinkedIN’s database SRE team discussed the company’s approach to securing their database deployment without introducing operational hiccups or adversely affecting performance.
Instead of just performing admin duties, Karthik’s team builds automated tools to scale their infrastructure, and he talked about some of these tailored tools in his presentation.</description></item><item><title>Join ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona on June 4th, 2020!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</guid><description>Long months of the pandemic lockdown have brought to life many great online events enabling the MySQL community to get together and stay informed about the very recent developments and innovations available to MySQL users. It isn’t over yet! Next Thursday, June 4th, Percona &amp;amp; ProxySQL are co-hosting the ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona virtual meetup covering ProxySQL, MySQL and Percona XtraDB Cluster.
The attendees are invited to participate in the two-hour deep-dive event with plenty of time for questions and answers (we will have two 40-minute sessions + 20 minutes allocated for Q&amp;amp;A).</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes, The Swiss Army Knife For Your ProxySQL Deployments – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/09/kubernetes-the-swiss-army-knife-for-your-proxysql-deployments-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 02:02:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/09/kubernetes-the-swiss-army-knife-for-your-proxysql-deployments-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 10:00 p.m. • London 3:00 a.m. (Wed) • New Delhi 7:30 a.m. (Wed)
Abstract ProxySQL is a high performance proxy from design to implementation. It speaks the MySQL protocol, and can go beyond load balancing. This talk covers various deployment options for ProxySQL in a Kubernetes environment.
Typically ProxySQL is deployed in one of three ways depending on the scale and needs of your environment:</description></item><item><title>How to contribute Dashboards to PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 14:54:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</guid><description>Have you already contributed to Percona’s open-source products or perhaps you wanted to try doing so?
I will tell you how to become a contributor to the popular open-source product from Percona in just a few hours. You don&amp;rsquo;t need any serious developer skills.
We earlier explained how to contribute to PMM documentation in our last post. Now we will contribute to PMM itself, namely to Dashboards. Dashboards are an important part of PMM, they are seen and used by thousands of users, so your contribution may be of benefit to many others.</description></item><item><title>The Anatomy of LuaJIT Tables and What's Special About Them</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/29/the-anatomy-of-luajit-tables-and-whats-special-about-them/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 13:18:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/29/the-anatomy-of-luajit-tables-and-whats-special-about-them/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but I really like to get inside all sorts of systems. In this article, I’m going to tell you about the internals of Lua tables and special considerations for their use. Lua is my primary professional programming language, and if one wants to write good code, one needs at least to peek behind the curtain. If you are curious, follow me.
Lua has several implementations and several versions.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Tarantool Cartridge Applications with Zero Effort (Part 2)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/01/deploying-tarantool-cartridge-applications-with-zero-effort-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 11:04:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/01/deploying-tarantool-cartridge-applications-with-zero-effort-part-2/</guid><description>We have recently talked about how to deploy a Tarantool Cartridge application. However, an application&amp;rsquo;s life doesn&amp;rsquo;t end with deployment, so today we will update our application and figure out how to manage topology, sharding, and authorization, and change the role configuration.
Feeling interested? Please continue reading under the cut.
Where did we leave off? Last time, we set up the following topology: The sample repository has changed a bit: there are new files called getting-started-app-2.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Tarantool Cartridge Applications with Zero Effort (Part 1)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/03/24/deploying-tarantool-cartridge-applications-with-zero-effort-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 14:04:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/03/24/deploying-tarantool-cartridge-applications-with-zero-effort-part-1/</guid><description>Tarantool is an open-source in-memory DB with a Lua application server on board. It&amp;rsquo;s best used for apps that require high performance and horizontal scaling. Out of the box we support horizontal scaling via the vshard module. There are quite a few things that you have to keep in mind when you work on your business logic, though. Not ideal.
We made it easier. All the lessons learned from creating distributed apps resulted in a framework called Tarantool Cartridge.</description></item><item><title>How To Contribute to PMM Documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 16:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;d love to see more contributions towards the development and improvement of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM), one of Percona&amp;rsquo;s most valued projects. Like all of Percona&amp;rsquo;s software, PMM is free and open-source. An area where we&amp;rsquo;d dearly love to see some community provided enhancement is in its documentation. In future blog posts, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide some insight on how to contribute to our software but&amp;hellip; the beauty of documentation is that it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to maintain, and you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to be a programmer to be able to provide valuable corrections and enhancements.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: Test Like a Boss</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/25/percona-live-europe-presents-test-like-a-boss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 06:31:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/25/percona-live-europe-presents-test-like-a-boss/</guid><description>My first talk is a tutorial Testing like a boss: Deploy and Test Complex Topologies With a Single Command, scheduled at Percona Live Europe in Amsterdam on September 30th at 13:30.
My second talk is Amazing sandboxes with dbdeployer scheduled on October 1st at 11:00. It is the same topic as the tutorial, but covers a narrow set of features, all in the *amazing* category.
The tutorial introduces a challenging topic, because when people hear testing, they imagine a troop of monkeys fiddling with a keyboard and a mouse, endlessly repeating a boring task.</description></item><item><title>Minimalist Tooling for MySQL/MariaDB DBAs</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/14/minimalist-tooling-for-mysql-mariadb-dbas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 14:21:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/14/minimalist-tooling-for-mysql-mariadb-dbas/</guid><description>In my roles as a DBA at various companies, I generally found the tooling to be quite lacking. Everything from metrics collection, alerting, backup management; they were either missing, incomplete or implemented poorly. DBA-Tools was born from a desire to build backup tools that supported my needs in smaller/non-cloud environments. As BASH is easily the most common shell available out there on systems running MySQL® or MariaDB®, it was an easy choice.</description></item><item><title>Tame Kubernetes with These Open-Source Tools</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/08/tame-kubernetes-with-open-source-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 13:03:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/08/tame-kubernetes-with-open-source-tools/</guid><description>Kubernetes’ popularity as the most-preferred open-source container-orchestration system has skyrocketed in the recent past. The overall container market is expected to cross USD 2.7 billion by 2020 with a CAGR of 40 percent. Three orchestrators spearhead this upward trend, namely Kubernetes, Mesos, and Docker Swarm. However, referring to the graph below, Kubernetes clearly leads the pack.
source: https://medium.com/@rdodev/saved-you-an-analyst-read-on-kubernetes-growth-2018-edition-810367876981 
The automation and infrastructural capabilities of Kubernetes are transforming the DevOps space, thereby enhancing the value of the business through software.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Setup at Hostinger Explained</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/11/mysql-setup-hostinger-explained/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 15:27:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/11/mysql-setup-hostinger-explained/</guid><description>Ever wondered how hosting companies manage their MySQL database architecture? At Hostinger, we have various MySQL setups starting from the standalone replica-less instances to Percona XtraDB Cluster (later just PXC), ProxySQL routing-based and even absolutely custom and unique solutions which I’m going to describe in this blog post.
We do not have elephant-sized databases for internal services like API, billing, and clients. Thus almost every decision ends up with high availability as a top priority instead of scalability.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: pg_chameleon MySQL to PostgreSQL Replica Made Easy</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 14:42:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</guid><description>What excites me is the possibility that this tool is giving to other people. Also, the challenges I’ve faced and the new ideas for the future releases are always source of interest that keep me focused on the project. So I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to sharing this with the conference delegates.
pg_chameleon can achieve two tasks in a very simple way. It can setup a permanent replica between MySQL and PostgreSQL, giving the freedom of choice for the right tool for the right job, or can migrate multiple schemas to a PostgreSQL database.</description></item><item><title>Export to JSON from MySQL All Ready for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/export-to-json-from-mysql-all-ready-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 15:18:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/export-to-json-from-mysql-all-ready-for-mongodb/</guid><description>This post walks through how to export data from MySQL® into JSON format, ready to ingest into MongoDB®. Starting from MySQL 5.7+, there is native support for JSON. MySQL provides functions that actually create JSON values, so I will be using these functions in this article to export to JSON from MySQL:
JSON_OBJECT JSON_ARRAY These functions make it easy to convert MySQL data to JSON e.g.
mysql&amp;gt; SELECT json_object(&amp;#39;employee_id&amp;#39;, emp_no, &amp;#39;first_name&amp;#39;, first_name ) AS &amp;#39;JSON&amp;#39; FROM employees LIMIT 2; +------------------------------------------------+ | JSON | +------------------------------------------------+ | {&amp;#34;first_name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Aamer&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;employee_id&amp;#34;: 444117} | | {&amp;#34;first_name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Aamer&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;employee_id&amp;#34;: 409151} | +------------------------------------------------+ 2 rows in set (0.</description></item><item><title>Generating Identifiers – from AUTO_INCREMENT to Sequence</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/12/generating-identifiers-auto_increment-sequence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/12/generating-identifiers-auto_increment-sequence/</guid><description>There are a number of options for generating ID values for your tables. In this post, Alexey Mikotkin of Devart explores your choices for generating identifiers with a look at auto_increment, triggers, UUID and sequences.
AUTO_INCREMENT Frequently, we happen to need to fill tables with unique identifiers. Naturally, the first example of such identifiers is PRIMARY KEY data. These are usually integer values hidden from the user since their specific values are unimportant.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Elasticsearch 101</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 07:17:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe, I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting the tutorial Elasticsearch 101 alongside my colleagues and fellow presenters from ObjectRocket Alex Cercel, DBA, and Mihai Aldoiu, Data Engineer. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief overview of our tutorial.
Elasticsearch® is well known as a highly scalable search engine that stores data in a structure optimized for language based searches but its capabilities and use cases don’t stop there. In this tutorial, we’ll give you a hands-on introduction to Elasticsearch and give you a glimpse at some of the fundamental concepts.</description></item><item><title>Easy and Effective Way of Building External Dictionaries for ClickHouse with Pentaho Data Integration Tool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</guid><description>In this post, I provide an illustration of how to use Pentaho Data Integration (PDI) tool to set up external dictionaries in MySQL to support ClickHouse. Although I use MySQL in this example, you can use any PDI supported source.
ClickHouse ClickHouse is an open-source column-oriented DBMS (columnar database management system) for online analytical processing. Source: wiki.
Pentaho Data Integration Information from the Pentaho wiki: Pentaho Data Integration (PDI, also called Kettle) is the component of Pentaho responsible for the Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) processes.</description></item></channel></rss>