<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amazon Aurora Community Track on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon Aurora Community Track on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Supporting Global Scale MySQL Applications With Amazon Aurora Global Database</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/3/</guid><description>Vijay Karumajj - AWS - Amazon Aurora Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Critical MySQL workloads with a global footprint, such as financial, travel, or gaming applications, have strict availability requirements and may need to tolerate a region-wide outage. Traditionally this required difficult tradeoffs between performance, availability, cost, and data integrity. In this session, learn how Amazon Aurora Global Database, which allows a single Amazon Aurora MySQL database to span multiple AWS regions, replicates your data with no impact on database performance, enables fast local reads with low latency in each region, and provides fast disaster recovery from region-wide outages.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Applications With Amazon RDS Proxy</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/2/</guid><description>Surendar Munimohan - AWS - Amazon Aurora Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Many applications, including those built on modern serverless architectures (https://aws.amazon.com/serverless/), can have a large number of open connections to the database server, and may open and close database connections at a high rate, exhausting database memory and compute resources. Amazon RDS Proxy allows applications to pool and share connections established with the database, improving database efficiency and application scalability.</description></item><item><title>Hyperscaling Workloads With Amazon RDS MySQL and Amazon Aurora MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/1/</guid><description>Sai Kondapalli - AWS - Amazon Aurora Community Track - Percona Live 2021
When the right factors align, businesses can grow at a sudden, unanticipated and exponential rate. That&amp;rsquo;s a good thing, but an unexpected and dramatic spinke in users and transactions of your MySQL database can strain resources, potential database failure, and, as a result, a bad user or customer experience. In this session, learn strategies and best practices quickly growing your MySQL deployment to ensure high performance and an exceptional user experience while maintaing ACID compliance and rock solid security.</description></item></channel></rss>