<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/authors/dave_cohen/</link><description>Recent content on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 17:38:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/authors/dave_cohen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Live Presents: An Open-Source, Cloud Native Database</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/14/percona-live-presents-open-source-cloud-native-database/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 17:38:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/14/percona-live-presents-open-source-cloud-native-database/</guid><description>During our presentation at Percona Live 2019 Intel and its software partners will introduce the audience to the work we’re doing to enable an open-source framework, we call Cloud Native Database. This is a collaborative effort between Intel, Rockset, PlanetScale, MariaDB and Percona.
Through the presentation the audience will be introduced to a set of principles and architectural elements that define what we mean by Cloud Native Database. We will discuss Rockset’s RocksDB-Cloud library and how it works with Facebook’s MyRocks storage engine.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The State of Databases in 2019</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</guid><description>At this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live I am talking about The State of Databases in 2019. As a Software Engineer in the thick of the Database landscape, there are two problems that I see repeatedly.
Due to the massive explosion of database solutions, it has become very difficult to evaluate what database solution will serve the best for one’s use case, and
The constant tug of war between database operators and users.</description></item></channel></rss>