<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>RDS on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/rds/</link><description>Recent content in RDS on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 11:45:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/rds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A First Look at Amazon RDS Proxy</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/07/a-first-look-at-amazon-rds-proxy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 11:45:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/07/a-first-look-at-amazon-rds-proxy/</guid><description>At re:Invent in Las Vegas in December 2019, AWS announced the public preview of RDS Proxy, a fully managed database proxy that sits between your application and RDS. The new service offers to &amp;ldquo;share established database connections, improving database efficiency and application scalability&amp;rdquo;.
But one of the benefits that caught my eye is the ability to reduce the downtime in case of an instance failure and a failover. As for the announcement:</description></item><item><title>How to Automate Minor Version Upgrades for MySQL on RDS</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/07/10/automate-minor-version-upgrades-mysql-rds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:19:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/07/10/automate-minor-version-upgrades-mysql-rds/</guid><description>Amazon RDS for MySQL offers the option to automate minor version upgrades using the minor version upgrade policy, a property that lets you decide if Amazon is allowed to perform the upgrades on your behalf. Usually the goal is not to upgrade automatically every RDS instance but to keep up to date automatically non-production deployments. This helps you address engine issues as soon as possible and improve the automation of the deployment process.</description></item></channel></rss>