<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Podcast on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/podcast/</link><description>Recent content in Podcast on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open on Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Dave Stokes Talks Open on Percona Live 2022 During the Percona Live 2022 in Austin, David Stokes, Percona’s Technical Evangelist, invited amazing event guests and speakers to talk to him about open source technologies and trends and record a podcast. Watch these videos to find out the latest news in the world of open source databases, cloud technologies, DevOps tools, and monitoring and hear from the outstanding experts. Don’t forget to like and share them with your friends!</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes talks open - Stoking the flames of open source - Episode 2 - Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-2/</guid><description>Bruce Momjian, VP, Postgres Evangelist at EDB, and Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona joined Dave Stokes, Technical Evangelist at Percona Live 2022. This is the recording of their talk on all things Postgres-related and OpenSource technologies.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/dcoQmgV2kBA</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes talks open - Stoking the flames of open source - Episode 1 - Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-1/</guid><description>Listen to the interviews from PerconaLive 2022. David Stokes invited amazing guests to talk to him about open source technologies.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/cOK4hzRLszo</description></item></channel></rss>