<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Podcast on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/podcast/</link><description>Recent content in Podcast on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Gravity Episode 3 - benny Vasquez - AlmaLinux Project and the Future of Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-3/</guid><description>In this episode, Joe Brockmeier interviews benny Vasquez of the AlmaLinux Project to discuss open source data, the future of databases, and how databases and Linux distros go together.
Episode 3 Link
All Data Gravity Podcast Episodes
Transcript Joe Brockmeier:
Good morning, good afternoon. Good evening. Whatever timezone it happens to be for you. This is Joe Brockmeier, the Head of Community at Percona. And you are listening to Data Gravity, our podcast about open source databases, control of your data and all things similar to that all kinds of open source.</description></item><item><title>Data Gravity Podcast</title><link>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/</guid><description>Data Gravity Podcast Data Gravity is Percona’s community podcast about open data topics. Percona’s Head of Community Joe Brockmeier invites recognized open source experts to talk all things related to open source databases, open source database tools, and open data. He talks to open source contributors, database practitioners, users, and other experts working with MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and other open source databases and tools. You can find all episodes on Podbean and on this page.</description></item><item><title>Data Gravity Episode 2 - Sonia Valeja and David Gonzalez - PostgreSQL for Jobseekers Book</title><link>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-2/</guid><description>In this episode, Joe Brockmeier talks to Percona&amp;rsquo;s Sonia Valeja and David Gonzalez, about their recent book PostgreSQL for Jobseekers. They talk about the inspiration for the book, why they focus on jobseekers, and what&amp;rsquo;s covered in the title.
Episode 2 Page
All Data Gravity Podcast Episodes</description></item><item><title>Data Gravity Episode 1 - Charles Thompson - Dolphie, a Real-Time MySQL Monitoring Assistant</title><link>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-1/</guid><description>In this episode, Joe Brockmeier talks to Charles Thompson, creator of Dolphie - a real-time MySQL monitoring assistant that&amp;rsquo;s open source and available for multiple platforms. He talks about creating Dolphie, how it fits into the MySQL monitoring space, and more.
Episode 1 Link
All Data Gravity Podcast Episodes</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 1 - Sai Kondapalli, Product Manager at Microsoft</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-1/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes interviewed Sai Kondapalli, Microsoft’s Product Manager of Azure Database for MySQL. Let’s listen more about Azure, Security issues, databases, and MySQL.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/RSNj-EgejFQ</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 2 - Roger Barga, Microsoft - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-2/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to Roger Barga, Microsoft’s Vice President and General Manager of Azure Database for MySQL. They discussed relations between open source projects and cloud providers, and what Microsoft does in the open source space and MySQL.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/5LzjKvtuxhQ</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 3 - David Fogle, Civo - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-3/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to David Fogle, Civo’s Research and Development Engineer. Civo has partnered with Percona with the PostgreSQL Kubernetes Operator, and David explained how to use the operator in your cloud environment best. They also discussed machine learning, DBaaS, and the upcoming Civo Navigate in London.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/2TbX_pEIekE</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 4 - Rachel Stephens, RedMonk - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-4/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to Rachel Stephens, Senior Industry Analyst at RedMonk. They discussed her keynote at Percona Live and trends in open source databases world.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/EExOAVhWrJ8</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 5 - Peter Farkas, FerretDB - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-5/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to Peter Farkas, CEO at FerretDB. Peter tells us how he helped envision a database that spoke MongoDB but ran atop PostgreSQL. They also discussed the recent release of FerretDB and where and how it was developing.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/IslVeaDxTtU</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 6 - David Murphy, Udemy - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-6/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to David Murphy, Principal Database Reliability Engineer at Udemy. David Murphy is responsible for various types of databases at scale and provides insights from his many years of experience in this area. His expertise might guide you through your future data battles.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/tqQaUdqCXNY</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 7 - Jan Wieremjewicz, Percona - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-7/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to Jan Wieremjewicz, Senior Product Manager at Percona. Do you wonder where Percona Software&amp;rsquo;s future is? Jan enlightens us about where the future of MongoDB and PostgreSQL will be as he leads us into tomorrow.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/iKOej3ICDqs</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 8 - Jignesh Shah, AWS - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-8/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to Jignesh Shah, General Manager of Amazon RDS Open Source Engines (ROSE) at AWS. Amazon Web Services and Percona are working together to store your data better. Jignesh tells us how RDS is evolving to meet AWS demand.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/0h46XU9B8gA</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 9 - Parikshit Savjani, Microsoft - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-9/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to Parikshit Savjani, Product Lead for Azure Database for MySQL and MariaDB services at Microsoft. They discussed how Microsoft has embraced these databases to serve customer needs best.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/hTfLcGq2658</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open on Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/</guid><description>Dave Stokes Talks Open on Percona Live 2023 On Percona Live 2023 in Denver, Colorado, Percona’s Technical Evangelist David Stokes talked to outstanding event guests and speakers and recorded a podcast right on the venue. They discussed up-to-date open source technologies and trends. Watch these videos to find out the latest news in the world of open source databases, cloud technologies, DevOps tools, and monitoring and hear from amazing experts.</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 10 - Michelle Egan, Percona - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-10/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to Michelle Egan, Senior Manager of Global Events at Percona. An event like Percona Live requires a lot of preparation, coordination, and hard work. Michelle provides some behind-the-scenes information on the creation of this year&amp;rsquo;s show.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/IrtzzzmUmmQ</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 11 - Ovais Tariq and Himank Chaudhary, Tigris Data - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-11/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to Ovais Tariq and Himank Chaudhary, Co-Founders of Tigris Data. Tigris is a Serverless NoSQL database and search platform that offers an open-source alternative to MongoDB and DynamoDB. Ovais and Himank discussed what had changed since Percona Live 2022 and where the product is heading.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/Oz8sett_i3A</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 12 - Matthew Boehm, Percona - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-12/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to Matthew Boehm, Principal Architect at Percona. One of the best at troubleshooting database problems discusses best practices for resolving issues. Do not miss his MySQL 5.7 to 8.0 upgrade examples.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/HdgJc8sCvls</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open - Episode 15 - MySQL Community Team, Oracle - Percona Live 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2023/dave-stokes-talks-open-14/</guid><description>At Percona Live, Dave Stokes talked to MySQL Community Team from Oracle. Frederic Descamps and Scott Stroz discussed how the MySQL Shell and VS Code Shell were changing command line access to the MySQL Server, plus the new release model of their software.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/MdjJ3vtVTp8</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes talks open - Stoking the flames of open source - Episode 2 - Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-2/</guid><description>Bruce Momjian, VP, Postgres Evangelist at EDB, and Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona joined Dave Stokes, Technical Evangelist at Percona Live 2022. This is the recording of their talk on all things Postgres-related and OpenSource technologies.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/dcoQmgV2kBA</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes talks open - Stoking the flames of open source - Episode 1 - Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-1/</guid><description>Listen to the interviews from PerconaLive 2022. David Stokes invited amazing guests to talk to him about open source technologies.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/cOK4hzRLszo</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open on Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Dave Stokes Talks Open on Percona Live 2022 During the Percona Live 2022 in Austin, David Stokes, Percona’s Technical Evangelist, invited amazing event guests and speakers to talk to him about open source technologies and trends and record a podcast. Watch these videos to find out the latest news in the world of open source databases, cloud technologies, DevOps tools, and monitoring and hear from the outstanding experts. Don’t forget to like and share them with your friends!</description></item></channel></rss>