<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/percona/</link><description>Recent content in Percona on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/percona/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The lost art of Database Server Initialization.</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/05/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/05/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</guid><description>With all the DBaaS, IaaS and PaaS environments, sometimes I think the Art of MySQL initialization is becoming a lost art. Many times we just delete the MySQL Server and order a new one.
Just recently I was talking with a colleague, and this subject came up. We both thought about it and decided we have become spoiled by automation. We were both rusty on this process. This gave me the idea for this post.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item></channel></rss>