<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/percona/</link><description>Recent content in Percona on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/percona/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to prevent unauthorized users from connecting to ProxySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/30/how-to-prevent-unauthorized-users-from-connecting-to-proxysql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/30/how-to-prevent-unauthorized-users-from-connecting-to-proxysql/</guid><description>ProxySQL is a great load balancer which however suffers from some shortcomings concerning the management of MySQL users. ProxySQL provides a firewall which, in my case, is not complete enough to properly manage users and secure their access. Indeed, this firewall does not accept subnets and keeps unauthorized connections in ProxySQL. We cannot then be sure of not suffering a DDOS attack on our ProxySQL instance. In this article, I will explain how I managed to overcome this problem.</description></item><item><title>How To Optimize the Structure of a Simple PHP Application as Your Project Grows</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/28/how-to-optimize-the-structure-of-a-simple-php-application-as-your-project-grows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/28/how-to-optimize-the-structure-of-a-simple-php-application-as-your-project-grows/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss the structure of our simple PHP application, folders, files, and functions and transform the project to grow it.
You and I have developed a small PHP application that makes an HTTP request to the GitHub API and stores the result in the database.
Step 1 - How to Develop a Simple Web Application Using Docker-compose, Nginx, PHP 8, and MongoDB 6. Step 2 - How to Make HTTP Requests to API in PHP App Using GitHub API Example and Write to Percona Server for MongoDB.</description></item><item><title>How to Make HTTP Requests to API in PHP App Using GitHub API Example and Write to Percona Server for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/how-to-make-http-requests-to-api-in-php-app-using-github-api-example-and-write-to-percona-server-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/how-to-make-http-requests-to-api-in-php-app-using-github-api-example-and-write-to-percona-server-for-mongodb/</guid><description>We learn how to work with HTTP requests in PHP and make API requests using the GitHub API as an example. We&amp;rsquo;ll get the data from the API and save it to the database.
In the previous article, we developed a simple application that connects to the MongoDB database (Percona Server for MongoDB) and writes documents in a loop. We only used Composer packages to work with MongoDB. We have set up the Docker-compose environment and have the app/ directory where the application code is located.</description></item><item><title>How to Develop a Simple Web Application Using Docker, Nginx, PHP, and Percona Server for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m developing an application that takes data from different sources, processes it, and prepares reports. In this series of articles, I will explain how to install and configure the tools, application, and database to develop and run the application.
About the application and choice of tools The application I develop gets data from GitHub, Jira, and websites via API, processes it and creates reports according to the desired requirements.
The application is developed with PHP version 8+ and Nginx as a web server, and Percona Server for MongoDB as a database.</description></item><item><title>Some Notable Bugfixes in MySQL 8.0.32</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/15/some-notable-bugfixes-in-mysql-8.0.32/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/15/some-notable-bugfixes-in-mysql-8.0.32/</guid><description>MySQL 8.0.32 came out recently and had some important bugfixes contributed by Perconians. Here is a brief overview of the work done.
Inconsistent data and GTIDs with mysqldump Marcelo Altmann (Senior Software Engineer) fixed the bug when data and GTIDs backed up by mysqldump were inconsistent. It happened when the options &amp;ndash;single-transaction and &amp;ndash;set-gtid-purged=ON were both used because GTIDs on the server could have already increased between the start of the transaction by mysqldump and the fetching of GTID_EXECUTED.</description></item><item><title>Using the JSON data type with MySQL 8</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/13/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/13/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8/</guid><description>If you are a mobile app, frontend, backend, or game developer, you use data types such as string, numeric, or DateTime. You also know that since the advent of non-relational databases (NoSQL) such as MongoDB, which, by not being tied to a traditional SQL schema, do reading and writing on databases much faster. But MySQL showed that storing the JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) data type could also improve the speed of reading and writing relational databases.</description></item><item><title>Monitor your databases with Open Source tools like PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/06/monitor-your-databases-with-open-source-tools-like-pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/06/monitor-your-databases-with-open-source-tools-like-pmm/</guid><description>In this post, we will cover the value of database monitoring and how we can use Open Source tools like PMM Percona Monitoring and Management to monitor and manage databases effectively.
Why should I care about database monitoring? Once you have passed the installation and configuration of your databases and it is well underway, you have to start monitoring it, and not only the database but the elements related to it.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Databases on Containers with Percona Server for MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/23/exploring-databases-on-containers-with-mysql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/23/exploring-databases-on-containers-with-mysql/</guid><description>In this blog, we will explore databases on containers. We will use Docker as a container engine tool and Percona Server for MySQL as a database administration tool. Both are open source tools.
MySQL is a relational database management system that stores data on disk. Percona Server for MySQL is a fork of MYSQL, providing much more advanced features. To run it correctly, we need to know volumes because we want to “persist” the data, the most important thing in databases.</description></item><item><title>What is Open Source and why should you care</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/14/what-is-open-source-and-why-should-you-care/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/14/what-is-open-source-and-why-should-you-care/</guid><description>The term Open Source Software reminds me of Abraham Lincoln&amp;rsquo;s widely accepted definition of Democracy. Lincoln said, &amp;ldquo;Democracy is the government of the people, by the people, and for the people&amp;rdquo;. Similarly, Open Source is software of the community, by the community, and for the community.
Formally, Open Source refers to projects or programs whose source code can be modified, shared, and/or commercialized by the public/community at will. A license that is attached to an Open Source project determines the extent to which the project can be consumed, modified, or utilized.</description></item><item><title>Recap Monthly Percona Developer Meetup Hacktoberfest</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/05/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/05/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>The Monthly Percona Developer Meetup is an opportunity to get a behind-the-scenes view of different projects in Percona and directly interact with the experts to exchange ideas, ask questions, etc.
From now on, Monthly Percona Developer Meetups will take place monthly to have open discussions and in-person (online) communication. You can join our Developer Meetup via Restream, the Percona YouTube channel, and LinkedIn events.
The topic of the first Monthly Percona Developer Meetup was Hacktoberfest.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Cloud Migrations With Databases on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
In this talk you will learn how Kubernetes and Percona Operators can help you to avoid vendor lock-in when you run your databases in containers with Percona Operators.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/-U8dOzQqlJI
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Percona Pstress: A Concurrency and Crash Recovery Testing Tool to Test MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
How Pstress works, success so far with MySQL testing.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/LB-dC9CDBOc
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Reduce Replication Lag</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/01/speed-up-replication-lag/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/01/speed-up-replication-lag/</guid><description>Replication Lag is just a fact of life with async-replication. We can&amp;rsquo;t stop lag, but we can help to reduce it. Many times the Seconds_Behind_Source can be very deciving, I have seen it go from 1 hour behind to 0 lag in the blink of an eye. There are many factors that can add to replica lag. Some of these are:
Network IO Disk IO Database Workload Database settings In this blog we will look a few database settings to help reduce lag.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Bullseye Percona Server 64bit</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>I love the Raspberry Pi, and I love Percona server. The combination of the two can provide a nice home database. I have been running a Percona Server database since 2019 to hold all the weather information, that I collect from several of my Weather Stations.
I did a my first blog post on installing Percona Server 5.7 on the Raspberry Pi 3+.
You can read that blog post here: How to Build a Percona Server &amp;ldquo;Stack&amp;rdquo; on a Raspberry Pi 3+</description></item><item><title>The Errant GTID</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</guid><description>Part 1 What is a GTID? Oracle/MySQL define a GTID as "A global transaction identifier (GTID) is a unique identifier created and associated with each transaction committed on the server of origin (the source). This identifier is unique not only to the server on which it originated, but is unique across all servers in a given replication topology." An errant transaction can make promotion of a replica to primary very difficult.</description></item><item><title>The lost art of Database Server Initialization.</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/06/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/06/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</guid><description>With all the DBaaS, IaaS and PaaS environments, sometimes I think the Art of MySQL initialization is becoming a lost art. Many times we just delete the MySQL Server and order a new one.
Just recently I was talking with a colleague, and this subject came up. We both thought about it and decided we have become spoiled by automation. We were both rusty on this process. This gave me the idea for this post.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item></channel></rss>