<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/percona/</link><description>Recent content in Percona on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/percona/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join Percona for Google Summer of Code 2025 – Explore, Innovate, and Contribute!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/02/05/google-summer-of-code-2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/02/05/google-summer-of-code-2025/</guid><description>Are you passionate about open-source databases, AI/ML, and security? Do you want to work on real-world projects that impact thousands of developers and enterprises worldwide? Percona is excited to invite students to participate in Google Summer of Code 2025 (GSoC) and help advance our cutting-edge open-source database solutions!
Why Contribute to Percona? At Percona, we believe that open world is a better world! GSoC is an excellent opportunity to work with seasoned developers, gain hands-on experience, and contribute to powerful database tools used by businesses globally.</description></item><item><title>Percona Operator for MongoDB 1.19: Remote Backups, Auto-Generated Passwords, and More!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/31/percona-operator-for-mongodb-1.19-remote-backups-auto-generated-passwords-and-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/31/percona-operator-for-mongodb-1.19-remote-backups-auto-generated-passwords-and-more/</guid><description>The latest release of the Percona Operator for MongoDB, version 1.19, is here. It brings a suite of enhancements designed to streamline your MongoDB deployments on Kubernetes. This release introduces a technical preview of remote file server backups, simplifies user management with auto-generated passwords, supports Percona Server for MongoDB 8.0, and includes numerous other improvements and bug fixes. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the details of what 1.19 has to offer.
Remote Backups with Network File System (Technical Preview) Backing up your MongoDB data is crucial, and Percona Operator for MongoDB 1.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0-GA</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/29/percona-monitoring-management-3-ga/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/29/percona-monitoring-management-3-ga/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the release of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 3.0.0 GA.
The Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 3.0.0 release delivers major security and stability enhancements. Notable security improvements include rootless deployments and encryption of sensitive data, along with improved API authentication using Grafana service accounts. Deployment options have expanded with official ARM support and the ability to use Podman for rootless deployments, providing flexibility and better security. Additionally, the introduction of containerized architecture has increased stability, and a streamlined upgrade process ensures reliability and ease of maintenance.</description></item><item><title>MySQL 8.4 Support in Percona Toolkit 3.7.0</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/06/mysql-8.4-support-in-percona-toolkit-3.7.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/06/mysql-8.4-support-in-percona-toolkit-3.7.0/</guid><description>Percona Toolkit 3.7.0 has been released on Dec 23, 2024. The main feature of this release is MySQL 8.4 support.
In this blog, I will explain what has been changed. A full list of improvements and bug fixes can be found in the release notes.
TLDR;
Replication statements in 8.4 are fully supported by the Percona Toolkit pt-slave-delay has been deprecated. pt-slave-find has been renamed to pt-replica-find. The old name has been deprecated but exists in the repository as an alias of the pt-replica-find.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0-Beta - Tech Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/12/02/percona-monitoring-management-technical-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/12/02/percona-monitoring-management-technical-preview/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0 Beta - Tech Preview We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the Tech Preview (Beta) release of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 3.0.0-Beta.
This release is intended for testing environments only, as it&amp;rsquo;s not yet production-ready. The GA (General Availability) release will be available through standard channels in the upcoming months.
Release notes To see the full list of changes, check out the 3.0.0-Beta - Tech Preview Release Notes</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: October 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Learn PostgreSQL and SQL Quickly and Free</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/20/learn-postgresql-and-sql-quickly-and-free/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/20/learn-postgresql-and-sql-quickly-and-free/</guid><description>Learn PostgreSQL and SQL Quickly and Free
Want to learn PostgreSQL? What if you could learn PostgreSQL without having to install the database, load data, find sample data, and it was free? PGExamples.com is what you are looking for.
First, let me state that I have no connection to the website or its author. I discovered PgExercises.com by accident and was impressed by its quality and completeness. I am so impressed that I am exploring a video series on it.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup May 15, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/15/release-roundup-may-15-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/15/release-roundup-may-15-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates April 30 - May 15, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup April 30, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/30/release-roundup-april-30-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/30/release-roundup-april-30-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates April 17 - April 30, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: April 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup April 2, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/02/release-roundup-april-2-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/02/release-roundup-april-2-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates March 18 - April 2, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Standby Cluster With the Percona Operator for PostgreSQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/27/creating-a-standby-cluster-with-the-percona-operator-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/27/creating-a-standby-cluster-with-the-percona-operator-for-postgresql/</guid><description>In this video, Nickolay Ihalainen, a Senior Scaling Specialist at Percona Global Services, explains how to set up replication with standby clusters for Kubernetes databases using Percona&amp;rsquo;s open-source tools, including the Percona Operator for PostgreSQL
A Standby Cluster is a backup version of your main database. It&amp;rsquo;s there to keep your data safe and make sure your database can keep running even if something goes wrong with the main one.</description></item><item><title>Open Door MongoDB Chats</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/26/open-door-mongodb-chats/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/26/open-door-mongodb-chats/</guid><description>Let’s talk about MongoDB! This week, Jan Wieremjewicz, Senior Product Manager, and Michal Nosek, Pre-Sales Enterprise Architect at Percona, made two series of videos covering basic to advanced concepts in MongoDB and backups. Le’s explore them together!
Enterprise Scale Backups for MongoDB with Open Source Software In the first video about enterprise-scale backups for MongoDB using open-source software, Jan and Michal discuss the challenges and solutions associated with backing up large datasets in MongoDB.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup March 4, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/04/release-roundup-march-4-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/04/release-roundup-march-4-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates February 21 - March 4, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup February 21, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/21/release-roundup-february-21-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/21/release-roundup-february-21-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates February 5 - February 21, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: January 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/19/percona-bug-report-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/19/percona-bug-report-january-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we believe that transparency is key to improving our products. We are dedicated to creating top-of-the-line open-source database solutions and providing support for any issues that may arise. We encourage feedback and bug reports to help us continually improve.
We stay updated on bug reports through our own platform as well as other sources to ensure we have the most up-to-date information. To make it easier for you, we have compiled a central list of the most critical bugs for your reference in this edition of our bug report.</description></item><item><title>Day 02: The Kubernetes Application Lifecycle</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/20/day-02-the-kubernetes-application-lifecycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/20/day-02-the-kubernetes-application-lifecycle/</guid><description>If you are in the world of application development, you know that every application has a lifecycle. An application lifecycle refers to the stages that our application goes through from initial planning, building, deployment, monitoring, and maintenance in different environments where our application can be executed.
On the other hand, the Kubernetes Application Lifecycle refers exclusively to applications deployed and managed in Kubernetes clusters. This differs from the normal application lifecycle because Kubernetes introduces new principles, practices, and tools for managing applications on containers.</description></item><item><title>How to Develop a Simple Web Application Using Docker, Nginx, PHP, and Percona Server for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m developing an application that takes data from different sources, processes it, and prepares reports. In this series of articles, I will explain how to install and configure the tools, application, and database to develop and run the application.
About the application and choice of tools The application I develop gets data from GitHub, Jira, and websites via API, processes it and creates reports according to the desired requirements.
The application is developed with PHP version 8+ and Nginx as a web server, and Percona Server for MongoDB as a database.</description></item><item><title>What is Open Source and why should you care</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/14/what-is-open-source-and-why-should-you-care/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/14/what-is-open-source-and-why-should-you-care/</guid><description>The term Open Source Software reminds me of Abraham Lincoln&amp;rsquo;s widely accepted definition of Democracy. Lincoln said, &amp;ldquo;Democracy is the government of the people, by the people, and for the people&amp;rdquo;. Similarly, Open Source is software of the community, by the community, and for the community.
Formally, Open Source refers to projects or programs whose source code can be modified, shared, and/or commercialized by the public/community at will. A license that is attached to an Open Source project determines the extent to which the project can be consumed, modified, or utilized.</description></item><item><title>Recap Monthly Percona Developer Meetup Hacktoberfest</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/05/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/05/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>The Monthly Percona Developer Meetup is an opportunity to get a behind-the-scenes view of different projects in Percona and directly interact with the experts to exchange ideas, ask questions, etc.
From now on, Monthly Percona Developer Meetups will take place monthly to have open discussions and in-person (online) communication. You can join our Developer Meetup via Restream, the Percona YouTube channel, and LinkedIn events.
The topic of the first Monthly Percona Developer Meetup was Hacktoberfest.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Cloud Migrations With Databases on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
In this talk you will learn how Kubernetes and Percona Operators can help you to avoid vendor lock-in when you run your databases in containers with Percona Operators.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/-U8dOzQqlJI
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Percona Pstress: A Concurrency and Crash Recovery Testing Tool to Test MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
How Pstress works, success so far with MySQL testing.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/LB-dC9CDBOc
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Reduce Replication Lag</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/01/speed-up-replication-lag/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/01/speed-up-replication-lag/</guid><description>Replication Lag is just a fact of life with async-replication. We can&amp;rsquo;t stop lag, but we can help to reduce it. Many times the Seconds_Behind_Source can be very deciving, I have seen it go from 1 hour behind to 0 lag in the blink of an eye. There are many factors that can add to replica lag. Some of these are:
Network IO Disk IO Database Workload Database settings In this blog we will look a few database settings to help reduce lag.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Bullseye Percona Server 64bit</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>I love the Raspberry Pi, and I love Percona server. The combination of the two can provide a nice home database. I have been running a Percona Server database since 2019 to hold all the weather information, that I collect from several of my Weather Stations.
I did a my first blog post on installing Percona Server 5.7 on the Raspberry Pi 3+.
You can read that blog post here: How to Build a Percona Server &amp;ldquo;Stack&amp;rdquo; on a Raspberry Pi 3+</description></item><item><title>The Errant GTID</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</guid><description>Part 1 What is a GTID? Oracle/MySQL define a GTID as "A global transaction identifier (GTID) is a unique identifier created and associated with each transaction committed on the server of origin (the source). This identifier is unique not only to the server on which it originated, but is unique across all servers in a given replication topology." An errant transaction can make promotion of a replica to primary very difficult.</description></item><item><title>The lost art of Database Server Initialization.</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/06/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/06/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</guid><description>With all the DBaaS, IaaS and PaaS environments, sometimes I think the Art of MySQL initialization is becoming a lost art. Many times we just delete the MySQL Server and order a new one.
Just recently I was talking with a colleague, and this subject came up. We both thought about it and decided we have become spoiled by automation. We were both rusty on this process. This gave me the idea for this post.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item></channel></rss>