<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/percona/</link><description>Recent content in Percona on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/percona/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reduce Replication Lag</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/01/speed-up-replication-lag/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/01/speed-up-replication-lag/</guid><description>Replication Lag is just a fact of life with async-replication. We can&amp;rsquo;t stop lag, but we can help to reduce it. Many times the Seconds_Behind_Source can be very deciving, I have seen it go from 1 hour behind to 0 lag in the blink of an eye. There are many factors that can add to replica lag. Some of these are:
Network IO Disk IO Database Workload Database settings In this blog we will look a few database settings to help reduce lag.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Bullseye Percona Server 64bit</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>I love the Raspberry Pi, and I love Percona server. The combination of the two can provide a nice home database. I have been running a Percona Server database since 2019 to hold all the weather information. That I collect from several of my Weather Stations.
I did a my first blog post on installing Percona Server 5.7 on the Raspberry Pi 3+.
You can read that blog post here: How to Build a Percona Server &amp;ldquo;Stack&amp;rdquo; on a Raspberry Pi 3+</description></item><item><title>The Errant GTID</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</guid><description>Part 1 What is a GTID? Oracle/MySQL define a GTID as "A global transaction identifier (GTID) is a unique identifier created and associated with each transaction committed on the server of origin (the source). This identifier is unique not only to the server on which it originated, but is unique across all servers in a given replication topology." An errant transaction can make promotion of a replica to primary very difficult.</description></item><item><title>The lost art of Database Server Initialization.</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/06/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/06/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</guid><description>With all the DBaaS, IaaS and PaaS environments, sometimes I think the Art of MySQL initialization is becoming a lost art. Many times we just delete the MySQL Server and order a new one.
Just recently I was talking with a colleague, and this subject came up. We both thought about it and decided we have become spoiled by automation. We were both rusty on this process. This gave me the idea for this post.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Cloud Migrations With Databases on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</guid><description>This session is presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Watch This Talk Here The talk will be live-streamed on several platforms. No registration is required. Feel free to ask your questions in chat. Follow the links now and subscribe to notifications not to miss anything!
YouTube LinkedIn Twitter @PerconaBytes Twitch PerconaCommunity In this talk you will learn how Kubernetes and Percona Operators can help you to avoid vendor lock-in when you run your databases in containers with Percona Operators.</description></item><item><title>Percona Pstress: A Concurrency and Crash Recovery Testing Tool to Test MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</guid><description>This session is presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Watch This Talk Here The talk will be live-streamed on several platforms. No registration is required. Feel free to ask your questions in chat. Follow the links now and subscribe to notifications not to miss anything!
YouTube LinkedIn Twitter @PerconaBytes Twitch PerconaCommunity How Pstress works, success so far with MySQL testing.</description></item></channel></rss>