<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PG on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/pg/</link><description>Recent content in PG on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/pg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Supports Community Events - Organize Yours With Us!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</guid><description>One of the things we love doing in Percona is participating in community events and inspiring people to stay connected in the changing world. We have experience in organizing community dinners, meetups, lectures at universities, booths, and even conferences both in-person and virtually. Percona speakers give talks on events all around the globe.
Have you ever thought about organizing a themed meeting for your local open source community? It may harbor many possibilities for you.</description></item><item><title>PMM development and testing with help of minikube</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</guid><description>Why Some time ago I needed to test PG14 with the new pg_stat_monitor version that wasn&amp;rsquo;t released. I decided to log my journey so I would spend less effort next time to replicate it.
I do use podman and run PMM with its help but I also like to hack PMM DBaaS features and think that k8s and minikube are perfect and better scalable solutions for the different development environments and especially for the number of clusters and DBs.</description></item></channel></rss>