<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PMM on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/categories/pmm/</link><description>Recent content in PMM on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/categories/pmm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0-GA</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/29/percona-monitoring-management-3-ga/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/29/percona-monitoring-management-3-ga/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the release of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 3.0.0 GA.
The Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 3.0.0 release delivers major security and stability enhancements. Notable security improvements include rootless deployments and encryption of sensitive data, along with improved API authentication using Grafana service accounts. Deployment options have expanded with official ARM support and the ability to use Podman for rootless deployments, providing flexibility and better security. Additionally, the introduction of containerized architecture has increased stability, and a streamlined upgrade process ensures reliability and ease of maintenance.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0-Beta - Tech Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/12/02/percona-monitoring-management-technical-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/12/02/percona-monitoring-management-technical-preview/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0 Beta - Tech Preview We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the Tech Preview (Beta) release of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 3.0.0-Beta.
This release is intended for testing environments only, as it&amp;rsquo;s not yet production-ready. The GA (General Availability) release will be available through standard channels in the upcoming months.
Release notes To see the full list of changes, check out the 3.0.0-Beta - Tech Preview Release Notes</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: October 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.43.0 Preview Release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/09/12/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/09/12/preview-release/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.43.0 Tech Preview Release Hello everyone! Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 2.43.0 is now available as a Tech Preview Release.
We encourage you to try this PMM preview release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
To see the full list of changes, check out the PMM 2.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: April 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup April 2, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/02/release-roundup-april-2-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/02/release-roundup-april-2-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates March 18 - April 2, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: January 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/19/percona-bug-report-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/19/percona-bug-report-january-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we believe that transparency is key to improving our products. We are dedicated to creating top-of-the-line open-source database solutions and providing support for any issues that may arise. We encourage feedback and bug reports to help us continually improve.
We stay updated on bug reports through our own platform as well as other sources to ensure we have the most up-to-date information. To make it easier for you, we have compiled a central list of the most critical bugs for your reference in this edition of our bug report.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: November 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/12/19/percona-bug-report-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/12/19/percona-bug-report-november-2023/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.41 preview release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/12/06/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/12/06/preview-release/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.41 preview release Hello folks! Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 2.41 is now available as a preview release.
We encourage you to try this PMM preview release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
To see the full list of changes, check out the PMM 2.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.40 preview release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/10/03/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/10/03/preview-release/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.40 preview release Hello folks! Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 2.40 is now available as a preview release.
We encourage you to try this PMM preview release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
To see the full list of changes, check out the PMM 2.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.38 preview release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/30/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/30/preview-release/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.38 preview release Hello folks! Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 2.38 is now available as a preview release.
We encourage you to try this PMM preview release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
To see the full list of changes, check out the PMM 2.</description></item><item><title>Percona University in Peru 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Peru is a country in South America home to a section of the Amazon rainforest and Machu Picchu ⛰️, an ancient Incan city high in the Andes mountains. Percona decided to hold the first event of Percona University 2023 in Lima, the capital of Peru, on June 10.
Percona University is a series of free technical events organized by Percona in various cities around the world since 2013. Percona uses these events to share its unbiased expertise on open source databases with the community, users, and organizations.</description></item><item><title>Easy Way to Start Contributing to Open Source With PMM Documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/18/easy-way-to-start-contributing-to-open-source-with-pmm-documentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/18/easy-way-to-start-contributing-to-open-source-with-pmm-documentation/</guid><description>If you are a user of Percona Monitoring and Management and noticed any typo or inaccurate information in its documentation, you can easily correct it yourself in the repository following detailed instructions in README.md. But if you are not experienced in open source contributions, you may still feel uneasy about following those steps. This post is for you! We will walk through the main steps with pictures and explanations.
Create a Fork First, you need to create a fork from the main repository to your account.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.37 preview release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/20/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/20/preview-release/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.37 preview release Hello folks! Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 2.37 is now available as a preview release.
We encourage you to try this PMM preview release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
You can find the Release Notes here
Percona Monitoring and Management server docker installation Instructions</description></item><item><title>How a Database Monitoring Tool Can Help a Developer. The Story of One Mistake.</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/07/how-a-database-monitoring-tool-can-help-a-developer.-the-story-of-one-mistake./</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/07/how-a-database-monitoring-tool-can-help-a-developer.-the-story-of-one-mistake./</guid><description>I will tell you the real story of using database monitoring tools when developing an application. I will show you an example of how I managed to detect and fix a problem in the application.
A small clarification, the real story from my development practice happened a little more than a week ago, but for the article I took graphs of final debugging, so that the graphs show the correct sequence and fit into the available for explanation and demonstration.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.36 preview release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/preview-release/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.36 preview release Hello folks! Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 2.36 is now available as a preview release.
We encourage you to try this PMM preview release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
You can find the Release Notes here
Percona Monitoring and Management server docker installation Instructions</description></item><item><title>Monitor your databases with Open Source tools like PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/06/monitor-your-databases-with-open-source-tools-like-pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/06/monitor-your-databases-with-open-source-tools-like-pmm/</guid><description>In this post, we will cover the value of database monitoring and how we can use Open Source tools like PMM Percona Monitoring and Management to monitor and manage databases effectively.
Why should I care about database monitoring? Once you have passed the installation and configuration of your databases and it is well underway, you have to start monitoring it, and not only the database but the elements related to it.</description></item><item><title>How to test code blocks in documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/28/doc-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/28/doc-testing/</guid><description>As any developer, I don&amp;rsquo;t like to write documentation. But if I am writing it, I would like to test that what I wrote works. I often found myself copy-pasting something from documentation and trying to run it in the terminal (commands, files, etc.), and it didn&amp;rsquo;t work.
There are usually some environment, typos, or even wrong commands in the doc (that people copy-pasted from the wrong place).
I know that issue, and after writing the documentation, I usually try to clean up everything in my environment and test the doc.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.35 preview release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/14/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/14/preview-release/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.35 preview release Hello folks! Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 2.35 is now available as a preview release.
We encourage you to try this PMM preview release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
You can find the Release Notes here
Percona Monitoring and Management server docker installation Instructions</description></item><item><title>Nurturing, Motivating and Recognizing Non-Code Contributions</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/08/nurturing-motivating-and-recognizing-non-code-contributions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/08/nurturing-motivating-and-recognizing-non-code-contributions/</guid><description>When discussing contributions, we still see a lot of emphasis on the code contributions into project repositories. But the open source world is extensive and diverse, and everyone can find their place there. Your project will benefit from various experiences that non-coders can bring to the table. Isn’t that cool when you receive an issue with an interesting bug from the community, read about a user case in a blog or a review, or someone makes a video guide for your product?</description></item><item><title>Node metrics available inside of a container</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/06/node-metrics-container/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/06/node-metrics-container/</guid><description>Several people asked me this question: Could we get Node metrics inside of a container?
Usually, this comes from the fact that PMM or standalone people run node_exporter inside a container. PMM does it as a sidecar along with many other exporters to monitor DBs, and node_exporter comes out of the box as a default one. So people could see accurate data on dashboards, like Memory and CPU, that node_exporter reads inside the container.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.34 preview release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/17/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/17/preview-release/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 2.34 preview release Hello folks! Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 2.34 is now available as a preview release.
We encourage you to try this PMM preview release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
You can find the Release Notes here
Percona Monitoring and Management server docker installation Instructions</description></item><item><title>Setting Up PMM For Monitoring Your Databases on Windows</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/16/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-your-databases-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/16/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-your-databases-on-windows/</guid><description>Before deploying Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) in production, you might want to test it or set up a development instance locally. Since many developers and DBAs have Windows desktops, I wanted to demonstrate how to set up PMM on Windows for an easy test environment. In this post, I’ll walk you through setting up PMM with Docker and WSL.
If you’re a Linux user, check the blog post I wrote on Setting up PMM for monitoring MySQL in a local environment.</description></item><item><title>How To Contribute to PMM Documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 16:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;d love to see more contributions towards the development and improvement of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM), one of Percona&amp;rsquo;s most valued projects. Like all of Percona&amp;rsquo;s software, PMM is free and open-source. An area where we&amp;rsquo;d dearly love to see some community provided enhancement is in its documentation. In future blog posts, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide some insight on how to contribute to our software but&amp;hellip; the beauty of documentation is that it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to maintain, and you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to be a programmer to be able to provide valuable corrections and enhancements.</description></item></channel></rss>