<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Oracle MySQL Community Track on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/</link><description>Recent content in Oracle MySQL Community Track on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MySQL Architectures in a Nutshell</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/10/</guid><description>Kenny Gryp - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Following MySQL InnoDB Cluster as our first, fully integrated MySQL High Availability solution based on Group Replication, MySQL Shell 8.0.19 includes MySQL InnoDB ReplicaSet which delivers another complete solution, this time based on MySQL Replication.
The basic idea for InnoDB ReplicaSet is to do the same for classic MySQL Replication as InnoDB Cluster did for Group Replication. We take a strong technology that is very powerful but can be complex, and provide an easy-to-use AdminAPI for it in the MySQL Shell.</description></item><item><title>DBdeployer in Action - Optimised MySQL Sandboxes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/9/</guid><description>Giuseppe Maxia and Frédéric Descamps - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
The Data Charmer will show how to use dbdeployer in the wild by answering the questions of lefred. This session will mimic an Ask Me Anything session where all chapters will be an answer to a specic question. Throught this list of questions, the audience will learn how to start with dbdeployer but also discover more advanced featured.</description></item><item><title>Validating JSON</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/8/</guid><description>Dave Stokes - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
JSON or JavaScript Object Notation has become the data interchange format of choice. Most relational databases have added a JSON data type (Oracle, Postgresql, MySQL) or some accommodation for JSON data (SQL Server, MariaDB). But the free form nature of JSON is problematic for relational databases resulting in compromises in speed, handling of key-value pairs, and general lack of the ability to validate data.</description></item><item><title>Successfully Run Your MySQL NDB Cluster in Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/7/</guid><description>Tiago Alves - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Fortunately, MySQL NDB Cluster already has auto-healing, data distribution, instant scaling and many other features built-in - making it a perfect t for Cloud Native. This session walks through the few steps necessary to deploy a distributed NDB setup in a Kubernetes cluster manually or with an operator.
NDB runs in Kubernetes serving mission critical microservices at the heart of Cloud Native production systems.</description></item><item><title>Migration From 5.6 to 8.xx.xx</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/6/</guid><description>Johannes Schlüter and Kenny Gryp - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Brand New Development announced at Percona Live !!
This talk is about something we cannot announce publicly now and will be exclusively announced during Percona Live.
This is something new, that will be released after the conference, don&amp;rsquo;t miss this session to discover new trendy stuff.
Brand New Development announced at Percona Live !!</description></item><item><title>Migration From 5.6 to 8.xx.xx</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/5/</guid><description>Luis Dias - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Intro I start working in a Belgium company that use Mysql 5.6. We use 6 production servers and we decide to migrate from this old version to mysql 8.0.19. All the servers have Centos 7 system (so RPM and YUM available)
The first test was done by devops team, they use mysqldump to make this job, but as each server is about 4T the down time was over 30 hours and it&amp;rsquo;s not acceptable for customer.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Shell for DBAs</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/4/</guid><description>Frédéric Descamps - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Get an overview of the possibilities offered by MySQL Shell for DBAs. How to deploy infrastructures (overview only), how to dump and load tables/schema/instances etc.. it&amp;rsquo;s time to t get more familiar with the util object. And finally see the possibility of User Defined Reports and Plugins for the MySQL Shell.
During the session we will cover the most useful plugins for general DBA tasks</description></item><item><title>Oracle MySQL Database Service with HeatWave for Real-Time Analytics</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/3/</guid><description>Carsten Thalheimer - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Since 2020 the MySQL development team is offering a fully managed database service of the MySQL Enterprise Edition. Traditionally MySQL InnoDB is designed for online transaction processing (OLTP) load. MySQL can cover online analytics processing (OLAP) load, but it is often rather slow and tricky. Beginning of December 2020, the MySQL team started a second MySQL Cloud offering called MySQL HeatWave for Real-time Analytics which is based on a new in-memory analytic accelerator which has been designed for extreme performance and cloud scale.</description></item><item><title>Insights Into the New Oracle MySQL Database Service</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/2/</guid><description>Carsten Thalheimer - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Oracle MySQL Database Cloud Service 2021 - Where we are today&amp;hellip;
Early 2020 Oracle introduced the MySQL Database Service (MDS) built on Oracle Gen 2 Cloud Infrastructure and MySQL 8. It is 100% developed, managed, and supported by the Oracle MySQL team. The service is available as a fully-managed service in all commercial regions of the Oracle Cloud.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Server Component Manifest Files</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/1/</guid><description>Georgi Kodinov - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
MySQL configuration has traditionally been done via system variables with values coming from either command line, config files or SET commands. This can be a security issue since it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support a trust model rooted in some well known trusted state that cannot be modified by less trusted actors.
This is what the manifest le security model is aiming at solving.</description></item></channel></rss>