<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Speakers on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/</link><description>Recent content in Speakers on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/alexander_zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/alexander_zaitsev/</guid><description>Alexey Milovidov was the original designer of ClickHouse, starting from its inception in 2008. He is an expert on high-performance C++, analytic applications, and SQL databases. Alexey is the lead committer of the ClickHouse open source project on Github. He leads the ClickHouse development team at Yandex and speaks regularly at community events</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/alexey_milovidov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/alexey_milovidov/</guid><description>Alexey Milovidov was the original designer of ClickHouse, starting from its inception in 2008. He is an expert on high-performance C++, analytic applications, and SQL databases. Alexey is the lead committer of the ClickHouse open source project on Github. He leads the ClickHouse development team at Yandex and speaks regularly at community events</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/amos_bird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/amos_bird/</guid><description>Amos Bird (郑天祺) is a software engineer at KuaiShou Technologies in China. He graduated from the Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Science, with a Doctor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Database Systems. He is an active ClickHouse contributor for over more than three years, and have accomplished some major improvements such as PROJECTIONs, ClickHouse-ETL, Balanced JBOD with HA, StringHashMap, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/anna_widenius/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/anna_widenius/</guid><description>Anna Widenius is a Chief of Sta in the MariaDB Foundation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/brian_olsen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/brian_olsen/</guid><description>Brian is a U.S. Marine turned software engineer and developer advocate working to foster the open-source Trino community. Brian spent four years as a data engineer at a cybersecurity company working on pipeline maintenance and query optimization. While in this role, Brian was responsible for maintaining data pipelines and migrations to include replacing some legacy data warehousing systems to use open-source Trino. Brian is a published author in ACM and IEEE geospatial database conferences.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/carsten_thalheimer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/carsten_thalheimer/</guid><description>Carsten Thalheimer has worked for over 20 years in IT industry world-leading technology companies, focusing on many aspects of a technology business. He worked for Integrata AG, SCO Group Inc., Tarantella Inc. and Sun Microsystems Inc. His long-standing passion for open-source technology led him to Open-/Star Oce and Cloud Oce in Sun Microsystems/Oracle. In 2011 he joined the MySQL GBU as a Solution Engineer helping leading customers across EMEA to successfully shape their projects.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/christoph_bussler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/christoph_bussler/</guid><description>Chris was always fascinated by systems and data integration between on-premises systems, clouds, and their combination. As a Solutions Architect at Google Cloud (Google, Inc.) he is focusing on databases, data migration, multi-cloud database deployments, and data integration in enterprise customer settings. Earlier in his career, Chris contributed to Enterprise Application System Integration (EAI), Business-to-Business Integration (B2B) as well as workflow management. In addition to implementing these technologies, he wrote several books on these topics and is publishing actively (see his professional page at www.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/dave_stokes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/dave_stokes/</guid><description>Dave Stokes is a MySQL Community Manager and the author of MySQL &amp;amp; JSON - A Practical Programming Guide</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/frederic_descamps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/frederic_descamps/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;@lefred&amp;rdquo; has been consulting OpenSource and MySQL for almost 20 years. After graduating in Management Information Technology, Frédéric Descamps started his career as a developer for an ERP under HPUX. He will then opt for a career in the world of open-source by joining one of the first Belgian start-up dedicated 100% to free projects around GNU/Linux. It is in 2011 that lefred joined Percona, one of the leading MySQL-based specialists.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/georgi_kodinov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/georgi_kodinov/</guid><description>Georgi &amp;ldquo;Joro&amp;rdquo; Kodinov has been working on MySQL for more than 10 years. He&amp;rsquo;s leading the Server General team that deals with security, performance monitoring and the mysql client server protocol. Before working on databases Joro was serving as an IT manager for a Bulgarian bank.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/giuseppe_maxia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/giuseppe_maxia/</guid><description>Formerly at MySQL AB, and then through acquisitions at Sun Microsystems and Oracle, and currently at VMware through a merge.
I am active member of the MySQL community and long timer open source enthusiast. During the past decades I have worked in various IT related elds, with focus on databases, software development, quality assurance, and system administration. Fluent in Italian, English, Go, Spanish, SQL, Bash, and good speaker of C, French, and Perl.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/jim_tommaney/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/jim_tommaney/</guid><description>Currently performance tuning at Databricks. Previously architect of InniDB (now available as MariaDB Columnstore)
Hands-on experience delivering solutions across verticals including Telco, Mobile Marketing, CRM, Genomics, fraud analytics and more.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/johannes_schluter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/johannes_schluter/</guid><description>Johannes Schlüter is a Software Engineering Manager in Oracle&amp;rsquo;s MySQL Team. After development and management for different MySQL Connectors, he is now leading a new team, working on improving the MySQL experience in Cloud environments. Johannes is a long term Open Source contributor, outside MySQL mostly known as Core Developer and Release Manager for the PHP programming language and runtime.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/justin_swanhart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/justin_swanhart/</guid><description>Justin Swanhart has over 20 years of experience working with database technologies. He is the author of WarpSQL, ShardQuery, Flexviews, and PHP-SQL-Parser. Currently the CEO of LeapDB, LLC, a company developing software as a service MySQL and MariaDB solutions for materialized views and streaming SQL queries, Justin was platform DBA at Yahoo!, a consultant, and trainer at Percona, a consultant at Proven Scaling, and a database engineer at Etsy, among other roles.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/kaj_arno/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/kaj_arno/</guid><description>Kaj Arnö is CEO of the MariaDB Foundation. He is a software industry generalist, having served as VP Professional Services, VP Engineering, CIO and VP Community Relations of MySQL AB prior to the acquisition by Sun Microsystems. At Sun, Kaj served as MySQL Ambassador to Sun and Sun VP of Database Community. Initiator of Projekt Fredrika, about Swedish Finland on Wikipedia. Past founder, CEO and 14 year main entrepreneur of Polycon Ab (Finland).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/kenny_gryp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/kenny_gryp/</guid><description>MySQL Product Manager focussing on InnoDB, Replication and all things High Availability.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/luis_dias/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/luis_dias/</guid><description>Oracle dba last 15 years Mysql dba since&amp;hellip;. the pandemic startup</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/matthew_formosa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/matthew_formosa/</guid><description>Matthew is an experienced Data Engineer having worked on several Big Data applications within various domains, including Gaming and FinTech. Being an AWS certified solutions architect, he is naturally highly comfortable working with AWS solutions, as well as Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, and the Hadoop Ecosystem amongst other technologies.
Matthew is most skilled in Java Spring, Scala and Python. Moreover, Matthew is currently reading a Masters Degree in Artificial Intelligence (FinTech) and is graduated with B.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/rachel_pedreschi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/rachel_pedreschi/</guid><description>A “Big Data Geek-ette,” No stranger to the world of high-performance databases and data warehouses, Rachel has more than 20 years of business intelligence and data engineering experience, and is a Cassandra, Vertica, Informix and Redbrick certified DBA on top of her work with Druid. Rachel has an M.B.A. from San Francisco State University and a B.A. in Mathematics from University of California, Santa Cruz.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_bindar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_bindar/</guid><description>Robert started working for the MariaDB Foundation in 2018 as a server developer. His main focus is divided between server development and helping the community contribute faster and more efficiently to the MariaDB codebase. Robert is based mostly in Brasov, Romania.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_hodges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_hodges/</guid><description>Robert Hodges has worked on database systems since 1983. During that he has loved, worked on, and occasionally despised 20 dierent DBMS types. His technical interests include data, distributed systems, virtualization technology, and security. He is currently CEO of Altinity, which supports and runs ClickHouse for enterprises.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/shashank_agarwal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/shashank_agarwal/</guid><description>Googld Cloud Architect with experience of working with bigdata complex, distributed applications based. Experience in designing and implementing solutions. Also certified GCP Cloud Architect, Java Developer and Web Components Developer.
Good understanding of the software development lifecycle (Jenkins CI), experience in establishing the development and release process (Maven, Git, Nexus) and system automation (Chef). Awesome experience with metrics collection and automated service monitoring using statsd, grfanana and Syren.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/srini_kadamati/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/srini_kadamati/</guid><description>Googld Cloud Architect with experience of working with bigdata complex, distributed applications based. Experience in designing and implementing solutions. Also certified GCP Cloud Architect, Java Developer and Web Components Developer.
Good understanding of the software development lifecycle (Jenkins CI), experience in establishing the development and release process (Maven, Git, Nexus) and system automation (Chef). Awesome experience with metrics collection and automated service monitoring using statsd, grfanana and Syren.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/stephen_borg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/stephen_borg/</guid><description>Stephen has had a career in technology for online and retail gambling, having worked close to business for a number of B2C and B2B providers. Sound background in technology, delivering affiliate and gambling platforms using both .NET and Java frameworks.
For the past 8 years Stephen has grown fond of Big Data and has led several high production transaction data lake projects both for on premise and on the cloud architectures.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/tiago_alves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/tiago_alves/</guid><description>Tiago is a software engineering manager for MySQL NDB Cluster. Tiago is passionate about software engineering with focus on software quality.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/vicentiu_ciorbaru/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/vicentiu_ciorbaru/</guid><description>Vicentiu works at the MariaDB Foundation as a Software Engineer and Team Lead. He focuses on optimizer development, but has also worked on other parts of the MariaDB Server. Vicențiu has been part of the MariaDB ecosystem since 2013, where he first contributed Roles to MariaDB. Over the years, Vicențiu has coded numerous features and helped with the packaging of MariaDB for various distributions. Recently, Vicențiu has also been involved in the QA process of MariaDB, by contributing to https://buildbot.</description></item><item><title>Eno Compton</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/eno_compton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/eno_compton/</guid><description>Kyle Davis is the Senior Developer Advocate with Open Distro for Elasticsearch at AWS. While being a relative newcomer to AWS, Kyle has a long history with software development and databases. When not working, Kyle enjoys 3D printing, and getting his hand dirty in his Edmonton, Alberta-based home garden.</description></item><item><title>Eno Compton</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/shachar_guz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/shachar_guz/</guid><description>Shachar is a product manager at Google Cloud, he works on the Cloud Database Migration Service. Shachar worked in various product and engineering roles and shares a true passion about data and helping customers get the most out of their data. Shachar was formerly a product manager for Alooma who got acquired by Google in 2019. He is passionate about building products that make cumbersome processes simple and straightforward and helping companies adopt Cloud technologies to accelerate their business.</description></item><item><title>federico_razzoli</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/federico_razzoli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/federico_razzoli/</guid><description>Passionate with databases, automation and open source. Federico was active in MariaDB and MySQL communities for years. He started Vettabase, a database automation and consulting company.</description></item><item><title>ian_gilfillan</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ian_gilfillan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ian_gilfillan/</guid><description>Ian first came across MySQL in the 90s, upgrading from mSQL while developing South Africas' first online grocery store, and teaching and developing internet programming courses. He was lead developer for South Africa’s largest media company from 2000, and wrote the book Mastering MySQL 4 in 2002. He wrote regular columns on MySQL and web programming in the 2000s, before founding and developing an online organic food co-operative in 2005.</description></item><item><title>Jan Kleinert</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/jan_kleinert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/jan_kleinert/</guid><description>Jan Kleinert leads a team of Developer Advocates as part of Google Cloud, focusing on Compute and Databases. Prior to joining Google, she worked in a variety of roles ranging from developer relations to web analytics and conversion optimization.</description></item><item><title>Kyle Davis</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/kyle_davis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/kyle_davis/</guid><description>Kyle Davis is the Senior Developer Advocate with Open Distro for Elasticsearch at AWS. While being a relative newcomer to AWS, Kyle has a long history with software development and databases. When not working, Kyle enjoys 3D printing, and getting his hand dirty in his Edmonton, Alberta-based home garden.</description></item></channel></rss>