<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Speakers on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/</link><description>Recent content in Speakers on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/alexander_korotkov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/alexander_korotkov/</guid><description>Alexander Korotkov is a PostgreSQL Major Contributor &amp;amp; Committer, and Ph.D. in computer science. He contributed many fields of PostgreSQL including indexing, statistics, concurrency, extensibility, and more. In 2015 Alexander co-founded and became the technical chief and development officer at Postgres Professional in Moscow. He is the inventor behind OrioleDB who seeks to deliver the solutions to PostgreSQL wicked problems.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/alexander_zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/alexander_zaitsev/</guid><description>Alexander is a co-founder of Altinity. He has 20 years of engineering and engineering management experience in several international companies. Alexander is an expert in high scale analytics systems design and implementation. He designed and deployed petabyte-scale data warehouses, including one of the earliest ClickHouse deployments outside of Yandex.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/alexey_milovidov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/alexey_milovidov/</guid><description>Alexey Milovidov was the original designer of ClickHouse, starting from its inception in 2008. He is an expert on high-performance C++, analytic applications, and SQL databases. Alexey is the lead committer of the ClickHouse open source project on Github. He leads the ClickHouse development team at Yandex and speaks regularly at community events</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/alkin_tezuysal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/alkin_tezuysal/</guid><description>Alkin Tezuysal has extensive experience in enterprise relational databases, working in various sectors for large corporations. With more than 20 years of industry experience, he has acquired skills for managing large projects from the ground up to production. For the past decade, he&amp;rsquo;s been focused on e-commerce, SaaS, and MySQL technologies. Alkin has managed and architected database topologies for high-volume sites at eBay Intl. He has several years of experience in 24X7 support and operational tasks and improving database systems for major companies.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/amanda_brock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/amanda_brock/</guid><description>Amanda is CEO of OpenUK, (@amandabrockUK @openuk_UK), representing the business of Open Technology in the UK. That&amp;rsquo;s open source software, open hardware and open data”; OpenUK; European Representative of the world’s biggest defensive patent pool, the Open Invention Network; OASIS Open Projects' Advisory Council Member (open source and open standards); Advisory Board Member KDE; Charity Trustee Creative Crieff; and a member of various commercial and start up Advisory Boards including Mimoto as well as mentoring C Suite individuals.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/amos_bird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/amos_bird/</guid><description>Amos Bird (郑天祺) is a software engineer at KuaiShou Technologies in China. He graduated from the Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Science, with a Doctor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Database Systems. He is an active ClickHouse contributor for over more than three years, and have accomplished some major improvements such as PROJECTIONs, ClickHouse-ETL, Balanced JBOD with HA, StringHashMap, etc.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/andrey_brodin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/andrey_brodin/</guid><description>Andrey is a software engineer, computer scientist, developer at Yandex, Ph.D., associated professor at Ural Federal University, co-founder of Octonica company. He is interested in backup technologies and data indexing and also teaches at Yandex School for Data Analysis and UrFU. His recent talk at Percona Live featured the architecture of point in time recovery with WAL-G in the cloud.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/andrey_minkin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/andrey_minkin/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/anna_widenius/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/anna_widenius/</guid><description>Anna Widenius is a Chief of Sta in the MariaDB Foundation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/anton_bystrov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/anton_bystrov/</guid><description>Engineer, working with monitoring.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/anurag_gupta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/anurag_gupta/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ariel_weisberg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ariel_weisberg/</guid><description>Currently working on Presto @ Facebook.
Previous was Apache Cassandra committer and PMC member
Before that I was the third engineer to start working on VoltDB back when it was incubating in Vertica and we called it Horizontica.
I enjoy developing scalable, reliable, consistently fast distributed systems and applications built on distributed systems as well as enabling other developers to be successful in selecting and using said systems through design, documentation, and implementation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/avi_press/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/avi_press/</guid><description>Avi is the founder &amp;amp; CEO of Scarf, a software engineer, and open-source advocate. Scarf is building advanced maintainer-friendly tools for open-source software distribution, analytics, and commercialization. Software engineer, functional programming enthusiast, open-source maintainer Former engineer at Pandora. Among other things, I built a concert recommendation system with Songkick and Ticketfly integrations to help people find great concerts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/barrett_chambers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/barrett_chambers/</guid><description>Barrett Chambers is the Director of Solutions Engineering at Percona. Prior to joining Percona, he acquired a range of full-stack perspectives as an Application Support Specialist, Operational DBA, SaaS engineer, and Solutions Engineer. Barrett has over 6 years of experience designing database solutions with consideration for high availability, disaster recovery, and performance for MySQL, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB environments.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/bart_farrell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/bart_farrell/</guid><description>CNCF Ambassador. Data on Kubernetes (@Dokcommunity) Community Leader, amateur rapper, tech from the human side. My bananas are my own.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/beinan_wang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/beinan_wang/</guid><description>Beinan builds large scale distributed SQL systems (presto&amp;amp;hive) for Twitter&amp;rsquo;s data platform team.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/brian_olsen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/brian_olsen/</guid><description>Brian is a U.S. Marine turned software engineer and developer advocate working to foster the open-source Trino community. Brian spent four years as a data engineer at a cybersecurity company working on pipeline maintenance and query optimization. While in this role, Brian was responsible for maintaining data pipelines and migrations to include replacing some legacy data warehousing systems to use open-source Trino. Brian is a published author in ACM and IEEE geospatial database conferences.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/brian_walters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/brian_walters/</guid><description>Brian has over 20 years of experience in the database and technology space. He holds a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Organizational Leadership. Brian&amp;rsquo;s career has included roles as Database Architect, Solutions Architect, Product Manager, and Pre-Sales Engineer. Brian spent 7 years at Teradata on their product engineering and product management teams followed by 7 years with Oracle as a Principal Sales Consultant. Brian is currently working at Percona as the Director of Solution Engineering.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/bruce_momjian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/bruce_momjian/</guid><description>Bruce Momjian is co-founder and core team member of the PostgreSQL Global Development Group, and has worked on PostgreSQL since 1996. He has been employed by EDB since 2006. He has spoken at many international open-source conferences and is the author of PostgreSQL: Introduction and Concepts, published by Addison-Wesley. Prior to his involvement with PostgreSQL, Bruce worked as a consultant, developing custom database applications for some of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest law firms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/carsten_thalheimer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/carsten_thalheimer/</guid><description>Carsten Thalheimer has worked for over 20 years in IT industry world-leading technology companies, focusing on many aspects of a technology business. He worked for Integrata AG, SCO Group Inc., Tarantella Inc. and Sun Microsystems Inc. His long-standing passion for open-source technology led him to Open-/Star Oce and Cloud Oce in Sun Microsystems/Oracle. In 2011 he joined the MySQL GBU as a Solution Engineer helping leading customers across EMEA to successfully shape their projects.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/charly_batista/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/charly_batista/</guid><description>Charly Batista is currently PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona. Possesses over twelve (12) years of experience in various areas of IT including Database Administration, Data Analysis, Systems Analysis and Software Development. Strong analytical skills combined with experience in object oriented programming techniques. Technical Leader for more than four (4) years for the Developer Team. Born in Brazil and now living in Shanghai-China.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/christoph_bussler/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/christoph_bussler/</guid><description>Chris was always fascinated by systems and data integration between on-premises systems, clouds, and their combination. As a Solutions Architect at Google Cloud (Google, Inc.) he is focusing on databases, data migration, multi-cloud database deployments, and data integration in enterprise customer settings. Earlier in his career, Chris contributed to Enterprise Application System Integration (EAI), Business-to-Business Integration (B2B) as well as workflow management. In addition to implementing these technologies, he wrote several books on these topics and is publishing actively (see his professional page at www.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/chunxu_tang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/chunxu_tang/</guid><description>Chunxu is a software engineer in Twitter&amp;rsquo;s Interactive Query team where he works on developing and maintaining Presto and Druid services. He received his doctoral degree from Syracuse University, where he did research on machine learning and distributed collaboration systems.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/clint_dovholuk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/clint_dovholuk/</guid><description>Experienced Director Of Software Development with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Strong professional skilled in IoT, java, golang, dotnet and a proven track record delivering high-quality features on-time. Clint enjoy being a mentor and others with technical challenges.
Currently working with a not-quite-startup in the exciting space of zero-trust app-embedded security via the openziti project. Developer and customer advocacy is his passion though he does whatever needs to get done.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/colin_charles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/colin_charles/</guid><description>Colin Charles is a Consultant at Codership, the makers of Galera Cluster. Previously, Colin was on the founding team of MariaDB Server, and has been around the MySQL ecosystem including being an early employee at MySQL, and worked actively on the Fedora and OpenOffice.org projects. Colin has been a MySQL user since 2000.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/corey_hulen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/corey_hulen/</guid><description>Corey is CTO and Co-Founder of Mattermost, Inc. which is an enterprise messaging workspace for teams to collaborate securely and effectively. He previously founded Tempo AI, an artificial intelligence startup. Earlier in his career, Corey served as engineering manager and architect for Microsoft Office. He was also an architect for VerticalNet, a publicly traded enterprise software company providing supply chain management solutions for the Global 2000.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/daniel_black/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/daniel_black/</guid><description>After a reasonable amount of time doing development and IT security work, Daniel landed a DBA Consultant job and loved it.
After writing a few too many bug fixes without a client to bill them to, he joined IBM to make MariaDB and MySQL scale on IBM POWER.
The love for the community brought him to MariaDB Foundation where he embraces the innovation of contributors and users to make MariaDB better for everyone.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/daniel_seybold/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/daniel_seybold/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/dave_stokes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/dave_stokes/</guid><description>Dave joined Percona last February 2022. Dave is MySQL Community Manager and the author of MySQL &amp;amp; JSON - A Practical Programming Guide</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/david_ducos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/david_ducos/</guid><description>David studied Computer Science in National University of La Plata and has worked as a DBA consultant since 2008. For 3 years he worked with a worldwide platform of free classifieds up until he joined Percona&amp;rsquo;s consulting team in November 2014. David lives in La Plata, near Buenos Aires, Argentina and in his free time loves to spend time with his family. He is also the maintainer of MyDumper.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/david_duncan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/david_duncan/</guid><description>David Duncan is helpful answering questions or solving problems involving Cloud systems and the use of support tools on Fedora and Fedora Cloud images. He is currently working as Principal Partner Solutions Architect and technical Linux lead focused on Platform Ecosystem Partners. Keenly focused on open source software and upstream contributions. Strong connection to development and configuration process.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/david_gonzalez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/david_gonzalez/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/david_murphy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/david_murphy/</guid><description>David is a Principal Architect in SRE, Database and Cloud. Previously he was the Practice Manager for MongoDB at Percona, and before that, he was one of the early members for ObjectRocket the leader in DBaaS for MongoDB specializing in performance. Other previous roles include Database System and Technology Architect as Electronic Arts. As a speaker, he prefers to focus on solutions in the real world to issues, to this point he tries to regularly publish code to help everyone use his solutions or have ideas to inspire their own.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/david_zhao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/david_zhao/</guid><description>Zhao Wei (David Zhao) has been working on database kernels throughout his career. He worked on Oracle Berkeley DB and MySQL in the two outstanding global teams in Oracle during 2007 and 2015, and he worked in Tencent to upgrade its TDSQL from a table sharding solution to a full-fledged distributed DBMS.
He left Tencent and started the kunlun distributed DBMS project and you can find more about this project in Kunlun and ZettaDB</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/denis_magda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/denis_magda/</guid><description>Denis Magda has spent half of his career working on distributed systems, applications, and databases. His experience spans from the development of distributed database engines and high-performance applications to training and education on the topic of distributed and cloud computing. Presently, Denis runs the Developer Relations team at Yugabyte and serves as a PMC Member for Apache Ignite. He started his professional career at Sun Microsystems and Oracle, where he led a Java development group and worked on technology evangelism efforts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/denys_kondratenko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/denys_kondratenko/</guid><description>I am Engineering Manager in Percona working on Percona Monitoring and Management solution.
My past experience is:
distributed storage as engineering manager: SUSE - Ceph; Seagate - Lustre Monitoring experience in Massive Solutions Embedded engineer in Mindspeed before that I love Linux, run full Wayland, openSUSEway (sway) and Fedora</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/derek_downey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/derek_downey/</guid><description>As a technologist excited about open source database systems and the businesses that they power, Derek is enthusiastic about efficiency through automation, Operational Visibility, and the adoption of Cloud Technologies.
Derek has helped with many customers implement automation for their critical database tasks.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/dipti_borkar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/dipti_borkar/</guid><description>Dipti is the co-founder and CPO of Ahana with over 15 years experience in distributed data and database technology including relational, NoSQL and federated systems. She is also the Presto Foundation Outreach Chairperson. Prior to Ahana, Dipti held VP roles at Alluxio, Kinetica and Couchbase. At Alluxio, she was Vice President of Products and at Couchbase she held several leadership positions there including VP, Product Marketing, Head of Global Technical Sales and Head of Product Management.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/divyanshu_soni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/divyanshu_soni/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/dor_laor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/dor_laor/</guid><description>Dor Laor is the CEO of ScyllaDB. Previously, Dor was part of the founding team of the KVM hypervisor under Qumranet that was acquired by Red Hat. At Red Hat Dor was managing the KVM and Xen development for several years. Dor holds an MSc from the Technion and a PhD in snowboarding.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/dr_gavin_mendel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/dr_gavin_mendel/</guid><description>Dr Gavin Mendel-Gleason is CTO of TerminusDB. He is a former research fellow at Trinity College Dublin in the School of Statistics and Computer Science. His research focuses on databases, logic and verification in software engineering. His work includes contributing to the Seshat global historical databank, an ambitious project to record and analyse patterns in human history. He is the inventor of the Web Object Query Language and the primary architect of TerminusDB.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/edith_puclla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/edith_puclla/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/eduardo_krieg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/eduardo_krieg/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/evgeniy_patlan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/evgeniy_patlan/</guid><description>Evgeniy Patlan is Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering Team at Percona. He is experienced Build And Release Engineer, Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Perl, JavaScript, Python, Session Initiation Protocol (SIP), SOAP, and Linux System Administration. Strong engineering professional with a specialist focused in Computer systems, Programming, System Administrating, Network Technologies.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/francesco_nobilia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/francesco_nobilia/</guid><description>Francesco is an enthusiastic engineer focused on building the next generation of a self-service and cost-effective streaming data platform. Event-Drive addicted. Apache Kafka fun. Kafka Summit and Meetup speaker. Currently, he is Principal Engineer at Nutmeg.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/francisco_bordenave/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/francisco_bordenave/</guid><description>Francisco has been working in MySQL since 2006, he has worked for several companies which includes Health Care industry to Gaming. Over the last years he has been working as a database architect which help him to acquire a lot of technical and multi-cultural skills</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/frederic_descamps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/frederic_descamps/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;@lefred&amp;rdquo; has been consulting OpenSource and MySQL for almost 20 years. After graduating in Management Information Technology, Frédéric Descamps started his career as a developer for an ERP under HPUX. He will then opt for a career in the world of open-source by joining one of the first Belgian start-up dedicated 100% to free projects around GNU/Linux. It is in 2011 that lefred joined Percona, one of the leading MySQL-based specialists.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/gabe_weiss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/gabe_weiss/</guid><description>Gabe Weiss had a first career as an actor and shifted into tech. He has found a job that neatly marries both of his careers into one job. Being a developer advocate means he gets the freedom to continually learn new skills and new ways of doing things, and then turn around and teach others how to do it. Through speaking in public, videos and blogs, he gets to reach a wide audience.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/gabi_ferrara/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/gabi_ferrara/</guid><description>Hi, I am Gabi! I am a Data Engineer working as a Developer Advocate.
My mission is to make database development not only a task achievable for DBAs but the every day developer. Questions? My Twitter DM are open: http://twitter.com/gabidavila</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/gabriel_ciciliani/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/gabriel_ciciliani/</guid><description>Gabriel has been dedicated to databases as a DBA and consultant for the last 15 years. He has led and participated in multiple projects across many technologies, including Oracle, MySQL, SQL Server and MongoDB. Gabriel defines himself as an automation super fan and he contributed to the development of two custom DBaaS platforms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/gary_stafford/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/gary_stafford/</guid><description>Gary is a solutions architect at AWS where he works with some of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest Enterprise customers to understand their business drivers, assess application portfolios, and design reliable and cost-effective cloud native architectures. Previously he was an enterprise architect at Paychex and a Sr. Manager of Technology Architecture Delivery at Accenture. He holds 8 AWS certifications.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/georgi_kodinov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/georgi_kodinov/</guid><description>Georgi &amp;ldquo;Joro&amp;rdquo; Kodinov has been working on MySQL for more than 10 years. He&amp;rsquo;s leading the Server General team that deals with security, performance monitoring and the mysql client server protocol. Before working on databases Joro was serving as an IT manager for a Bulgarian bank.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/giuseppe_maxia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/giuseppe_maxia/</guid><description>Formerly at MySQL AB, and then through acquisitions at Sun Microsystems and Oracle, and currently at VMware through a merge.
I am active member of the MySQL community and long timer open source enthusiast. During the past decades I have worked in various IT related elds, with focus on databases, software development, quality assurance, and system administration. Fluent in Italian, English, Go, Spanish, SQL, Bash, and good speaker of C, French, and Perl.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/guillermo_ortega/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/guillermo_ortega/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/guy_harrison/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/guy_harrison/</guid><description>Guy Harrison is CTO at Southbank Software, a database and blockchain tools company. He is the author of MongoDB Performance Tuning, Next Generation Databases, MySQL Stored Procedure Programming and many other books, articles and presentations on database technology. He writes the &amp;ldquo;MongoDB Matters&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Emerging Technologies&amp;rdquo; columns at Database Trends and Applications.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/hamid_akhtar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/hamid_akhtar/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/hemant_bhanawat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/hemant_bhanawat/</guid><description>Founded Falarica Analytics which was acquired by YugabyteDB. Founding engineer with SnappyData which was acquired by TIBCO. More than 18 years of experience in building and delivering products like distributed databases, distributed query processing engines and distributed KV stores.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/henrik_ingo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/henrik_ingo/</guid><description>Open Source expert, with 13+ years experience with open source databases. One of the leading European experts both in MySQL and MongoDB databases. Particular interest in distributed systems and performance. I also have experience from several business management roles, such as managing 25 mobile developers and as COO and Advisor at 2 startups in the MySQL space.
I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed code to Linux, Drupal and impress.js. I&amp;rsquo;ve volunteered on the OSI license review process almost from the beginning.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/himank_chaudhary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/himank_chaudhary/</guid><description>Himank is the Tech Lead of Docstore at Uber. His primary focus area is building distributed databases that scale along with Uber&amp;rsquo;s hyper-growth. Prior to Uber, he worked at Yahoo in the mail backend team to build a metadata store. Himank holds a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science from the State University of New York with a specialization in distributed systems. Himank has proven ability to learn challenging concepts quickly and he has developed competencies in diverse areas.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ibrar_ahmed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ibrar_ahmed/</guid><description>Ibrar Ahmed is a Software Architect in Percona LLC. Prior to coming to open source development, he had vast experience in software design and development. His main focus was on system-level embedded development. After joining EnterpriseDB in 2006, an Enterprise PostgreSQL company, he started his career in open source development specifically in PostgreSQL. He has contributed to the PostgreSQL community as well as other open source communities. His contribution ranges from the main performance feature enhancements to various PostgreSQL modules.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ivan_groenwold/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ivan_groenwold/</guid><description>More than 15 years providing support to mission critical environments for first line companies. Experience in various on-prem and cloud platforms running Oracle, MySQL and MongoDB databases. Ivan regularly present talks at conferences and contribute to open-source projects.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/jean_da_silva/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/jean_da_silva/</guid><description>Jean joined Percona as a Support Engineer in 2020. Before joining the team, he worked in a mission-critical environment for 4 years, helping administrate databases like MySQL, MongoDB, and Oracle DB. Specializing in Database Engineering, and Big Data, he likes to watch Formula 1 in his free time.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/jean_joseph/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/jean_joseph/</guid><description>Jean Joseph is a Data Engineer/DBA, Speaker, IT Event Planner, Blogger, Data Driven Community Builder, Founder &amp;amp; main organizer of Cloud Data Driven User Group &amp;amp; Future Data Driven Summit, highly experienced in Traditional Database, and Big Data technologies with a history of successes in designing, implementing complex technical projects for diverse businesses in various stages of their development.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/jeremy_frenay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/jeremy_frenay/</guid><description>Jeremy Frenay is an Engineering manager at Babylon Health. He has been leading Babylon’s Data Operations efforts since late 2017, building the Kafka based data infrastructure, the automation and the tooling required to support teams of software and data engineers working on data integration pipelines in a cloud-native environment.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/jim_tommaney/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/jim_tommaney/</guid><description>Currently performance tuning at Databricks. Previously architect of InniDB (now available as MariaDB Columnstore)
Hands-on experience delivering solutions across verticals including Telco, Mobile Marketing, CRM, Genomics, fraud analytics and more.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/jobin_augustine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/jobin_augustine/</guid><description>Jobin Augustine is a PostgreSQL expert and Open Source advocate and has more than 19 years of working experience as consultant, architect, administrator, writer, and trainer in PostgreSQL, Oracle and other database technologies. He has always been an active participant in the Open Source communities and his main focus area is database performance and optimization. He is a contributor to various Open Source Projects and is an active blogger and loves to code in C++ and Python.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/johannes_schluter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/johannes_schluter/</guid><description>Johannes Schlüter is a Software Engineering Manager in Oracle&amp;rsquo;s MySQL Team. After development and management for different MySQL Connectors, he is now leading a new team, working on improving the MySQL experience in Cloud environments. Johannes is a long term Open Source contributor, outside MySQL mostly known as Core Developer and Release Manager for the PHP programming language and runtime.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/justin_swanhart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/justin_swanhart/</guid><description>Justin Swanhart has over 20 years of experience working with database technologies. He is the author of WarpSQL, ShardQuery, Flexviews, and PHP-SQL-Parser. Currently the CEO of LeapDB, LLC, a company developing software as a service MySQL and MariaDB solutions for materialized views and streaming SQL queries, Justin was platform DBA at Yahoo!, a consultant, and trainer at Percona, a consultant at Proven Scaling, and a database engineer at Etsy, among other roles.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/kai_wagner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/kai_wagner/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/kaj_arno/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/kaj_arno/</guid><description>Kaj Arnö is CEO of the MariaDB Foundation. He is a software industry generalist, having served as VP Professional Services, VP Engineering, CIO and VP Community Relations of MySQL AB prior to the acquisition by Sun Microsystems. At Sun, Kaj served as MySQL Ambassador to Sun and Sun VP of Database Community. Initiator of Projekt Fredrika, about Swedish Finland on Wikipedia. Past founder, CEO and 14 year main entrepreneur of Polycon Ab (Finland).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/karthik_appigatla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/karthik_appigatla/</guid><description>Karthik Appigatla has been working on various large scale data stores for a decade primarily focused on MySQL. Currently, he has been working for LinkedIn for the last 5 years. Prior to LinkedIn, he worked for Yahoo, Pythian and Percona where he was responsible for helping clients scale their databases.
He authored the MySQL 8 cookbook covering the new features and performance tuning of MySQL 8 - https://www.amazon.in/MySQL-8-Cookbook-Karthik-Appigatla-ebook/dp/B0753D434Q</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/karthik_ranganathan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/karthik_ranganathan/</guid><description>Karthik was one of the original database engineers at Facebook responsible for building distributed databases including Cassandra and HBase. He is an Apache HBase committer, and also an early contributor to Cassandra, before it was open-sourced by Facebook. He is currently the co-founder and CTO of the company behind YugabyteDB, a fully open-source distributed SQL database for building cloud-native and geo-distributed applications.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/karthik_satchitanand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/karthik_satchitanand/</guid><description>Karthik Satchitanand is one of the maintainers of the CNCF sandbox project LitmusChaos. He is passionate about all things Kubernetes, and is generally interested in DevOps, storage performance/benchmarking &amp;amp; chaos engineering.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/kedar_vaijanapurkar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/kedar_vaijanapurkar/</guid><description>Kedar is an experienced Database Consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. He&amp;rsquo;s been working with MySQL ecosystem and interested in expanding his knowledge in Cloud Databases. He lives in Vadodara, India with kids, Aarya &amp;amp; Rudra and a better half, Madhumita.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/kenny_gryp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/kenny_gryp/</guid><description>MySQL Product Manager focussing on InnoDB, Replication and all things High Availability.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/lenz_grimmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/lenz_grimmer/</guid><description>Lenz Grimmer supports and leads the engineering teams at Percona that work on server products like Percona Server for MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL and related components. He&amp;rsquo;s been involved in Linux and Open Source technologies in various roles and capacities since the mid-90s and has worked at companies like SUSE, MySQL, Sun Microsystems and Oracle.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/leonardo_bacchi_fernandes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/leonardo_bacchi_fernandes/</guid><description>Leonardo joined Percona as a Support Engineer in 2019 where he works mainly with MySQL and MongoDB. Leonardo has a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science and has been working with databases for the last 8 years.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/liquan_pei/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/liquan_pei/</guid><description>Liquan Pei is currently a Senior Software Engineer, Database Kernel at PingCAP. PingCAP is founded by the team that built TiDB.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/lorna_mitchell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/lorna_mitchell/</guid><description>Lorna Mitchell is currently working as ead of Developer Relations at Aiven. Lorna is a Developer Experience and Open Source specialist. She writes, speaks, and codes, enabling and educating developers everywhere.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/luis_dias/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/luis_dias/</guid><description>Oracle dba last 15 years Mysql dba since&amp;hellip;. the pandemic startup</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/lukas_eder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/lukas_eder/</guid><description>Lukas Eder is the CEO and founder of Data Geekery GmbH, the company behind JooQ an open source Java framework that gives you an API that allows you to write SQL statements through natural Java api calls.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/maksim_gramin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/maksim_gramin/</guid><description>Applicant 1: Maksim Gramin is a software consultant, researcher and developer passionate about Databases and SQL</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/marcelo_altmann/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/marcelo_altmann/</guid><description>Marcelo Altmann is a C++ Software Engineer on MySQL related products @ Percona. At Percona he has also worked as a Senior Support Engineer and a Tech Lead of the Support Team. Prior to joining Percona , he worked as a MySQL DBA at Ireland’s CCTLD, and worked as a DBA/PHP developer in Brazil. Its focuses are Database Administration, specifically MySQL.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/marcos_albe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/marcos_albe/</guid><description>After 12 years working as a developer for local and remote firms, Marcos decided to pursuit true love and become full time DBA, so he has been doing MySQL Support at Percona for the past 8+ years, providing lead web properties with advise on anything-MySQL and in-depth system performance analysis.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/mario_garcia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/mario_garcia/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/matt_farina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/matt_farina/</guid><description>Matt Farina is a Distinguished Engineer, driving development of new open source solutions and supporting open source software leveraged by SUSE. Matt is a software engineer and architect primarily focused on cloud applications, web applications, and services. He is also and author and speaker.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/matt_yonkovit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/matt_yonkovit/</guid><description>Matt is currently working as the Head of Open Source Strategy (HOSS) for Percona, a leader in open source database software and services. He has over 15 years of experience in the open source industry including over 10 years of executive-level experience leading open source teams. Matt’s experience merges the technical and business aspects of the open source database experience with both a passion for hands on development and management and the leadership of building strong teams.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/matthew_formosa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/matthew_formosa/</guid><description>Matthew is an experienced Data Engineer having worked on several Big Data applications within various domains, including Gaming and FinTech. Being an AWS certified solutions architect, he is naturally highly comfortable working with AWS solutions, as well as Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, and the Hadoop Ecosystem amongst other technologies.
Matthew is most skilled in Java Spring, Scala and Python. Moreover, Matthew is currently reading a Masters Degree in Artificial Intelligence (FinTech) and is graduated with B.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/matthias_crauwels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/matthias_crauwels/</guid><description>Matthias Crauwels is Experienced Database Consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Strong information technology professional skilled in MySQL, PHP, Go and several scripting languages. He brought a talk about &amp;ldquo;MySQL Backup Solutions in 2021&amp;rdquo; during the Percona Live 2021.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/michael_coburn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/michael_coburn/</guid><description>Michael Coburn, is Principal Architect at Percona. Michael joined Percona as a Consultant in 2012 after having worked with high-volume stock photography websites and email service provider platforms. With a foundation in Systems Administration, Michael acted as Product Manager responsible for Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/michel_tricot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/michel_tricot/</guid><description>Michel has been working in data engineering for the past 15 years. As head of integrations and engineering director at Liveramp (NYSE: RAMP), he grew the team responsible for building and scaling the data ingestion and data distribution connectors, syncing 100s TB every day.
In 2020, he co-founded Airbyte, the new open-source data integration platform, with the vision to commoditize data integration pipelines across all industries and organizations.
After just ve months, Airbyte raised $5.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/mike_benshoof/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/mike_benshoof/</guid><description>Michael is currently a US based Technical Account Manager at Percona, originally joining the team as a consultant in 2012. Prior to Percona, Michael spent several years in a DevOps role in a company that developed and maintained a SaaS application specializing in social networking. His experiences include application development and scaling, systems administration, along with database administration and design. He enjoys designing extensible and exible solutions to problems and has a strong background in HA systems.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/morgan_tocker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/morgan_tocker/</guid><description>I joined MySQL AB in January 2006, working remotely from my home in Brisbane, Australia.
I used the opportunity of working remotely to relocate to Canada. In 2008, after Sun Microsystems acquired MySQL, I joined Percona. I later rejoined the MySQL team under Oracle and worked as Product Manager for the MySQL Server until 2017.
I live in the Canadian Rockies with my wife, kids, and dog. I’m a fulltime employee of PingCAP, where we are building a horizontally scalable NewSQL database that speaks the MySQL protocol.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/muhammad_usama/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/muhammad_usama/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/nagavamsi_ponnekanti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/nagavamsi_ponnekanti/</guid><description>Nagavamsi Ponnekanti is Software Engineer at Quora. Vamsi has more than 20 years experience with databases</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/naveed_shaikh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/naveed_shaikh/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/nickolay_ihalainen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/nickolay_ihalainen/</guid><description>Nickolay Ihalainen is currently working as a Senior Technical Support Engineer at Percona He handled emergency and data recovery cases, and for the last several years helped Percona&amp;rsquo;s customers with complex performance issues and MySQL crashes.
Provide any information related to mysql: details/internals/solutions for performance issues Fix performance issues for any Web applications Linux kernel and user space tuning MySQL InnoDb data recovery develop and maintain &amp;ldquo;glue&amp;rdquo; scripts and applications in python, bash, Golang MySQL replication and clustering solutions</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/oleksandr_kuzminskyi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/oleksandr_kuzminskyi/</guid><description>Aleks works at Pinterest on automating its MySQL fleet operation. Before, he worked for Box, Dropbox, and Percona. He believes in Infrastructure as a Code principle and CI/CD with a goal to exterminate toil.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ovais_tariq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ovais_tariq/</guid><description>Engineering leader with 15 years of experience in database infrastructure and site reliability engineering. Currently building the core storage platform and leading production engineering for storage at Uber.
Ovais is a Sr. Manager in the Core Storage team at Uber. He leads the Operational Storage Platform group with a focus on providing a world-class platform that powers all the critical business functions and lines of business at Uber. The platform serves tens of millions of QPS with an availability of 99.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/pandit_prasad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/pandit_prasad/</guid><description>Pandit Prasad is a Principal Product Manager at Amazon RDS. He brings with him 28 years of Hi-Tech industry experience.
Prior to this role, he led the product management for IBM’s Db2, Big Data and Cloud portfolio of products (Monitoring, Automation and IT Analytics). Prior to that he led the global product marketing team at IBM. Earlier, as an IT Architect working for PwC and other consulting companies, he implemented ERP, CRM and Data warehouse applications for Large Enterprise including several Fortune100 companies.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/patrick_mcfadin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/patrick_mcfadin/</guid><description>Patrick McFadin is one of the leading experts of Apache Cassandra and data modeling techniques. As the Chief Evangelist for Apache Cassandra and consultant for DataStax, he has helped build some of the largest and exciting deployments in production. Previous to DataStax, he was Chief Architect at Hobsons and an Oracle DBA/Developer for over 15 years.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/pep_pla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/pep_pla/</guid><description>Pep has been working with databases all his life. Born in a small village by the Mediterranean, he currently lives in Barcelona. He loves tech, traveling, good food, music and, all things NASA. He hates talking about himself in the third person and has a particular sense of humor. Happily married, he is the father of three boys and two cats.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/peter_zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/peter_zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. As one of the foremost experts on MySQL strategy and optimization, Peter leveraged both his technical vision and entrepreneurial skills to grow Percona from a two-person shop to one of the most respected open source companies in the business. A serial entrepreneur, Peter co-founded his rst startup while attending Moscow State University where he majored in Computer Science. Peter is a co-author of High Performance MySQL: Optimization, Backups, and Replication, one of the most popular books on MySQL performance.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/rachel_pedreschi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/rachel_pedreschi/</guid><description>A “Big Data Geek-ette,” No stranger to the world of high-performance databases and data warehouses, Rachel has more than 20 years of business intelligence and data engineering experience, and is a Cassandra, Vertica, Informix and Redbrick certified DBA on top of her work with Druid. Rachel has an M.B.A. from San Francisco State University and a B.A. in Mathematics from University of California, Santa Cruz.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/rahul_malik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/rahul_malik/</guid><description>C++ Software Engineer in Percona</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ravi_shankar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ravi_shankar/</guid><description>Chief Consultant at PassionBytes providing big data consultancy and services in United States and an early adopter of Presto since it has been open sourced by Facebook. Ravi’s passion is to combine/merge various systems/components into a more reusable and innovative platform, reducing proliferation of tools and manual interventions allowing straight through processing of data and expose it for AI/ML applications. Ravi has 25 years of experience as Developer, Senior Architect, Project Manager, Senior Vice President and CTO.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ravikumar_buragapu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ravikumar_buragapu/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/rob_richardson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/rob_richardson/</guid><description>Rob Richardson is a software craftsman building web properties in ASP.NET and Node, React and Vue. He’s a Microsoft MVP, published author, frequent speaker at conferences, user groups, and community events, and a diligent teacher and student of high quality software development. You can find recent talks and musings on https://robrich.org/presentations and follow him on twitter at @rob_rich.
Internationally recognized technical speaker, speaking since 2008 Microsoft MVP since 2014 AZGiveCamp founders Award, 2015 and 2016 Red Gate Database Delivery Panel 2013-2014 Friend of Red Gate since 2009 Microsoft Partner since 2005 Leader, Southeast Valley .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_bindar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_bindar/</guid><description>Robert started working for the MariaDB Foundation in 2018 as a server developer. His main focus is divided between server development and helping the community contribute faster and more efficiently to the MariaDB codebase. Robert is based mostly in Brasov, Romania.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_hodges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_hodges/</guid><description>Robert Hodges has worked on database systems since 1983. During that he has loved, worked on, and occasionally despised 20 dierent DBMS types. His technical interests include data, distributed systems, virtualization technology, and security. He is currently CEO of Altinity, which supports and runs ClickHouse for enterprises.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_reeves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/robert_reeves/</guid><description>Robert Reeves is currently CTO at Liquibase Prior to co-founding Datical (now Liquibase), Robert was a Director at the Austin Technology Incubator. Robert co-founded Phurnace Software in 2005. He invented and created the flagship product, Phurnace Deliver, which provides middleware infrastructure management to multiple Fortune 500 companies.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/sai_kondapalli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/sai_kondapalli/</guid><description>Sai Kondapalli is a Database Specialist Solutions Architect at Amazon Web Services specializing on MySQL services and assists customers to migrate and optimize their workloads on RDS MySQL, MariaDB and Aurora MySQL.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/sergey_kuzmichev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/sergey_kuzmichev/</guid><description>Sergey is a support engineer in Percona. Interested in all things databases, he&amp;rsquo;s currently working mainly with MySQL and PostgreSQL. He started his career working as an Oracle DBA, later moving to a DevOps engineer role supporting a Java-based trading platform running on PostgreSQL. After being a jack of all trades for a while, he&amp;rsquo;s now focusing on what he enjoys most: open source databases, systems performance, and reliability.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/sergey_pronin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/sergey_pronin/</guid><description>Sergey is a passionate technology &amp;ldquo;driver&amp;rdquo;. After graduation worked in various fields: internet service provider, financial sector and M&amp;amp;A business. Main focal points were infrastructure and products around it. At Percona as a Product Owner drives forward Kubernetes and Cloud databases solutions.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/shashank_agarwal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/shashank_agarwal/</guid><description>Googld Cloud Architect with experience of working with bigdata complex, distributed applications based. Experience in designing and implementing solutions. Also certified GCP Cloud Architect, Java Developer and Web Components Developer.
Good understanding of the software development lifecycle (Jenkins CI), experience in establishing the development and release process (Maven, Git, Nexus) and system automation (Chef). Awesome experience with metrics collection and automated service monitoring using statsd, grfanana and Syren.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/shlomi_noach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/shlomi_noach/</guid><description>Engineer and database geek, works at PlanetScale as a maintainer for open source Vitess. Previously at GitHub. Interested in database infrastructure solutions such as high availability, reliability, enablement, automation and testing. Shlomi is an active MySQL community member, authors orchestrator, gh-ost, common_schema and other open source tools, and blogs at http://openark.org. He is the recipient of MySQL Community Member of the Year, Oracle ACE (Alumni) &amp;amp; Oracle Technologist of the Year awards.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/sidney_chen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/sidney_chen/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/sri_sakthivel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/sri_sakthivel/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/srini_kadamati/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/srini_kadamati/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Senior Data Scientist that&amp;rsquo;s on a mission to enable more people to work with data effectively. I spent 5 years building an online learning platform specifically to help people learn existing data tools before turning my attention to improving the data tools themselves. I now am a Developer Advocate at Preset.io, the main company driving and helping grow the Apache Superset project.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/stephen_borg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/stephen_borg/</guid><description>Stephen has had a career in technology for online and retail gambling, having worked close to business for a number of B2C and B2B providers. Sound background in technology, delivering affiliate and gambling platforms using both .NET and Java frameworks.
For the past 8 years Stephen has grown fond of Big Data and has led several high production transaction data lake projects both for on premise and on the cloud architectures.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/steve_hoffman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/steve_hoffman/</guid><description>Technology leader who thrives in challenging, fast-paced environments committed to delivering solutions and value to both the internal and external customer. Rich mix of business management and technology coupled with demonstrated ability to lead multiple development teams on multiple platforms focusing on meeting performance, operational and financial objectives.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/surendar_munimohan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/surendar_munimohan/</guid><description>Surendar Munimohan is a Senior Database Specialist Solutions Architect at Amazon Web Services. He works with customer to provide guidance and technical assistance on database projects. He holds Masters of Information Technology from Central Queensland University, Australia.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/tiago_alves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/tiago_alves/</guid><description>Tiago is a software engineering manager for MySQL NDB Cluster. Tiago is passionate about software engineering with focus on software quality.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/tim_meehan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/tim_meehan/</guid><description>Tim is a Software Engineer at Facebook working on Presto and is also a Presto Foundation Technical Steering Committee member and Committer. His interests are in Presto reliability and scalability.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/umair_shahid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/umair_shahid/</guid><description>Umair counts 20 years experience in PostgreSQL and open source experience serving some of the highly competitive technology markets in USA &amp;amp; Europe in roles of increasing responsibility. Proven track record of the unique ability to bridge the gap between business objectives and engineering :
Product management, with a focus on growth Data-driven business development Leadership skills with the ability to rally a geographically dispersed team</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/vadim_tkachenko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/vadim_tkachenko/</guid><description>Vadim Tkachenko is Co-founder of Percona Company Experienced Chief Technology Officer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Strong entrepreneurship professional skilled in Scalability, Performance Tuning, Software Engineering.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/vaibhav_upadhyay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/vaibhav_upadhyay/</guid><description>Vaibhav Upadhyay is a Lead Database Administrator at ROKA I am working with Techmojo solutions as a lead for production Support &amp;amp; DBA Like to play sports particularly Snooker and Cricket I enjoy working in operations environment/domain and as part of It like to work on performance and scaling issues</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/vaidyanathan_subramanian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/vaidyanathan_subramanian/</guid><description>Vaidyanathan is an Engineering Manager at India&amp;rsquo;s largest e-commerce company, Flipkart. He has close to 13 years of experience working across multiple startups and larger companies like Yahoo. He has built and architected the central managed platform for MySQL in Flipkart and is currently managing three critical PaaS services - Managed Distributed SQL, Managed SQL and Managed Backup &amp;amp; Restore products in Flipkart. In his career of 7.5 years in Flipkart, he was instrumental in recognising the various problems of independently managed MySQL clusters and solving it for Flipkart at scale.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/valerii_kravchuk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/valerii_kravchuk/</guid><description>Valerii Kravchuk helps MySQL and MariaDB users and DBAs to resolve their problems since 2005. Worked in MySQL AB, Sun, Oracle, Percona and, since 2016, in MariaDB Corporation. MySQL Community Contributor of the year 2019.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/vicentiu_ciorbaru/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/vicentiu_ciorbaru/</guid><description>Vicentiu works at the MariaDB Foundation as a Software Engineer and Team Lead. He focuses on optimizer development, but has also worked on other parts of the MariaDB Server. Vicențiu has been part of the MariaDB ecosystem since 2013, where he first contributed Roles to MariaDB. Over the years, Vicențiu has coded numerous features and helped with the packaging of MariaDB for various distributions. Recently, Vicențiu has also been involved in the QA process of MariaDB, by contributing to https://buildbot.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/vijay_karumajj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/vijay_karumajj/</guid><description>Vijay Karumajj is a Senior Database Specialist Solutions Architect at Amazon Web Services. He has worked as a SQL Server DBA at Blue Cross Blue Shield, Verizon, and Southwest Airlines. He holds a Bachelor’s degree in computer science from Andhra University and a Master’s degree in computer science from the University of Wolverhampton.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/vinicius_grippa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/vinicius_grippa/</guid><description>Vinicius Grippa is a Senior Support Engineer at Percona. Vinicius joined Percona Support Engineer team in 2017. He has a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science with a passion for technology and more than 13 years experiences in databases systems. He has experience in designing databases for critical applications and, in the last few years, has become a specialist in MySQL and MongoDB ecosystems. He has helped Percona customers with hundreds of different cases featuring a vast range of scenarios and complexities.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/vinodh_krishnaswamy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/vinodh_krishnaswamy/</guid><description>Vinodh Krishnaswamy is a Support Engineer at Percona. Vinodh loves to work in a team as a team player, leading the team, solving problems and partying with them. His friends/colleagues call him &amp;ldquo;Guruji&amp;rdquo;, who shares the knowledge. He agreed to join our community meetup and to share his knowledge about MongoDB. He helped many clients to move into MongoDB and solved their problem to deal with huge data and reducing the focus on Normalization / design of RDBMS &amp;amp; focus on handling data.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/walter_garcia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/walter_garcia/</guid><description>Walter has worked as a DBA since 2010 in few companies like social gaming company in Latin America and other company in Spain. He lives in Mendoza, Argentina, He likes play football and he is learning to play guitar in his free time.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/wayne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/wayne/</guid><description>When I&amp;rsquo;m not working with MySQL or other Open-source software packages. I like to do woodworking, 3D design and Printing, listening to all forms of Metal music and electronic projects with Raspberry PI, Arduino. Wayne lives in Powell Ohio, with his wife, daughter, 6 cats and 2 dogs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/wey_gu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/wey_gu/</guid><description>Wey is a software engineer living in Shanghai, China. He enjoys building things with magic and scaling the magic to the wizard community in the day time and sings sometime at night.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/yahav_biran/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/yahav_biran/</guid><description>Yahav Biran is a Principal Solutions Architect at AWS, focused on game tech at scale. Yahav enjoys contributing to open-source projects and publishes in the AWS blog and academic journals. He currently contributes to the K8s Helm community, Percona Live, AWS databases and compute blogs, and Journal of Systems Engineering. He delivers technical presentations at technology events and works with customers to design their applications in the cloud. He received his PhD (Systems Engineering) from Colorado State University.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/yang_keao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/yang_keao/</guid><description>Yang Keao is a developer at PingCAP and a maintainer of Chaos Mesh, a cloud native chaos engineering platform for Kubernetes. He also helps the database developers and QA team to promote the stability of TiDB, which is a distributed database developed by PingCAP.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/yunus_shaikh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/yunus_shaikh/</guid><description>Yunus is experienced Database administrator currently working in Percona as MySQL DBA II. He lives in Mumbai, India. Always keen to explore new open source tools.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/speakers/yury_selivanov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/yury_selivanov/</guid><description>Yury Selivanov is Co-founder and CEO at EdgeDB. Bringing state-of-the-art database technology to the masses. EdgeDB is an open-source object-relational database built on top of PostgreSQL. The goal of EdgeDB is to empower its users to build safe and efficient software with less effort.</description></item><item><title>agustin_gallego</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/agustin_gallego/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/agustin_gallego/</guid><description>Agustín joined Percona&amp;rsquo;s Support team in December 2013, after being part of the Administrative team from February 2012. He has previously worked as a Cambridge IT examinations Supervisor and as a Junior BI, SQL &amp;amp; C# developer. He is currently a Computer Analyst, and continues studying to get a Computer Systems Engineer degree at the Universidad de la República, in Uruguay.</description></item><item><title>alawi_assaggaf</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/alawi_assaggaf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/alawi_assaggaf/</guid><description>MySQL DBA with 10 years experience in the industry.</description></item><item><title>alvaro_hernandez</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/alvaro_hernandez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/alvaro_hernandez/</guid><description>Alvaro Hernandez is a passionate database and software developer. After several unsuccessful ventures, Alvaro founded and work as the CEO of OnGres, a PostGres startup set to disrupt the database market. He has been dedicated to PostgreSQL and R&amp;amp;D in databases since two decades ago. Alvaro is an open source advocate and developer and a well-known member of the PostgreSQL Community.</description></item><item><title>ananias_tsalouchidis</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ananias_tsalouchidis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ananias_tsalouchidis/</guid><description>Ananias Tsalouchidis is a Principal MySQL DBA who joined Percona on May 2017. He holds a BSc and a MSc in computer science and has a 10+ years working experience as a systems and databases administrator. He loves databases and perl scripting. He has worked for some big Greek companies and academic institutions and has also been involved in numerous research programs. He is located in Greece.</description></item><item><title>Andreas Scherbaum</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/andreas_scherbaum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/andreas_scherbaum/</guid><description>Andreas Scherbaum is working with PostgreSQL since 1997. He is involved in several PostgreSQL related community projects, member of the Board of Directors of the European PostgreSQL User Group and also wrote a PostgreSQL book (in German). Since 2011 he was working for EMC/Greenplum/Pivotal and tackled very big databases. Nowadays he does the same - but with maybe even more and bigger databases - for Adjust GmbH in Berlin.</description></item><item><title>Andrew Pogrebnoi</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/andrew_pogrebnoi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/andrew_pogrebnoi/</guid><description>Andrew Pogrebnoi is Principal Software Engineer at Percona. He says: “I like to make fast, reliable and valuable things. Try to keep it working, consistent and available. Enjoyed with compilers, databases, distributed systems, and performance.”</description></item><item><title>ege_gunes</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ege_gunes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ege_gunes/</guid><description>Ege Güneş is Software Engineer at Percona. Ege has both developer and DevOps background, managing Kubernetes clusters and databases in the past. He started as a software developer in 2016. He joined the Cloud Engineering Team as a Golang Developer to help with Kubernetes Operators development. He has contributed actively to the development of Percona Server for MongoDB (PSMDB), especially the cross cluster replication.</description></item><item><title>elisa_usai</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/elisa_usai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/elisa_usai/</guid><description/></item><item><title>emily_omier</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/emily_omier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/emily_omier/</guid><description>Emily Omier is specializing in helping startups in the cloud native ecosystem and/or built around an open source project create the right set of assumptions so that prospects and customers understand the product&amp;rsquo;s value immediately. Do you have a sinking feeling that prospects don&amp;rsquo;t understand your product? If your prospects consistently compare you with the wrong alternatives, overlook your awesome features and can&amp;rsquo;t figure out how your thing would fit into their workflow and their tech stack, you might have a positioning problem.</description></item><item><title>Eno Compton</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/eno_compton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/eno_compton/</guid><description>Eno is a Developer Relations Engineer at Google working on Cloud SQL. He is one of the maintainers of the Cloud SQL Auth proxy. He is also a total language nerd with a Ph.D. in Classical Chinese and Japanese and a decade of experience in nearly a dozen computer languages. Nowadays he works exclusively in Go and loves network programming, delightful APIs, and deleting code in pursuit of simplicity.</description></item><item><title>Eno Compton</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/shachar_guz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/shachar_guz/</guid><description>Shachar is a product manager at Google Cloud, he works on the Cloud Database Migration Service. Shachar worked in various product and engineering roles and shares a true passion about data and helping customers get the most out of their data. Shachar was formerly a product manager for Alooma who got acquired by Google in 2019. He is passionate about building products that make cumbersome processes simple and straightforward and helping companies adopt Cloud technologies to accelerate their business.</description></item><item><title>farokh_shahabi</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/farokh_shahabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/farokh_shahabi/</guid><description>Co-founder &amp;amp; CEO of Formaloo</description></item><item><title>federico_razzoli</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/federico_razzoli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/federico_razzoli/</guid><description>Passionate with databases, automation and open source. Federico was active in MariaDB and MySQL communities for years. He started Vettabase, a database automation and consulting company.</description></item><item><title>fernando_laudares</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/fernando_laudares/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/fernando_laudares/</guid><description>Fernando joined Percona in early 2013 after 8 years working for a Canadian company specialized in Linux and Open Source technologies. As a member of Percona&amp;rsquo;s Support team, Fernando works closely with customers helping them troubleshoot issues with MySQL, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB servers and looking for answers to various database-related questions and challenges. He also has a personal interest in education in general and loves to read and talk about this subject.</description></item><item><title>ian_gilfillan</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/ian_gilfillan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/ian_gilfillan/</guid><description>Ian first came across MySQL in the 90s, upgrading from mSQL while developing South Africas' first online grocery store, and teaching and developing internet programming courses. He was lead developer for South Africa’s largest media company from 2000, and wrote the book Mastering MySQL 4 in 2002. He wrote regular columns on MySQL and web programming in the 2000s, before founding and developing an online organic food co-operative in 2005.</description></item><item><title>Jan Kleinert</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/jan_kleinert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/jan_kleinert/</guid><description>Jan Kleinert leads a team of Developer Advocates as part of Google Cloud, focusing on Compute and Databases. Prior to joining Google, she worked in a variety of roles ranging from developer relations to web analytics and conversion optimization.</description></item><item><title>Javier Jaramago Fernández</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/javier_fernandez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/javier_fernandez/</guid><description>Systems engineer, OpenSource contributor, currently at ProxySQL. Interested in systems programming, databases, distributed and critical systems.</description></item><item><title>Jono Bacon</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/jono_bacon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/jono_bacon/</guid><description>Jono is the author of &amp;lsquo;People Powered: How communities can supercharge your business, brand, and teams&amp;rsquo;, and &amp;lsquo;The Art of Community&amp;rsquo;. Jono has also written on community for Forbes, Harvard Business Review, Fortune, and elsewhere. Listen into this dive into building and managing communities.</description></item><item><title>Joshua Drake</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/joshua_drake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/joshua_drake/</guid><description>President of Command Prompt, Inc., the oldest Postgres Company. We specialize in Full Stack Postgres Support and consulting including Oracle to Postgres Migrations. I am also Co-Chair of Postgres Conference (PostgresConf), the largest non-profit Postgres Community and Ecosystem conference. Connect with us to find out how we can help your business either with Oracle Migrations, 24x7 Postgres Support, Professional Services or build a relationship around your company success with PostgresConf.</description></item><item><title>Kimberly Wilkins</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/kimberly_wilkins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/kimberly_wilkins/</guid><description>Kimberly Wilkins is MongoDB Technical Lead at Percona currently. She has over 20 years experience managing and architecting database systems. She worked with MongoDB customers of all sizes in many industries and helped them to plan, deploy, troubleshoot, tune, and horizontally shard and scale to handle heavy workloads and keep their applications running and their businesses growing.</description></item><item><title>Kyle Davis</title><link>https://percona.community/speakers/kyle_davis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/speakers/kyle_davis/</guid><description>Kyle Davis is the Senior Developer Advocate with Open Distro for Elasticsearch at AWS. While being a relative newcomer to AWS, Kyle has a long history with software development and databases. When not working, Kyle enjoys 3D printing, and getting his hand dirty in his Edmonton, Alberta-based home garden.</description></item></channel></rss>