<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kubernetes on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/kubernetes/</link><description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Node metrics available inside of a container</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/06/node-metrics-container/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/06/node-metrics-container/</guid><description>Several people asked me this question: Could we get Node metrics inside of a container?
Usually, this comes from the fact that PMM or standalone people run node_exporter inside a container. PMM does it as a sidecar along with many other exporters to monitor DBs, and node_exporter comes out of the box as a default one. So people could see accurate data on dashboards, like Memory and CPU, that node_exporter reads inside the container.</description></item><item><title>Binding your application to the database in the Kubernetes cluster</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</guid><description>dbaas-operator is Yet Another DBaaS Kubernetes Operator (need to suggest yadbko as a name) that tries to simplify and unify Database Cluster deployments by building a higher abstraction layer on top of Percona Kubernetes Operators.
So it becomes much easier to deploy the DB cluster with dbaas-operator and PMM DBaaS on top of it.
But another part of the picture is applications and their workloads to connect to the deployed DB Clusters.</description></item><item><title>Learning Kubernetes Operators with Percona Operator for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</guid><description>One of the topics that have resonated a lot for me since the first KubeCon I attended in 2018 is Kubernetes Operators.
The concept of Operators was introduced much earlier in 2016 by the CoreOS Linux development team. They were looking for a way to improve automated container management in Kubernetes.
What do we mean by a Kubernetes Operator? We use the definition of CNCF. The Kubernetes project defines “Operator” simply: “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components“.</description></item><item><title>Hacktoberfest with Percona - We Want You! - September 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>October is close, and it is time for Hacktoberfest! Join our stream to talk online about this fantastic challenge at 2:30 UTC on Wednesday, September 28th. And yes, you can be a part of the conversation with experts and jump into the stream to address the audience!
If you love open source as much as we do, Hacktoberfest is created for you. It is a unique opportunity to be a part of a great open source community.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Kubernetes cluster on Amazon EKS with eksctl</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/09/13/creating-a-kubernetes-cluster-on-amazon-eks-with-eksctl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/09/13/creating-a-kubernetes-cluster-on-amazon-eks-with-eksctl/</guid><description>Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS) is a managed Kubernetes service that makes it easy for you to run Kubernetes on AWS and on-premises. Kubernetes is an open-source system for automating deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. Amazon EKS is certified Kubernetes-conformant, so existing applications that run on upstream Kubernetes are compatible with Amazon EKS.
Getting started guides available in the AWS documentation explain two different procedures for creating an EKS cluster.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Cloud Migrations With Databases on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
In this talk you will learn how Kubernetes and Percona Operators can help you to avoid vendor lock-in when you run your databases in containers with Percona Operators.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/-U8dOzQqlJI
Transcript</description></item><item><title>PMM on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
How to run PMM on Kubernetes, demonstration and discussion of technology choices. Tip and tricks and relation to DBaaS. Q&amp;amp;A
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/bqvE_5tcL5M
Transcript</description></item><item><title>How and Why Contribute to Communities</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/30/csi-minikube-multinode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/30/csi-minikube-multinode/</guid><description>Why Lets start with a simple question &amp;ldquo;Why to contribute?&amp;rdquo;.
In our day to day development&amp;rsquo;s and user&amp;rsquo;s life we use tons of OSS (open source) software. Ppl develop that software together to have ability to use them in more standard and open way, so they spend less time negotiating on interfaces and tools (and that is not the main reason, one of the reasons for OSS).
As any sustainable process, OSS development also needs not only users but contributors to be able to move project forward as well as to sustain bugs, time and new tech trends.</description></item><item><title> Installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes Operator - Community MeetUp - March 10th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-10-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-10-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</guid><description>Check this full recording of the Percona Community MeetUp of March 10th hosted and learn more about installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes operator. Matt Yonkovit, the Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona, and Sergey Pronin, Product Owner at Percona, took us through the step-by-step setup to get us started with a new MongoDB cluster.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/HZ9yaS-ZS48
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Helloб everyone out there in the stream land. Welcome to another Percona Livestream.</description></item><item><title> Community MeetUp - Installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes Operator - POSTPONED</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-24-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-24-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</guid><description>Hello,
We are sorry to inform you that we have to POSTPONE our Community MeetUp of Today Thursday, Feb 24th, 11 am EST (5:00 pm CEST / 9:30 pm IST). A new schedule of the meeting will be announced soon.
Thank you for your understanding.
Percona Community Team
Join us in The Percona Community MeetUp and walk with us through the installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes operator. Sergey Pronin will take us through all steps of the setup to get us started with a new MongoDB Cluster.</description></item><item><title>Balalaika Meetup With Local Community in Ulyanovsk</title><link>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</guid><description>On November 15th, Percona organized a meetup with the local community in Ulyanovsk (Russia). From Percona, there were Peter Zaitsev (CEO), Maria Azizova (Staff Executive), and Aleksandra Abramova (Community Specialist). They had a chance to meet engineers from different IT companies who live nearby.
The event took place in an interesting location. It was a private Balalaika&amp;rsquo;s Museum. It is a Russian national musical instrument. If you wonder how it sounds like, there are some examples on YouTube like this one.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native Data Management Day</title><link>https://percona.community/events/cloud-native-data-management-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/cloud-native-data-management-day/</guid><description>MongoDB on Kubernetes with GitOps by Sergey Pronin GitOps quickly found its way into DevOps and developer’s hearts as it greatly simplifies the application delivery pipeline. GitOps can be also used to deploy and more importantly - manage - MongoDB on Kubernetes. In this video, Sergey Pronin explains how MongoDB users can benefit from the collaboration of Kubernetes and GitOps and shows a quick demo of the example.
Video Link: https://www.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Highly Available PostgreSQL With GKE</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/4/</guid><description>Christoph Bussler and Shashank Agarwal - Google - Percona Live 2021
When you have an application running in Google Kubernetes Engine, there are multiple options and considerations for how to deploy a database. In this session, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn some of the architectural considerations for choosing a database deployment option in GKE. We will demonstrate one of these options, as you learn how to configure PostgreSQL as a container in GKE based on regional persistent disks and PersistentVolumeClaims.</description></item><item><title>How To Choose the Right Solution When Lifting and Shifting Your Database to the Cloud</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/3/</guid><description>Shachar Guz - Google - Percona Live 2021
Database migrations can be complex, time-consuming, and costly, increasing the risk of moving to the cloud. Enterprises need effective and reliable database migration tools that help automate this process for seamless cloud adoption. In this session, we will elaborate on the considerations to take into account when choosing database migration methods and technology, and the different aspects that can impact risk such as migration fidelity and downtime.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying Database Performance Issues With SQL Commenter and Cloud SQL Insights</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/2/</guid><description>Jan Kleinert - Google - Percona Live 2021
Have you ever tried to troubleshoot a database performance issue in an application that was built using an ORM? ORMs can simplify development of applications that communicate with databases, but since the ORMs are generating the SQL statements, it can be difficult to determine which application code is resulting in slow queries.
SQL Commenter is an open source library that enables ORMs to augment SQL statements with comments about the code that caused its execution, making it easier to correlate your application code with the SQL statements that were generated by the ORM.</description></item><item><title>Working Effectively with Cloud SQL on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/1/</guid><description>Eno Compton - Google - Percona Live 2021
There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like about Kubernetes and Cloud SQL, but it&amp;rsquo;s not always clear how to use them together. This talk will be a deep-dive into Cloud SQL and how to work with it effectively on Kubernetes. The talk will be developer-centric and will start with the basics of connecting to Cloud SQL from Kubernetes. It will include how to run load tests and then size an instance.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Operator for Presto</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/1/</guid><description>Hemant Bhanawat - Yugabyte - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto Operator for Kubernetes is used to manage Presto clusters which are deployed as custom resources. In short, the task of configuring, creating and managing of Presto cluster(s) in a Kubernetes environment has been made simple, easy and quick with a Presto Operator.
This session will be a walkthrough of provisioning Presto in K8s using Presto Operator. The advanced features of Presto Operator like HTTPS support, additional volumes support, autoscaling and graceful shutdown of workers will also be discussed.</description></item><item><title>How Open Source Powers the Modern Data Stack</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/5/</guid><description>Michel Tricot - Airbyte - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
In this talk, we’ll describe how you can leverage 3 open-source standards - workflow management with Aifrow, EL with Airbyte, transformation with DBT - to build your organization&amp;rsquo;s modern data stack.
We’ll explain how to configure your Aifrow DAG to trigger Airbyte’s data replication jobs and DBT’s transformations with a concrete use case.</description></item><item><title>Towards a K8s Native Streaming Application</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/4/</guid><description>Jérémy Frénay (Babylon Health) and Francesco Nobilia (Nutmeg) - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
Starting from a simple application which can be deployed in every machine running Docker, we will go through all steps required to transform the simple app into a Kubernetes native streaming application. We will explain the theory and then exemplify the learnt concepts to dene a recipe for running streaming applications on Kubernetes. We will focus both on cultural and technical tricks to help you successfully adopt streaming applications at scale.</description></item><item><title>Wrangling Data to Multiple Places With Fluent Bit</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/3/</guid><description>Anurag Gupta - Calyptia - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
As more and more users move to Kubernetes they also may start using multiple backends and analytic tools. How do you collect once and send everywhere? In this talk, Anurag will talk about a Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) graduated project Fluent Bit and how you can collect once, and send to all the backends you want. Additionally, Anurag will discuss some of Fluent Bit&amp;rsquo;s advanced capabilities such as enrichment, parsing, and data reduction that helps users get the most out of their backends.</description></item><item><title>Everything You Ever Wanted To Know About Databases but Were Too Afraid To Ask</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/2/</guid><description>Dr Gavin Mendel - TerminusDb - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
The talk does exactly what it says on the tin - everything you want to know about databases from somebody with decades of experience implementing, architecting, and building databases. Gavin will talk through the way he currently thinks about implementation - the problems he most cares about - and then will open up to your questions! In the absence of Stonebreaker, nobody is better placed to answer database Q&amp;amp;A.</description></item><item><title>Native Chaos Engineering in Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/1/</guid><description>Karthik Satchitanand - ChaosNative - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
Chaos Engineering is revolutionizing testing means and doing it the cloud-native way is the best way in today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly changing world with a huge shift in the paradigm of Kubernetes resiliency. Karthik S, one of the maintainers for LitmusChaos would be introducing how to carry out Chaos Engineering, the cloud-native way. Further, he will touch upon how Chaos Engineering is carried out in Cloud-Native Databases with LitmusChaos.</description></item><item><title>Supporting Global Scale MySQL Applications With Amazon Aurora Global Database</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/3/</guid><description>Vijay Karumajj - AWS - Amazon Aurora Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Critical MySQL workloads with a global footprint, such as financial, travel, or gaming applications, have strict availability requirements and may need to tolerate a region-wide outage. Traditionally this required difficult tradeoffs between performance, availability, cost, and data integrity. In this session, learn how Amazon Aurora Global Database, which allows a single Amazon Aurora MySQL database to span multiple AWS regions, replicates your data with no impact on database performance, enables fast local reads with low latency in each region, and provides fast disaster recovery from region-wide outages.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Applications With Amazon RDS Proxy</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/2/</guid><description>Surendar Munimohan - AWS - Amazon Aurora Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Many applications, including those built on modern serverless architectures (https://aws.amazon.com/serverless/), can have a large number of open connections to the database server, and may open and close database connections at a high rate, exhausting database memory and compute resources. Amazon RDS Proxy allows applications to pool and share connections established with the database, improving database efficiency and application scalability.</description></item><item><title>Hyperscaling Workloads With Amazon RDS MySQL and Amazon Aurora MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/1/</guid><description>Sai Kondapalli - AWS - Amazon Aurora Community Track - Percona Live 2021
When the right factors align, businesses can grow at a sudden, unanticipated and exponential rate. That&amp;rsquo;s a good thing, but an unexpected and dramatic spinke in users and transactions of your MySQL database can strain resources, potential database failure, and, as a result, a bad user or customer experience. In this session, learn strategies and best practices quickly growing your MySQL deployment to ensure high performance and an exceptional user experience while maintaing ACID compliance and rock solid security.</description></item><item><title>Mayastor: Lightning Fast Storage for Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/23/mayastor-lightning-fast-storage-for-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 14:03:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/23/mayastor-lightning-fast-storage-for-kubernetes/</guid><description>At MayaData we like new tech. Tech that makes our databases perform better. Tech like lockless ring buffers, NVMe-oF, and Kubernetes. In this blog post we’re going to see those technologies at work to give us awesome block storage performance with flexibility and simple operations.
Mayastor + SPDK + NVMe = fast databases Mayastor is new tech, it’s fast, and it’s based on SPDK. Why is SPDK exciting? It’s a new generation in storage software, designed for super high speed low latency NVMe devices.</description></item><item><title>IIoT platform databases - How Mail.ru Cloud Solutions deals with petabytes of data coming from a multitude of devices</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:11:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</guid><description>Hello, my name is Andrey Sergeyev and I work as a Head of IoT Solution Development at Mail.ru Cloud Solutions. We all know there is no such thing as a universal database. Especially when the task is to build an IoT platform that would be capable of processing millions of events from various sensors in near real-time.
Our product Mail.ru IoT Platform started as a Tarantool-based prototype. I’m going to tell you about our journey, the problems we faced and the solutions we found.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE: MySQL on Google Cloud: War and Peace! by Akshay Suryawanshi &amp; Jeremy Cole</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:12:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</guid><description>This session at Percona Live ONLINE was presented by Akshay Suryawanshi, Senior Production Engineer at Shopify, and Jeremy Cole, Senior Staff Production Engineer - Datastores at Shopify. Shopify is an online and on-premise commerce platform, founded in 2006.
Shopify is used by more than a million merchants, and hundreds of billions of dollars of sales have happened on the platform since its inception. The company is a large user of MySQL, and the Black Friday and Cyber Monday weekends are their peak dates during the year, handling hundreds of billions of queries with MySQL.</description></item><item><title>Join ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona on June 4th, 2020!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</guid><description>Long months of the pandemic lockdown have brought to life many great online events enabling the MySQL community to get together and stay informed about the very recent developments and innovations available to MySQL users. It isn’t over yet! Next Thursday, June 4th, Percona &amp;amp; ProxySQL are co-hosting the ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona virtual meetup covering ProxySQL, MySQL and Percona XtraDB Cluster.
The attendees are invited to participate in the two-hour deep-dive event with plenty of time for questions and answers (we will have two 40-minute sessions + 20 minutes allocated for Q&amp;amp;A).</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes, The Swiss Army Knife For Your ProxySQL Deployments – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/08/kubernetes-the-swiss-army-knife-for-your-proxysql-deployments-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 02:02:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/08/kubernetes-the-swiss-army-knife-for-your-proxysql-deployments-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 10:00 p.m. • London 3:00 a.m. (Wed) • New Delhi 7:30 a.m. (Wed)
Abstract ProxySQL is a high performance proxy from design to implementation. It speaks the MySQL protocol, and can go beyond load balancing. This talk covers various deployment options for ProxySQL in a Kubernetes environment.
Typically ProxySQL is deployed in one of three ways depending on the scale and needs of your environment:</description></item><item><title>Orchestrating Cassandra with Kubernetes Operator and Yelp PaaSTA - Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/06/orchestrating-cassandra-with-kubernetes-operator-and-yelp-paasta-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/06/orchestrating-cassandra-with-kubernetes-operator-and-yelp-paasta-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 3:00 p.m. • London 8:00 p.m. • New Delhi 12:30 a.m. (Wed) Level: Intermediate
Abstract At Yelp, Cassandra, our NoSQL database of choice, has been deployed on AWS compute (EC2) and AutoScaling Groups (ASG), backed by Block Storage (EBS). This deployment model has been quite robust over the years while presenting its own set of challenges. To make our Cassandra deployment more resilient and reduce the engineering toil associated with our constantly growing infrastructure, we are abstracting Cassandra deployments further away from EC2 with Kubernetes and orchestrating with our Cassandra Operator.</description></item><item><title>Tame Kubernetes with These Open-Source Tools</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/08/tame-kubernetes-with-open-source-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 13:03:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/08/tame-kubernetes-with-open-source-tools/</guid><description>Kubernetes’ popularity as the most-preferred open-source container-orchestration system has skyrocketed in the recent past. The overall container market is expected to cross USD 2.7 billion by 2020 with a CAGR of 40 percent. Three orchestrators spearhead this upward trend, namely Kubernetes, Mesos, and Docker Swarm. However, referring to the graph below, Kubernetes clearly leads the pack.
source: https://medium.com/@rdodev/saved-you-an-analyst-read-on-kubernetes-growth-2018-edition-810367876981 The automation and infrastructural capabilities of Kubernetes are transforming the DevOps space, thereby enhancing the value of the business through software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Gonymizer, A Tool to Anonymize Sensitive PostgreSQL Data Tables for Use in QA and Testing</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/17/percona-live-gonymizer-tool-anonymize-sensitive-postgresql-data-testing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 11:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/17/percona-live-gonymizer-tool-anonymize-sensitive-postgresql-data-testing/</guid><description>SmithRX is a next generation pharmacy benefit platform that is using the latest technology to radically reshape the prescription benefit management industry. To move quickly, we require the ability to iterate and test new versions of our software using production like data without violating Health Information Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) regulations.
At Percona Live 2019, we are introducing a project we open sourced to anonymize our sensitive production data for use in rapid QA and testing of our software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The First Ever TiDB Track</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 20:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</guid><description>The PingCAP team has always been a strong supporter of Percona and the wider open source database community. As the people who work day in and day out on TiDB, an open source NewSQL database with MySQL compatibility, open source database is what gets us in the morning, and there’s no better place to share that passion than Percona Live.
At this year’s Percona Live Open Source Database Conference in Austin, Texas, we are particularly excited to bring you a full track of talks and demo on the latest development in TiDB during Day 1 of the conference.</description></item><item><title>Deploying MySQL on Kubernetes with a Percona-based Operator</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:03:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</guid><description>In the context of providing managed WordPress hosting services, at Presslabs we operate with lots of small to medium-sized databases, in a DB-per-service model, as we call it. The workloads are mostly reads, so we need to efficiently scale that. The MySQL® asynchronous replication model fits the bill very well, allowing us to scale horizontally from one server—with the obvious availability pitfalls—to tens of nodes. The next release of the stack is going to be open-sourced.</description></item></channel></rss>