<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lorraine.pocklington on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/lorraine.pocklington/</link><description>Recent content in lorraine.pocklington on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 10:21:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/lorraine.pocklington/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#ilovefs Valentine's Day Celebration (I Love Free Software)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/02/14/ilovefs-valentines-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 10:21:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/02/14/ilovefs-valentines-day/</guid><description>Free Software Foundation Europe (FSFE) is celebrating the creators of free software with their I Love Free Software campaign #ilovefs, a social campaign for Valentine’s Day.
The idea is to show some appreciation to the makers of free software. Most of our communications with free software creators are about bugs and feature requests and maybe we just forget to say &amp;ldquo;Thanks&amp;rdquo;. So FSFE are trying to provide some balance.
FSFE were promoting the campaign at FOSDEM at the beginning of this month.</description></item><item><title>Writing a Killer Conference Proposal</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/01/03/writing-a-killer-conference-proposal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 10:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/01/03/writing-a-killer-conference-proposal/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to submit a proposal to Percona Live but suffering a little writer’s block, or at least want to be sure to make a good impression on our track selectors, there’s some great content online that can help. If you’re an old hand, you probably won’t need this, though it’s possible you’ll find some interesting stuff here nevertheless.
Your job is to make it easy for the selectors to choose your talk.</description></item></channel></rss>