<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Databases on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/databases/</link><description>Recent content in Databases on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HighLoad++ Spring 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</guid><description>Percona team participated in the HighLoad ++ Spring conference in Moscow on May 17-18, 2021. It is the most famous IT conference in Russia for developers of highload projects. This year it brought together 2000 participants offline and 2000 online running 8 parallel tracks and having 20+ company stands for networking.
On the conference, Percona speakers presented 4 talks:
MySQL 8 Observability and Query Analysis with PMM by Peter Zaitsev (CEO) Comparison of Kubernetes Operators for MySQL by Sergey Pronin (Product Owner) Migrations between schemas and updates in MySQL: mechanisms, locks, loads by Nikolay Ihalainen (Senior Support Engineer) Anatomy of a Kubernetes Operator for a database by Peter Zaitsev and Sergey Pronin.</description></item><item><title>How to Write Your Index in Tarantool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 17:23:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</guid><description>Tarantool is an application server and a database. The server part is written in C, and the user is provided with a Lua interface to use it. Then, Tarantool is an open-source product with its source code in open access, and anyone can develop and distribute Tarantool-based software freely.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you about an attempt to write my own data structure for the search (the Z-order curve) and build it into the Tarantool ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Liquibase Data: Version Control and Collaboration for the Database</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</guid><description>This session is presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Liquibase is the defacto standard for versioning your database schema. With 15 years of use by the largest enterprises, Liquibase is a proven Open Source DevOps Solution. Now, with Liquibase Data, users can apply git-like workflows to development and test environments. See how free Open Source Liquibase can accelerate database development and cross-team deployments.</description></item><item><title>Making Databases as Easy as Legos: No code, No problem!</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-farokh-shahabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-farokh-shahabi/</guid><description>This session is presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
The race to reinvent databases for non-developers has just begun and no, businesses won&amp;rsquo;t settle to spreadsheets.
Check out the full schedule of Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022</description></item><item><title>The Lost Art of Database Design</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-matt-yonkovit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-matt-yonkovit/</guid><description>This session is presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Check out the full schedule of Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022</description></item></channel></rss>