<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Databases on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/databases/</link><description>Recent content in Databases on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FTD Data 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</guid><description>A big part of the Percona Brazilian team gathered together in Florianópolis to participate in a special edition of the Floripa Tech Day (FTD), focused on DATA. The agenda included talks on various technologies: MongoDB, MS-SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, and PostgreSQL.
It was a 1-day event with 13 talks from early morining till late evening. Three of them were deliverd by Percona speakers:
Online Backup in MySQL with XtraBackup by Marcelo Altmann (Software Engineer).</description></item><item><title>HighLoad++ Spring 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</guid><description>Percona team participated in the HighLoad ++ Spring conference in Moscow on May 17-18, 2021. It is the most famous IT conference in Russia for developers of highload projects. This year it brought together 2000 participants offline and 2000 online running 8 parallel tracks and having 20+ company stands for networking.
On the conference, Percona speakers presented 4 talks:
MySQL 8 Observability and Query Analysis with PMM by Peter Zaitsev (CEO) Comparison of Kubernetes Operators for MySQL by Sergey Pronin (Product Owner) Migrations between schemas and updates in MySQL: mechanisms, locks, loads by Nikolay Ihalainen (Senior Support Engineer) Anatomy of a Kubernetes Operator for a database by Peter Zaitsev and Sergey Pronin.</description></item><item><title>How to Write Your Index in Tarantool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 17:23:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</guid><description>Tarantool is an application server and a database. The server part is written in C, and the user is provided with a Lua interface to use it. Then, Tarantool is an open-source product with its source code in open access, and anyone can develop and distribute Tarantool-based software freely.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you about an attempt to write my own data structure for the search (the Z-order curve) and build it into the Tarantool ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Data Wrangling With MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-jean-joseph/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-jean-joseph/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
This presentation is based on data wrangling with MongoDB. After this presentation, you will have the mindset of data wrangling. It is 70% demo, and 30% talk. Jean covers the goal of data wrangling, how to think about data wrangling, and then the technical tips for data wrangling in MongoDB.</description></item><item><title>Liquibase Data: Version Control and Collaboration for the Database</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Liquibase is the defacto standard for versioning your database schema. With 15 years of use by the largest enterprises, Liquibase is a proven Open Source DevOps Solution. Now, with Liquibase Data, users can apply git-like workflows to development and test environments. See how free Open Source Liquibase can accelerate database development and cross-team deployments.</description></item><item><title>Making Databases as Easy as Legos: No code, No problem!</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-farokh-shahabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-farokh-shahabi/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
The race to reinvent databases for non-developers has just begun and no, businesses won&amp;rsquo;t settle to spreadsheets.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/tP1pEr3sS0w
Transcript</description></item><item><title>ProxySQL 2021 Dev Submit</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-javier-fernandez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-javier-fernandez/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
ProxySQL has proven itself as the de-facto standard reverse proxy for MySQL, yet, we are always looking for new features and improvements. During this past year starting with v2.1.0, four new major ProxySQL versions were released, and with them new features of all sorts were introduced, ranging from protocol changes, authentication improvements, clustering improvements, new monitoring features (for Galera, Group Replication, Aurora AWS) to DDOS protection.</description></item><item><title>The Lost Art of Database Design</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-matt-yonkovit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-matt-yonkovit/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Right now we are in a spot where people think that the databases are just part of the commoditized infrastructure. But unfortunately, that leads us to a lot of problems. And Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona, is talking about database design here. There are a lot of people out there who have never heard why they should focus on designing their databases, and their database infrastructure a little better.</description></item></channel></rss>