<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Databases on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/databases/</link><description>Recent content in Databases on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Timeline for Database on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>The Evolution Since its inception in June 2014, Kubernetes has dramatically transformed container orchestration, revolutionizing the management and scaling of applications. To mark its tenth anniversary, the Data on Kubernetes Community (DoKC) released an infographic showcasing key milestones and community contributions to the evolution of operators for managing stateful applications. This project was made possible by the collaboration of DoKC members Edith Puclla, Sergey Pronin, Robert Hodges, Gabriele Bartolini, Chris Malarky, Mark Kember, Paul Au, and Luciano Stabel.</description></item><item><title>Percona Joins Community Over Code 2024 in Bratislava, Slovakia</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/21/percona-joins-community-over-code-2024-in-bratislava-slovakia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/21/percona-joins-community-over-code-2024-in-bratislava-slovakia/</guid><description>Last week, I participated as a speaker for the first time at Community Over Code 2024.
Community Over Code Community Over Code is a key principle at Apache, highlighting the importance of having a solid and collaborative community rather than just focusing on the code. While good code is essential, the community&amp;rsquo;s strength and resilience keep a project going and growing. I love how this is expressed in the &amp;ldquo;Apache Way.</description></item><item><title>How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes with Percona Everest Summary</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</guid><description>Kubernetes continues evolving, and the complexity of deploying and managing databases within the ecosystem is a topic of considerable discussion and importance these days. This article summarizes a detailed discussion between Piotr Szczepaniak and Diogo Recharte, who offer insights and live demonstrations to simplify database operations on Kubernetes with a new technology for cloud-native applications: Percona Everest. If you want to watch the full video, check out How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes Webinar.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Percona Everest on GCP with Kubectl for Windows 11 Users</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/19/deploying-percona-everest-on-gcp-with-kubectl-for-windows-11-users/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/19/deploying-percona-everest-on-gcp-with-kubectl-for-windows-11-users/</guid><description>Welcome to this blog post! Today, our primary goal is to guide you through deploying Percona Everest on GCP using Kubectl, specifically for users on Windows 11. It&amp;rsquo;s been some time since I last used Windows, so this will be an excellent opportunity to do it from scratch.
Let me tell you a little bit about Percona Everest. You may have already heard it recently. It is the new open source tool launched by Percona and is already well-received by Kubernetes database users.</description></item><item><title>Data On Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/10/data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/10/data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve attended one of the Kubecon talks or related events, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely encountered the phrase Data on Kubernetes. To understand what this means, let&amp;rsquo;s explore some fundamental concepts related to Kubernetes, workload, stateless, and stateful applications.
Kubernetes, workload, stateless and stateful applications Kubernetes is a container orchestration tool that has already become an industry standard. When we talk about &amp;ldquo;container orchestration&amp;rdquo;, we are referring to the automated management and coordination of containers using Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Kubernetes Operators</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/03/kubernetes-operators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/03/kubernetes-operators/</guid><description>The concept of Kubernetes Operators was introduced around 2016 by the CoreOS Linuxdevelopment team. They were in search of a solution to improve automated container management within Kubernetes, primarily with the goal of incorporating operational expertise directly into the software.
According to the Cloud Native Computing Foundation, “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components”.
Kubernetes is designed for automation, offering essential automation features. It can automatically deploy and manage workloads.</description></item><item><title>HighLoad++ Serbia 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2023/</guid><description>This summer Percona Team traveled to Belgrade in Serbia to participate in 2 events - Highload++ Serbia 2023 and Percona University Belgrade.
The journey started with team building for those who arrived early. They went to a segway tour around the city and visited Belgrade Fortress with Kalemegdan park with an amazing guide who told them a lot about Serbia history. They also ride segways in the city center to get acquainted with the main tourist attractions.</description></item><item><title>Percona University in Peru 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Peru is a country in South America home to a section of the Amazon rainforest and Machu Picchu ⛰️, an ancient Incan city high in the Andes mountains. Percona decided to hold the first event of Percona University 2023 in Lima, the capital of Peru, on June 10.
Percona University is a series of free technical events organized by Percona in various cities around the world since 2013. Percona uses these events to share its unbiased expertise on open source databases with the community, users, and organizations.</description></item><item><title>FerretDB - A Quick Look</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/12/ferretdb-a-quick-look/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/12/ferretdb-a-quick-look/</guid><description>There is an old saying that what looks like a duck and quacks like a duck is probably a duck. But what looks like MongoDB and acts like MongoDB could be FerretDB! To greatly simplify the technology behind this project, FerretDB speaks, or quacks, MongoDB but stores the data in PostgreSQL. PostgreSQL has had a rich JSON data environment for years and FerrtDB takes advantage of this capability. This is a truly Open Source MongoDB alternative and was released under the Apache 2.</description></item><item><title>​​Using the JSON data type with MySQL 8 - Part II</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/11/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8-ii/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/11/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8-ii/</guid><description>If you read - Using the JSON data type with MySQL 8 - Part I, you will see that inserting data into MySQL of JSON type is a very common and effective practice. Now we&amp;rsquo;ll see how to do it with a Python project, using SQLAlchemy and Docker Compose, which further automates this example. You can run this example using a single command: docker-compose up
Before getting down to work, we will review some important concepts:</description></item><item><title>How to prevent unauthorized users from connecting to ProxySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/30/how-to-prevent-unauthorized-users-from-connecting-to-proxysql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/30/how-to-prevent-unauthorized-users-from-connecting-to-proxysql/</guid><description>ProxySQL is a great load balancer which however suffers from some shortcomings concerning the management of MySQL users. ProxySQL provides a firewall which, in my case, is not complete enough to properly manage users and secure their access. Indeed, this firewall does not accept subnets and keeps unauthorized connections in ProxySQL. We cannot then be sure of not suffering a DDOS attack on our ProxySQL instance. In this article, I will explain how I managed to overcome this problem.</description></item><item><title>How To Optimize the Structure of a Simple PHP Application as Your Project Grows</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/28/how-to-optimize-the-structure-of-a-simple-php-application-as-your-project-grows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/28/how-to-optimize-the-structure-of-a-simple-php-application-as-your-project-grows/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss the structure of our simple PHP application, folders, files, and functions and transform the project to grow it.
You and I have developed a small PHP application that makes an HTTP request to the GitHub API and stores the result in the database.
Step 1 - How to Develop a Simple Web Application Using Docker-compose, Nginx, PHP 8, and MongoDB 6. Step 2 - How to Make HTTP Requests to API in PHP App Using GitHub API Example and Write to Percona Server for MongoDB.</description></item><item><title>How to Make HTTP Requests to API in PHP App Using GitHub API Example and Write to Percona Server for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/how-to-make-http-requests-to-api-in-php-app-using-github-api-example-and-write-to-percona-server-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/how-to-make-http-requests-to-api-in-php-app-using-github-api-example-and-write-to-percona-server-for-mongodb/</guid><description>We learn how to work with HTTP requests in PHP and make API requests using the GitHub API as an example. We&amp;rsquo;ll get the data from the API and save it to the database.
In the previous article, we developed a simple application that connects to the MongoDB database (Percona Server for MongoDB) and writes documents in a loop. We only used Composer packages to work with MongoDB. We have set up the Docker-compose environment and have the app/ directory where the application code is located.</description></item><item><title>How to Develop a Simple Web Application Using Docker, Nginx, PHP, and Percona Server for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m developing an application that takes data from different sources, processes it, and prepares reports. In this series of articles, I will explain how to install and configure the tools, application, and database to develop and run the application.
About the application and choice of tools The application I develop gets data from GitHub, Jira, and websites via API, processes it and creates reports according to the desired requirements.
The application is developed with PHP version 8+ and Nginx as a web server, and Percona Server for MongoDB as a database.</description></item><item><title>Some Notable Bugfixes in MySQL 8.0.32</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/15/some-notable-bugfixes-in-mysql-8.0.32/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/15/some-notable-bugfixes-in-mysql-8.0.32/</guid><description>MySQL 8.0.32 came out recently and had some important bugfixes contributed by Perconians. Here is a brief overview of the work done.
Inconsistent data and GTIDs with mysqldump Marcelo Altmann (Senior Software Engineer) fixed the bug when data and GTIDs backed up by mysqldump were inconsistent. It happened when the options &amp;ndash;single-transaction and &amp;ndash;set-gtid-purged=ON were both used because GTIDs on the server could have already increased between the start of the transaction by mysqldump and the fetching of GTID_EXECUTED.</description></item><item><title>Using the JSON data type with MySQL 8</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/13/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/13/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8/</guid><description>If you are a mobile app, frontend, backend, or game developer, you use data types such as string, numeric, or DateTime. You also know that since the advent of non-relational databases (NoSQL) such as MongoDB, which, by not being tied to a traditional SQL schema, do reading and writing on databases much faster. But MySQL showed that storing the JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) data type could also improve the speed of reading and writing relational databases.</description></item><item><title>Monitor your databases with Open Source tools like PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/06/monitor-your-databases-with-open-source-tools-like-pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/06/monitor-your-databases-with-open-source-tools-like-pmm/</guid><description>In this post, we will cover the value of database monitoring and how we can use Open Source tools like PMM Percona Monitoring and Management to monitor and manage databases effectively.
Why should I care about database monitoring? Once you have passed the installation and configuration of your databases and it is well underway, you have to start monitoring it, and not only the database but the elements related to it.</description></item><item><title>Binding your application to the database in the Kubernetes cluster</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</guid><description>dbaas-operator is Yet Another DBaaS Kubernetes Operator (need to suggest yadbko as a name) that tries to simplify and unify Database Cluster deployments by building a higher abstraction layer on top of Percona Kubernetes Operators.
So it becomes much easier to deploy the DB cluster with dbaas-operator and PMM DBaaS on top of it.
But another part of the picture is applications and their workloads to connect to the deployed DB Clusters.</description></item><item><title>Learning Kubernetes Operators with Percona Operator for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</guid><description>One of the topics that have resonated a lot for me since the first KubeCon I attended in 2018 is Kubernetes Operators.
The concept of Operators was introduced much earlier in 2016 by the CoreOS Linux development team. They were looking for a way to improve automated container management in Kubernetes.
What do we mean by a Kubernetes Operator? We use the definition of CNCF. The Kubernetes project defines “Operator” simply: “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components“.</description></item><item><title>Recap Monthly Percona Developer Meetup Hacktoberfest</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/05/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/05/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>The Monthly Percona Developer Meetup is an opportunity to get a behind-the-scenes view of different projects in Percona and directly interact with the experts to exchange ideas, ask questions, etc.
From now on, Monthly Percona Developer Meetups will take place monthly to have open discussions and in-person (online) communication. You can join our Developer Meetup via Restream, the Percona YouTube channel, and LinkedIn events.
The topic of the first Monthly Percona Developer Meetup was Hacktoberfest.</description></item><item><title>FTD Data 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</guid><description>A big part of the Percona Brazilian team gathered together in Florianópolis to participate in a special edition of the Floripa Tech Day (FTD), focused on DATA. The agenda included talks on various technologies: MongoDB, MS-SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, and PostgreSQL.
It was a 1-day event with 13 talks from early morining till late evening. Three of them were deliverd by Percona speakers:
Online Backup in MySQL with XtraBackup by Marcelo Altmann (Software Engineer).</description></item><item><title>Data Wrangling With MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-jean-joseph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-jean-joseph/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
This presentation is based on data wrangling with MongoDB. After this presentation, you will have the mindset of data wrangling. It is 70% demo, and 30% talk. Jean covers the goal of data wrangling, how to think about data wrangling, and then the technical tips for data wrangling in MongoDB.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.</description></item><item><title>Liquibase Data: Version Control and Collaboration for the Database</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Liquibase is the defacto standard for versioning your database schema. With 15 years of use by the largest enterprises, Liquibase is a proven Open Source DevOps Solution. Now, with Liquibase Data, users can apply git-like workflows to development and test environments. See how free Open Source Liquibase can accelerate database development and cross-team deployments.</description></item><item><title>Making Databases as Easy as Legos: No code, No problem!</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-farokh-shahabi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-farokh-shahabi/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
The race to reinvent databases for non-developers has just begun and no, businesses won&amp;rsquo;t settle to spreadsheets.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/tP1pEr3sS0w
Transcript</description></item><item><title>ProxySQL 2021 Dev Submit</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-javier-fernandez/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-javier-fernandez/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
ProxySQL has proven itself as the de-facto standard reverse proxy for MySQL, yet, we are always looking for new features and improvements. During this past year starting with v2.1.0, four new major ProxySQL versions were released, and with them new features of all sorts were introduced, ranging from protocol changes, authentication improvements, clustering improvements, new monitoring features (for Galera, Group Replication, Aurora AWS) to DDOS protection.</description></item><item><title>The Lost Art of Database Design</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-matt-yonkovit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-matt-yonkovit/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Right now we are in a spot where people think that the databases are just part of the commoditized infrastructure. But unfortunately, that leads us to a lot of problems. And Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona, is talking about database design here. There are a lot of people out there who have never heard why they should focus on designing their databases, and their database infrastructure a little better.</description></item><item><title>HighLoad++ Spring 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</guid><description>Percona team participated in the HighLoad ++ Spring conference in Moscow on May 17-18, 2021. It is the most famous IT conference in Russia for developers of highload projects. This year it brought together 2000 participants offline and 2000 online running 8 parallel tracks and having 20+ company stands for networking.
On the conference, Percona speakers presented 4 talks:
MySQL 8 Observability and Query Analysis with PMM by Peter Zaitsev (CEO) Comparison of Kubernetes Operators for MySQL by Sergey Pronin (Product Owner) Migrations between schemas and updates in MySQL: mechanisms, locks, loads by Nikolay Ihalainen (Senior Support Engineer) Anatomy of a Kubernetes Operator for a database by Peter Zaitsev and Sergey Pronin.</description></item><item><title>How to Write Your Index in Tarantool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 17:23:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</guid><description>Tarantool is an application server and a database. The server part is written in C, and the user is provided with a Lua interface to use it. Then, Tarantool is an open-source product with its source code in open access, and anyone can develop and distribute Tarantool-based software freely.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you about an attempt to write my own data structure for the search (the Z-order curve) and build it into the Tarantool ecosystem.</description></item></channel></rss>