<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CNCF on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/cncf/</link><description>Recent content in CNCF on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/cncf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Timeline for Database on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>The Evolution Since its inception in June 2014, Kubernetes has dramatically transformed container orchestration, revolutionizing the management and scaling of applications. To mark its tenth anniversary, the Data on Kubernetes Community (DoKC) released an infographic showcasing key milestones and community contributions to the evolution of operators for managing stateful applications. This project was made possible by the collaboration of DoKC members Edith Puclla, Sergey Pronin, Robert Hodges, Gabriele Bartolini, Chris Malarky, Mark Kember, Paul Au, and Luciano Stabel.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Kubernetes Operators</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/03/kubernetes-operators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/03/kubernetes-operators/</guid><description>The concept of Kubernetes Operators was introduced around 2016 by the CoreOS Linuxdevelopment team. They were in search of a solution to improve automated container management within Kubernetes, primarily with the goal of incorporating operational expertise directly into the software.
According to the Cloud Native Computing Foundation, “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components”.
Kubernetes is designed for automation, offering essential automation features. It can automatically deploy and manage workloads.</description></item><item><title>Data on Kubernetes Meetup May 23</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Percona has started to participate in Data on Kubernetes (DoK) meetings about Kubernetes Operators. These meetings are an initiative of DoK meetups that spotlight DoK case studies. In this blog post series, I will summarize the topics covered in each meeting.
On May 23, very interesting topics were discussed on the agenda. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin to summarize it.
We start with a new project proposal, which is called: Distributed Systems Operator Interface (DSOI).</description></item><item><title>​What experts said at Kubecon about Data on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Melissa Logan, managing director of Data on Kubernetes (DoK), led one of the best panels I’ve been to at a conference at Kubecon EU in Amsterdam about challenges with and the state of the art of running databases on Kubernetes.
This panel united the Data on Kubernetes Community Operator SIG and Kubernetes Storage SIG to discuss key features of Kubernetes database operators. Xing Yang from VMware, Sergey Pronin from Percona, and Álvaro Hernández from OnGres came together to discuss what works, what doesn’t, and where the industry is going.</description></item><item><title>​My Experience at Kubecon Europe in Amsterdam</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/11/experience-at-kubecon-europe-in-amsterdam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/11/experience-at-kubecon-europe-in-amsterdam/</guid><description>Kubecon is the most significant event focused on the Kubernetes ecosystem. It takes place once a year in North America, Europe, and Asia. It is a perfect opportunity to learn from experts, meet friends, grow your network, and attend talks at a varied technical level and meetings focused on CNCF communities. This time I attended Kubecon in Amsterdam. The theme for this version of Kubecon was: community-in-bloom because we are still healing from COVID, and people are getting back to feeling comfortable participating in events.</description></item></channel></rss>