<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/authors/kaj_arno/</link><description>Recent content on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 09:34:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/authors/kaj_arno/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two weeks to MariaDB Server Fest</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 09:34:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</guid><description>There is still time to register for the MariaDB Server Fest 2020!
MariaDB Fest 2020[/caption]
Our Fest is the opportunity to have live interactions with the key players on MariaDB Server: the developers of MariaDB Server, the service providers, the experts, the system integrators, and – perhaps most importantly – your fellow users!
Interactivity happens all the time, with the presenters being cloned and available for answering questions throughout the presentation.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB Server Fest: Call for Papers</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/26/mariadb-server-fest-call-for-papers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 21:42:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/26/mariadb-server-fest-call-for-papers/</guid><description>In the week of 14-20 September 2020, MariaDB Foundation will host the MariaDB Server Fest Online Conference. We welcome the Percona Community not just to participate, but also to submit papers for the event. We already have Peter Zaitsev joining as keynoter; we hope for more to come.
Our target audience are the users of MariaDB Server – current and future ones. We are looking for use cases, practices, tools and insights from our user base as well as from application developers, service providers and other experts.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.4 and the Competition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 23:10:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 12:30 p.m. • London 5:30 p.m. • New Delhi 10:00 p.m.
Abstract There are many good databases out there. Picking the right database for your project is never easy. There are technical criteria, business criteria, perhaps even ethical criteria. In this keynote, MariaDB Foundation CEO Kaj Arno will present his - obviously completely impartial - view of the process. Should you pick a database in the cloud or on premise?</description></item></channel></rss>