<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Supports Community Events - Organize Yours With Us!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</guid><description>One of the things we love doing in Percona is participating in community events and inspiring people to stay connected in the changing world. We have experience in organizing community dinners, meetups, lectures at universities, booths, and even conferences both in-person and virtually. Percona speakers give talks on events all around the globe.
Have you ever thought about organizing a themed meeting for your local open source community? It may harbor many possibilities for you.</description></item><item><title>DBdeployer, the Community Edition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/14/dbdeployer-the-community-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 18:44:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/14/dbdeployer-the-community-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 3:30 a.m. • London 8:30 a.m. • New Delhi 1:00 p.m. • Singapore 3:30 p.m.
Abstract DBdeployer, an open source tool that allows easy deployment of many MySQL/Percona servers in the same host, has passed two years of development. Its latest additions have aimed at improving ease of use for both beginners and experts. This talk will show how to start with dbdeployer with an empty box, and quickly populate it with recent and less recent server versions, all at the command line.</description></item><item><title>Analytical Queries in MySQL – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 17:05:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 6:00 p.m. • London 11:00 p.m. • New Delhi 3:30 a.m. • Singapore 6:00 a.m.
Abstract MySQL&amp;rsquo;s sweet spot is known to be online transaction processing (OLTP), and it can support a very high load of short transactions. Many users will also want to run analytical queries (OLAP) on their MySQL data. Often they achieve this by exporting their data to another database system that is tailored for analytical queries.</description></item><item><title>Serverless Databases: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/08/serverless-databases-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 20:58:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/08/serverless-databases-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 4:30 a.m. • London 9:30 a.m • New Delhi 2:00 p.m. • Singapore 4:30 p.m.
Abstract Starting with AWS, the major cloud providers offer different options to run a MySQL or a MySQL-compatible database on the cloud. A new approach is to rely on so-called serverless (relational) databases like Aurora Serverless that offer both traditional TCP connections and HTTP API access.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Ecosystem on ARM – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/07/mysql-ecosystem-on-arm-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 02:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/07/mysql-ecosystem-on-arm-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 8:00 p.m. • London 1:00 a.m (next day) • New Delhi 5:30 a.m. • Singapore 8:00 a.m.
Abstract? The ARM ecosystem is quickly evolving as a cost-effective alternative to run High-Performance Computing (HPC) software. It continues to grow with some major cloud players hosting ARM-based cloud servers. MySQL too joined the ecosystem with 8.x. MariaDB already has made its presence.</description></item><item><title>NoSQL Endgame – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/05/nosql-endgame-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 01:08:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/05/nosql-endgame-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 3:00 p.m. • London 8:00 p.m. • New Delhi 12:30 a.m. (next day) • Singapore 3:00 a.m.
Abstract The amount of data collected by applications nowadays is growing at a scary pace. Many of them need to handle billions of users generating and consuming data at an incredible speed. Maybe you are wondering how to create an application like this?</description></item><item><title>Kunlun Distributed DB Cluster Intro – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 22:25:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 9:30 p.m. • London 02:30 a.m. (next day) • New Delhi 7:00 a.m. • Singapore 09:30 a.m.
Abstract Kunlun Distributed Database Cluster is a distributed DBMS that aims to combine the best of both MySQL and PostgreSQL for a highly performant, highly available, highly scalable and fault-tolerant, easy to use and manage database system that requires minimal human maintenance. It enables users to define table sharding rules so that it automatically distributes tables properly to available storage shards; implements the two-phase commit protocol to do distributed transaction commit; uses MySQL group replication for high availability in storage shards; fixes a series of MySQL XA bugs to make distributed transactions highly reliable, among many other enhancements.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.5 New Features for Troubleshooting – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/mariadb-10-5-new-features-for-troubleshooting-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/mariadb-10-5-new-features-for-troubleshooting-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Aug • New York 12:00 midnight • London 05:00 a.m. • New Delhi 9:30 a.m. • Singapore 12:00 noon
Abstract I want to help DBAs and Support engineers find out what&amp;rsquo;s really going on when some problem strikes. My goal is to show new ways to diagnose problems now available in MariaDB 10.5. See the full abstract for more.
Why Is Your Talk Exciting?</description></item><item><title>Two weeks to MariaDB Server Fest</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 09:34:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</guid><description>There is still time to register for the MariaDB Server Fest 2020!
MariaDB Fest 2020[/caption]
Our Fest is the opportunity to have live interactions with the key players on MariaDB Server: the developers of MariaDB Server, the service providers, the experts, the system integrators, and – perhaps most importantly – your fellow users!
Interactivity happens all the time, with the presenters being cloned and available for answering questions throughout the presentation.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB Server Fest: Call for Papers</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/26/mariadb-server-fest-call-for-papers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 21:42:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/26/mariadb-server-fest-call-for-papers/</guid><description>In the week of 14-20 September 2020, MariaDB Foundation will host the MariaDB Server Fest Online Conference. We welcome the Percona Community not just to participate, but also to submit papers for the event. We already have Peter Zaitsev joining as keynoter; we hope for more to come.
Our target audience are the users of MariaDB Server – current and future ones. We are looking for use cases, practices, tools and insights from our user base as well as from application developers, service providers and other experts.</description></item><item><title>Cassandra Where and How by John Schulz</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</guid><description>If Percona Live ONLINE had graded its talks by skill level this year, John Schulz’s talk would have been essential viewing in the Beginners track. (You can watch all the event’s presentations now on Percona’s YouTube channel.) This talk was a good overview and meant for anyone who had heard of the Apache Cassandra distributed database but wasn’t sure whether it would be suitable for their project or not.
Database-veteran, John Schulz has been tinkering with Cassandra for about a decade and to help anyone get started he gave a whistle-stop tour of the Cassandra ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Percona Projects for Google Summer of Code - 2020</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that Percona was selected as a participating organization for the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2020 program, this is our second year as a participating org with the GSoC program.
GSoC is a great program to involve young student developers in open source projects. We participated in the program in 2019 for the first time and we were really happy and satisfied with the results.</description></item><item><title>Anti-Cheating Tool for Massive Multiplayer Games Using Amazon Aurora and Amazon ML Services – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/13/anti-cheating-tool-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 16:06:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/13/anti-cheating-tool-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 4 p.m. • London 9 p.m. • New Delhi 1:30 a.m. (Wed) Level: Intermediate
Abstract Multiplayer video games are among the most lucrative online services. The overall games industry worldwide generated an estimated $174B in 2019, according to IDC. With this popularity, cheating becomes a common trend. Cheating in multiplayer games negatively impacts the game experience for players who play by the rules, and it becomes a revenue issue for game developers and publishers.</description></item><item><title>State of the Dolphin – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/12/state-of-the-dolphin-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/12/state-of-the-dolphin-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 11:00 a.m. • London 4:00 p.m. • New Delhi 8:30 p.m.
Abstract I will talk about the latest improvements in MySQL 8.0.20 and the MySQL Engineering Team&amp;rsquo;s steady progress with MySQL 8.0. These include solutions like Document Store, InnoDB Cluster, and InnoDB ReplicaSet where MySQL Router and MySQL Shell are playing an important role. All of these Oracle solutions are completely open source.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes, The Swiss Army Knife For Your ProxySQL Deployments – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/08/kubernetes-the-swiss-army-knife-for-your-proxysql-deployments-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 02:02:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/08/kubernetes-the-swiss-army-knife-for-your-proxysql-deployments-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 10:00 p.m. • London 3:00 a.m. (Wed) • New Delhi 7:30 a.m. (Wed)
Abstract ProxySQL is a high performance proxy from design to implementation. It speaks the MySQL protocol, and can go beyond load balancing. This talk covers various deployment options for ProxySQL in a Kubernetes environment.
Typically ProxySQL is deployed in one of three ways depending on the scale and needs of your environment:</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.4 and the Competition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 23:10:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 12:30 p.m. • London 5:30 p.m. • New Delhi 10:00 p.m.
Abstract There are many good databases out there. Picking the right database for your project is never easy. There are technical criteria, business criteria, perhaps even ethical criteria. In this keynote, MariaDB Foundation CEO Kaj Arno will present his - obviously completely impartial - view of the process. Should you pick a database in the cloud or on premise?</description></item><item><title>Orchestrating Cassandra with Kubernetes Operator and Yelp PaaSTA - Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/06/orchestrating-cassandra-with-kubernetes-operator-and-yelp-paasta-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/06/orchestrating-cassandra-with-kubernetes-operator-and-yelp-paasta-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 3:00 p.m. • London 8:00 p.m. • New Delhi 12:30 a.m. (Wed) Level: Intermediate
Abstract At Yelp, Cassandra, our NoSQL database of choice, has been deployed on AWS compute (EC2) and AutoScaling Groups (ASG), backed by Block Storage (EBS). This deployment model has been quite robust over the years while presenting its own set of challenges. To make our Cassandra deployment more resilient and reduce the engineering toil associated with our constantly growing infrastructure, we are abstracting Cassandra deployments further away from EC2 with Kubernetes and orchestrating with our Cassandra Operator.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Tracing for Finding and Solving MariaDB (and MySQL) Performance Problems on Linux - Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/05/dynamic-tracing-for-finding-and-solving-mariadb-and-mysql-performance-problems-on-linux-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 21:13:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/05/dynamic-tracing-for-finding-and-solving-mariadb-and-mysql-performance-problems-on-linux-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot (CORRECTED): Wed 20 May • New York 6:00 a.m. • London 11:00 a.m. • New Delhi 3:30 p.m. Level: Advanced
Abstract While troubleshooting MariaDB server performance problems it is important to find out where the time is spent in the mysqld process, on-CPU and off-CPU. The process of investigation should have as small influence as possible on the server we try to troubleshoot. Performance_schema introduced in MySQL 5.</description></item><item><title>Expert MariaDB: Utilize MariaDB Server Effectively - Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/expert-mariadb-utilize-mariadb-server-effectively-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/expert-mariadb-utilize-mariadb-server-effectively-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 11:00 p.m. • London 4:00 a.m. (Wed) • New Delhi 8:30 a.m. (Wed) Level: Intermediate
Abstract MariaDB Server 10.4 has been out for some time now (June 2019) and it has many new features, some of which MySQL does not have. Feature-wise, it is important to know what MariaDB Server 10.4 has (e.g. system tables in the Aria storage engine, ability to reload SSL certificates without a restart and more!</description></item><item><title>Our Offer to Online Meetups and Community Leaders</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/07/our-offer-to-online-meetups-and-community-leaders/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 10:52:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/07/our-offer-to-online-meetups-and-community-leaders/</guid><description>Percona’s Community team organizes our speakers at in-person events around the world, such as Percona Live, Percona University, and events sponsored by other organizations. However, like everyone else around the world, all our plans are on hold due to the Coronavirus pandemic.
Perhaps you, like many others, are organizing online events, such as virtual meetups on Meetup.com. We can help you by making Percona’s team of experienced and well-known speakers available for your event.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: Test Like a Boss</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/25/percona-live-europe-presents-test-like-a-boss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 06:31:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/25/percona-live-europe-presents-test-like-a-boss/</guid><description>My first talk is a tutorial Testing like a boss: Deploy and Test Complex Topologies With a Single Command, scheduled at Percona Live Europe in Amsterdam on September 30th at 13:30.
My second talk is Amazing sandboxes with dbdeployer scheduled on October 1st at 11:00. It is the same topic as the tutorial, but covers a narrow set of features, all in the *amazing* category.
The tutorial introduces a challenging topic, because when people hear testing, they imagine a troop of monkeys fiddling with a keyboard and a mouse, endlessly repeating a boring task.</description></item><item><title>Are your Database Backups Good Enough?</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</guid><description>In the last few years there have been several examples of major service problems affecting businesses data: outages causing data inconsistencies; unavailability or data loss, and worldwide cyberattacks encrypting your files and asking for a ransom.
Database-related incidents are a very common industry issue- even if the root cause is not the database system itself. No matter if your main relational system is MySQL, MariaDB, PostgresQL or AWS Aurora -there will be a time where you will need to make use of backups to recover to a previous state.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe '19: MongoDB 4.2</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/18/percona-live-europe-19-mongodb-4-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 15:22:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/18/percona-live-europe-19-mongodb-4-2/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s all about MongoDB® 4.2 this time. MongoDB 4.2 released like a month ago (still newborn) and I am going to cover what&amp;rsquo;s new in three different areas: sharding, indexing, and the aggregation framework. I can promise you this, there are a lot of new features and improvements in MongoDB 4.2 and I am thrilled to present those to you. Join me at Percona Live Europe, and discover how distributed transactions, wildcard indexes and materialized views (plus many other new features) actually work and fit on your workload.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Globalizing Player Accounts with MySQL at Riot Games</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/28/percona-live-presents-globalizing-player-accounts-mysql-riot-games/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:48:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/28/percona-live-presents-globalizing-player-accounts-mysql-riot-games/</guid><description>During my presentation at Percona Live 2019, I’ll be talking about how Riot Games, the company behind League of Legends, migrated hundreds of millions of player accounts to unlock opportunities for us to delight players. This meant moving ten geographically distributed databases into a single global database replicated into four AWS regions. I’ll talk about some of the technical decisions we made, the expected vs actual outcomes, and lessons we learned along the way.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Gonymizer, A Tool to Anonymize Sensitive PostgreSQL Data Tables for Use in QA and Testing</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/17/percona-live-gonymizer-tool-anonymize-sensitive-postgresql-data-testing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 11:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/17/percona-live-gonymizer-tool-anonymize-sensitive-postgresql-data-testing/</guid><description>SmithRX is a next generation pharmacy benefit platform that is using the latest technology to radically reshape the prescription benefit management industry. To move quickly, we require the ability to iterate and test new versions of our software using production like data without violating Health Information Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) regulations.
At Percona Live 2019, we are introducing a project we open sourced to anonymize our sensitive production data for use in rapid QA and testing of our software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: An Open-Source, Cloud Native Database</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/14/percona-live-presents-open-source-cloud-native-database/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 17:38:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/14/percona-live-presents-open-source-cloud-native-database/</guid><description>During our presentation at Percona Live 2019 Intel and its software partners will introduce the audience to the work we’re doing to enable an open-source framework, we call Cloud Native Database. This is a collaborative effort between Intel, Rockset, PlanetScale, MariaDB and Percona.
Through the presentation the audience will be introduced to a set of principles and architectural elements that define what we mean by Cloud Native Database. We will discuss Rockset’s RocksDB-Cloud library and how it works with Facebook’s MyRocks storage engine.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The State of Databases in 2019</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</guid><description>At this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live I am talking about The State of Databases in 2019. As a Software Engineer in the thick of the Database landscape, there are two problems that I see repeatedly.
Due to the massive explosion of database solutions, it has become very difficult to evaluate what database solution will serve the best for one’s use case, and
The constant tug of war between database operators and users.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The MySQL Query Optimizer Explained Through Optimizer Trace</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/24/mysql-query-optimizer-explained-optimizer-trace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 16:16:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/24/mysql-query-optimizer-explained-optimizer-trace/</guid><description>During my presentation at Percona Live 2019 I will show how using Optimizer Trace can give insight into the inner workings of the MySQL Query Optimizer. Through the presentation, the audience will both be introduced to optimizer trace, learn more about the decisions the query optimizer makes, and learn about the query execution strategies the query optimizer has at its disposal. I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the main phases of the MySQL optimizer and its optimization strategies, including query transformations, data access strategies, the range optimizer, the join optimizer, and subquery optimization.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Vitess – Running Sharded MySQL on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/18/percona-live-presents-vitess-running-sharded-mysql-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 17:19:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/18/percona-live-presents-vitess-running-sharded-mysql-kubernetes/</guid><description>The topic I&amp;rsquo;m presenting addresses a growing and unfulfilled need: the ability to run stateful workloads in Kubernetes. Running stateless applications is now considered a solved problem. However, it&amp;rsquo;s currently not practical to put databases like MySQL in containers, give them to Kubernetes, and expect it to manage their life cycles.
Sugu Sougoumarane, CTO of Planetscale and creator of Vitess.
Vitess addresses this need by providing all the necessary orchestration and safety, and it has multiple years of mileage to show for it.</description></item><item><title>London Open Source Database Community Meetup</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 09:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</guid><description>I strongly believe in the community.
Communities are the real strength of open source. Not just the theoretical ability to study, modify and share code – but the fact that other people out there are doing these things. Creating a base of knowledge and a network of relations.These can become work relationships, valuable discussions, open source tools, or even friendships.
That is why, when I heard that several people from the Percona support team will soon be in London, I badly wanted to organise an event.</description></item><item><title>#ilovefs Valentine's Day Celebration (I Love Free Software)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/02/14/ilovefs-valentines-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 10:21:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/02/14/ilovefs-valentines-day/</guid><description>Free Software Foundation Europe (FSFE) is celebrating the creators of free software with their I Love Free Software campaign #ilovefs, a social campaign for Valentine’s Day.
The idea is to show some appreciation to the makers of free software. Most of our communications with free software creators are about bugs and feature requests and maybe we just forget to say &amp;ldquo;Thanks&amp;rdquo;. So FSFE are trying to provide some balance.
FSFE were promoting the campaign at FOSDEM at the beginning of this month.</description></item><item><title>Writing a Killer Conference Proposal</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/01/03/writing-killer-conference-proposal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 10:40:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/01/03/writing-killer-conference-proposal/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to submit a proposal to Percona Live but suffering a little writer’s block, or at least want to be sure to make a good impression on our track selectors, there’s some great content online that can help. If you’re an old hand, you probably won’t need this, though it’s possible you’ll find some interesting stuff here nevertheless.
Your job is to make it easy for the selectors to choose your talk.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: ClickHouse at Messagebird: Analysing Billions of Events in Real-Time*</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/29/clickhouse-at-messagebird-analysing-billions-of-events-in-real-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 17:28:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/29/clickhouse-at-messagebird-analysing-billions-of-events-in-real-time/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll look into how Clickhouse allows us to ingest a large amount of data and run complex analytical interactive queries at MessageBird. We also present the business needs that brought ClickHouse to our attention and detail the journey to its deployment. We cover the problems we faced, and how we dealt with them. We talk about our current Cloud production setup and how we deployed and use it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: pg_chameleon MySQL to PostgreSQL Replica Made Easy</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 14:42:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</guid><description>What excites me is the possibility that this tool is giving to other people. Also, the challenges I’ve faced and the new ideas for the future releases are always source of interest that keep me focused on the project. So I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to sharing this with the conference delegates.
pg_chameleon can achieve two tasks in a very simple way. It can setup a permanent replica between MySQL and PostgreSQL, giving the freedom of choice for the right tool for the right job, or can migrate multiple schemas to a PostgreSQL database.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: MariaDB 10.4 Reverse Privileges (DENY)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/23/mariadb-10-4-reverse-privileges-deny/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 11:41:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/23/mariadb-10-4-reverse-privileges-deny/</guid><description>One of the most common questions about privileges in MySQL and MariaDB is how would a user revoke access to a particular table, in a large database with hundreds or thousands of tables, while keeping the rest available. Currently, there is no easy solution. Just grant access to everything else, individually. Not only does this reduce server performance, but is a nightmare to maintain. Reverse privileges solve this and more.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: Need for speed - Boosting Apache Cassandra's performance using Netty</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/22/percona-live-europe-presents-need-speed-boosting-apache-cassandras-performance-using-netty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 08:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/22/percona-live-europe-presents-need-speed-boosting-apache-cassandras-performance-using-netty/</guid><description>My talk is titled Need for speed: Boosting Apache Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s performance using Netty. Over the years that I have worked in the software industry, making code run fast has fascinated me. So, naturally when I first started contributing to Apache Cassandra, I started looking opportunities to improve its performance. My talk takes us through some interesting challenges within a distributed system like Apache Cassandra and various techniques to significantly improve its performance.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: The Latest MySQL Replication Features</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/19/latest-mysql-replication-features/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 15:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/19/latest-mysql-replication-features/</guid><description>Considering the modern world of technology, where distributed system play a key role, replication in MySQL® is at the very heart of that change. It is very exciting to deliver this presentation and to be able to show everyone the greatest and the latest features that MySQL brings in order to continue the success that it has always been in the past.
The talk is suitable for anyone that&amp;rsquo;s interested in knowing what Oracle is doing with MySQL replication.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: MariaDB System-Versioned Tables</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/17/percona-live-europe-presents-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 16:14:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/17/percona-live-europe-presents-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</guid><description>System-versioned tables, or temporal tables, are a typical feature of proprietary database management systems like DB2, Oracle and SQL Server. They also appeared at some point in PostgreSQL, but only as an extension; and also in CockroachDB, but in a somewhat limited fashion.
The MariaDB® implementation is the first appearance of temporal tables in the MySQL ecosystem, and the most complete implementation in the open source world.
My presentation will be useful for analysts, and some managers, who will definitely benefit from learning how to use temporal tables.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Session: What's New in MariaDB Server 10.3</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/percona-live-europe-session-whats-new-mariadb-server-10-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 12:42:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/percona-live-europe-session-whats-new-mariadb-server-10-3/</guid><description>** Having spent my recent years &amp;ldquo;in the real world&amp;rdquo;, working with many users, I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt that a particular new feature does not necessarily excite users as much as one might expect. MariaDB 10.3 however actually has some very interesting features that users do get excited about.
So that&amp;rsquo;s great!
My session at Percona Live Europe in Frankfurt is going to be best for people deploying MariaDB or related infra, who haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to explore what the various features actually mean, or what they can do with them.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Query Optimization and TLS at Large Scale</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 14:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe this year, I got accepted a workshop on query optimization and a 50-minute talk covering TLS for MySQL at Large Scale, talking about our experiences at the Wikimedia Foundation.
Workshop The 3-hour workshop on Monday, titled Query Optimization with MySQL 8.0 and MariaDB 10.3: The Basics is a beginners' tutorial–though dense in content. It&amp;rsquo;s for people who are more familiar with database storage systems other than InnoDB for MySQL, MariaDB or Percona Server.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Elasticsearch 101</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 07:17:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe, I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting the tutorial Elasticsearch 101 alongside my colleagues and fellow presenters from ObjectRocket Alex Cercel, DBA, and Mihai Aldoiu, Data Engineer. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief overview of our tutorial.
Elasticsearch® is well known as a highly scalable search engine that stores data in a structure optimized for language based searches but its capabilities and use cases don’t stop there. In this tutorial, we’ll give you a hands-on introduction to Elasticsearch and give you a glimpse at some of the fundamental concepts.</description></item></channel></rss>