<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intermediate Level on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/intermediate-level/</link><description>Recent content in Intermediate Level on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/intermediate-level/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unexpected Stalled Upgrade to MySQL 8.0</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/26/unexpected-stalled-upgrade-to-mysql-8-0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/26/unexpected-stalled-upgrade-to-mysql-8-0/</guid><description>A multi-tenant database is a database that serves multiple clients, or tenants, who share the same database schema but have separate data sets. One way to achieve data isolation for each client is to create a separate MySQL database for each tenant.
Some advantages of this approach are:
It allows for easy backup and restore of individual tenant data. It simplifies the database administration and maintenance tasks, as each database can be managed independently.</description></item><item><title>How to Write Your Index in Tarantool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 17:23:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</guid><description>Tarantool is an application server and a database. The server part is written in C, and the user is provided with a Lua interface to use it. Then, Tarantool is an open-source product with its source code in open access, and anyone can develop and distribute Tarantool-based software freely.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you about an attempt to write my own data structure for the search (the Z-order curve) and build it into the Tarantool ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>How to contribute Dashboards to PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 14:54:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</guid><description>Have you already contributed to Percona’s open-source products or perhaps you wanted to try doing so?
I will tell you how to become a contributor to the popular open-source product from Percona in just a few hours. You don&amp;rsquo;t need any serious developer skills.
We earlier explained how to contribute to PMM documentation in our last post. Now we will contribute to PMM itself, namely to Dashboards. Dashboards are an important part of PMM, they are seen and used by thousands of users, so your contribution may be of benefit to many others.</description></item><item><title>Unexpected slow ALTER TABLE in MySQL 5.7</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/23/unexpected-slow-alter-table-mysql-5-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:47:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/23/unexpected-slow-alter-table-mysql-5-7/</guid><description>Usually one would expect that ALTER TABLE with ALGORITHM=COPY will be slower than the default ALGORITHM=INPLACE. In this blog post we describe the case when this is not so.
One of the reasons for such behavior is the lesser known limitation of ALTER TABLE (with default ALGORITHM=INPLACE) that avoids REDO operations. As a result, all dirty pages of the altered table/tablespace have to be flushed before the ALTER TABLE completion.</description></item><item><title>Percona Server for MySQL 8.0 – New Data Masking Feature</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/12/13/percona-server-for-mysql-8-0-new-data-masking-feature/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 10:43:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/12/13/percona-server-for-mysql-8-0-new-data-masking-feature/</guid><description>Database administrators are responsible for maintaining the privacy and integrity of data. When the data contains confidential information, your company has a legal obligation to ensure that privacy is maintained. Even so, being able to access the information contained in that dataset, for example for testing or reporting purposes, has great value so what to do? MySQL Enterprise Edition offers data masking and de-identification, so I decided to contribute similar functionality to Percona Server for MySQL.</description></item></channel></rss>