<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/categories/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/categories/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Joins Community Over Code 2024 in Bratislava, Slovakia</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/21/percona-joins-community-over-code-2024-in-bratislava-slovakia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/21/percona-joins-community-over-code-2024-in-bratislava-slovakia/</guid><description>Last week, I participated as a speaker for the first time at Community Over Code 2024.
Community Over Code Community Over Code is a key principle at Apache, highlighting the importance of having a solid and collaborative community rather than just focusing on the code. While good code is essential, the community&amp;rsquo;s strength and resilience keep a project going and growing. I love how this is expressed in the &amp;ldquo;Apache Way.</description></item><item><title>Take a Clone it will last longer</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/02/take-a-clone-it-will-last-longer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/02/take-a-clone-it-will-last-longer/</guid><description>So cloning is a great subject. I mean we clone sheep, we can clone human organs in time we might be able to clone humans, but thats a topic for scientist and philosophers.
What is MySQL Replicaion:
The MySQL clone plugin can be used to replicate data from a MySQL server to another MySQL server, and it supports replication. The cloning process creates a physical snapshot of the data, including tables, schemas, tablespaces, and data dictionary metadata.</description></item><item><title>How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes with Percona Everest Summary</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</guid><description>Kubernetes continues evolving, and the complexity of deploying and managing databases within the ecosystem is a topic of considerable discussion and importance these days. This article summarizes a detailed discussion between Piotr Szczepaniak and Diogo Recharte, who offer insights and live demonstrations to simplify database operations on Kubernetes with a new technology for cloud-native applications: Percona Everest. If you want to watch the full video, check out How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes Webinar.</description></item><item><title>Using ProxySQL Query Mirroring to test query performance on a new cluster</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/01/using-proxysql-query-mirroring-to-test-query-peromance-on-a-new-cluster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/01/using-proxysql-query-mirroring-to-test-query-peromance-on-a-new-cluster/</guid><description>ProxySQL is an SQL aware proxy, which gives DBA&amp;rsquo;s fine grained control over clients’ access to the MySQL cluster. A key part of our DBA team’s process in testing and preparing for major MySQL version upgrades is comparing query plans using ProxySQL query mirroring. This feature allows us to mirror queries to another cluster / host, by configuring query rules. What makes mirroring particularly useful is the ability to selectively mirror queries based on the query digest, or client user.</description></item><item><title>Data on Kubernetes Community initiatives: Automated storage scaling</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/data-on-kubernetes-community-initiatives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/data-on-kubernetes-community-initiatives/</guid><description>In the world of Kubernetes, where everything evolves quickly. Automated storage scaling stands out as a critical challenge. Members of the Data on Kubernetes Community have proposed a solution to address this issue for Kubernetes operators.
If, like me, this is your first time hearing about Automated storage scaling, this will help you understand it better:
Storage scaling in Kubernetes Operators refers to the ability of an application running on Kubernetes to adjust its storage capacity automatically based on demand.</description></item><item><title>Volunteering as a Program Committee Member for Data on Kubernetes Day Europe 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/volunteering-program-committee-data-kubernetes-europe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/volunteering-program-committee-data-kubernetes-europe/</guid><description>The Data on Kubernetes Day Europe 2024 Program Committee is a group of professionals and experts responsible for organizing the Data on Kubernetes Day Europe 2024 content for the upcoming co-located events at Kubecon in Paris on 19 March.
As Data on Kubernetes community members, Sergey Pronin (Group Product Manager at @Percona) and I (Tech Evangelist) volunteered to evaluate proposal topics submitted for the event through the Sessionize platform. Not only us but also many other members of the Data on Kubernetes community participated as volunteers.</description></item><item><title>Data On Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/10/data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/10/data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve attended one of the Kubecon talks or related events, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely encountered the phrase Data on Kubernetes. To understand what this means, let&amp;rsquo;s explore some fundamental concepts related to Kubernetes, workload, stateless, and stateful applications.
Kubernetes, workload, stateless and stateful applications Kubernetes is a container orchestration tool that has already become an industry standard. When we talk about &amp;ldquo;container orchestration&amp;rdquo;, we are referring to the automated management and coordination of containers using Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Community Days UK: Keynote Cilium and eBPF</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/10/24/kcduk-cilium-ebpf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/10/24/kcduk-cilium-ebpf/</guid><description>This week, at Kubernetes Community Days UK in London. Liz Rice, Chief Open Source Officer at Isovalent, delivered a keynote on Cilium, eBPF, and the new feature of Cilium: Mutual Authentication.
Figure 1. Liz Rice Keynote KCD UK, London. Tuesday 17, 2023
Cilium is an eBPF-powered open source, cloud native solution for delivering, securing, and observing network connectivity between workloads.
eBPF is a technology that allows us to create modules to modify the behavior of the Linux kernel, but why would we want to change the Linux kernel?</description></item><item><title>Open Source And Recession – An Economic Outlook</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/09/14/open-source-and-recession-an-economic-outlook/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/09/14/open-source-and-recession-an-economic-outlook/</guid><description>Initially, I dropped an idea of writing this blog by reckoning the amount of time and energy required to perform research. However, my mentor Ramona Gerum motivated me and provided inputs to write this blog. This would not have been possible without her help. Thank you very much Ramona.
Introduction In October 2022, the term recession gained popularity on Google trends. This happened as many economists already predicted a slowdown, and it started flashing on news channels world-wide.</description></item><item><title>Percona University in Peru 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Peru is a country in South America home to a section of the Amazon rainforest and Machu Picchu ⛰️, an ancient Incan city high in the Andes mountains. Percona decided to hold the first event of Percona University 2023 in Lima, the capital of Peru, on June 10.
Percona University is a series of free technical events organized by Percona in various cities around the world since 2013. Percona uses these events to share its unbiased expertise on open source databases with the community, users, and organizations.</description></item><item><title>Data on Kubernetes Meetup May 23</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Percona has started to participate in Data on Kubernetes (DoK) meetings about Kubernetes Operators. These meetings are an initiative of DoK meetups that spotlight DoK case studies. In this blog post series, I will summarize the topics covered in each meeting.
On May 23, very interesting topics were discussed on the agenda. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin to summarize it.
We start with a new project proposal, which is called: Distributed Systems Operator Interface (DSOI).</description></item><item><title>​What experts said at Kubecon about Data on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Melissa Logan, managing director of Data on Kubernetes (DoK), led one of the best panels I’ve been to at a conference at Kubecon EU in Amsterdam about challenges with and the state of the art of running databases on Kubernetes.
This panel united the Data on Kubernetes Community Operator SIG and Kubernetes Storage SIG to discuss key features of Kubernetes database operators. Xing Yang from VMware, Sergey Pronin from Percona, and Álvaro Hernández from OnGres came together to discuss what works, what doesn’t, and where the industry is going.</description></item><item><title>Easy Way to Start Contributing to Open Source With PMM Documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/18/easy-way-to-start-contributing-to-open-source-with-pmm-documentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/18/easy-way-to-start-contributing-to-open-source-with-pmm-documentation/</guid><description>If you are a user of Percona Monitoring and Management and noticed any typo or inaccurate information in its documentation, you can easily correct it yourself in the repository following detailed instructions in README.md. But if you are not experienced in open source contributions, you may still feel uneasy about following those steps. This post is for you! We will walk through the main steps with pictures and explanations.
Create a Fork First, you need to create a fork from the main repository to your account.</description></item><item><title>FerretDB - A Quick Look</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/12/ferretdb-a-quick-look/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/12/ferretdb-a-quick-look/</guid><description>There is an old saying that what looks like a duck and quacks like a duck is probably a duck. But what looks like MongoDB and acts like MongoDB could be FerretDB! To greatly simplify the technology behind this project, FerretDB speaks, or quacks, MongoDB but stores the data in PostgreSQL. PostgreSQL has had a rich JSON data environment for years and FerrtDB takes advantage of this capability. This is a truly Open Source MongoDB alternative and was released under the Apache 2.</description></item><item><title>How To Generate Test Data for Your Database With SQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/30/how-to-generate-test-data-for-your-database-with-sql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/30/how-to-generate-test-data-for-your-database-with-sql/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed several posts on the Percona Community blog about test data generation. This is a great trend, as such data enables us to test applications more easily and efficiently and detect problems before they appear in production. One article was devoted to the Pagila standard DB schema and another to generating test data with Python. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to continue this tradition and write an article about generating data using SQL.</description></item><item><title>How to prevent unauthorized users from connecting to ProxySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/30/how-to-prevent-unauthorized-users-from-connecting-to-proxysql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/30/how-to-prevent-unauthorized-users-from-connecting-to-proxysql/</guid><description>ProxySQL is a great load balancer which however suffers from some shortcomings concerning the management of MySQL users. ProxySQL provides a firewall which, in my case, is not complete enough to properly manage users and secure their access. Indeed, this firewall does not accept subnets and keeps unauthorized connections in ProxySQL. We cannot then be sure of not suffering a DDOS attack on our ProxySQL instance. In this article, I will explain how I managed to overcome this problem.</description></item><item><title>How To Optimize the Structure of a Simple PHP Application as Your Project Grows</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/28/how-to-optimize-the-structure-of-a-simple-php-application-as-your-project-grows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/28/how-to-optimize-the-structure-of-a-simple-php-application-as-your-project-grows/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss the structure of our simple PHP application, folders, files, and functions and transform the project to grow it.
You and I have developed a small PHP application that makes an HTTP request to the GitHub API and stores the result in the database.
Step 1 - How to Develop a Simple Web Application Using Docker-compose, Nginx, PHP 8, and MongoDB 6. Step 2 - How to Make HTTP Requests to API in PHP App Using GitHub API Example and Write to Percona Server for MongoDB.</description></item><item><title>How to Make HTTP Requests to API in PHP App Using GitHub API Example and Write to Percona Server for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/how-to-make-http-requests-to-api-in-php-app-using-github-api-example-and-write-to-percona-server-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/how-to-make-http-requests-to-api-in-php-app-using-github-api-example-and-write-to-percona-server-for-mongodb/</guid><description>We learn how to work with HTTP requests in PHP and make API requests using the GitHub API as an example. We&amp;rsquo;ll get the data from the API and save it to the database.
In the previous article, we developed a simple application that connects to the MongoDB database (Percona Server for MongoDB) and writes documents in a loop. We only used Composer packages to work with MongoDB. We have set up the Docker-compose environment and have the app/ directory where the application code is located.</description></item><item><title>How to Develop a Simple Web Application Using Docker, Nginx, PHP, and Percona Server for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m developing an application that takes data from different sources, processes it, and prepares reports. In this series of articles, I will explain how to install and configure the tools, application, and database to develop and run the application.
About the application and choice of tools The application I develop gets data from GitHub, Jira, and websites via API, processes it and creates reports according to the desired requirements.
The application is developed with PHP version 8+ and Nginx as a web server, and Percona Server for MongoDB as a database.</description></item><item><title>How to test code blocks in documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/28/doc-testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/28/doc-testing/</guid><description>As any developer, I don&amp;rsquo;t like to write documentation. But if I am writing it, I would like to test that what I wrote works. I often found myself copy-pasting something from documentation and trying to run it in the terminal (commands, files, etc.), and it didn&amp;rsquo;t work.
There are usually some environment, typos, or even wrong commands in the doc (that people copy-pasted from the wrong place).
I know that issue, and after writing the documentation, I usually try to clean up everything in my environment and test the doc.</description></item><item><title>Database Schema Management Via Liquibase</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 22:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</guid><description>Creating the database for an application is simple and easy. However, database script management gets complicated in a hurry when you need to support multiple versions, work with multiple teams, and apply the same changes to multiple types of databases. One open-source tool that helps teams track, version, and deploy database schema changes is Liquibase. It executes database scripts sequentially, allows for the automatic creation and execution of rollback scripts for failed updates, and provides an easy way to use the same scripts and apply them to different types of databases.</description></item><item><title>Generating Identifiers – from AUTO_INCREMENT to Sequence</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/12/generating-identifiers-auto_increment-sequence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/12/generating-identifiers-auto_increment-sequence/</guid><description>There are a number of options for generating ID values for your tables. In this post, Alexey Mikotkin of Devart explores your choices for generating identifiers with a look at auto_increment, triggers, UUID and sequences.
AUTO_INCREMENT Frequently, we happen to need to fill tables with unique identifiers. Naturally, the first example of such identifiers is PRIMARY KEY data. These are usually integer values hidden from the user since their specific values are unimportant.</description></item><item><title>Deploying MySQL on Kubernetes with a Percona-based Operator</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:03:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</guid><description>In the context of providing managed WordPress hosting services, at Presslabs we operate with lots of small to medium-sized databases, in a DB-per-service model, as we call it. The workloads are mostly reads, so we need to efficiently scale that. The MySQL® asynchronous replication model fits the bill very well, allowing us to scale horizontally from one server—with the obvious availability pitfalls—to tens of nodes. The next release of the stack is going to be open-sourced.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Elasticsearch 101</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 07:17:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe, I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting the tutorial Elasticsearch 101 alongside my colleagues and fellow presenters from ObjectRocket Alex Cercel, DBA, and Mihai Aldoiu, Data Engineer. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief overview of our tutorial.
Elasticsearch® is well known as a highly scalable search engine that stores data in a structure optimized for language based searches but its capabilities and use cases don’t stop there. In this tutorial, we’ll give you a hands-on introduction to Elasticsearch and give you a glimpse at some of the fundamental concepts.</description></item><item><title>Minimize MySQL Deadlocks with 3 Steps</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/24/minimize-mysql-deadlocks-3-steps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 10:49:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/24/minimize-mysql-deadlocks-3-steps/</guid><description>MySQL has locking capabilities, for example table and row level locking, and such locks are needed to control data integrity in multi-user concurrency. Deadlocks—where two or more transactions are waiting for one another to give up locks before the transactions can proceed successfully—are an unwanted situation. It is a classic problem for all databases including MySQL/PostgreSQL/Oracle etc. By default, MySQL detects the deadlock condition and to break the deadlock it rolls back one of the transactions.</description></item><item><title>Multi-master with MariaDB 10 - a tutorial</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:57:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</guid><description>The goal of this tutorial is to show you how to use multi-master to aggregate databases with the same name, but different data from different masters, on the same slave.
Example:
master1 =&amp;gt; a French subsidiary master2 =&amp;gt; a British subsidiary Both have the same database PRODUCTION but the data are totally different.
This screenshot is made from my own monitoring tool: PmaControl. You have to read 10.10.16.232 on master2 and not 10.</description></item><item><title>Easy and Effective Way of Building External Dictionaries for ClickHouse with Pentaho Data Integration Tool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</guid><description>In this post, I provide an illustration of how to use Pentaho Data Integration (PDI) tool to set up external dictionaries in MySQL to support ClickHouse. Although I use MySQL in this example, you can use any PDI supported source.
ClickHouse ClickHouse is an open-source column-oriented DBMS (columnar database management system) for online analytical processing. Source: wiki.
Pentaho Data Integration Information from the Pentaho wiki: Pentaho Data Integration (PDI, also called Kettle) is the component of Pentaho responsible for the Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) processes.</description></item><item><title>A Nice Feature in MariaDB 10.3: no InnoDB Buffer Pool in Core Dumps</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/28/nice-feature-in-mariadb-103-no-innodb-buffer-pool-in-coredumps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 12:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/28/nice-feature-in-mariadb-103-no-innodb-buffer-pool-in-coredumps/</guid><description>MariaDB 10.3 is now generally available (10.3.7 was released GA on 2018-05-25). The article What&amp;rsquo;s New in MariaDB Server 10.3 by the MariaDB Corporation lists three key improvements in 10.3: temporal data processing, Oracle compatibility features, and purpose-built storage engines. Even if I am excited about MyRocks and curious on Spider, I am also very interested in less flashy but still very important changes that make running the database in production easier.</description></item><item><title>TiSpark: More Data Insights, No More ETL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/18/tispark-data-insights-no-etl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 13:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/18/tispark-data-insights-no-etl/</guid><description>When we released TiDB 2.0 in April, part of that announcement also included the release of TiSpark 1.0&amp;ndash;an integral part of the TiDB platform that makes complex analytics on “fresh” transactional data possible. Since then, many people in the TiDB community have been asking for more information about TiSpark. In this post, I will explain the motivation, inner workings, and future roadmap of this project.
Motivation The motivation behind building TiSpark was to enable real-time analytics on TiDB without the delay and challenges of ETL.</description></item></channel></rss>