<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MySQL on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/mysql/</link><description>Recent content in MySQL on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/mysql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Release Roundup April 17, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/17/release-roundup-april-17-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/17/release-roundup-april-17-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates April 2 - April 17, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup April 2, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/02/release-roundup-april-2-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/02/release-roundup-april-2-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates March 18 - April 2, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup March 18, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/18/release-roundup-march-18-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/18/release-roundup-march-18-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates March 5 - March 18, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup February 21, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/21/release-roundup-february-21-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/21/release-roundup-february-21-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates February 5 - February 21, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monthly Bug Report: January 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/19/percona-monthly-bug-report-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/19/percona-monthly-bug-report-january-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we believe that transparency is key to improving our products. We are dedicated to creating top-of-the-line open-source database solutions and providing support for any issues that may arise. We encourage feedback and bug reports to help us continually improve.
We stay updated on bug reports through our own platform as well as other sources to ensure we have the most up-to-date information. To make it easier for you, we have compiled a central list of the most critical bugs for your reference in this edition of our bug report.</description></item><item><title>Unexpected Stalled Upgrade to MySQL 8.0</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/26/unexpected-stalled-upgrade-to-mysql-8-0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/26/unexpected-stalled-upgrade-to-mysql-8-0/</guid><description>A multi-tenant database is a database that serves multiple clients, or tenants, who share the same database schema but have separate data sets. One way to achieve data isolation for each client is to create a separate MySQL database for each tenant.
Some advantages of this approach are:
It allows for easy backup and restore of individual tenant data. It simplifies the database administration and maintenance tasks, as each database can be managed independently.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monthly Bug Report: November 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/12/19/percona-monthly-bug-report-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/12/19/percona-monthly-bug-report-november-2023/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Dolphie, your real-time MySQL monitoring assistant</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/22/dolphie-your-real-time-mysql-monitoring-assistant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/22/dolphie-your-real-time-mysql-monitoring-assistant/</guid><description>For as long as I can remember, Innotop has been the go-to terminal tool for real-time MySQL monitoring. It is an invaluable addition to any DBA&amp;rsquo;s toolkit, but unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s not really actively maintained these days, except for addressing critical issues, and it hasn&amp;rsquo;t kept pace with the evolving capabilities of modern terminals. With no viable alternatives except for InnotopGo, which is also no longer actively maintained and limited to MySQL 8 (while many still use 5.</description></item><item><title>PMM Client on Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/15/pmm-client-on-raspberry-pi-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/15/pmm-client-on-raspberry-pi-4/</guid><description>This will be the third in my series of Percona Products on a Raspberry Pi. My previous posts:
How to Build a Percona Server &amp;ldquo;Stack&amp;rdquo; on a Raspberry Pi 3+ Raspberry Pi Bullseye Percona Server 64bit Before I get started I would like to thank guriandoro, for the work he did in compiling the PMM Client tools in his 2021 blog.
My regular readers know how much I love the Raspberry Pi and MySQL.</description></item><item><title>​​Using the JSON data type with MySQL 8 - Part II</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/11/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8-ii/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/11/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8-ii/</guid><description>If you read - Using the JSON data type with MySQL 8 - Part I, you will see that inserting data into MySQL of JSON type is a very common and effective practice. Now we&amp;rsquo;ll see how to do it with a Python project, using SQLAlchemy and Docker Compose, which further automates this example. You can run this example using a single command: docker-compose up
Before getting down to work, we will review some important concepts:</description></item><item><title>Some Notable Bugfixes in MySQL 8.0.32</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/15/some-notable-bugfixes-in-mysql-8.0.32/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/15/some-notable-bugfixes-in-mysql-8.0.32/</guid><description>MySQL 8.0.32 came out recently and had some important bugfixes contributed by Perconians. Here is a brief overview of the work done.
Inconsistent data and GTIDs with mysqldump Marcelo Altmann (Senior Software Engineer) fixed the bug when data and GTIDs backed up by mysqldump were inconsistent. It happened when the options &amp;ndash;single-transaction and &amp;ndash;set-gtid-purged=ON were both used because GTIDs on the server could have already increased between the start of the transaction by mysqldump and the fetching of GTID_EXECUTED.</description></item><item><title>Using the JSON data type with MySQL 8</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/13/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/13/using-the-json-data-type-with-mysql-8/</guid><description>If you are a mobile app, frontend, backend, or game developer, you use data types such as string, numeric, or DateTime. You also know that since the advent of non-relational databases (NoSQL) such as MongoDB, which, by not being tied to a traditional SQL schema, do reading and writing on databases much faster. But MySQL showed that storing the JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) data type could also improve the speed of reading and writing relational databases.</description></item><item><title>Backups for MySQL With mysqldump</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/10/backups-for-mysql-with-mysqldump/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/10/backups-for-mysql-with-mysqldump/</guid><description>Basic Usage mysqldump is a client utility that can be used for doing logical backups. It will generate the necessary SQL statements to reproduce the original database.
Backup by Nick Youngson CC BY-SA 3.0 Pix4free The following statements are some common uses of mysqldump:
mysqldump -u username -p database_name [table_name] &amp;gt; dump.sql mysqldump -u username -p --databases db1_name db2_name &amp;gt; dump.sql mysqldump -u username -p --all-databases &amp;gt; dump.sql The first example is for backing up a single database.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Databases on Containers with Percona Server for MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/23/exploring-databases-on-containers-with-mysql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/23/exploring-databases-on-containers-with-mysql/</guid><description>In this blog, we will explore databases on containers. We will use Docker as a container engine tool and Percona Server for MySQL as a database administration tool. Both are open source tools.
MySQL is a relational database management system that stores data on disk. Percona Server for MySQL is a fork of MYSQL, providing much more advanced features. To run it correctly, we need to know volumes because we want to “persist” the data, the most important thing in databases.</description></item><item><title>Deploying MySQL Group Replication With Terraform</title><link>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2023-02-15-deploying-mysql-group-replication-terraform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2023-02-15-deploying-mysql-group-replication-terraform/</guid><description>Previously, I wrote about our Terraform provider to deploy Percona Server for MySQL (Percona Server for MySQL: Automatic Cloud Deployment With Terraform) and Percona Monitoring and Management (Deploying Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) With Terraform). Now we also added the capability to deploy Group Replication configuration with Percona Server for MySQL, and assuming we have PMM installed (see previous post), we also can automatically add Group Replication nodes to PMM monitoring.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up PMM For Monitoring Your Databases on Windows</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/16/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-your-databases-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/16/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-your-databases-on-windows/</guid><description>Before deploying Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) in production, you might want to test it or set up a development instance locally. Since many developers and DBAs have Windows desktops, I wanted to demonstrate how to set up PMM on Windows for an easy test environment. In this post, I’ll walk you through setting up PMM with Docker and WSL.
If you’re a Linux user, check the blog post I wrote on Setting up PMM for monitoring MySQL in a local environment.</description></item><item><title>How To Generate Test Data for Your Database Project With Python</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/09/how-to-generate-test-data-for-your-database-project-with-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/09/how-to-generate-test-data-for-your-database-project-with-python/</guid><description>If you need test data for the database of your project, you can get a dataset from Kaggle or use a data generator. In the first case, if you need to process the data before inserting it into the database, you can use Pandas, a widely used Python library for data analysis. This library supports different formats, including CSV and JSON, and it also provides a method for inserting data into a SQL database.</description></item><item><title>MySQL performance troubleshooting with PMM - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - December 16th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-12-16-mysql-performance-troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-12-16-mysql-performance-troubleshooting/</guid><description> Percona Community Live Stream for MySQL will focus on MySQL performance troubleshooting with PMM. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/mV3zXEiY-cM
TRANSCRIPT</description></item><item><title>How to Secure MySQL Database - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Nov 11th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-11-11-how-to-secure-mysql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-11-11-how-to-secure-mysql/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for MySQL will focus on securing MySQL. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/Bei-AhP52vc
TRANSCRIPT Mario Garcia:
Hello, everyone! Welcome to our stream this week. I am Mario Garcia, Technical Evangelist at Percona. Today we have Marcos Albe, Principal Support Engineer, who will talk about how to secure MySQL.</description></item><item><title>Percona Server for MySQL – Automatic Cloud Deployment with Terraform</title><link>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2022-10-20-terraform-percona-server-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2022-10-20-terraform-percona-server-for-mysql/</guid><description>We are looking to provide simplified ways to deploy Percona software in cloud environments, especially for more advanced scenarios like replication and multi-node cluster (in the case of Percona XtraDB Cluster).
For this I propose trying out our new Terraform provider, with the capabilities:
Deploy in AWS or GCP Cloud. The provider will automatically create instances and deploy Percona Server for MySQL Deploy either Percona Server for MySQL or Percona XtraDB Cluster Choose instance size Choose storage volume size, type, and IOPs Multi-node async replication or multi-node Percona XtraDB Cluster Customize MySQL configuration file Capability to deploy MyRocks Engine To get more understanding let’s review some examples, but before that, where you can obtain modules:</description></item><item><title>MySQL: Tracing a single query with PERFORMANCE_SCHEMA</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/18/mysql-tracing-a-single-query-with-performance_schema/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/18/mysql-tracing-a-single-query-with-performance_schema/</guid><description>My task is to collect performance data about a single query, using PERFORMANCE_SCHEMA (P_S for short) in MySQL, to ship it elsewhere for integration with other data.
In a grander scheme of things, I will need to define what performance data from a query I am actually interested in. I will also need to find a way to attribute the query (as seen on the server) to a point in the codebase of the client, which is not always easy when an ORM or other SQL generator is being used.</description></item><item><title>How to Benchmark Your MySQL Database - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Oct 14th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-10-28-how-to-benchmark-your-mysql-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-10-28-how-to-benchmark-your-mysql-database/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for MySQL will focus on benchmarking a MySQL database. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/OOp8vy1Wxko
SLIDES Check out Marcos&amp;rsquo; slides HERE.
TRANSCRIPT Mario Garcia:
Hello, everyone. Thank you for joining us today. I am Mario Garcia, I&amp;rsquo;m a Technical Evangelist at Percona.</description></item><item><title>Finding Poorly Designed Schema's and How to Fix Them - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Sept 30th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-09-30-finding-poorly-designed-schema/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-09-30-finding-poorly-designed-schema/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for MySQL will focus on Finding Poorly Designed Schema&amp;rsquo;s and How to Fix Them. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions. Add this event to your Google Calendar.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/PDYWBDGLBE0
TRANSCRIPT Dave Stokes: This is a podcast or stream cast we&amp;rsquo;re doing on finding poorly designed schemas, featuring Marcos Albe, who is our resident expert.</description></item><item><title>Hacktoberfest with Percona - We Want You! - September 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>October is close, and it is time for Hacktoberfest! Join our stream to talk online about this fantastic challenge at 2:30 UTC on Wednesday, September 28th. And yes, you can be a part of the conversation with experts and jump into the stream to address the audience!
If you love open source as much as we do, Hacktoberfest is created for you. It is a unique opportunity to be a part of a great open source community.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Designing a Schema - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Sept 2nd</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-09-02-designing-a-schema/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-09-02-designing-a-schema/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for MySQL will focus on Designing a Schema. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/PEa3cBKwAI4
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Good Morning, good evening, good afternoon, good whatever it is, wherever you are. I&amp;rsquo;m Dave Stokes from Percona and with me is Marcos Albe.</description></item><item><title>Installing and Setting Up MySQL on Kubernetes - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - August 19th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-08-19-installing-and-setting-up-mysql-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-08-19-installing-and-setting-up-mysql-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Start running MySQL on Kubernetes with the lead of Percona Experts. Dave and Marcos were at the Community Live stream to share some tips and tricks.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/VflG2XicCCE
TRANSCRIPT Marcos Albe:
Good morning, Dave. Good morning.
Dave Stokes: So today we&amp;rsquo;re talking about installing and setting up MySQL on Kubernetes. And yes, I am fumbling around the basics of Kubernetes. And you&amp;rsquo;re going to enlighten us and make us all experts.</description></item><item><title>Migrating MySQL to a New Server - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - August 5th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-08-05-migrating-mysql-to-a-new-server/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-08-05-migrating-mysql-to-a-new-server/</guid><description>Our experts run a demo and took us through all steps to migrate MySQL database to a new server. Get more tips to improve your database skill with Dave Stokes and Marcos Albe.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/QQJMGONBwWw
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Amazing right that&amp;rsquo;s so cool. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Good morning, good afternoon. Good evening, depending where you are. I&amp;rsquo;m Dave Stokes. I&amp;rsquo;m a Technology Evangelist with Percona. And I have Marcos Albe with me.</description></item><item><title>Running PMM with Docker on Ubuntu 20.04</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</guid><description>I started at Percona a few weeks ago and was looking for a quick way to learn about PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management), which is one of my favorite technologies within Percona to monitor the health of our database infrastructure, explore new patterns in the database behavior, manage and improve the performance of our databases, all with customizable dashboards and real-time alerts using Grafana and VictoriaMetrics.
The best of all is that PMM is Open Source, you can check the PMM repository in case you want to contribute.</description></item><item><title>Setting up PMM for monitoring MySQL on a local environment</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-mysql-on-a-local-environment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-mysql-on-a-local-environment/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) is an open source database monitoring, observability, and management tool that can be used for monitoring the health of your database infrastructure, exploring new patterns in database behavior, and managing and improving the performance of your databases no matter where they are located or deployed.
PMM is designed to work with MySQL (including Percona Server for MySQL, Percona XtraDB Cluster, Oracle MySQL Community Edition, Oracle MySQL Enterprise Edition, and MariaDB), PostgreSQL (including Percona Distribution for PostgreSQL), MongoDB (including Percona Server for MongoDB), Amazon RDS, Amazon Aurora, Proxy SQL, and Percona XtraDB Cluster.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Failover via a Replica for MySQL - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - July 8th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-07-08-setting-up-failover-via-a-replica-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-07-08-setting-up-failover-via-a-replica-for-mysql/</guid><description>This Community Live Stream is talking about Failover and Replica for MySQL. Our experts Dave Stokes and Marcos Albe took us through the setting to make it easier.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/c5tj-0THNLI
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Oh, one. And there we are.
Marcos Albe:
Hey there. Hello, Mr. Stokes.
Dave Stokes:
Hello, Mr. Albe. Good evening, good morning, good afternoon, good, whatever, wherever you are. This is, a live stream on setting up failover via a replica for MySQL, I see we&amp;rsquo;re live on Twitch, not sure what&amp;rsquo;s going with YouTube, but we&amp;rsquo;re gonna go as we are, and we&amp;rsquo;ll post the recording later.</description></item><item><title>Percona Pstress: A Concurrency and Crash Recovery Testing Tool to Test MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
How Pstress works, success so far with MySQL testing.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/LB-dC9CDBOc
Transcript</description></item><item><title>PMM Development Process</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko2/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
I would discuss how to contribute to the PMM project, what process we use and show example of code contribution to the parts of PMM.
Watch Video Here Transcript</description></item><item><title>The MySQL Ecosystem in 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-colin-charles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-colin-charles/</guid><description>This session is presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Watch This Talk Here The talk will be live-streamed on several platforms. No registration is required. Feel free to ask your questions in chat. Follow the links now and subscribe to notifications not to miss anything!
YouTube LinkedIn Twitter @PerconaBytes Twitch PerconaCommunity 27 years of the MySQL ecosystem, not only is there the core product from Oracle, there is a branch from Percona and a fork from MariaDB.</description></item><item><title>Database Reliability Engineering for MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-matthias-crauwels/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-matthias-crauwels/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
A common request that we get from our clients is to make MySQL highly available or to enhance existing architecture. We have standardized our approach by combining a proxy layer, for traffic redirection, a topology management tool, for master failover/switchover, and some additional tools to glue together both layers.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.</description></item><item><title>Let's Talk About MySQL Query Tuning</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-gabriel-ciciliani/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-gabriel-ciciliani/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Regardless of development frameworks, despite linters, besides countless sessions with the DBA, slow queries always end up making it to production. Proactive and reactive slow query tuning is still critical to ensure poorly written queries aren&amp;rsquo;t undermining server performance and wasting valuable compute resources. Cloud-based database managed services are not the exception: slow query root cause analysis requires human intervention.</description></item><item><title>Optimization Techniques in MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-yunus-shaikh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-yunus-shaikh/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Optimization of mysql with indexing, server tuning and OS tuning to make performance better
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/oFTFch9_wSM
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Overview of Different ALTER Algorithms and Its Locking Scenarios in MySQL (DEMO)</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sri-sakthivel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sri-sakthivel/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
I would like to show the demo session on describing the different MySQL ALTER Algorithms ( COPY / INPLACE / INSTANT ) and how they are performing with different locking methods ( Exclusive / Shared / None ).
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/MqWQH-WWFBE
Transcript</description></item><item><title>The Low Hanging Fruits of MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-kedar-vaijanapurkar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-kedar-vaijanapurkar/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
MySQL is one of the top used database system and with highly active community. Though without proper configuration you may not squeeze the most out of it.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/y8-ecVLcaaY
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Liquibase Data: Version Control and Collaboration for the Database</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Liquibase is the defacto standard for versioning your database schema. With 15 years of use by the largest enterprises, Liquibase is a proven Open Source DevOps Solution. Now, with Liquibase Data, users can apply git-like workflows to development and test environments. See how free Open Source Liquibase can accelerate database development and cross-team deployments.</description></item><item><title>Percona Database Distributions - An Overview</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-lenz-grimmer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-lenz-grimmer/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
In this presentation, Lenz is providing an overview and update about Percona&amp;rsquo;s database distributions for MongoDB, MySQL and PostgreSQL. Attendees will learn more about Percona&amp;rsquo;s role in the open source database ecosystems and how Percona&amp;rsquo;s database distributions help to solve common production use cases. The talk will also go over the most notable feature highlights that have been added to the distributions lately.</description></item><item><title>The Lost Art of Database Design</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-matt-yonkovit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-matt-yonkovit/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Right now we are in a spot where people think that the databases are just part of the commoditized infrastructure. But unfortunately, that leads us to a lot of problems. And Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona, is talking about database design here. There are a lot of people out there who have never heard why they should focus on designing their databases, and their database infrastructure a little better.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Backups and Scheduling Regular MySQL Backups - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - June 10th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-06-10-setting-up-backups-and-scheduling-regular-mysql-backups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-06-10-setting-up-backups-and-scheduling-regular-mysql-backups/</guid><description>Learn more about Backup best practices to ensure the availability of your database. This is a part of the bi-weekly live-streamed meetup dedicated to MySQL.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/6Ai149MDjFo
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Yes, Miss Foreign minister that was singled out scintillating conversation ever had because I forgot to hit the wrong button for those who are expecting Matt Yonkovit, but he&amp;rsquo;s on his way to the Southeast Linux Fest today. So you&amp;rsquo;re stuck with me a very poor second choice, but you have the great Marcos Albe, who&amp;rsquo;s going to run through everything you need to do need to know about setting up backups and scheduling regular MySQL backups.</description></item><item><title>Reduce Replication Lag</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/01/speed-up-replication-lag/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/01/speed-up-replication-lag/</guid><description>Replication Lag is just a fact of life with async-replication. We can&amp;rsquo;t stop lag, but we can help to reduce it. Many times the Seconds_Behind_Source can be very deciving, I have seen it go from 1 hour behind to 0 lag in the blink of an eye. There are many factors that can add to replica lag. Some of these are:
Network IO Disk IO Database Workload Database settings In this blog we will look a few database settings to help reduce lag.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for MySQL - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - May, 27th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-05-27-setting-up-alerts-and-basic-automation-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-05-27-setting-up-alerts-and-basic-automation-for-mysql/</guid><description>Percona Community live stream for MySQL is back. Matt Yonkovit and Marcos Albe talked about Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for MySQL during the session of May 27th. Check full recording and transcript! Follow us on Twitter and stay tuned to all upcoming Percona events.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/0fhiioT0Tbg
Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hello, everybody. We had a little bit of a delay there. We&amp;rsquo;ve been fighting with some new equipment because guess what happened?</description></item><item><title>The MySQL Workshop Book Review</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/03/the-mysql-workshop-book-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/03/the-mysql-workshop-book-review/</guid><description>Good books on MySQL for beginners are rare and excellent ones are even rarer. I often get requests from novices starting with MySQL or intermediates looking to level up on recommendations on books targeted at their level. The MySQL Workshop (Amazon link) by Thomas Pettit and Scott Cosentino is a must buy for those two groups, or those of us who would like a handy reference.
This is a great book and I recommend getting a copy regardless of your MySQL expertise.</description></item><item><title>Observing &amp; Tuning Your MySQL Workload Using PMM - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - April, 29th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-15-observing-tuning-your-mysql-workload-using-pmm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-15-observing-tuning-your-mysql-workload-using-pmm/</guid><description>Percona Community live stream for MySQL is a biweekly events with Matt Yonkovit and Marcos Albe. This is the recording for the session of April, 29th. We have talked about Observing &amp;amp; Tuning Your MySQL Workload Using PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management). Follow us on Twitter and stay tuned to all upcoming Percona events.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/4ccEZZtjqWg
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
We&amp;rsquo;re live and you&amp;rsquo;re singing… Marcos was here, you know, singing the song of folks on the PT stock song.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Bullseye Percona Server 64bit</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>I love the Raspberry Pi, and I love Percona server. The combination of the two can provide a nice home database. I have been running a Percona Server database since 2019 to hold all the weather information, that I collect from several of my Weather Stations.
I did a my first blog post on installing Percona Server 5.7 on the Raspberry Pi 3+.
You can read that blog post here: How to Build a Percona Server &amp;ldquo;Stack&amp;rdquo; on a Raspberry Pi 3+</description></item><item><title>Installing MySQL and Setting Up a Default Configuration - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - April, 1st</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-01-install-mysql-setting-up-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-01-install-mysql-setting-up-configuration/</guid><description>Watch out this recording from Percona Community live stream of April 1st. Learn how to install MySQL and Setting Up a Default Configuration with Matt Yonkovit and Marcos Albe. This is a series of live stream to discuss MySQL tricks with experts.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/AMGNklpAjJ8
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
We might even be live right now. Marcos, we might be live oh we are live oh we see now we&amp;rsquo;re live there we popped in.</description></item><item><title>The Ins and Outs of PostgreSQL Default Configuration Tuning</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/03/31/the-ins-and-outs-of-postgresql-default-configuration-tuning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/03/31/the-ins-and-outs-of-postgresql-default-configuration-tuning/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what the optimal settings for a newly installed Postgres database are, here are some simple steps to take to tune it right from the start. Matt Yonkovit discussed them with Charly Batista, Postgres Tech Lead at Percona during the live-streamed meetup. Watch the recording to see how Charly tunes a default installation of Percona Distribution for PostgreSQL 13.
Most of the default settings have been defined long, long time ago, where one gigabyte of RAM was very expensive.</description></item><item><title> Comunity MeetUp - Installation of the main part of Percona products - February 9th, 2022 at 10:00 am EST</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</guid><description>This video and its transcript are from the Percona Commmunity Meetup that we had with Evgeniy Patlan last February 9th, 2022. We have talked how to install Percona&amp;rsquo;s various components, the different software that we have, specifically looking at our server software in Postgres, MySQL, and MongoDB. We tackle how to install from a repository and what are the different install options that we have?
Video Link: https://youtu.be/LkmbEql9Mj8
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:</description></item><item><title>5 Steps to Improve Performance of Default MySQL Installation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/01/27/5-steps-to-improve-performance-of-default-mysql-installation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/01/27/5-steps-to-improve-performance-of-default-mysql-installation/</guid><description>Let’s say you have a fresh MySQL installation. Are there any possible steps to improve performance right away? Yes, there are!
Recently, Marcos Albe (Principal Support Engineer, Percona) did an online tuning on the MySQL Meetup hosted by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy, Percona). Here are some steps you can consider to make your fresh MySQL installation to run better right from the start.
So, we have a very basic default MySQL installation with some workload.</description></item><item><title> MeetUp MySQL - Troubleshooting Database Outages, Slowdowns, and Security Issues - Jan 14th, 2022 at 12:00 pm EST</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-01-14-percona-meetup-for-mysql-january-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-01-14-percona-meetup-for-mysql-january-2022/</guid><description>If you missed the meetup of Friday January 14th, 2022 at 12:00 pm EST with Matt Yonkovit and Marcos Albe, here is the recording as they talk about why complexity is driving outages, slowdowns, and security issues. Matt play stump the expert and see if Marcos can improve my MySQL workload.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/s9y0wawM8cM
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Well, welcome, everyone. Hey, we started the live stream a couple of minutes early here, we&amp;rsquo;re testing out some new software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Supports Community Events - Organize Yours With Us!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</guid><description>One of the things we love doing in Percona is participating in community events and inspiring people to stay connected in the changing world. We have experience in organizing community dinners, meetups, lectures at universities, booths, and even conferences both in-person and virtually. Percona speakers give talks on events all around the globe.
Have you ever thought about organizing a themed meeting for your local open source community? It may harbor many possibilities for you.</description></item><item><title> MeetUp for MySQL - Database Tuning Secrets of the Stars - Dec 8th 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-december-2021-new/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-december-2021-new/</guid><description>Listen to this Community MeetUp for MySQL hosted by Matt Yonkovit to discuss Database Tuning and Troubleshooting with Marcos Albe and Nando Camargos. They reveal some Support Cases From Hell, Database Tuning Secrets of the Stars and stump the expert Troubleshooting on RDS/Aurora.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/i4DG30guHmA
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Oh my goodness! Welcome welcome welcome all you out in stream land and what Welcome to a late late afternoon edition for most of us of the Percona meetup.</description></item><item><title>The Errant GTID</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</guid><description>Part 1 What is a GTID? Oracle/MySQL define a GTID as "A global transaction identifier (GTID) is a unique identifier created and associated with each transaction committed on the server of origin (the source). This identifier is unique not only to the server on which it originated, but is unique across all servers in a given replication topology." An errant transaction can make promotion of a replica to primary very difficult.</description></item><item><title> MeetUp for MySQL - Database Backup and Xtrabackup - Nov 3rd 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-november-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-november-2021/</guid><description>Full recording of the Percona MeetUp for MySQL of Nov 3rd 2021. Marcelo Altmann and Pep Pla joined Matt Yonkovit to talk about Database Backup and Xtrabackup. In this video you will be aware of different database Backup solutions out there, Best practices vs. wrong strategies, Percona XtraBackup and more. As usual during the Community Meetup, They have answered questions from attendees live.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/FMFu6aFZx64
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Oh, welcome, everyone, to another Percona live stream, today I am joined by two awesome guests to talk about MySQL.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MySQL Oct 6th 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-october-2021/</guid><description>The Community MeetUp for MySQL on Oct 6th 2021 was about MySQL basics for prod environment starting from the system level and monitoring with PMM or Zabbix and backups. In addition, it was a great talk how to enable MySQL Audit Logging and to view the output. Watch the video here!
Video Link: https://youtu.be/KULzKh2H8XA
Transcript Matt Yonkovit
Hello everyone welcome to another live stream we are live on Twitch and on YouTube today I am glad you joined us.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MySQL Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-september-2021/</guid><description>Watch the video record of the live-streamed Community MeetUp for MySQL we held on September 8, 2021. Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS, sat down with 2 MySQL experts, Nando Camargos and Marcos Albe, and discusses the ways you REALLY can make your database faster. They touched query optimization, indexes, the art of database design, hiding columns, and things that occupy Matt’s thoughts when he wakes up at 3 AM.
Video Link: https://youtu.</description></item><item><title>The lost art of Database Server Initialization.</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/06/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/06/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</guid><description>With all the DBaaS, IaaS and PaaS environments, sometimes I think the Art of MySQL initialization is becoming a lost art. Many times we just delete the MySQL Server and order a new one.
Just recently I was talking with a colleague, and this subject came up. We both thought about it and decided we have become spoiled by automation. We were both rusty on this process. This gave me the idea for this post.</description></item><item><title>Lets be inSync!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/22/lets-be-insync/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/22/lets-be-insync/</guid><description>Percona Toolkit + pt-table-checksum + pt-table-sync = Faster Replica Recovery Asynchronous replication with MySQL is a tried and true technology. Add the use of GTID’s and you have a very stable solution.
The fundamental issue with async replication is that writes sent to the Replica are not guaranteed to be written. I have only seen a handful of times when writes did not get applied to the replica. Most of the time this happens is due to network packet drops or a replica crashes before new data is committed.</description></item><item><title>Create your own Exporter in Go!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/21/create-your-own-exporter-in-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/21/create-your-own-exporter-in-go/</guid><description>Overview Hi, it’s too hot summer in Korea. Today I want to talk about an interesting and exciting topic. Try to making your own exporter in Go language.
If you register a specific query, it is a simple program that shows the result of this query as an exporter result metrics. Some of you may still be unfamiliar with what Expoter is.
I will explain about Exporter step by step in today’s post.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Architectures in a Nutshell</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/10/</guid><description>Kenny Gryp - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Following MySQL InnoDB Cluster as our first, fully integrated MySQL High Availability solution based on Group Replication, MySQL Shell 8.0.19 includes MySQL InnoDB ReplicaSet which delivers another complete solution, this time based on MySQL Replication.
The basic idea for InnoDB ReplicaSet is to do the same for classic MySQL Replication as InnoDB Cluster did for Group Replication. We take a strong technology that is very powerful but can be complex, and provide an easy-to-use AdminAPI for it in the MySQL Shell.</description></item><item><title>DBdeployer in Action - Optimised MySQL Sandboxes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/9/</guid><description>Giuseppe Maxia and Frédéric Descamps - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
The Data Charmer will show how to use dbdeployer in the wild by answering the questions of lefred. This session will mimic an Ask Me Anything session where all chapters will be an answer to a specic question. Throught this list of questions, the audience will learn how to start with dbdeployer but also discover more advanced featured.</description></item><item><title>Validating JSON</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/8/</guid><description>Dave Stokes - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
JSON or JavaScript Object Notation has become the data interchange format of choice. Most relational databases have added a JSON data type (Oracle, Postgresql, MySQL) or some accommodation for JSON data (SQL Server, MariaDB). But the free form nature of JSON is problematic for relational databases resulting in compromises in speed, handling of key-value pairs, and general lack of the ability to validate data.</description></item><item><title>Successfully Run Your MySQL NDB Cluster in Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/7/</guid><description>Tiago Alves - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Fortunately, MySQL NDB Cluster already has auto-healing, data distribution, instant scaling and many other features built-in - making it a perfect t for Cloud Native. This session walks through the few steps necessary to deploy a distributed NDB setup in a Kubernetes cluster manually or with an operator.
NDB runs in Kubernetes serving mission critical microservices at the heart of Cloud Native production systems.</description></item><item><title>Brand New Development Announced at PL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/6/</guid><description>Johannes Schlüter and Kenny Gryp - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Brand New Development announced at Percona Live !!
This talk is about something we cannot announce publicly now and will be exclusively announced during Percona Live.
This is something new, that will be released after the conference, don&amp;rsquo;t miss this session to discover new trendy stuff.
Brand New Development announced at Percona Live !!</description></item><item><title>Migration From 5.6 to 8.xx.xx</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/5/</guid><description>Luis Dias - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Intro I start working in a Belgium company that use Mysql 5.6. We use 6 production servers and we decide to migrate from this old version to mysql 8.0.19. All the servers have Centos 7 system (so RPM and YUM available)
The first test was done by devops team, they use mysqldump to make this job, but as each server is about 4T the down time was over 30 hours and it&amp;rsquo;s not acceptable for customer.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Shell for DBAs</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/4/</guid><description>Frédéric Descamps - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Get an overview of the possibilities offered by MySQL Shell for DBAs. How to deploy infrastructures (overview only), how to dump and load tables/schema/instances etc.. it&amp;rsquo;s time to t get more familiar with the util object. And finally see the possibility of User Defined Reports and Plugins for the MySQL Shell.
During the session we will cover the most useful plugins for general DBA tasks</description></item><item><title>Oracle MySQL Database Service with HeatWave for Real-Time Analytics</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/3/</guid><description>Carsten Thalheimer - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Since 2020 the MySQL development team is offering a fully managed database service of the MySQL Enterprise Edition. Traditionally MySQL InnoDB is designed for online transaction processing (OLTP) load. MySQL can cover online analytics processing (OLAP) load, but it is often rather slow and tricky. Beginning of December 2020, the MySQL team started a second MySQL Cloud offering called MySQL HeatWave for Real-time Analytics which is based on a new in-memory analytic accelerator which has been designed for extreme performance and cloud scale.</description></item><item><title>Insights Into the New Oracle MySQL Database Service</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/2/</guid><description>Carsten Thalheimer - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Oracle MySQL Database Cloud Service 2021 - Where we are today&amp;hellip;
Early 2020 Oracle introduced the MySQL Database Service (MDS) built on Oracle Gen 2 Cloud Infrastructure and MySQL 8. It is 100% developed, managed, and supported by the Oracle MySQL team. The service is available as a fully-managed service in all commercial regions of the Oracle Cloud.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Server Component Manifest Files</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/1/</guid><description>Georgi Kodinov - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
MySQL configuration has traditionally been done via system variables with values coming from either command line, config files or SET commands. This can be a security issue since it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support a trust model rooted in some well known trusted state that cannot be modified by less trusted actors.
This is what the manifest le security model is aiming at solving.</description></item><item><title>Automating MariaDB Deployments With Ansible</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/6/</guid><description>Federico Razzoli - Vettabase - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
This demo shows how to deploy MariaDB with Ansible. We&amp;rsquo;ll look into the Ansible playbook and the Ansible commands to use to install MariaDB, upgrade MariaDB, and modify MariaDB configuration on any number of servers. The Playbook we&amp;rsquo;ll use is a realistic production installation: it includes scheduled backups and a PMM agent to monitor the server performance. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how using Ansible saves long work hours, makes operations virtually error-free, and provides a complete documentation of servers configuration.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB ColumnStore – A Columnar Storage Engine, First Class Citizen in MariaDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/5/</guid><description>Vicențiu Ciorbaru - MariaDB Foundation - MariaDB ColumnStore – A Columnar Storage Engine, First Class Citizen in MariaDB - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
MariaDB has had ColumnStore (a columnar storage engine) available for a while now. The problem was that ColumnStore (formerly known as InniDB) was coded in such a way that required a custom version of MariaDB to function. The installation was also non-trivial, with quite a set of dependencies needed.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Work and Leadership in the Time of Pandemics</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/4/</guid><description>Anna Widenius - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
Virtual work and leadership in the time of pandemics MariaDB Foundation has been a virtual organization long before the pandemic struck. That gave us a head start in finding ways to adapt team leadership and management to the new times. Team leadership and management are different in a virtual organization, and in this session, we will talk about best practices within development teams.</description></item><item><title>JSON Additions in MariaDB - Featuring JSON_TABLE</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/3/</guid><description>Vicențiu Ciorbaru - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
MariaDB has had JSON support for a while now. Released initially in 10.2, MariaDB tries to follow the SQL standard as close as possible. One of the new additions coming to MariaDB 10.6 is support for JSON_TABLE. In this talk we will go through the details of this new feature, as well use cases and interactions with JSON path.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration in Open Source: A Q&amp;A on Github, Jira, Zulip and Knowledgebase</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/2/</guid><description>Kaj Arnö, Ian Gilfillan, Robert Bindar, Vicențiu Ciorbaru, Anna Widenius - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
This is an extended, interactive panel / Q&amp;amp;A version of the 20 min talk on Collaboration in Open Source. Whereas the 20 min talk sets expectations, this session in the MariaDB Community Room goes in depth and solicits input from the audience. How can MariaDB Foundation improve its level of interactivity and collaboration with its developer community?</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.6 - What's New?</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/1/</guid><description>Vicențiu Ciorbaru - MariaDB Foundation - MariaDB Community Track - Percona Live 2021
MariaDB&amp;rsquo;s 10.6 is coming with a lot of improvements, specifically centered around performance. Although the contents of this talk will depend on exactly what makes it into MariaDB 10.6 GA, the following topics will be covered.
Atomic DDL in MariaDB Optimizer changes InnoDB changes Oracle compatibility changes and parser changes</description></item><item><title>Not JOINing on PERFORMANCE_SCHEMA</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/01/not-joining-on-performance_schema/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 19:22:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/01/not-joining-on-performance_schema/</guid><description>The tables in PERFORMANCE_SCHEMA (P_S) are not actually tables. You should not think of them as tables, even if your SQL works on them. You should not JOIN them, and you should not GROUP or ORDER BY them.
Unlocked memory buffers without indexes The stuff in P_S has been created with “keep the impact on production small” in mind. That is, from a users point of view, you can think of them as unlocked memory buffers - the values in there change as you look at them, and there are precisely zero stability guarantees.</description></item><item><title>On the Observability of Outliers</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/11/23/on-the-observability-of-outliers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 17:41:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/11/23/on-the-observability-of-outliers/</guid><description>At work, I am in an ongoing discussion with a number of people on the Observability of Outliers. It started with the age-old question “How do I find slow queries in my application?” aka “What would I want from tooling to get that data and where should that tooling sit?”
As a developer, I just want to automatically identify and isolate slow queries!
Where I work, we do have SolarWinds Database Performance Monitor aka Vividcortex to find slow queries, so that helps.</description></item><item><title>Zero downtime schema change with Liquibase &amp; Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/26/zero-downtime-schema-change-with-liquibase-percona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 14:14:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/26/zero-downtime-schema-change-with-liquibase-percona/</guid><description>I am always surprised to learn something new whenever I talk to a member of the open-source community. No matter how much I think I have heard of every use case there is for Liquibase (and database change management in general), I always hear something that makes this space still feel new. There’s always something left to discover.
Today, that new something is the problem of how to perform large batches of changes with SQL ALTER TABLE statements.</description></item><item><title>Mayastor: Lightning Fast Storage for Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/23/mayastor-lightning-fast-storage-for-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 14:03:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/23/mayastor-lightning-fast-storage-for-kubernetes/</guid><description>At MayaData we like new tech. Tech that makes our databases perform better. Tech like lockless ring buffers, NVMe-oF, and Kubernetes. In this blog post we’re going to see those technologies at work to give us awesome block storage performance with flexibility and simple operations.
Mayastor + SPDK + NVMe = fast databases Mayastor is new tech, it’s fast, and it’s based on SPDK. Why is SPDK exciting? It’s a new generation in storage software, designed for super high speed low latency NVMe devices.</description></item><item><title>MySQL 8.0 Document Store, Discovery of a New World – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/19/mysql-8-0-document-store-discovery-of-a-new-world-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 14:01:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/19/mysql-8-0-document-store-discovery-of-a-new-world-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 5:00 a.m. • London 10:00 a.m. • New Delhi 2:30 p.m. • Singapore 5:00 p.m.
Abstract MySQL Document Store enables us to work with SQL relational tables and schema-less JSON collections. So instead of having a mixed bag of databases, you can just rely on MySQL, where the JSON documents can be stored in collections and managed with CRUD operations.</description></item><item><title>The State of ProxySQL, 2020 Edition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/16/the-state-of-proxysql-2020-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 20:08:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/16/the-state-of-proxysql-2020-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 7:30 a.m. • London 12:30 p.m. • New Delhi 5:00 p.m. • Singapore 7:30 p.m.
Abstract ProxySQL is a high performance, high available, protocol aware proxy for MySQL. 2.0 has been GA for some time now, and there have been a lot of changes that come in point releases as well, such that you can benefit from them. Listen to René, the founder of ProxySQL, take you through some of the new features in 2.</description></item><item><title>DBdeployer, the Community Edition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/14/dbdeployer-the-community-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 18:44:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/14/dbdeployer-the-community-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 3:30 a.m. • London 8:30 a.m. • New Delhi 1:00 p.m. • Singapore 3:30 p.m.
Abstract DBdeployer, an open source tool that allows easy deployment of many MySQL/Percona servers in the same host, has passed two years of development. Its latest additions have aimed at improving ease of use for both beginners and experts. This talk will show how to start with dbdeployer with an empty box, and quickly populate it with recent and less recent server versions, all at the command line.</description></item><item><title>Sharding: DIY or Out of the Box Solution? – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/13/sharding-diy-or-out-of-the-box-solution-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 03:04:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/13/sharding-diy-or-out-of-the-box-solution-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 7:00 a.m. • London 12:00 noon • New Delhi 4:30 p.m. • Singapore 7:00 p.m.
Why is your talk exciting? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if my talk is exciting, but I&amp;rsquo;m quite positive the subject is! Vitess has been gaining a lot of traction over the past few years and I must admit that I&amp;rsquo;ve been keen to get hands-on experience with it for years.</description></item><item><title>Vitess Online Schema Migration Automation – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/vitess-online-schema-migration-automation-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 17:28:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/vitess-online-schema-migration-automation-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 2:30 a.m. • London 7:30 a.m. • New Delhi 12:00 noon • Singapore 2:30 p.m.
Abstract For many, running an online schema migration operation is still a manual job: from building the correct command, through identifying where the migration should run and which servers are to be affected, to auditing progress and completing the migration. Sharded environment poses an additional burden, as any logical migration must be applied multiple times, once for each shard.</description></item><item><title>Analytical Queries in MySQL – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 17:05:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 6:00 p.m. • London 11:00 p.m. • New Delhi 3:30 a.m. • Singapore 6:00 a.m.
Abstract MySQL&amp;rsquo;s sweet spot is known to be online transaction processing (OLTP), and it can support a very high load of short transactions. Many users will also want to run analytical queries (OLAP) on their MySQL data. Often they achieve this by exporting their data to another database system that is tailored for analytical queries.</description></item><item><title>Serverless Databases: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/08/serverless-databases-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 20:58:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/08/serverless-databases-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 4:30 a.m. • London 9:30 a.m • New Delhi 2:00 p.m. • Singapore 4:30 p.m.
Abstract Starting with AWS, the major cloud providers offer different options to run a MySQL or a MySQL-compatible database on the cloud. A new approach is to rely on so-called serverless (relational) databases like Aurora Serverless that offer both traditional TCP connections and HTTP API access.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Ecosystem on ARM – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/07/mysql-ecosystem-on-arm-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 02:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/07/mysql-ecosystem-on-arm-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 8:00 p.m. • London 1:00 a.m (next day) • New Delhi 5:30 a.m. • Singapore 8:00 a.m.
Abstract? The ARM ecosystem is quickly evolving as a cost-effective alternative to run High-Performance Computing (HPC) software. It continues to grow with some major cloud players hosting ARM-based cloud servers. MySQL too joined the ecosystem with 8.x. MariaDB already has made its presence.</description></item><item><title>Kunlun Distributed DB Cluster Intro – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 22:25:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 9:30 p.m. • London 02:30 a.m. (next day) • New Delhi 7:00 a.m. • Singapore 09:30 a.m.
Abstract Kunlun Distributed Database Cluster is a distributed DBMS that aims to combine the best of both MySQL and PostgreSQL for a highly performant, highly available, highly scalable and fault-tolerant, easy to use and manage database system that requires minimal human maintenance. It enables users to define table sharding rules so that it automatically distributes tables properly to available storage shards; implements the two-phase commit protocol to do distributed transaction commit; uses MySQL group replication for high availability in storage shards; fixes a series of MySQL XA bugs to make distributed transactions highly reliable, among many other enhancements.</description></item><item><title>Database Schema Management Via Liquibase</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 22:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</guid><description>Creating the database for an application is simple and easy. However, database script management gets complicated in a hurry when you need to support multiple versions, work with multiple teams, and apply the same changes to multiple types of databases. One open-source tool that helps teams track, version, and deploy database schema changes is Liquibase. It executes database scripts sequentially, allows for the automatic creation and execution of rollback scripts for failed updates, and provides an easy way to use the same scripts and apply them to different types of databases.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code Refactor PMM Framework Project with Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:08:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</guid><description>I am Meet Patel, 2nd year undergraduate at DAIICT, Gandhinagar, India; pursuing a bachelor’s degree in Information and Communication Technology with a minor in Computational Science.
I am proud to be selected for the Google Summer of Code program under an open source organization as big and impactful as Percona. As we head towards the end of this amazing program, I’ll try to share a general overview of what and how all of it has been implemented.</description></item><item><title>Two weeks to MariaDB Server Fest</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 09:34:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</guid><description>There is still time to register for the MariaDB Server Fest 2020!
MariaDB Fest 2020[/caption]
Our Fest is the opportunity to have live interactions with the key players on MariaDB Server: the developers of MariaDB Server, the service providers, the experts, the system integrators, and – perhaps most importantly – your fellow users!
Interactivity happens all the time, with the presenters being cloned and available for answering questions throughout the presentation.</description></item><item><title>IoT Performance Bottlenecks &amp; Open Source Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</guid><description>The Internet of Things (IoT), in essence, is all about everyday devices that are readable, recognizable, trackable, and/or controllable via the Internet, regardless of the communication means — RFID, wireless LAN, and so on. The total installed base of IoT connected devices is projected to amount to 21.5 billion units worldwide by 2025. Thanks to IoT, the proliferation of data can be quite daunting. Hence, businesses should effectively organize and work with this enormous amount of valuable data.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB Server Fest: Call for Papers</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/26/mariadb-server-fest-call-for-papers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 21:42:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/26/mariadb-server-fest-call-for-papers/</guid><description>In the week of 14-20 September 2020, MariaDB Foundation will host the MariaDB Server Fest Online Conference. We welcome the Percona Community not just to participate, but also to submit papers for the event. We already have Peter Zaitsev joining as keynoter; we hope for more to come.
Our target audience are the users of MariaDB Server – current and future ones. We are looking for use cases, practices, tools and insights from our user base as well as from application developers, service providers and other experts.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE: Anti-cheating tools for massive multiplayer games using Amazon Aurora and Amazon ML services</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/11/percona-live-online-anti-cheating-tools-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 14:21:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/11/percona-live-online-anti-cheating-tools-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services/</guid><description>Would you play a multiplayer game if you discovered other people are cheating? According to a survey by Irdeto, 60% of online games were negatively impacted by cheaters, and 77% of players said they would stop playing a multiplayer game if they think opponents are cheating. Player churn grows as cheating grows.
Stopping this is therefore essential if you want to build and develop your community, which is essential to success for today’s gaming companies.</description></item><item><title>Percona Projects for Google Summer of Code - 2020</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that Percona was selected as a participating organization for the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2020 program, this is our second year as a participating org with the GSoC program.
GSoC is a great program to involve young student developers in open source projects. We participated in the program in 2019 for the first time and we were really happy and satisfied with the results.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE: MySQL on Google Cloud: War and Peace! by Akshay Suryawanshi &amp; Jeremy Cole</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:12:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</guid><description>This session at Percona Live ONLINE was presented by Akshay Suryawanshi, Senior Production Engineer at Shopify, and Jeremy Cole, Senior Staff Production Engineer - Datastores at Shopify. Shopify is an online and on-premise commerce platform, founded in 2006.
Shopify is used by more than a million merchants, and hundreds of billions of dollars of sales have happened on the platform since its inception. The company is a large user of MySQL, and the Black Friday and Cyber Monday weekends are their peak dates during the year, handling hundreds of billions of queries with MySQL.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Enhancing MySQL security at LinkedIn by Karthik Appigatla</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/01/percona-live-online-talk-enhancing-mysql-security-at-linkedin-by-karthik-appigatla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 08:01:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/01/percona-live-online-talk-enhancing-mysql-security-at-linkedin-by-karthik-appigatla/</guid><description>MySQL, arguably the most popular relational database, is used pretty extensively at the popular professional social network LinkedIn. At Percona Live ONLINE 2020, the company’s flagship event held online for the first time due to the Covid-19 pandemic, Karthik Appigatla from LinkedIN’s database SRE team discussed the company’s approach to securing their database deployment without introducing operational hiccups or adversely affecting performance.
Instead of just performing admin duties, Karthik’s team builds automated tools to scale their infrastructure, and he talked about some of these tailored tools in his presentation.</description></item><item><title>Join ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona on June 4th, 2020!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</guid><description>Long months of the pandemic lockdown have brought to life many great online events enabling the MySQL community to get together and stay informed about the very recent developments and innovations available to MySQL users. It isn’t over yet! Next Thursday, June 4th, Percona &amp;amp; ProxySQL are co-hosting the ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona virtual meetup covering ProxySQL, MySQL and Percona XtraDB Cluster.
The attendees are invited to participate in the two-hour deep-dive event with plenty of time for questions and answers (we will have two 40-minute sessions + 20 minutes allocated for Q&amp;amp;A).</description></item><item><title>State of the Dolphin – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/12/state-of-the-dolphin-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/12/state-of-the-dolphin-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 11:00 a.m. • London 4:00 p.m. • New Delhi 8:30 p.m.
Abstract I will talk about the latest improvements in MySQL 8.0.20 and the MySQL Engineering Team&amp;rsquo;s steady progress with MySQL 8.0. These include solutions like Document Store, InnoDB Cluster, and InnoDB ReplicaSet where MySQL Router and MySQL Shell are playing an important role. All of these Oracle solutions are completely open source.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.4 and the Competition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 23:10:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 12:30 p.m. • London 5:30 p.m. • New Delhi 10:00 p.m.
Abstract There are many good databases out there. Picking the right database for your project is never easy. There are technical criteria, business criteria, perhaps even ethical criteria. In this keynote, MariaDB Foundation CEO Kaj Arno will present his - obviously completely impartial - view of the process. Should you pick a database in the cloud or on premise?</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Tracing for Finding and Solving MariaDB (and MySQL) Performance Problems on Linux - Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/05/dynamic-tracing-for-finding-and-solving-mariadb-and-mysql-performance-problems-on-linux-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 21:13:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/05/dynamic-tracing-for-finding-and-solving-mariadb-and-mysql-performance-problems-on-linux-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot (CORRECTED): Wed 20 May • New York 6:00 a.m. • London 11:00 a.m. • New Delhi 3:30 p.m. Level: Advanced
Abstract While troubleshooting MariaDB server performance problems it is important to find out where the time is spent in the mysqld process, on-CPU and off-CPU. The process of investigation should have as small influence as possible on the server we try to troubleshoot. Performance_schema introduced in MySQL 5.</description></item><item><title>Unexpected slow ALTER TABLE in MySQL 5.7</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/23/unexpected-slow-alter-table-mysql-5-7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 15:47:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/23/unexpected-slow-alter-table-mysql-5-7/</guid><description>Usually one would expect that ALTER TABLE with ALGORITHM=COPY will be slower than the default ALGORITHM=INPLACE. In this blog post we describe the case when this is not so.
One of the reasons for such behavior is the lesser known limitation of ALTER TABLE (with default ALGORITHM=INPLACE) that avoids REDO operations. As a result, all dirty pages of the altered table/tablespace have to be flushed before the ALTER TABLE completion.</description></item><item><title>Finding MySQL Scaling Problems Using perf</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/02/05/finding-mysql-scaling-problems-using-perf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:18:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/02/05/finding-mysql-scaling-problems-using-perf/</guid><description>The thing I wish I&amp;rsquo;d learned while still a DBA is how to use perf. Conversely after moving to a developer role, getting access to real external client workloads to get a perf recording directly is rare. To bridge this gap, I hope to encourage a bit of perf usage to help DBAs report bugs/feature requests in more detail to MySQL developers, who can then serve your needs better.
A recent client request showed how useful perf is in exposing the areas of MySQL that are otherwise well tuned, but can still be in need of coding improvements that increase throughput.</description></item><item><title>Disk of Yesteryear Compared to Today’s SSD Drives</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/17/disk-of-yesteryear-compared-to-todays-ssd-drives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/17/disk-of-yesteryear-compared-to-todays-ssd-drives/</guid><description>In my [last blog post](https://www.percona.com/ community-blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/) I showed you how to get the entire Percona “Stack&amp;quot; up and running on a Raspberry Pi. This time around, I would like to show the impact on performance between using an SSD hard disk and a standard hard disk.
Disk performance is a key factor in Percona Server for MySQL (or any RDB platform) performance on a Raspberry Pi 4.
Test set up Each test below was run three times per Hard Disk and I took the best of the three for comparison.</description></item><item><title>A First Look at Amazon RDS Proxy</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/07/a-first-look-at-amazon-rds-proxy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 11:45:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/07/a-first-look-at-amazon-rds-proxy/</guid><description>At re:Invent in Las Vegas in December 2019, AWS announced the public preview of RDS Proxy, a fully managed database proxy that sits between your application and RDS. The new service offers to &amp;ldquo;share established database connections, improving database efficiency and application scalability&amp;rdquo;.
But one of the benefits that caught my eye is the ability to reduce the downtime in case of an instance failure and a failover. As for the announcement:</description></item><item><title>Percona Server for MySQL 8.0 – New Data Masking Feature</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/12/13/percona-server-for-mysql-8-0-new-data-masking-feature/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 10:43:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/12/13/percona-server-for-mysql-8-0-new-data-masking-feature/</guid><description>Database administrators are responsible for maintaining the privacy and integrity of data. When the data contains confidential information, your company has a legal obligation to ensure that privacy is maintained. Even so, being able to access the information contained in that dataset, for example for testing or reporting purposes, has great value so what to do? MySQL Enterprise Edition offers data masking and de-identification, so I decided to contribute similar functionality to Percona Server for MySQL.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: Test Like a Boss</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/25/percona-live-europe-presents-test-like-a-boss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 06:31:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/25/percona-live-europe-presents-test-like-a-boss/</guid><description>My first talk is a tutorial Testing like a boss: Deploy and Test Complex Topologies With a Single Command, scheduled at Percona Live Europe in Amsterdam on September 30th at 13:30.
My second talk is Amazing sandboxes with dbdeployer scheduled on October 1st at 11:00. It is the same topic as the tutorial, but covers a narrow set of features, all in the *amazing* category.
The tutorial introduces a challenging topic, because when people hear testing, they imagine a troop of monkeys fiddling with a keyboard and a mouse, endlessly repeating a boring task.</description></item><item><title>Are your Database Backups Good Enough?</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</guid><description>In the last few years there have been several examples of major service problems affecting businesses data: outages causing data inconsistencies; unavailability or data loss, and worldwide cyberattacks encrypting your files and asking for a ransom.
Database-related incidents are a very common industry issue- even if the root cause is not the database system itself. No matter if your main relational system is MySQL, MariaDB, PostgresQL or AWS Aurora -there will be a time where you will need to make use of backups to recover to a previous state.</description></item><item><title>Minimalist Tooling for MySQL/MariaDB DBAs</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/14/minimalist-tooling-for-mysql-mariadb-dbas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 14:21:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/14/minimalist-tooling-for-mysql-mariadb-dbas/</guid><description>In my roles as a DBA at various companies, I generally found the tooling to be quite lacking. Everything from metrics collection, alerting, backup management; they were either missing, incomplete or implemented poorly. DBA-Tools was born from a desire to build backup tools that supported my needs in smaller/non-cloud environments. As BASH is easily the most common shell available out there on systems running MySQL® or MariaDB®, it was an easy choice.</description></item><item><title>MySQL 5.6/Maria 10.1 : How we got from 30k qps to 101k qps.....</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/07/mysql-how-we-got-from-30k-qps-to-101k-qps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 07:52:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/07/mysql-how-we-got-from-30k-qps-to-101k-qps/</guid><description>Late one evening, I was staring at one of our large MySQL installations and noticed the database was hovering around 7-10 run queue length (48 cores, ~500 gigs memory, fusionIO cards). I had been scratching my head on how to get more throughput from the database. This blog records the changes I made to tune performance in order to achieve a 300% better throughput in MySQL. I tested my theories on MySQL 5.</description></item><item><title>How to Build a Percona Server "Stack" on a Raspberry Pi 3+</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 12:50:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</guid><description>The blog post How to Compile Percona Server for MySQL 5.7 in Raspberry Pi 3 by Walter Garcia, inspired me to create an updated install of Percona Server for the Raspberry Pi 3+.
This how-to post covers installing from source and being able to use Percona Server for MySQL in any of your maker projects. I have included everything you need to have a complete Percona Server, ready to store data collection for your weather station, your GPS data, or any other project you can think of that would require data collection in a database.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Optimizer: Naughty Aberrations on Queries Combining WHERE, ORDER BY and LIMIT</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/29/mysql-optimizer-naughty-aberrations-on-queries-combining-where-order-by-and-limit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 11:50:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/29/mysql-optimizer-naughty-aberrations-on-queries-combining-where-order-by-and-limit/</guid><description>Sometimes, the MySQL Optimizer chooses a wrong plan, and a query that should execute in less than 0.1 second ends-up running for 12 minutes!This is not a new problem: bugs about this can be traced back to 2014, and a blog post on this subject was published in 2015.But even if this is old news, because this problem recently came yet again to my attention, and because this is still not fixed in MySQL 5.</description></item><item><title>Impact of innodb_file_per_table Option On Crash Recovery Time</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/23/impact-of-innodb_file_per_table-option-on-crash-recovery-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 13:34:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/23/impact-of-innodb_file_per_table-option-on-crash-recovery-time/</guid><description>Starting at version MySQL5.6+ by default innodb_file_per_table is enabled and all data is stored in separate tablespaces. It provides some advantages.
I will highlight some of them:
You can reclaim disk space when truncating or dropping a table stored in a file-per-table tablespace. Truncating or dropping tables stored in the shared system tablespace creates free space internally in the system tablespace data files (ibdata files) which can only be used for new InnoDB data.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Globalizing Player Accounts with MySQL at Riot Games</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/28/percona-live-presents-globalizing-player-accounts-mysql-riot-games/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:48:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/28/percona-live-presents-globalizing-player-accounts-mysql-riot-games/</guid><description>During my presentation at Percona Live 2019, I’ll be talking about how Riot Games, the company behind League of Legends, migrated hundreds of millions of player accounts to unlock opportunities for us to delight players. This meant moving ten geographically distributed databases into a single global database replicated into four AWS regions. I’ll talk about some of the technical decisions we made, the expected vs actual outcomes, and lessons we learned along the way.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: An Open-Source, Cloud Native Database</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/14/percona-live-presents-open-source-cloud-native-database/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 17:38:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/14/percona-live-presents-open-source-cloud-native-database/</guid><description>During our presentation at Percona Live 2019 Intel and its software partners will introduce the audience to the work we’re doing to enable an open-source framework, we call Cloud Native Database. This is a collaborative effort between Intel, Rockset, PlanetScale, MariaDB and Percona.
Through the presentation the audience will be introduced to a set of principles and architectural elements that define what we mean by Cloud Native Database. We will discuss Rockset’s RocksDB-Cloud library and how it works with Facebook’s MyRocks storage engine.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The First Ever TiDB Track</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 20:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</guid><description>The PingCAP team has always been a strong supporter of Percona and the wider open source database community. As the people who work day in and day out on TiDB, an open source NewSQL database with MySQL compatibility, open source database is what gets us in the morning, and there’s no better place to share that passion than Percona Live.
At this year’s Percona Live Open Source Database Conference in Austin, Texas, we are particularly excited to bring you a full track of talks and demo on the latest development in TiDB during Day 1 of the conference.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The MySQL Query Optimizer Explained Through Optimizer Trace</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/24/mysql-query-optimizer-explained-optimizer-trace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 16:16:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/24/mysql-query-optimizer-explained-optimizer-trace/</guid><description>During my presentation at Percona Live 2019 I will show how using Optimizer Trace can give insight into the inner workings of the MySQL Query Optimizer. Through the presentation, the audience will both be introduced to optimizer trace, learn more about the decisions the query optimizer makes, and learn about the query execution strategies the query optimizer has at its disposal. I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the main phases of the MySQL optimizer and its optimization strategies, including query transformations, data access strategies, the range optimizer, the join optimizer, and subquery optimization.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Vitess – Running Sharded MySQL on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/18/percona-live-presents-vitess-running-sharded-mysql-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 17:19:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/18/percona-live-presents-vitess-running-sharded-mysql-kubernetes/</guid><description>The topic I&amp;rsquo;m presenting addresses a growing and unfulfilled need: the ability to run stateful workloads in Kubernetes. Running stateless applications is now considered a solved problem. However, it&amp;rsquo;s currently not practical to put databases like MySQL in containers, give them to Kubernetes, and expect it to manage their life cycles.
Sugu Sougoumarane, CTO of Planetscale and creator of Vitess.
Vitess addresses this need by providing all the necessary orchestration and safety, and it has multiple years of mileage to show for it.</description></item><item><title>London Open Source Database Community Meetup</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 09:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</guid><description>I strongly believe in the community.
Communities are the real strength of open source. Not just the theoretical ability to study, modify and share code – but the fact that other people out there are doing these things. Creating a base of knowledge and a network of relations.These can become work relationships, valuable discussions, open source tools, or even friendships.
That is why, when I heard that several people from the Percona support team will soon be in London, I badly wanted to organise an event.</description></item><item><title>Some Notes on MariaDB system-versioned Tables</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/14/notes-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 14:53:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/14/notes-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</guid><description>As mentioned in a previous post, I gave a talk at Percona Live Europe 2018 about system-versioned tables. This is a new MariaDB 10.3 feature, which consists of preserving old versions of a table rows. Each version has two timestamps that indicate the start (INSERT,UPDATE) of the validity of that version, and its end (DELETE, UPDATE). As a result, the user is able to query these tables as they appear at a point in the past, or how data evolved in a certain time range.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Setup at Hostinger Explained</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/11/mysql-setup-hostinger-explained/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 15:27:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/11/mysql-setup-hostinger-explained/</guid><description>Ever wondered how hosting companies manage their MySQL database architecture? At Hostinger, we have various MySQL setups starting from the standalone replica-less instances to Percona XtraDB Cluster (later just PXC), ProxySQL routing-based and even absolutely custom and unique solutions which I’m going to describe in this blog post.
We do not have elephant-sized databases for internal services like API, billing, and clients. Thus almost every decision ends up with high availability as a top priority instead of scalability.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: ClickHouse at Messagebird: Analysing Billions of Events in Real-Time\*</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/29/clickhouse-at-messagebird-analysing-billions-of-events-in-real-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 17:28:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/29/clickhouse-at-messagebird-analysing-billions-of-events-in-real-time/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll look into how Clickhouse allows us to ingest a large amount of data and run complex analytical interactive queries at MessageBird. We also present the business needs that brought ClickHouse to our attention and detail the journey to its deployment. We cover the problems we faced, and how we dealt with them. We talk about our current Cloud production setup and how we deployed and use it.
We are really enthusiastic to share a use case of Clickhouse, how it helped us to scale our analytics stack with the good, the bad and the ugly.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: pg_chameleon MySQL to PostgreSQL Replica Made Easy</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 14:42:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</guid><description>What excites me is the possibility that this tool is giving to other people. Also, the challenges I’ve faced and the new ideas for the future releases are always source of interest that keep me focused on the project. So I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to sharing this with the conference delegates.
pg_chameleon can achieve two tasks in a very simple way. It can setup a permanent replica between MySQL and PostgreSQL, giving the freedom of choice for the right tool for the right job, or can migrate multiple schemas to a PostgreSQL database.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: MariaDB 10.4 Reverse Privileges (DENY)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/23/mariadb-10-4-reverse-privileges-deny/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 11:41:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/23/mariadb-10-4-reverse-privileges-deny/</guid><description>One of the most common questions about privileges in MySQL and MariaDB is how would a user revoke access to a particular table, in a large database with hundreds or thousands of tables, while keeping the rest available. Currently, there is no easy solution. Just grant access to everything else, individually. Not only does this reduce server performance, but is a nightmare to maintain. Reverse privileges solve this and more.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: Need for speed - Boosting Apache Cassandra's performance using Netty</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/22/percona-live-europe-presents-need-speed-boosting-apache-cassandras-performance-using-netty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 08:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/22/percona-live-europe-presents-need-speed-boosting-apache-cassandras-performance-using-netty/</guid><description>My talk is titled Need for speed: Boosting Apache Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s performance using Netty. Over the years that I have worked in the software industry, making code run fast has fascinated me. So, naturally when I first started contributing to Apache Cassandra, I started looking opportunities to improve its performance. My talk takes us through some interesting challenges within a distributed system like Apache Cassandra and various techniques to significantly improve its performance.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: The Latest MySQL Replication Features</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/19/latest-mysql-replication-features/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 15:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/19/latest-mysql-replication-features/</guid><description>Considering the modern world of technology, where distributed system play a key role, replication in MySQL® is at the very heart of that change. It is very exciting to deliver this presentation and to be able to show everyone the greatest and the latest features that MySQL brings in order to continue the success that it has always been in the past.
The talk is suitable for anyone that&amp;rsquo;s interested in knowing what Oracle is doing with MySQL replication.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: MariaDB System-Versioned Tables</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/17/percona-live-europe-presents-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 16:14:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/17/percona-live-europe-presents-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</guid><description>System-versioned tables, or temporal tables, are a typical feature of proprietary database management systems like DB2, Oracle and SQL Server. They also appeared at some point in PostgreSQL, but only as an extension; and also in CockroachDB, but in a somewhat limited fashion.
The MariaDB® implementation is the first appearance of temporal tables in the MySQL ecosystem, and the most complete implementation in the open source world.
My presentation will be useful for analysts, and some managers, who will definitely benefit from learning how to use temporal tables.</description></item><item><title>Export to JSON from MySQL All Ready for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/export-to-json-from-mysql-all-ready-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 15:18:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/export-to-json-from-mysql-all-ready-for-mongodb/</guid><description>This post walks through how to export data from MySQL® into JSON format, ready to ingest into MongoDB®. Starting from MySQL 5.7+, there is native support for JSON. MySQL provides functions that actually create JSON values, so I will be using these functions in this article to export to JSON from MySQL:
JSON_OBJECT JSON_ARRAY These functions make it easy to convert MySQL data to JSON e.g.
mysql&amp;gt; SELECT json_object(&amp;#39;employee_id&amp;#39;, emp_no, &amp;#39;first_name&amp;#39;, first_name ) AS &amp;#39;JSON&amp;#39; FROM employees LIMIT 2; +------------------------------------------------+ | JSON | +------------------------------------------------+ | {&amp;#34;first_name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Aamer&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;employee_id&amp;#34;: 444117} | | {&amp;#34;first_name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Aamer&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;employee_id&amp;#34;: 409151} | +------------------------------------------------+ 2 rows in set (0.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Query Optimization and TLS at Large Scale</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 14:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe this year, I got accepted a workshop on query optimization and a 50-minute talk covering TLS for MySQL at Large Scale, talking about our experiences at the Wikimedia Foundation.
Workshop The 3-hour workshop on Monday, titled Query Optimization with MySQL 8.0 and MariaDB 10.3: The Basics is a beginners&amp;rsquo; tutorial–though dense in content. It&amp;rsquo;s for people who are more familiar with database storage systems other than InnoDB for MySQL, MariaDB or Percona Server.</description></item><item><title>Generating Identifiers – from AUTO_INCREMENT to Sequence</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/12/generating-identifiers-auto_increment-sequence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/12/generating-identifiers-auto_increment-sequence/</guid><description>There are a number of options for generating ID values for your tables. In this post, Alexey Mikotkin of Devart explores your choices for generating identifiers with a look at auto_increment, triggers, UUID and sequences.
AUTO_INCREMENT Frequently, we happen to need to fill tables with unique identifiers. Naturally, the first example of such identifiers is PRIMARY KEY data. These are usually integer values hidden from the user since their specific values are unimportant.</description></item><item><title>Deploying MySQL on Kubernetes with a Percona-based Operator</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:03:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</guid><description>In the context of providing managed WordPress hosting services, at Presslabs we operate with lots of small to medium-sized databases, in a DB-per-service model, as we call it. The workloads are mostly reads, so we need to efficiently scale that. The MySQL® asynchronous replication model fits the bill very well, allowing us to scale horizontally from one server—with the obvious availability pitfalls—to tens of nodes. The next release of the stack is going to be open-sourced.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Elasticsearch 101</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 07:17:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe, I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting the tutorial Elasticsearch 101 alongside my colleagues and fellow presenters from ObjectRocket Alex Cercel, DBA, and Mihai Aldoiu, Data Engineer. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief overview of our tutorial.
Elasticsearch® is well known as a highly scalable search engine that stores data in a structure optimized for language based searches but its capabilities and use cases don’t stop there. In this tutorial, we’ll give you a hands-on introduction to Elasticsearch and give you a glimpse at some of the fundamental concepts.</description></item><item><title>Minimize MySQL Deadlocks with 3 Steps</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/24/minimize-mysql-deadlocks-3-steps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 10:49:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/24/minimize-mysql-deadlocks-3-steps/</guid><description>MySQL has locking capabilities, for example table and row level locking, and such locks are needed to control data integrity in multi-user concurrency. Deadlocks—where two or more transactions are waiting for one another to give up locks before the transactions can proceed successfully—are an unwanted situation. It is a classic problem for all databases including MySQL/PostgreSQL/Oracle etc. By default, MySQL detects the deadlock condition and to break the deadlock it rolls back one of the transactions.</description></item><item><title>Multi-master with MariaDB 10 - a tutorial</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:57:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</guid><description>The goal of this tutorial is to show you how to use multi-master to aggregate databases with the same name, but different data from different masters, on the same slave.
Example:
master1 =&amp;gt; a French subsidiary master2 =&amp;gt; a British subsidiary Both have the same database PRODUCTION but the data are totally different.
This screenshot is made from my own monitoring tool: PmaControl. You have to read 10.10.16.232 on master2 and not 10.</description></item><item><title>Question about Semi-Synchronous Replication: the Answer with All the Details</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/23/question-about-semi-synchronous-replication-answer-with-all-the-details/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:49:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/23/question-about-semi-synchronous-replication-answer-with-all-the-details/</guid><description>I was recently asked a question by mail about MySQL Lossless Semi-Synchronous Replication. As I think the answer could benefit many people, I am answering it in a blog post. The answer brings us to the internals of transaction committing, of semi-synchronous replication, of MySQL (server) crash recovery, and of storage engine (InnoDB) crash recovery. I am also debunking some misconceptions that I have often seen and heard repeated by many.</description></item><item><title>Easy and Effective Way of Building External Dictionaries for ClickHouse with Pentaho Data Integration Tool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</guid><description>In this post, I provide an illustration of how to use Pentaho Data Integration (PDI) tool to set up external dictionaries in MySQL to support ClickHouse. Although I use MySQL in this example, you can use any PDI supported source.
ClickHouse ClickHouse is an open-source column-oriented DBMS (columnar database management system) for online analytical processing. Source: wiki.
Pentaho Data Integration Information from the Pentaho wiki: Pentaho Data Integration (PDI, also called Kettle) is the component of Pentaho responsible for the Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) processes.</description></item><item><title>How to Automate Minor Version Upgrades for MySQL on RDS</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/07/10/automate-minor-version-upgrades-mysql-rds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:19:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/07/10/automate-minor-version-upgrades-mysql-rds/</guid><description>Amazon RDS for MySQL offers the option to automate minor version upgrades using the minor version upgrade policy, a property that lets you decide if Amazon is allowed to perform the upgrades on your behalf. Usually the goal is not to upgrade automatically every RDS instance but to keep up to date automatically non-production deployments. This helps you address engine issues as soon as possible and improve the automation of the deployment process.</description></item><item><title>A Nice Feature in MariaDB 10.3: no InnoDB Buffer Pool in Core Dumps</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/28/nice-feature-in-mariadb-103-no-innodb-buffer-pool-in-coredumps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 12:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/28/nice-feature-in-mariadb-103-no-innodb-buffer-pool-in-coredumps/</guid><description>MariaDB 10.3 is now generally available (10.3.7 was released GA on 2018-05-25). The article What&amp;rsquo;s New in MariaDB Server 10.3 by the MariaDB Corporation lists three key improvements in 10.3: temporal data processing, Oracle compatibility features, and purpose-built storage engines. Even if I am excited about MyRocks and curious on Spider, I am also very interested in less flashy but still very important changes that make running the database in production easier.</description></item><item><title>Character Sets: Migrating to utf8mb4 with pt_online_schema_change</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/12/character-sets-migrating-utf8mb4-pt_online_schema_change/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 11:27:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/12/character-sets-migrating-utf8mb4-pt_online_schema_change/</guid><description>Modern applications often feature the use of data in many different languages. This is often true even of applications that only offer a user facing interface in a single language. Many users may, for example, need to enter names which, although using Latin characters, feature diacritics; in other cases, they may need to enter text which contains Chinese or Japanese characters. Even if a user is capable of using an application localized for only one language, it may be necessary to deal with data from a wide variety of languages.</description></item><item><title>Enabling KMS encryption for a running Amazon RDS instance</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/08/enabling-kms-encryption-running-amazon-rds-instance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 11:40:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/08/enabling-kms-encryption-running-amazon-rds-instance/</guid><description>Since summer 2017, Amazon RDS supports encryption at rest using AWS Key Management Service (KMS) for db.t2.small and db.t2.medium database instances, making the feature now available to virtually every instance class and type.
Unless you are running Previous Generation DB Instances or you can only afford to run a db.t2.micro, every other instance class now supports native encryption at rest using KMS. As for the Amazon documentation:
Encryption on smaller T2 database instances is useful for development and test use cases, where you want the environment to have identical security characteristics as the planned production environment.</description></item></channel></rss>