<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Replication on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/replication/</link><description>Recent content in Replication on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/replication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Errant GTID</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/11/08/the-errant-gtid-pt1/</guid><description>Part 1 What is a GTID? Oracle/MySQL define a GTID as "A global transaction identifier (GTID) is a unique identifier created and associated with each transaction committed on the server of origin (the source). This identifier is unique not only to the server on which it originated, but is unique across all servers in a given replication topology." An errant transaction can make promotion of a replica to primary very difficult.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction To MongoDB Replication</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/01/14/introduction-mongodb-replication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 11:21:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/01/14/introduction-mongodb-replication/</guid><description>MongoDB® is database software that stores data in the same format as JSON. The data structure of the database can be changed when required. The performance of the database is good and developers can easily use to it to connect their code to the database.
The database, MongoDB is platform independent and runs in the same way on all platforms. It is an open source database and is based on a document-oriented database model.</description></item><item><title>Multi-master with MariaDB 10 - a tutorial</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:57:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</guid><description>The goal of this tutorial is to show you how to use multi-master to aggregate databases with the same name, but different data from different masters, on the same slave.
Example:
master1 =&amp;gt; a French subsidiary master2 =&amp;gt; a British subsidiary Both have the same database PRODUCTION but the data are totally different.
This screenshot is made from my own monitoring tool: PmaControl. You have to read 10.</description></item><item><title>Question about Semi-Synchronous Replication: the Answer with All the Details</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/23/question-about-semi-synchronous-replication-answer-with-all-the-details/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:49:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/23/question-about-semi-synchronous-replication-answer-with-all-the-details/</guid><description>I was recently asked a question by mail about MySQL Lossless Semi-Synchronous Replication. As I think the answer could benefit many people, I am answering it in a blog post. The answer brings us to the internals of transaction committing, of semi-synchronous replication, of MySQL (server) crash recovery, and of storage engine (InnoDB) crash recovery. I am also debunking some misconceptions that I have often seen and heard repeated by many.</description></item></channel></rss>