<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community Live 2022 on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/</link><description>Recent content in Percona Community Live 2022 on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Common Possible Preventative Measures to Avoid Locking Issue in PostgreSQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-naveed-shaikh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-naveed-shaikh/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cross-Cloud Migrations With Databases on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin/</guid><description>In this talk you will learn how Kubernetes and Percona Operators can help you to avoid vendor lock-in when you run your databases in containers with Percona Operators.</description></item><item><title>Database as Code. Not only migrations</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-maksim-gramin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-maksim-gramin/</guid><description>If you have just dropped your DB migrations scripts to your pipeline, then it&amp;rsquo;s great, but that&amp;rsquo;s where &amp;ldquo;Database as Code&amp;rdquo; is just getting started. In this talk, I will share my view on &amp;ldquo;Database as Code&amp;rdquo; mantra.</description></item><item><title>Database Reliability Engineering for MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-matthias-crauwels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-matthias-crauwels/</guid><description>A common request that we get from our clients is to make MySQL highly available or to enhance existing architecture. We have standardized our approach by combining a proxy layer, for traffic redirection, a topology management tool, for master failover/switchover, and some additional tools to glue together both layers.</description></item><item><title>Let's Talk About MySQL Query Tuning</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-gabriel-ciciliani/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-gabriel-ciciliani/</guid><description>Regardless of development frameworks, despite linters, besides countless sessions with the DBA, slow queries always end up making it to production. Proactive and reactive slow query tuning is still critical to ensure poorly written queries aren&amp;rsquo;t undermining server performance and wasting valuable compute resources. Cloud-based database managed services are not the exception: slow query root cause analysis requires human intervention. In this session I will discuss why slow query tuning is more relevant than ever, how to detect problems and guidelines to fix them.</description></item><item><title>Optimization Techniques in MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-yunus-shaikh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-yunus-shaikh/</guid><description>Optimization of mysql with indexing, server tuning and OS tuning to make performance better</description></item><item><title>Overview of Different ALTER Algorithms and Its Locking Scenarios in MySQL DEMO</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sri-sakthivel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sri-sakthivel/</guid><description>I would like to show the demo session on describing the different MySQL ALTER Algorithms ( COPY / INPLACE / INSTANT ) and how they are performing with different locking methods ( Exclusive / Shared / None ).</description></item><item><title>Percona Database Distributions - An Overview</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-lenz-grimmer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-lenz-grimmer/</guid><description>In this presentation, Lenz is providing an overview and update about Percona&amp;rsquo;s database distributions for MongoDB, MySQL and PostgreSQL. Attendees will learn more about Percona&amp;rsquo;s role in the open source database ecosystems and how Percona&amp;rsquo;s database distributions help to solve common production use cases. The talk will also go over the most notable feature highlights that have been added to the distributions lately.</description></item><item><title>Percona Pstress: A Concurrency and Crash Recovery Testing Tool to Test MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-rahul-malik/</guid><description>How Pstress works, success so far with MySQL testing.</description></item><item><title>Physical Backups with Percona Backup for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin2/</guid><description>Reduce Recovery Time Objective with new Physical Backups functionality in Percona Backup for MongoDB (PBM). We will explain the value, the limitations of our solution and go deeper into the mechanics of how it works.</description></item><item><title>PMM Development Process</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko2/</guid><description>I would discuss how to contribute to the PMM project, what process we use and show example of code contribution to the parts of PMM.</description></item><item><title>PMM on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko/</guid><description>How to run PMM on Kubernetes, demonstration and discussion of technology choices. Tip and tricks and relation to DBaaS. Q&amp;amp;A</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL and Artificial intelligence</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-ibrar-ahmed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-ibrar-ahmed/</guid><description>Artificial intelligence, machine learning, and deep learning are intertwined capabilities that attempt to solve problems that defy traditional computational solutions &amp;mdash; problems including fraud detection, voice recognition, and search result recommendations. While they elude simple computation, they are computationally expensive, involving the calculation of perhaps millions of probabilities and weights. These computations can be done outside the database, but there are specific advantages of doing machine learning inside it, close to where the data is stored.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Query Performance Insights</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-hamid-akhtar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-hamid-akhtar/</guid><description>Understanding query performance patterns are essentially the foundation for query performance tuning. It, in many ways, dictates how a database cluster evolves. And then there are obviously direct and indirect cost connotations as well.
With improved observability, using the right tools, you can get the best out of your existing setup and ensure that it is able to handle not only the average load profile but peak load as well. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how different tools like pg_stat_activity, pg_stat_statements, auto_explain, pgBadger, and pg_stat_monitor can deliver a complete picture to help measure, analyze and optimize your queries and database system.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Replication Conflicts: Avoiding Pitfalls</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-hamid-akhtar2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-hamid-akhtar2/</guid><description>Experiencing replication conflicts is not too unfamiliar a sight. Whether one experiences replication lag, slots, locks, snapshots, tablespace issues, or other conflicts, establishing a set of best practices along with using proper observability tools will help avoid potential issues. This talk focuses on what to do and what not to in order to avoid database conflicts in streaming replication setups by providing deep insight into how issues are PostgreSQL internals.</description></item><item><title>Production with ProxySQL and Consul</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-alawi-assaggaf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-alawi-assaggaf/</guid><description>Covering 3 use case scenarios to implement HA utilizing ProxySQL, Orchestrator and Load Balancers in production environments</description></item><item><title>The Future of MyDumper</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-david-ducos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-david-ducos/</guid><description>MyDumper has changed a lot in the last year. We are going to high-level review the features added, new use cases and enhancements that are going to be added in future release and how they are going to impact in performance.</description></item><item><title>The Journey to Achieve 1000x TPS for a Real-World Core Banking Application on TiDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sidney-chen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sidney-chen/</guid><description>Performance tuning is complicated, especially with a distributed database like TiDB. It becomes even more challenging when the whole system is running on arm64-based servers.</description></item><item><title>The Low Hanging Fruits of MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-kedar-vaijanapurkar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-kedar-vaijanapurkar/</guid><description>MySQL is one of the top used database system and with highly active community. Though without proper configuration you may not squeeze the most out of it.</description></item><item><title>The MySQL Ecosystem in 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-colin-charles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-colin-charles/</guid><description>27 years of the MySQL ecosystem, not only is there the core product from Oracle, there is a branch from Percona and a fork from MariaDB. You&amp;rsquo;re a busy DBA having to maintain a mix of this. Or you&amp;rsquo;re a CIO planning to choose one branch/fork. How do you go about picking? How do you go about supporting multiple databases? Find out more in this talk.</description></item><item><title>The Open-Source Distributed Graph Database: Nebula Graph</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-wey-gu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-wey-gu/</guid><description>Nebula Graph is a young Open Source Graph Database that excels at huge data volume OLTP scenarios, started from 18' with v3.0 being released on Feb. 22', Nebula had been adopted by many teams including WeChat/Baidu/Meituan/Bigo/Akulaku as the Graph Storage Layer.</description></item><item><title>Using PMM Alerting in Production</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-francisco-bordenave/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-francisco-bordenave/</guid><description>Now that you&amp;rsquo;re using PMM to identify slow queries and chart your database activity, what PMM can do for you to avoid problems? PMM is getting more and more popular for monitoring databases while features are increasing and allowing us to do more with less effort. In this talk we will show you how PMM can help you on your day to day operational tasks to prevent issues by setting up alerts.</description></item><item><title>Walking Through Identifying and Drilling Into a Slow Down in MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-divyanshu-soni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-divyanshu-soni/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>