<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dashboard on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/dashboard/</link><description>Recent content in dashboard on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Community Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/</guid><description>Good news! We are happy to announce a new 100% virtual event coming up this summer - Percona Community Live!
It will take place on June 21-23 online and will be live-streamed on YouTube, LinkedIn, and Twitch. It is an excellent opportunity to learn from the best-of-breed experts directly from your home! We will focus on the latest trends in the database world, and secret tricks from the open source stars.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Links Percona Live 2022 was an amazing 3-day event of keynotes, educational sessions, hands-on activities, and more. It took place in Austin, TX on May 16th-18th. Attendees could hear the biggest names in the industry, discuss their experience, dive deep into software, and offer actionable advice. They also learned about how open source database technology can power applications, improve websites, secure data, and solve critical database issues. On this page, you can find the list of presentations from Percona Live 2022.</description></item><item><title>Road to Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/road-to-percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/road-to-percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Percona Live 2022 is coming soon! Get to know the talk of the amazing speakers and best-of-breed open source database experts, who will come to Austin to present for you this year. Matt Yonkovit, the Percona’s HOSS, met some of them virtually and recorded small previews of their talks. Watch them, find out more details about the upcoming presentations and choose which ones to join during the event.</description></item></channel></rss>