<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dashboard on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/dashboard/</link><description>Recent content in dashboard on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dashboard Story: How We Created PMM Dashboard for Highload</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/22/dashboard-story-how-we-created-pmm-dashboard-for-highload/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/22/dashboard-story-how-we-created-pmm-dashboard-for-highload/</guid><description>Let’s say you have highload instances. How do you monitor them? There are a lot of servers with 100, 200… 500+ nodes. How can we collect, check, and analyze metrics from all these servers? How can we understand what and where something happened? Scroll, scroll, scroll&amp;hellip; down? That was the task that we faced at Percona and successfully resolved.
Issue With Home Dashboard Percona Monitoring and Management dashboards are based on Grafana.</description></item><item><title>Elisa Usai at POUG 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/elisa-pmm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/elisa-pmm/</guid><description>Elisa Usai from dbi participated in POUG 2022 and gave a talk about Percona Monitoring and Management. POUG (Polish Oracle User Group) organizes as usual his annual conference in Poland in September to discuss about Oracle topics. The 7th edition of 2022 took place in Wrocław on September 9 and 10.
Elisa is an amazing speaker. She give an overview of the tool, explained how easy it is to install and turn on monitoring and show the some features such as integrated alerting, Query Analytics to get performance metrics over a period of time, Advisors checks to perform some security checks on databases, and more!</description></item><item><title>Percona Community Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/</guid><description>Good news! We are happy to announce a new 100% virtual event coming up this summer - Percona Community Live!
Agenda is ready and published here Links to the streaming here It will take place on June 21-23 online and will be live-streamed on YouTube, LinkedIn, and Twitch. It is an excellent opportunity to learn from the best-of-breed experts directly from your home! We will focus on the latest trends in the database world, and secret tricks from the open source stars.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Links Percona Live 2022 was an amazing 3-day event of keynotes, educational sessions, hands-on activities, and more. It took place in Austin, TX on May 16th-18th. Attendees could hear the biggest names in the industry, discuss their experience, dive deep into software, and offer actionable advice. They also learned about how open source database technology can power applications, improve websites, secure data, and solve critical database issues. On this page, you can find the list of presentations from Percona Live 2022.</description></item><item><title>Road to Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/road-to-percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/road-to-percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Percona Live 2022 is coming soon! Get to know the talk of the amazing speakers and best-of-breed open source database experts, who will come to Austin to present for you this year. Matt Yonkovit, the Percona’s HOSS, met some of them virtually and recorded small previews of their talks. Watch them, find out more details about the upcoming presentations and choose which ones to join during the event.</description></item></channel></rss>