<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>author_gaurav on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/author_gaurav/</link><description>Recent content in author_gaurav on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:35:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/author_gaurav/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IoT Performance Bottlenecks &amp; Open Source Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</guid><description>The Internet of Things (IoT), in essence, is all about everyday devices that are readable, recognizable, trackable, and/or controllable via the Internet, regardless of the communication means — RFID, wireless LAN, and so on. The total installed base of IoT connected devices is projected to amount to 21.5 billion units worldwide by 2025. Thanks to IoT, the proliferation of data can be quite daunting. Hence, businesses should effectively organize and work with this enormous amount of valuable data.</description></item><item><title>Tame Kubernetes with These Open-Source Tools</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/08/tame-kubernetes-with-open-source-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 13:03:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/08/tame-kubernetes-with-open-source-tools/</guid><description>Kubernetes’ popularity as the most-preferred open-source container-orchestration system has skyrocketed in the recent past. The overall container market is expected to cross USD 2.7 billion by 2020 with a CAGR of 40 percent. Three orchestrators spearhead this upward trend, namely Kubernetes, Mesos, and Docker Swarm. However, referring to the graph below, Kubernetes clearly leads the pack.
source: https://medium.com/@rdodev/saved-you-an-analyst-read-on-kubernetes-growth-2018-edition-810367876981 
The automation and infrastructural capabilities of Kubernetes are transforming the DevOps space, thereby enhancing the value of the business through software.</description></item></channel></rss>