<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Monitoring and Management on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/percona-monitoring-and-management/</link><description>Recent content in Percona Monitoring and Management on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/percona-monitoring-and-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Projects for Google Summer of Code - 2020</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that Percona was selected as a participating organization for the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2020 program, this is our second year as a participating org with the GSoC program.
GSoC is a great program to involve young student developers in open source projects. We participated in the program in 2019 for the first time and we were really happy and satisfied with the results.</description></item><item><title>How To Contribute to PMM Documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 16:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;d love to see more contributions towards the development and improvement of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM), one of Percona&amp;rsquo;s most valued projects. Like all of Percona&amp;rsquo;s software, PMM is free and open-source. An area where we&amp;rsquo;d dearly love to see some community provided enhancement is in its documentation. In future blog posts, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide some insight on how to contribute to our software but&amp;hellip; the beauty of documentation is that it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to maintain, and you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to be a programmer to be able to provide valuable corrections and enhancements.</description></item></channel></rss>