<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chernihiv.IT Conf: Tech Front</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-conf-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-conf-2022/</guid><description>Percona sponsored an amazing event organized by Chernihiv.IT Cluster - Chernihiv.IT Conf: Tech Front. It was an online event organized in support to Chernihiv and IT industry in this city. It was an online event and it attackted a lot of attendees from Chernihiv and all over Ukraine.
Evgeniy Patlan, Manager in Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering, was in the role of the host greeting speakers, communicating with them and asking questions.</description></item><item><title>Running PMM with Docker on Ubuntu 20.04</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</guid><description>I started at Percona a few weeks ago and was looking for a quick way to learn about PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management), which is one of my favorite technologies within Percona to monitor the health of our database infrastructure, explore new patterns in the database behavior, manage and improve the performance of our databases, all with customizable dashboards and real-time alerts using Grafana and VictoriaMetrics.
The best of all is that PMM is Open Source, you can check the PMM repository in case you want to contribute.</description></item><item><title>Liquibase Data is Git for Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/25/liquibase-data-is-git-for-databases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/25/liquibase-data-is-git-for-databases/</guid><description>Author&amp;rsquo;s Note: Robert will be demoing Liquibase Data at Percona Live 2022 on Wednesday, May 18 at 11:50am. Add this presentation to your schedule.
Git is an amazing tool for collaboration — developers can work together to build better software faster. However, the usual Git workflow neglects the database. With Liquibase Data we’re bringing git to the database so you can easily version containerized databases, share changes with team members, store versions in remote locations, and tag versions.</description></item><item><title>Chernihiv.IT Cluster Sponsorship</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-cluster/</guid><description>Percona is thrilled to support Chernihiv.IT Cluster and help to develop the local IT community in Chernihiv, Ukraine. The cluster was founded in 2017 and it unites the efforts of 11 IT companies. Percona&amp;rsquo;s engineers Evgeniy Patlan, Serhii Stasiuk, Mykola Marzhan, Maxim Kondratenko, and other Perconians in the city eagerly participate in Cluster&amp;rsquo;s activities, both online and in-person, and willingly share their knowledge and experience with others.
CHERNIHIV.IT DevOps Crash Course</description></item><item><title>Online Public Lecture “What is DevOps?”</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</guid><description>Percona’s Evgeniy Patlan (Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering) and Serhii Stasiuk (Build/Release Engineer) participated in an online public meetup “What is DevOps?” for students of Chernihiv Polytechnic National University. Together with Volodymyr Rudiy (CEO, Agilevision.io) and Volodymyr Bazilevich (Academic, Chernihiv Polytechnic National University), they discussed the modern views on DevOps methodology, practices and people who do this job nowadays, tasks and challenges that they face and what is expected of them on the modern labor market.</description></item><item><title>Nerdearla 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/nerdearla-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/nerdearla-2021/</guid><description>One of the virtual events Percona was happy to support this year was Nerdearla 2021, the most important IT conference in the Latin American region.
Ivan Groenewold (Architect, Percona) presented his talk “Deployando MongoDB sharded con Terraform y Ansible” (Deploying MongoDB Sharded Clusters With Terraform and Ansible”.
Link: https://youtu.be/okCaeIHa4cY
We also welcomed people to our virtual booth and distributed some white paper collateral.
Though it was lots of fun virtually, we hope that in the future we will be able to meet in person again!</description></item><item><title>Embracing the Stream</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/10/embracing-the-stream/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/10/embracing-the-stream/</guid><description>So this happened: CentOS Project shifts focus to CentOS Stream
The future of the CentOS Project is CentOS Stream, and over the next year we’ll be shifting focus from CentOS Linux, the rebuild of Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), to CentOS Stream, which tracks just ahead of a current RHEL release. CentOS Linux 8, as a rebuild of RHEL 8, will end at the end of 2021. CentOS Stream continues after that date, serving as the upstream (development) branch of Red Hat Enterprise Linux.</description></item><item><title>How to build a high-performance application on Tarantool from scratch</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</guid><description>I came to Mail.ru Group in 2013, and I required a queue for one task. First of all, I decided to check what the company had already got. They told me they had this Tarantool product, and I checked how it worked and decided that adding a queue broker to it could work perfectly well. I contacted Kostja Osipov, the senior expert in Tarantool, and the next day he gave me a 250-string script that was capable of managing almost everything I needed.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Data Reliably Using SLO Theory – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/15/engineering-data-reliably-using-slo-theory-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 02:43:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/15/engineering-data-reliably-using-slo-theory-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 12:30 p.m. • London 5:30 p.m. • New Delhi 10:00 p.m. • Singapore 12:30 a.m. (next day)
Abstract Not so long ago, operations specialists worked much like today&amp;rsquo;s data engineers do: with specialized skills, they were the people who kept sites running, who responded to emergencies, and who—unfortunately—spent much of their time dealing with incidents and other &amp;ldquo;fires.&amp;rdquo; When the DevOps revolution came, this began to change.</description></item><item><title>IIoT platform databases - How Mail.ru Cloud Solutions deals with petabytes of data coming from a multitude of devices</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:11:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</guid><description>Hello, my name is Andrey Sergeyev and I work as a Head of IoT Solution Development at Mail.ru Cloud Solutions. We all know there is no such thing as a universal database. Especially when the task is to build an IoT platform that would be capable of processing millions of events from various sensors in near real-time.
Our product Mail.ru IoT Platform started as a Tarantool-based prototype. I’m going to tell you about our journey, the problems we faced and the solutions we found.</description></item><item><title>Cassandra Where and How by John Schulz</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</guid><description>If Percona Live ONLINE had graded its talks by skill level this year, John Schulz’s talk would have been essential viewing in the Beginners track. (You can watch all the event’s presentations now on Percona’s YouTube channel.) This talk was a good overview and meant for anyone who had heard of the Apache Cassandra distributed database but wasn’t sure whether it would be suitable for their project or not.
Database-veteran, John Schulz has been tinkering with Cassandra for about a decade and to help anyone get started he gave a whistle-stop tour of the Cassandra ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Making a Tarantool-Based Investment Business Core for Alfa-Bank</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/19/making-a-tarantool-based-investment-business-core-for-alfa-bank/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 13:23:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/19/making-a-tarantool-based-investment-business-core-for-alfa-bank/</guid><description>A still from &amp;ldquo;Our Secret Universe: The Hidden Life of the Cell&amp;rdquo;
Investment business is one of the most complex domains in the banking world. It&amp;rsquo;s about not just credits, loans, and deposits — there are also securities, currencies, commodities, derivatives, and all kinds of complex stuff like structured products.
Recently, people have become increasingly aware of their finances. More and more get involved in securities trading. Individual investment accounts have emerged not so long ago.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE: MySQL on Google Cloud: War and Peace! by Akshay Suryawanshi &amp; Jeremy Cole</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:12:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</guid><description>This session at Percona Live ONLINE was presented by Akshay Suryawanshi, Senior Production Engineer at Shopify, and Jeremy Cole, Senior Staff Production Engineer - Datastores at Shopify. Shopify is an online and on-premise commerce platform, founded in 2006.
Shopify is used by more than a million merchants, and hundreds of billions of dollars of sales have happened on the platform since its inception. The company is a large user of MySQL, and the Black Friday and Cyber Monday weekends are their peak dates during the year, handling hundreds of billions of queries with MySQL.</description></item><item><title>A First Look at Amazon RDS Proxy</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/07/a-first-look-at-amazon-rds-proxy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 11:45:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/07/a-first-look-at-amazon-rds-proxy/</guid><description>At re:Invent in Las Vegas in December 2019, AWS announced the public preview of RDS Proxy, a fully managed database proxy that sits between your application and RDS. The new service offers to &amp;ldquo;share established database connections, improving database efficiency and application scalability&amp;rdquo;.
But one of the benefits that caught my eye is the ability to reduce the downtime in case of an instance failure and a failover. As for the announcement:</description></item><item><title>Tame Kubernetes with These Open-Source Tools</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/08/tame-kubernetes-with-open-source-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 13:03:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/08/tame-kubernetes-with-open-source-tools/</guid><description>Kubernetes’ popularity as the most-preferred open-source container-orchestration system has skyrocketed in the recent past. The overall container market is expected to cross USD 2.7 billion by 2020 with a CAGR of 40 percent. Three orchestrators spearhead this upward trend, namely Kubernetes, Mesos, and Docker Swarm. However, referring to the graph below, Kubernetes clearly leads the pack.
source: https://medium.com/@rdodev/saved-you-an-analyst-read-on-kubernetes-growth-2018-edition-810367876981 
The automation and infrastructural capabilities of Kubernetes are transforming the DevOps space, thereby enhancing the value of the business through software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: Need for speed - Boosting Apache Cassandra's performance using Netty</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/22/percona-live-europe-presents-need-speed-boosting-apache-cassandras-performance-using-netty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 08:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/22/percona-live-europe-presents-need-speed-boosting-apache-cassandras-performance-using-netty/</guid><description>My talk is titled Need for speed: Boosting Apache Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s performance using Netty. Over the years that I have worked in the software industry, making code run fast has fascinated me. So, naturally when I first started contributing to Apache Cassandra, I started looking opportunities to improve its performance. My talk takes us through some interesting challenges within a distributed system like Apache Cassandra and various techniques to significantly improve its performance.</description></item><item><title>Deploying MySQL on Kubernetes with a Percona-based Operator</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:03:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</guid><description>In the context of providing managed WordPress hosting services, at Presslabs we operate with lots of small to medium-sized databases, in a DB-per-service model, as we call it. The workloads are mostly reads, so we need to efficiently scale that. The MySQL® asynchronous replication model fits the bill very well, allowing us to scale horizontally from one server—with the obvious availability pitfalls—to tens of nodes. The next release of the stack is going to be open-sourced.</description></item><item><title>How to Automate Minor Version Upgrades for MySQL on RDS</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/07/10/automate-minor-version-upgrades-mysql-rds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:19:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/07/10/automate-minor-version-upgrades-mysql-rds/</guid><description>Amazon RDS for MySQL offers the option to automate minor version upgrades using the minor version upgrade policy, a property that lets you decide if Amazon is allowed to perform the upgrades on your behalf. Usually the goal is not to upgrade automatically every RDS instance but to keep up to date automatically non-production deployments. This helps you address engine issues as soon as possible and improve the automation of the deployment process.</description></item></channel></rss>