<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Toolkit on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/categories/toolkit/</link><description>Recent content in Toolkit on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/categories/toolkit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Bug Report: April 2025</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/05/19/percona-bug-report-april-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/05/19/percona-bug-report-april-2025/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Join Us Online: Stream About Percona Toolkit for MySQL!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/03/14/join-us-online-stream-about-percona-toolkit-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/03/14/join-us-online-stream-about-percona-toolkit-for-mysql/</guid><description>Are you passionate about databases and want to stay on top of the latest advancements in MySQL and Percona Toolkit? You&amp;rsquo;re in luck! We are excited to invite you to our upcoming online stream, where we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into some exciting changes and updates.
Date: March 27, 2025
Time: 13:30 GMT / 9:30 ET
Streaming Live on: LinkedIn and YouTube
About the Event Our featured speaker, Sveta Smirnova, Principal Support Engineering Coordinator at Percona, will share her insights on the recent updates in MySQL, focusing on the removal of offensive replication statements like START/STOP SLAVE.</description></item><item><title>MySQL 8.4 Support in Percona Toolkit 3.7.0</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/06/mysql-8.4-support-in-percona-toolkit-3.7.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/06/mysql-8.4-support-in-percona-toolkit-3.7.0/</guid><description>Percona Toolkit 3.7.0 has been released on Dec 23, 2024. The main feature of this release is MySQL 8.4 support.
In this blog, I will explain what has been changed. A full list of improvements and bug fixes can be found in the release notes.
TLDR;
Replication statements in 8.4 are fully supported by the Percona Toolkit pt-slave-delay has been deprecated. pt-slave-find has been renamed to pt-replica-find. The old name has been deprecated but exists in the repository as an alias of the pt-replica-find.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: October 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: April 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: January 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/19/percona-bug-report-january-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/02/19/percona-bug-report-january-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we believe that transparency is key to improving our products. We are dedicated to creating top-of-the-line open-source database solutions and providing support for any issues that may arise. We encourage feedback and bug reports to help us continually improve.
We stay updated on bug reports through our own platform as well as other sources to ensure we have the most up-to-date information. To make it easier for you, we have compiled a central list of the most critical bugs for your reference in this edition of our bug report.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: November 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/12/19/percona-bug-report-november-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/12/19/percona-bug-report-november-2023/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Percona University in Peru 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Peru is a country in South America home to a section of the Amazon rainforest and Machu Picchu ⛰️, an ancient Incan city high in the Andes mountains. Percona decided to hold the first event of Percona University 2023 in Lima, the capital of Peru, on June 10.
Percona University is a series of free technical events organized by Percona in various cities around the world since 2013. Percona uses these events to share its unbiased expertise on open source databases with the community, users, and organizations.</description></item><item><title>Lets be inSync!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/22/lets-be-insync/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/22/lets-be-insync/</guid><description>Percona Toolkit + pt-table-checksum + pt-table-sync = Faster Replica Recovery Asynchronous replication with MySQL is a tried and true technology. Add the use of GTID’s and you have a very stable solution.
The fundamental issue with async replication is that writes sent to the Replica are not guaranteed to be written. I have only seen a handful of times when writes did not get applied to the replica. Most of the time this happens is due to network packet drops or a replica crashes before new data is committed.</description></item><item><title>Zero downtime schema change with Liquibase &amp; Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/26/zero-downtime-schema-change-with-liquibase-percona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 14:14:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/26/zero-downtime-schema-change-with-liquibase-percona/</guid><description>I am always surprised to learn something new whenever I talk to a member of the open-source community. No matter how much I think I have heard of every use case there is for Liquibase (and database change management in general), I always hear something that makes this space still feel new. There’s always something left to discover.
Today, that new something is the problem of how to perform large batches of changes with SQL ALTER TABLE statements.</description></item><item><title>How to Build a Percona Server "Stack" on a Raspberry Pi 3+</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 12:50:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</guid><description>The blog post How to Compile Percona Server for MySQL 5.7 in Raspberry Pi 3 by Walter Garcia, inspired me to create an updated install of Percona Server for the Raspberry Pi 3+.
This how-to post covers installing from source and being able to use Percona Server for MySQL in any of your maker projects. I have included everything you need to have a complete Percona Server, ready to store data collection for your weather station, your GPS data, or any other project you can think of that would require data collection in a database.</description></item><item><title>Character Sets: Migrating to utf8mb4 with pt_online_schema_change</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/12/character-sets-migrating-utf8mb4-pt_online_schema_change/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 11:27:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/12/character-sets-migrating-utf8mb4-pt_online_schema_change/</guid><description>Modern applications often feature the use of data in many different languages. This is often true even of applications that only offer a user facing interface in a single language. Many users may, for example, need to enter names which, although using Latin characters, feature diacritics; in other cases, they may need to enter text which contains Chinese or Japanese characters. Even if a user is capable of using an application localized for only one language, it may be necessary to deal with data from a wide variety of languages.</description></item></channel></rss>