<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VictoriaMetrics on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/victoriametrics/</link><description>Recent content in VictoriaMetrics on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/victoriametrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optimizing the Storage of Large Volumes of Metrics for a Long Time in VictoriaMetrics</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/02/long-time-keeping-metrics-victoriametrics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/06/02/long-time-keeping-metrics-victoriametrics/</guid><description>Introduction Nowadays, the main tools for monitoring the operation of any application are metrics and logs. An important role is played by the time of their storage. Often, in order to understand certain processes and predict their development in the future, we need to analyze metrics over a fairly long period of time. In the case, when the project is just starting, their volume is relatively small, but over time it becomes larger and larger and there is a need for optimization.</description></item><item><title>How long do you keep the metrics in PMM?</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/02/11/poll-metrics-keep/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/02/11/poll-metrics-keep/</guid><description>Hello everyone! We are indeed excited to announce that the new release of VictoriaMetrics has many exciting features, one of them being downsampling.
Downsampling helps to reduce disk space usage and improves query performance in a big and long time series if applied independently per each time series. However, this feature works only with a large number of samples per series.
As we are keen on implementing downsampling in our future releases, we would like to understand how long you keep your metrics in PMM.</description></item><item><title>How do We Keep Metrics for a Long Time in VictoriaMetrics</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-anton-bystrov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-anton-bystrov/</guid><description>This session is presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
What is VictoriaMetrics? Why we choose it. Some data to compare VM and Prometheus. What is TSDB? How tuneup VM to prevent crashes. What is deduplication, dawnsampling. How does it work?
Check out the full schedule of Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022</description></item></channel></rss>