<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/</link><description>Recent content on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Articles about Percona products</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/articles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/articles/</guid><description>Thank you to users of our products, customers, communities, and authors for your research, studies, reviews, and articles. If you wrote a post abour Percona product, feel free to add it on this page with the Edit this page on GitHub button below. We would love to see it and send you a piece of Swag!
MySQL Migration from HBase to MyRocks at Quora - Vamsi Ponnekanti - September 14, 2021 Percona Toolkit | Altering large MySQL tables with no locks Ultimate Guide 2021 Update - David Shen - March 2, 2021 Percona Series / Zero downtime migration from 5.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/coc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/coc/</guid><description>Percona Community is a community around developing, installing, running, optimizing, learning everything around databases and the needed infrastructure.
The ABCs Assume good intentions. Be nice to each other - being civil and respectful goes a long way. Criticize code, tools, other types of contributions, and situations - not people and their personalities. Rules We respect all members of the Percona Community - that involves everyone’s contributions in code, text, visuals, and chat.</description></item><item><title>Open Topics: Blog, Talks, Guides</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/opentopics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/opentopics/</guid><description>You can find our list of topics here. We are excited to hear back from you if you would like to speak on any of these topics at a conference or meetup, or if you are interested in creating content such as blog posts, guides, videos, podcasts, or whatever else you can think of.
Databases Automate your database setup for production in under x hours Backup and disaster recovery strategies Failure stories DevOps Database Reliability Engineering (DBRE) Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) Monitoring and SLAs Useful scripts for production Testing and QA Distributed Computing Consensus algorithms and implementations Synchronous and asynchronous replication - advantages, disadvantages, implementations How-Tos Moving from a single node to a cluster setup (any DB engine) Batch processing Stream processing Metrics Measure your open source project success Bug squashing dong right Open Source Licensing Vendor lock-in Let us know on Discord or via e-mail to community-team@percona.</description></item></channel></rss>