<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/</link><description>Recent content on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Articles about Percona products</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/articles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/articles/</guid><description>Thank you to users of our products, customers, communities, and authors for your research, studies, reviews, and articles. If you wrote a post abour Percona product, feel free to add it on this page with the Edit this page on GitHub button below. We would love to see it and send you a piece of Swag!
MySQL Percona Xtrabackup Backup &amp;amp; Recovery - Satya - February 10, 2022 Installation &amp;amp; Usage of Percona Toolkit 3 - Satya - January 28, 2022 ProxySQL 2 configuration/installation - Satya - January 5, 2022 [Installing Percona XtraDB Cluster (PXC) 8](Installing Percona XtraDB Cluster (PXC) 8) - Satya - August 20, 2021 Upgrading MySQL at Shopify - Yi Qing Sim - December 2, 2021 Mitigating MySQL Downtime for big migrations - Ashutosh Mittal - November 20, 2021 Migration from HBase to MyRocks at Quora - Vamsi Ponnekanti - September 14, 2021 Scaling WordPress to Handle the Largest WordPress Virtual Conference - Tom Fanelli - April 5, 2021 Percona Toolkit | Altering large MySQL tables with no locks Ultimate Guide 2021 Update - David Shen - March 2, 2021 Percona Series / Zero downtime migration from 5.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/coc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/coc/</guid><description>Percona Community is a community around developing, installing, running, optimizing, learning everything around databases and the needed infrastructure.
The ABCs Assume good intentions. Be nice to each other - being civil and respectful goes a long way. Criticize code, tools, other types of contributions, and situations - not people and their personalities. Rules We respect all members of the Percona Community - that involves everyone’s contributions in code, text, visuals, and chat.</description></item><item><title>Help Wanted</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/help-wanted/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/help-wanted/</guid><description>Want to contribute to open source and earn a valuable gift from Percona? Help us with the most wanted content and code, and join the ranks of contributors. On this page, we gathered some tasks that we offer you to accomplish. In exchange for that, you will gain not only the feeling of belonging to the big open source community, but also get some enjoyable gift from Percona Community Team. Just contact us at community-team@percona.</description></item><item><title>Open Topics: Blog, Talks, Guides</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/opentopics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/opentopics/</guid><description>You can find our list of topics here. We are excited to hear back from you if you would like to speak on any of these topics at a conference or meetup, or if you are interested in creating content such as blog posts, guides, videos, podcasts, or whatever else you can think of.
Databases Automate your database setup for production in under x hours Backup and disaster recovery strategies Failure stories DevOps Database Reliability Engineering (DBRE) Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) Monitoring and SLAs Useful scripts for production Testing and QA Distributed Computing Consensus algorithms and implementations Synchronous and asynchronous replication - advantages, disadvantages, implementations How-Tos Moving from a single node to a cluster setup (any DB engine) Batch processing Stream processing Metrics Measure your open source project success Bug squashing dong right Open Source Licensing Vendor lock-in Let us know on Discord or via e-mail to community-team@percona.</description></item><item><title>Testimonials &amp; Surveys</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/testimonials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/testimonials/</guid><description>Testimonials Share your story with us! Together we will build a strong community and take it to the next level.
Just complete this simple form. It is short and will take no more than 5-8 minutes of your time.
Let&amp;#39;s start How often are you among like-minded people? How often do you feel that you are understood, and you have something to discuss?
We want everyone who use Percona software to feel supported by people who share common attitudes, interests, and goals.</description></item><item><title>Videos</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/videos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/videos/</guid><description>Videos about Percona created by the community
Events Set Your Long Query Time in MySQL - Monitoring MySQL Database Tutorial
Marcos Albe (Percona), Matt Yonkovit (Percona) - May 5, 2022
Tuning MySQL with PMM Pt 1 - MySQL Database tuning tutorial
Marcos Albe (Percona), Matt Yonkovit (Percona) - May 4, 2022
Installing PMM on Rocky Linux Server - Monitoring Database tutorial</description></item><item><title>YouTube Playlists</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/youtube_playlists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/youtube_playlists/</guid><description>Learn From the Leading Database Experts Talks and Share Your Knowledge With Others Here we gathered together videos with talks, webinars and tutorials from Percona experts and community members about Percona software. They are organized in YouTube playlists.
Help us expand this knowledgebase! Share and like videos, participate in live streams, record your own video tutorials and send them to us.
Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp;amp; Chat</description></item></channel></rss>