<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/</link><description>Recent content on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/contribute/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Articles About Percona Software</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/articles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/articles/</guid><description>Thank you to users of our products, customers, communities, and authors for your research, studies, reviews, and articles. If you wrote a post abour Percona product, feel free to add it on this page with the Edit this page on GitHub button below. We would love to see it and send you a piece of Swag!
MySQL Oracle Support for MySQL 5.7 Ends Soon, Key Upgrades in 8.0 - Jelani Harper - May 30, 2023 Are you planning ahead for the MySQL 5.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/coc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/coc/</guid><description>Percona Community is a community around developing, installing, running, optimizing, learning everything around databases and the needed infrastructure.
The ABCs Assume good intentions. Be nice to each other - being civil and respectful goes a long way. Criticize code, tools, other types of contributions, and situations - not people and their personalities. Rules We respect all members of the Percona Community - that involves everyone’s contributions in code, text, visuals, and chat.</description></item><item><title>Developer Artifacts and Useful Repositories</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/dev/</guid><description>Here you can find useful artifacts from the community related to Percona software. This is a collection of tools and repositories that ease the life of the engineer working with PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management) and other Percona products. We really hope that you will like them. Feel free to add yours to the list and share them with the community!
We welcome:
Custom PMM dashboards Advisors Ansible/Terraform/other IaaC code to deploy and manage Percona products Other stuff that you use as a developer/DBA with Percona products PMM Awesome PMM - A curated list of awesome Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) free and open-source software, libraries and resources.</description></item><item><title>Get Involved</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/how-to-get-involved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/how-to-get-involved/</guid><description>All of Percona&amp;rsquo;s software is open source, which means we accept and value contributions. We also know that open source is more than code, so we emphasize all kinds of contributions, including:
Writing a blog post Answering questions on the Percona Forum Creating a video tutorial or giving a talk on how to use Percona software Contributing to documentation Submitting and helping close bug reports Ready to join the ranks of contributors?</description></item><item><title>Open Topics: Blog, Talks, Guides</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/opentopics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/opentopics/</guid><description>Open Topics: Blog, Talks, Guides You can find our list of topics here. We are excited to hear from you if you would like to speak on any of these topics at a conference or meetup, or if you are interested in creating content such as blog posts, guides, videos, podcasts, or whatever else you can think of.
Databases Automate your database setup for production in under x hours Backup and disaster recovery strategies Failure stories DevOps Database Reliability Engineering (DBRE) Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) Monitoring and SLAs Useful scripts for production Testing and QA Distributed Computing Consensus algorithms and implementations Synchronous and asynchronous replication - advantages, disadvantages, implementations How-Tos Moving from a single node to a cluster setup (any DB engine) Batch processing Stream processing Metrics Measure your open source project success Bug squashing done right Open Source Licensing Vendor lock-in Let us know via e-mail to community-team@percona.</description></item><item><title>Reviews</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/reviews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/reviews/</guid><description>Reviewer Product Platform Date Anonymous (Administrator) Percona Server for MongoDB G2 2022-01-28 Anonymous (-) Percona XtraDB Cluster Reviews Capterra 2022-01-25 Anshika Gupta (Mykare) Percona Server for MySQL Capterra 2022-02-03 Anonymous (-) Percona Server for MySQL G2 2022-02-21 Anonymous (Head of Data Services) Percona Distribution for PostgreSQL Sourceforge 2022-03-15 Anonymous (DBA) Percona XtraBackup Sourceforge 2022-03-15 SelvaKumar KuppuSamy (ReadyNetworks) Percona Server for MySQL Sourceforge 2022-03-19 SelvaKumar K. (Data Architect) Percona Backup for MongoDB Sourceforge 2022-03-19 Warren R.</description></item><item><title>Testimonials &amp; Surveys</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/testimonials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/testimonials/</guid><description>Testimonials Share your story with us! Together we will build a strong community and take it to the next level.
Just complete this simple form. It is short and will take no more than 5-8 minutes of your time.
Let&amp;#39;s start How often are you among like-minded people? How often do you feel that you are understood, and you have something to discuss?
We want everyone who use Percona software to feel supported by people who share common attitudes, interests, and goals.</description></item><item><title>Videos</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/videos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/videos/</guid><description>Here you can find various videos about Percona software created by the community. We gather together a wide range of educational content - from presentations by Percona speakers on different online events to videos recorded by database lovers and published on their YouTube channels. If you recorded such a video or just found an interesting one and would like to see it posted here, just send it to us at community-team@percona.</description></item><item><title>YouTube Playlists</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/youtube_playlists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/youtube_playlists/</guid><description>Learn From the Leading Database Experts Talks and Share Your Knowledge With Others Here we gathered together videos with talks, webinars and tutorials from Percona experts and community members about Percona software. They are organized in YouTube playlists.
Help us expand this knowledgebase! Share and like videos, participate in live streams, record your own video tutorials and send them to us.
Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp;amp; Chat PLAY ALL</description></item></channel></rss>