<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>edith_puclla on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/edith_puclla/</link><description>Recent content in edith_puclla on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/edith_puclla/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our Top Picks from the Kubernetes 1.29 Release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/12/our-top-picks-from-the-kubernetes-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/12/our-top-picks-from-the-kubernetes-release/</guid><description>The latest Kubernetes version, 1.29, was released on December 13th 2023. Inspired by the Mandala and symbolizing universal perfection, it concludes the 2023 release calendar. This version comes with various exciting improvements, many of which will be helpful for users who run databases on Kubernetes.
Figure 1 - Mandala created in Excalidraw, not perfectly symmetrical.
Here, we highlight this latest release&amp;rsquo;s four key features and improvements. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at them together.</description></item><item><title>Data on Kubernetes Community initiatives: Automated storage scaling</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/data-on-kubernetes-community-initiatives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/data-on-kubernetes-community-initiatives/</guid><description>In the world of Kubernetes, where everything evolves quickly. Automated storage scaling stands out as a critical challenge. Members of the Data on Kubernetes Community have proposed a solution to address this issue for Kubernetes operators.
If, like me, this is your first time hearing about Automated storage scaling, this will help you understand it better:
Storage scaling in Kubernetes Operators refers to the ability of an application running on Kubernetes to adjust its storage capacity automatically based on demand.</description></item><item><title>Volunteering as a Program Committee Member for Data on Kubernetes Day Europe 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/volunteering-program-committee-data-kubernetes-europe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/volunteering-program-committee-data-kubernetes-europe/</guid><description>The Data on Kubernetes Day Europe 2024 Program Committee is a group of professionals and experts responsible for organizing the Data on Kubernetes Day Europe 2024 content for the upcoming co-located events at Kubecon in Paris on 19 March.
As Data on Kubernetes community members, Sergey Pronin (Group Product Manager at @Percona) and I (Tech Evangelist) volunteered to evaluate proposal topics submitted for the event through the Sessionize platform. Not only us but also many other members of the Data on Kubernetes community participated as volunteers.</description></item></channel></rss>