<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raspberry Pi on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/raspberry-pi/</link><description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Raspberry Pi Bullseye Percona Server 64bit</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/05/percona-server-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>I love the Raspberry Pi, and I love Percona server. The combination of the two can provide a nice home database. I have been running a Percona Server database since 2019 to hold all the weather information, that I collect from several of my Weather Stations.
I did a my first blog post on installing Percona Server 5.7 on the Raspberry Pi 3+.
You can read that blog post here: How to Build a Percona Server &amp;ldquo;Stack&amp;rdquo; on a Raspberry Pi 3+</description></item><item><title>How to Build a Percona Server "Stack" on a Raspberry Pi 3+</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 12:50:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</guid><description>The blog post How to Compile Percona Server for MySQL 5.7 in Raspberry Pi 3 by Walter Garcia, inspired me to create an updated install of Percona Server for the Raspberry Pi 3+.
This how-to post covers installing from source and being able to use Percona Server for MySQL in any of your maker projects. I have included everything you need to have a complete Percona Server, ready to store data collection for your weather station, your GPS data, or any other project you can think of that would require data collection in a database.</description></item></channel></rss>