<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data on Kubernetes Track on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/</link><description>Recent content in Data on Kubernetes Track on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Open Source Powers the Modern Data Stack</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/5/</guid><description>Michel Tricot - Airbyte - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
In this talk, we’ll describe how you can leverage 3 open-source standards - workflow management with Aifrow, EL with Airbyte, transformation with DBT - to build your organization&amp;rsquo;s modern data stack.
We’ll explain how to configure your Aifrow DAG to trigger Airbyte’s data replication jobs and DBT’s transformations with a concrete use case.</description></item><item><title>Towards a K8s Native Streaming Application</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/4/</guid><description>Jérémy Frénay (Babylon Health) and Francesco Nobilia (Nutmeg) - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
Starting from a simple application which can be deployed in every machine running Docker, we will go through all steps required to transform the simple app into a Kubernetes native streaming application. We will explain the theory and then exemplify the learnt concepts to dene a recipe for running streaming applications on Kubernetes. We will focus both on cultural and technical tricks to help you successfully adopt streaming applications at scale.</description></item><item><title>Wrangling Data to Multiple Places With Fluent Bit</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/3/</guid><description>Anurag Gupta - Calyptia - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
As more and more users move to Kubernetes they also may start using multiple backends and analytic tools. How do you collect once and send everywhere? In this talk, Anurag will talk about a Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) graduated project Fluent Bit and how you can collect once, and send to all the backends you want. Additionally, Anurag will discuss some of Fluent Bit&amp;rsquo;s advanced capabilities such as enrichment, parsing, and data reduction that helps users get the most out of their backends.</description></item><item><title>Everything You Ever Wanted To Know About Databases but Were Too Afraid To Ask</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/2/</guid><description>Dr Gavin Mendel - TerminusDb - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
The talk does exactly what it says on the tin - everything you want to know about databases from somebody with decades of experience implementing, architecting, and building databases. Gavin will talk through the way he currently thinks about implementation - the problems he most cares about - and then will open up to your questions! In the absence of Stonebreaker, nobody is better placed to answer database Q&amp;amp;A.</description></item><item><title>Native Chaos Engineering in Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/1/</guid><description>Karthik Satchitanand - ChaosNative - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
Chaos Engineering is revolutionizing testing means and doing it the cloud-native way is the best way in today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly changing world with a huge shift in the paradigm of Kubernetes resiliency. Karthik S, one of the maintainers for LitmusChaos would be introducing how to carry out Chaos Engineering, the cloud-native way. Further, he will touch upon how Chaos Engineering is carried out in Cloud-Native Databases with LitmusChaos.</description></item></channel></rss>