<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/authors/timur_solodovnikov/</link><description>Recent content on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 13:34:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/authors/timur_solodovnikov/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Impact of innodb_file_per_table Option On Crash Recovery Time</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/23/impact-of-innodb_file_per_table-option-on-crash-recovery-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 13:34:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/23/impact-of-innodb_file_per_table-option-on-crash-recovery-time/</guid><description>Starting at version MySQL5.6+ by default innodb_file_per_table is enabled and all data is stored in separate tablespaces. It provides some advantages.
I will highlight some of them:
You can reclaim disk space when truncating or dropping a table stored in a file-per-table tablespace. Truncating or dropping tables stored in the shared system tablespace creates free space internally in the system tablespace data files (ibdata files) which can only be used for new InnoDB data.</description></item><item><title>Easy and Effective Way of Building External Dictionaries for ClickHouse with Pentaho Data Integration Tool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</guid><description>In this post, I provide an illustration of how to use Pentaho Data Integration (PDI) tool to set up external dictionaries in MySQL to support ClickHouse. Although I use MySQL in this example, you can use any PDI supported source.
ClickHouse ClickHouse is an open-source column-oriented DBMS (columnar database management system) for online analytical processing. Source: wiki.
Pentaho Data Integration Information from the Pentaho wiki: Pentaho Data Integration (PDI, also called Kettle) is the component of Pentaho responsible for the Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) processes.</description></item></channel></rss>