<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Google Community Track on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/</link><description>Recent content in Google Community Track on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying Highly Available PostgreSQL With GKE</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/4/</guid><description>Christoph Bussler and Shashank Agarwal - Google - Percona Live 2021
When you have an application running in Google Kubernetes Engine, there are multiple options and considerations for how to deploy a database. In this session, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn some of the architectural considerations for choosing a database deployment option in GKE. We will demonstrate one of these options, as you learn how to configure PostgreSQL as a container in GKE based on regional persistent disks and PersistentVolumeClaims.</description></item><item><title>How To Choose the Right Solution When Lifting and Shifting Your Database to the Cloud</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/3/</guid><description>Shachar Guz - Google - Percona Live 2021
Database migrations can be complex, time-consuming, and costly, increasing the risk of moving to the cloud. Enterprises need effective and reliable database migration tools that help automate this process for seamless cloud adoption. In this session, we will elaborate on the considerations to take into account when choosing database migration methods and technology, and the different aspects that can impact risk such as migration fidelity and downtime.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying Database Performance Issues With SQL Commenter and Cloud SQL Insights</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/2/</guid><description>Jan Kleinert - Google - Percona Live 2021
Have you ever tried to troubleshoot a database performance issue in an application that was built using an ORM? ORMs can simplify development of applications that communicate with databases, but since the ORMs are generating the SQL statements, it can be difficult to determine which application code is resulting in slow queries.
SQL Commenter is an open source library that enables ORMs to augment SQL statements with comments about the code that caused its execution, making it easier to correlate your application code with the SQL statements that were generated by the ORM.</description></item><item><title>Working Effectively with Cloud SQL on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/1/</guid><description>Eno Compton - Google - Percona Live 2021
There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like about Kubernetes and Cloud SQL, but it&amp;rsquo;s not always clear how to use them together. This talk will be a deep-dive into Cloud SQL and how to work with it effectively on Kubernetes. The talk will be developer-centric and will start with the basics of connecting to Cloud SQL from Kubernetes. It will include how to run load tests and then size an instance.</description></item></channel></rss>