<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Gravity on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/data-gravity/</link><description>Recent content in Data Gravity on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/data-gravity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Gravity Episode 3 - benny Vasquez - AlmaLinux Project and the Future of Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-3/</guid><description>In this episode, Joe Brockmeier interviews benny Vasquez of the AlmaLinux Project to discuss open source data, the future of databases, and how databases and Linux distros go together.
Episode 3 Link
All Data Gravity Podcast Episodes</description></item><item><title>Data Gravity Podcast</title><link>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/</guid><description>Data Gravity Podcast Data Gravity is Percona’s community podcast about open data topics. Percona’s Head of Community Joe Brockmeier invites recognized open source experts to talk all things related to open source databases, open source database tools, and open data. He talks to open source contributors, database practitioners, users, and other experts working with MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and other open source databases and tools. You can find all episodes on Podbean and on this page.</description></item><item><title>Data Gravity Episode 2 - Sonia Valeja and David Gonzalez - PostgreSQL for Jobseekers Book</title><link>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-2/</guid><description>In this episode, Joe Brockmeier talks to Percona&amp;rsquo;s Sonia Valeja and David Gonzalez, about their recent book PostgreSQL for Jobseekers. They talk about the inspiration for the book, why they focus on jobseekers, and what&amp;rsquo;s covered in the title.
Episode 2 Page
All Data Gravity Podcast Episodes</description></item><item><title>Data Gravity Episode 1 - Charles Thompson - Dolphie, a Real-Time MySQL Monitoring Assistant</title><link>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/data-gravity/data-gravity-episode-1/</guid><description>In this episode, Joe Brockmeier talks to Charles Thompson, creator of Dolphie - a real-time MySQL monitoring assistant that&amp;rsquo;s open source and available for multiple platforms. He talks about creating Dolphie, how it fits into the MySQL monitoring space, and more.
Episode 1 Link
All Data Gravity Podcast Episodes</description></item></channel></rss>