<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Containers on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/containers/</link><description>Recent content in Containers on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:16:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/containers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona on June 4th, 2020!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</guid><description>Long months of the pandemic lockdown have brought to life many great online events enabling the MySQL community to get together and stay informed about the very recent developments and innovations available to MySQL users. It isn’t over yet! Next Thursday, June 4th, Percona &amp;amp; ProxySQL are co-hosting the ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona virtual meetup covering ProxySQL, MySQL and Percona XtraDB Cluster.
The attendees are invited to participate in the two-hour deep-dive event with plenty of time for questions and answers (we will have two 40-minute sessions + 20 minutes allocated for Q&amp;amp;A).</description></item><item><title>Deploying MySQL on Kubernetes with a Percona-based Operator</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 17:03:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/11/deploying-mysql-on-kubernetes-with-a-percona-based-operator/</guid><description>In the context of providing managed WordPress hosting services, at Presslabs we operate with lots of small to medium-sized databases, in a DB-per-service model, as we call it. The workloads are mostly reads, so we need to efficiently scale that. The MySQL® asynchronous replication model fits the bill very well, allowing us to scale horizontally from one server—with the obvious availability pitfalls—to tens of nodes. The next release of the stack is going to be open-sourced.</description></item></channel></rss>