<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>author_dinesh on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/author_dinesh/</link><description>Recent content in author_dinesh on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:20:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/author_dinesh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The State of Databases in 2019</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</guid><description>At this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live I am talking about The State of Databases in 2019. As a Software Engineer in the thick of the Database landscape, there are two problems that I see repeatedly.
Due to the massive explosion of database solutions, it has become very difficult to evaluate what database solution will serve the best for one’s use case, and
The constant tug of war between database operators and users.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: Need for speed - Boosting Apache Cassandra's performance using Netty</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/22/percona-live-europe-presents-need-speed-boosting-apache-cassandras-performance-using-netty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 08:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/22/percona-live-europe-presents-need-speed-boosting-apache-cassandras-performance-using-netty/</guid><description>My talk is titled Need for speed: Boosting Apache Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s performance using Netty. Over the years that I have worked in the software industry, making code run fast has fascinated me. So, naturally when I first started contributing to Apache Cassandra, I started looking opportunities to improve its performance. My talk takes us through some interesting challenges within a distributed system like Apache Cassandra and various techniques to significantly improve its performance.</description></item></channel></rss>