<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>perconalive on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/perconalive/</link><description>Recent content in perconalive on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/perconalive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Quick Guide To Austin For Percona Live 2022 Attendees</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/11/percona-live-austin-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/11/percona-live-austin-guide/</guid><description>Percona Live returns again to Austin May 16th through the 18th will find the city vibrant, charming, and weird. The semi-official motto for the city is ‘Keep Austin Weird’ and during your visit you will indeed see many of the residents working hard to do just that. Not in a bad way. Austin is at the intersection of so many cultural, artistic, and lifestyle modes that there are a fair amount of many different things happening at the same time to ensure that any dull moments you have will have to be an active choice on your part.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.5 New Features for Troubleshooting – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/mariadb-10-5-new-features-for-troubleshooting-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/mariadb-10-5-new-features-for-troubleshooting-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Aug • New York 12:00 midnight • London 05:00 a.m. • New Delhi 9:30 a.m. • Singapore 12:00 noon
Abstract I want to help DBAs and Support engineers find out what&amp;rsquo;s really going on when some problem strikes. My goal is to show new ways to diagnose problems now available in MariaDB 10.5. See the full abstract for more.
Why Is Your Talk Exciting?</description></item><item><title>Are your Database Backups Good Enough?</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</guid><description>In the last few years there have been several examples of major service problems affecting businesses data: outages causing data inconsistencies; unavailability or data loss, and worldwide cyberattacks encrypting your files and asking for a ransom.
Database-related incidents are a very common industry issue- even if the root cause is not the database system itself. No matter if your main relational system is MySQL, MariaDB, PostgresQL or AWS Aurora -there will be a time where you will need to make use of backups to recover to a previous state.</description></item></channel></rss>