<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in Docker on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning Kubernetes Operators with Percona Operator for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>One of the topics that have resonated a lot for me since the first KubeCon I attended in 2018 is Kubernetes Operators.
The concept of Operators was introduced much earlier in 2016 by the CoreOS Linux development team. They were looking for a way to improve automated container management in Kubernetes.
What do we mean by a Kubernetes Operator? We use the definition of CNCF. The Kubernetes project defines “Operator” simply: “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components“.</description></item><item><title>Running PMM with Docker on Ubuntu 20.04</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</guid><description>I started at Percona a few weeks ago and was looking for a quick way to learn about PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management), which is one of my favorite technologies within Percona to monitor the health of our database infrastructure, explore new patterns in the database behavior, manage and improve the performance of our databases, all with customizable dashboards and real-time alerts using Grafana and VictoriaMetrics.
The best of all is that PMM is Open Source, you can check the PMM repository in case you want to contribute.</description></item><item><title>How to replace `docker` with `podman` for PMM development</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/27/replace-docker-with-podman-for-pmm-dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/27/replace-docker-with-podman-for-pmm-dev/</guid><description>What is Podman? Podman is a daemonless container engine for developing, managing, and running OCI (Open Container Initiative) Containers on your Linux System. Containers can either be run as root or in rootless mode. More details here.
Check out also Kubernetes Podcast to learn more about podman and listen to it&amp;rsquo;s creators.
Why to replace? Especially in development I need simplest possible solution, I don&amp;rsquo;t need additional daemon running or allowing something to run with elevated privileges.</description></item><item><title>Cassandra Where and How by John Schulz</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</guid><description>If Percona Live ONLINE had graded its talks by skill level this year, John Schulz’s talk would have been essential viewing in the Beginners track. (You can watch all the event’s presentations now on Percona’s YouTube channel.) This talk was a good overview and meant for anyone who had heard of the Apache Cassandra distributed database but wasn’t sure whether it would be suitable for their project or not.
Database-veteran, John Schulz has been tinkering with Cassandra for about a decade and to help anyone get started he gave a whistle-stop tour of the Cassandra ecosystem.</description></item></channel></rss>