<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in Docker on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>​My Experience at Kubecon Europe in Amsterdam</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/11/experience-at-kubecon-europe-in-amsterdam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/11/experience-at-kubecon-europe-in-amsterdam/</guid><description>Kubecon is the most significant event focused on the Kubernetes ecosystem. It takes place once a year in North America, Europe, and Asia. It is a perfect opportunity to learn from experts, meet friends, grow your network, and attend talks at a varied technical level and meetings focused on CNCF communities. This time I attended Kubecon in Amsterdam. The theme for this version of Kubecon was: community-in-bloom because we are still healing from COVID, and people are getting back to feeling comfortable participating in events.</description></item><item><title>How To Optimize the Structure of a Simple PHP Application as Your Project Grows</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/28/how-to-optimize-the-structure-of-a-simple-php-application-as-your-project-grows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/28/how-to-optimize-the-structure-of-a-simple-php-application-as-your-project-grows/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss the structure of our simple PHP application, folders, files, and functions and transform the project to grow it.
You and I have developed a small PHP application that makes an HTTP request to the GitHub API and stores the result in the database.
Step 1 - How to Develop a Simple Web Application Using Docker-compose, Nginx, PHP 8, and MongoDB 6. Step 2 - How to Make HTTP Requests to API in PHP App Using GitHub API Example and Write to Percona Server for MongoDB.</description></item><item><title>How to Make HTTP Requests to API in PHP App Using GitHub API Example and Write to Percona Server for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/how-to-make-http-requests-to-api-in-php-app-using-github-api-example-and-write-to-percona-server-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/20/how-to-make-http-requests-to-api-in-php-app-using-github-api-example-and-write-to-percona-server-for-mongodb/</guid><description>We learn how to work with HTTP requests in PHP and make API requests using the GitHub API as an example. We&amp;rsquo;ll get the data from the API and save it to the database.
In the previous article, we developed a simple application that connects to the MongoDB database (Percona Server for MongoDB) and writes documents in a loop. We only used Composer packages to work with MongoDB. We have set up the Docker-compose environment and have the app/ directory where the application code is located.</description></item><item><title>How to Develop a Simple Web Application Using Docker, Nginx, PHP, and Percona Server for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/03/17/how-to-develop-a-simple-web-application-using-docker-nginx-php-and-percona-server-for-mongodb/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m developing an application that takes data from different sources, processes it, and prepares reports. In this series of articles, I will explain how to install and configure the tools, application, and database to develop and run the application.
About the application and choice of tools The application I develop gets data from GitHub, Jira, and websites via API, processes it and creates reports according to the desired requirements.
The application is developed with PHP version 8+ and Nginx as a web server, and Percona Server for MongoDB as a database.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Databases on Containers with Percona Server for MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/23/exploring-databases-on-containers-with-mysql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/23/exploring-databases-on-containers-with-mysql/</guid><description>In this blog, we will explore databases on containers. We will use Docker as a container engine tool and Percona Server for MySQL as a database administration tool. Both are open source tools.
MySQL is a relational database management system that stores data on disk. Percona Server for MySQL is a fork of MYSQL, providing much more advanced features. To run it correctly, we need to know volumes because we want to “persist” the data, the most important thing in databases.</description></item><item><title>How To Generate Data With Pagila in Percona Distribution for PostgreSQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/13/how-to-generate-data-with-pagila-in-percona-distribution-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/13/how-to-generate-data-with-pagila-in-percona-distribution-for-postgresql/</guid><description>Have you ever faced the need to generate test data for your Postgres database? I am sure you have! This blog post will guide you step-by-step through one of the many ways to get it fast and easy. That will leave you plenty of time to focus on queries. No need to spend time creating your data generation scripts!
For this guide, we will use Pagila, a tool that provides a standard schema that we can use for examples in books, tutorials, articles, samples, etc.</description></item><item><title>Learning Kubernetes Operators with Percona Operator for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</guid><description>One of the topics that have resonated a lot for me since the first KubeCon I attended in 2018 is Kubernetes Operators.
The concept of Operators was introduced much earlier in 2016 by the CoreOS Linux development team. They were looking for a way to improve automated container management in Kubernetes.
What do we mean by a Kubernetes Operator? We use the definition of CNCF. The Kubernetes project defines “Operator” simply: “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components“.</description></item><item><title>Running PMM with Docker on Ubuntu 20.04</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</guid><description>I started at Percona a few weeks ago and was looking for a quick way to learn about PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management), which is one of my favorite technologies within Percona to monitor the health of our database infrastructure, explore new patterns in the database behavior, manage and improve the performance of our databases, all with customizable dashboards and real-time alerts using Grafana and VictoriaMetrics.
The best of all is that PMM is Open Source, you can check the PMM repository in case you want to contribute.</description></item><item><title>How to replace `docker` with `podman` for PMM development</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/27/replace-docker-with-podman-for-pmm-dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/27/replace-docker-with-podman-for-pmm-dev/</guid><description>What is Podman? Podman is a daemonless container engine for developing, managing, and running OCI (Open Container Initiative) Containers on your Linux System. Containers can either be run as root or in rootless mode. More details here.
Check out also Kubernetes Podcast to learn more about podman and listen to it&amp;rsquo;s creators.
Why to replace? Especially in development I need simplest possible solution, I don&amp;rsquo;t need additional daemon running or allowing something to run with elevated privileges.</description></item><item><title>Cassandra Where and How by John Schulz</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</guid><description>If Percona Live ONLINE had graded its talks by skill level this year, John Schulz’s talk would have been essential viewing in the Beginners track. (You can watch all the event’s presentations now on Percona’s YouTube channel.) This talk was a good overview and meant for anyone who had heard of the Apache Cassandra distributed database but wasn’t sure whether it would be suitable for their project or not.
Database-veteran, John Schulz has been tinkering with Cassandra for about a decade and to help anyone get started he gave a whistle-stop tour of the Cassandra ecosystem.</description></item></channel></rss>