<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MariaDB on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/mariadb/</link><description>Recent content in MariaDB on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/mariadb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating MariaDB Deployments With Ansible</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/6/</guid><description>Federico Razzoli - Vettabase - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
This demo shows how to deploy MariaDB with Ansible. We&amp;rsquo;ll look into the Ansible playbook and the Ansible commands to use to install MariaDB, upgrade MariaDB, and modify MariaDB configuration on any number of servers. The Playbook we&amp;rsquo;ll use is a realistic production installation: it includes scheduled backups and a PMM agent to monitor the server performance. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how using Ansible saves long work hours, makes operations virtually error-free, and provides a complete documentation of servers configuration.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB ColumnStore – A Columnar Storage Engine, First Class Citizen in MariaDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/5/</guid><description>Vicențiu Ciorbaru - MariaDB Foundation - MariaDB ColumnStore – A Columnar Storage Engine, First Class Citizen in MariaDB - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
MariaDB has had ColumnStore (a columnar storage engine) available for a while now. The problem was that ColumnStore (formerly known as InniDB) was coded in such a way that required a custom version of MariaDB to function. The installation was also non-trivial, with quite a set of dependencies needed.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Work and Leadership in the Time of Pandemics</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/4/</guid><description>Anna Widenius - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
Virtual work and leadership in the time of pandemics MariaDB Foundation has been a virtual organization long before the pandemic struck. That gave us a head start in finding ways to adapt team leadership and management to the new times. Team leadership and management are different in a virtual organization, and in this session, we will talk about best practices within development teams.</description></item><item><title>JSON Additions in MariaDB - Featuring JSON_TABLE</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/3/</guid><description>Vicențiu Ciorbaru - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
MariaDB has had JSON support for a while now. Released initially in 10.2, MariaDB tries to follow the SQL standard as close as possible. One of the new additions coming to MariaDB 10.6 is support for JSON_TABLE. In this talk we will go through the details of this new feature, as well use cases and interactions with JSON path.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration in Open Source: A Q&amp;A on Github, Jira, Zulip and Knowledgebase</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/2/</guid><description>Kaj Arnö, Ian Gilfillan, Robert Bindar, Vicențiu Ciorbaru, Anna Widenius - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
This is an extended, interactive panel / Q&amp;amp;A version of the 20 min talk on Collaboration in Open Source. Whereas the 20 min talk sets expectations, this session in the MariaDB Community Room goes in depth and solicits input from the audience. How can MariaDB Foundation improve its level of interactivity and collaboration with its developer community?</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.6 - What's New?</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/1/</guid><description>Vicențiu Ciorbaru - MariaDB Foundation - MariaDB Community Track - Percona Live 2021
MariaDB&amp;rsquo;s 10.6 is coming with a lot of improvements, specifically centered around performance. Although the contents of this talk will depend on exactly what makes it into MariaDB 10.6 GA, the following topics will be covered.
Atomic DDL in MariaDB Optimizer changes InnoDB changes Oracle compatibility changes and parser changes</description></item><item><title>What If We Could Use Machine Learning Models as Tables – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/12/what-if-we-could-use-machine-learning-models-as-tables-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 17:56:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/12/what-if-we-could-use-machine-learning-models-as-tables-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 1:30 p.m. • London 6:30 p.m. • New Delhi 11:00 p.m. • Singapore 1:30 a.m. (next day)
Abstract In most machine learning tasks, one has to first organize data in some form and then turn it into information about the problem that needs to be solved. One could say that the requirement to train many machine learning algorithms is information, not just data.</description></item><item><title>Analytical Queries in MySQL – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 17:05:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 6:00 p.m. • London 11:00 p.m. • New Delhi 3:30 a.m. • Singapore 6:00 a.m.
Abstract MySQL&amp;rsquo;s sweet spot is known to be online transaction processing (OLTP), and it can support a very high load of short transactions. Many users will also want to run analytical queries (OLAP) on their MySQL data. Often they achieve this by exporting their data to another database system that is tailored for analytical queries.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Ecosystem on ARM – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/07/mysql-ecosystem-on-arm-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 02:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/07/mysql-ecosystem-on-arm-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 8:00 p.m. • London 1:00 a.m (next day) • New Delhi 5:30 a.m. • Singapore 8:00 a.m.
Abstract? The ARM ecosystem is quickly evolving as a cost-effective alternative to run High-Performance Computing (HPC) software. It continues to grow with some major cloud players hosting ARM-based cloud servers. MySQL too joined the ecosystem with 8.x. MariaDB already has made its presence.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.5 New Features for Troubleshooting – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/mariadb-10-5-new-features-for-troubleshooting-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/mariadb-10-5-new-features-for-troubleshooting-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Aug • New York 12:00 midnight • London 05:00 a.m. • New Delhi 9:30 a.m. • Singapore 12:00 noon
Abstract I want to help DBAs and Support engineers find out what&amp;rsquo;s really going on when some problem strikes. My goal is to show new ways to diagnose problems now available in MariaDB 10.5. See the full abstract for more.
Why Is Your Talk Exciting?</description></item><item><title>Two weeks to MariaDB Server Fest</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 09:34:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</guid><description>There is still time to register for the MariaDB Server Fest 2020!
MariaDB Fest 2020[/caption]
Our Fest is the opportunity to have live interactions with the key players on MariaDB Server: the developers of MariaDB Server, the service providers, the experts, the system integrators, and – perhaps most importantly – your fellow users!
Interactivity happens all the time, with the presenters being cloned and available for answering questions throughout the presentation.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB Server Fest: Call for Papers</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/26/mariadb-server-fest-call-for-papers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 21:42:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/26/mariadb-server-fest-call-for-papers/</guid><description>In the week of 14-20 September 2020, MariaDB Foundation will host the MariaDB Server Fest Online Conference. We welcome the Percona Community not just to participate, but also to submit papers for the event. We already have Peter Zaitsev joining as keynoter; we hope for more to come.
Our target audience are the users of MariaDB Server – current and future ones. We are looking for use cases, practices, tools and insights from our user base as well as from application developers, service providers and other experts.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.4 and the Competition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 23:10:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 12:30 p.m. • London 5:30 p.m. • New Delhi 10:00 p.m.
Abstract There are many good databases out there. Picking the right database for your project is never easy. There are technical criteria, business criteria, perhaps even ethical criteria. In this keynote, MariaDB Foundation CEO Kaj Arno will present his - obviously completely impartial - view of the process. Should you pick a database in the cloud or on premise?</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Tracing for Finding and Solving MariaDB (and MySQL) Performance Problems on Linux - Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/05/dynamic-tracing-for-finding-and-solving-mariadb-and-mysql-performance-problems-on-linux-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 21:13:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/05/dynamic-tracing-for-finding-and-solving-mariadb-and-mysql-performance-problems-on-linux-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot (CORRECTED): Wed 20 May • New York 6:00 a.m. • London 11:00 a.m. • New Delhi 3:30 p.m. Level: Advanced
Abstract While troubleshooting MariaDB server performance problems it is important to find out where the time is spent in the mysqld process, on-CPU and off-CPU. The process of investigation should have as small influence as possible on the server we try to troubleshoot. Performance_schema introduced in MySQL 5.</description></item><item><title>Expert MariaDB: Utilize MariaDB Server Effectively - Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/expert-mariadb-utilize-mariadb-server-effectively-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 20:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/expert-mariadb-utilize-mariadb-server-effectively-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 11:00 p.m. • London 4:00 a.m. (Wed) • New Delhi 8:30 a.m. (Wed) Level: Intermediate
Abstract MariaDB Server 10.4 has been out for some time now (June 2019) and it has many new features, some of which MySQL does not have. Feature-wise, it is important to know what MariaDB Server 10.4 has (e.g. system tables in the Aria storage engine, ability to reload SSL certificates without a restart and more!</description></item><item><title>Finding MySQL Scaling Problems Using perf</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/02/05/finding-mysql-scaling-problems-using-perf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:18:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/02/05/finding-mysql-scaling-problems-using-perf/</guid><description>The thing I wish I&amp;rsquo;d learned while still a DBA is how to use perf. Conversely after moving to a developer role, getting access to real external client workloads to get a perf recording directly is rare. To bridge this gap, I hope to encourage a bit of perf usage to help DBAs report bugs/feature requests in more detail to MySQL developers, who can then serve your needs better.
A recent client request showed how useful perf is in exposing the areas of MySQL that are otherwise well tuned, but can still be in need of coding improvements that increase throughput.</description></item><item><title>Minimalist Tooling for MySQL/MariaDB DBAs</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/14/minimalist-tooling-for-mysql-mariadb-dbas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 14:21:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/14/minimalist-tooling-for-mysql-mariadb-dbas/</guid><description>In my roles as a DBA at various companies, I generally found the tooling to be quite lacking. Everything from metrics collection, alerting, backup management; they were either missing, incomplete or implemented poorly. DBA-Tools was born from a desire to build backup tools that supported my needs in smaller/non-cloud environments. As BASH is easily the most common shell available out there on systems running MySQL® or MariaDB®, it was an easy choice.</description></item><item><title>MySQL 5.6/Maria 10.1 : How we got from 30k qps to 101k qps.....</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/07/mysql-how-we-got-from-30k-qps-to-101k-qps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 07:52:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/07/mysql-how-we-got-from-30k-qps-to-101k-qps/</guid><description>Late one evening, I was staring at one of our large MySQL installations and noticed the database was hovering around 7-10 run queue length (48 cores, ~500 gigs memory, fusionIO cards). I had been scratching my head on how to get more throughput from the database. This blog records the changes I made to tune performance in order to achieve a 300% better throughput in MySQL. I tested my theories on MySQL 5.</description></item><item><title>London Open Source Database Community Meetup</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 09:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</guid><description>I strongly believe in the community.
Communities are the real strength of open source. Not just the theoretical ability to study, modify and share code – but the fact that other people out there are doing these things. Creating a base of knowledge and a network of relations.These can become work relationships, valuable discussions, open source tools, or even friendships.
That is why, when I heard that several people from the Percona support team will soon be in London, I badly wanted to organise an event.</description></item><item><title>Some Notes on MariaDB system-versioned Tables</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/14/notes-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 14:53:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/14/notes-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</guid><description>As mentioned in a previous post, I gave a talk at Percona Live Europe 2018 about system-versioned tables. This is a new MariaDB 10.3 feature, which consists of preserving old versions of a table rows. Each version has two timestamps that indicate the start (INSERT,UPDATE) of the validity of that version, and its end (DELETE, UPDATE). As a result, the user is able to query these tables as they appear at a point in the past, or how data evolved in a certain time range.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: MariaDB 10.4 Reverse Privileges (DENY)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/23/mariadb-10-4-reverse-privileges-deny/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 11:41:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/23/mariadb-10-4-reverse-privileges-deny/</guid><description>One of the most common questions about privileges in MySQL and MariaDB is how would a user revoke access to a particular table, in a large database with hundreds or thousands of tables, while keeping the rest available. Currently, there is no easy solution. Just grant access to everything else, individually. Not only does this reduce server performance, but is a nightmare to maintain. Reverse privileges solve this and more.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: MariaDB System-Versioned Tables</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/17/percona-live-europe-presents-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 16:14:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/17/percona-live-europe-presents-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</guid><description>System-versioned tables, or temporal tables, are a typical feature of proprietary database management systems like DB2, Oracle and SQL Server. They also appeared at some point in PostgreSQL, but only as an extension; and also in CockroachDB, but in a somewhat limited fashion.
The MariaDB® implementation is the first appearance of temporal tables in the MySQL ecosystem, and the most complete implementation in the open source world.
My presentation will be useful for analysts, and some managers, who will definitely benefit from learning how to use temporal tables.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Session: What's New in MariaDB Server 10.3</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/percona-live-europe-session-whats-new-mariadb-server-10-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 12:42:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/percona-live-europe-session-whats-new-mariadb-server-10-3/</guid><description>** Having spent my recent years &amp;ldquo;in the real world&amp;rdquo;, working with many users, I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt that a particular new feature does not necessarily excite users as much as one might expect. MariaDB 10.3 however actually has some very interesting features that users do get excited about.
So that&amp;rsquo;s great!
My session at Percona Live Europe in Frankfurt is going to be best for people deploying MariaDB or related infra, who haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to explore what the various features actually mean, or what they can do with them.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Query Optimization and TLS at Large Scale</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 14:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe this year, I got accepted a workshop on query optimization and a 50-minute talk covering TLS for MySQL at Large Scale, talking about our experiences at the Wikimedia Foundation.
Workshop The 3-hour workshop on Monday, titled Query Optimization with MySQL 8.0 and MariaDB 10.3: The Basics is a beginners' tutorial–though dense in content. It&amp;rsquo;s for people who are more familiar with database storage systems other than InnoDB for MySQL, MariaDB or Percona Server.</description></item><item><title>Generating Identifiers – from AUTO_INCREMENT to Sequence</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/12/generating-identifiers-auto_increment-sequence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/12/generating-identifiers-auto_increment-sequence/</guid><description>There are a number of options for generating ID values for your tables. In this post, Alexey Mikotkin of Devart explores your choices for generating identifiers with a look at auto_increment, triggers, UUID and sequences.
AUTO_INCREMENT Frequently, we happen to need to fill tables with unique identifiers. Naturally, the first example of such identifiers is PRIMARY KEY data. These are usually integer values hidden from the user since their specific values are unimportant.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Elasticsearch 101</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 07:17:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe, I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting the tutorial Elasticsearch 101 alongside my colleagues and fellow presenters from ObjectRocket Alex Cercel, DBA, and Mihai Aldoiu, Data Engineer. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief overview of our tutorial.
Elasticsearch® is well known as a highly scalable search engine that stores data in a structure optimized for language based searches but its capabilities and use cases don’t stop there. In this tutorial, we’ll give you a hands-on introduction to Elasticsearch and give you a glimpse at some of the fundamental concepts.</description></item><item><title>Multi-master with MariaDB 10 - a tutorial</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:57:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</guid><description>The goal of this tutorial is to show you how to use multi-master to aggregate databases with the same name, but different data from different masters, on the same slave.
Example:
master1 =&amp;gt; a French subsidiary master2 =&amp;gt; a British subsidiary Both have the same database PRODUCTION but the data are totally different.
This screenshot is made from my own monitoring tool: PmaControl. You have to read 10.</description></item><item><title>Question about Semi-Synchronous Replication: the Answer with All the Details</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/23/question-about-semi-synchronous-replication-answer-with-all-the-details/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:49:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/23/question-about-semi-synchronous-replication-answer-with-all-the-details/</guid><description>I was recently asked a question by mail about MySQL Lossless Semi-Synchronous Replication. As I think the answer could benefit many people, I am answering it in a blog post. The answer brings us to the internals of transaction committing, of semi-synchronous replication, of MySQL (server) crash recovery, and of storage engine (InnoDB) crash recovery. I am also debunking some misconceptions that I have often seen and heard repeated by many.</description></item><item><title>A Nice Feature in MariaDB 10.3: no InnoDB Buffer Pool in Core Dumps</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/28/nice-feature-in-mariadb-103-no-innodb-buffer-pool-in-coredumps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 12:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/28/nice-feature-in-mariadb-103-no-innodb-buffer-pool-in-coredumps/</guid><description>MariaDB 10.3 is now generally available (10.3.7 was released GA on 2018-05-25). The article What&amp;rsquo;s New in MariaDB Server 10.3 by the MariaDB Corporation lists three key improvements in 10.3: temporal data processing, Oracle compatibility features, and purpose-built storage engines. Even if I am excited about MyRocks and curious on Spider, I am also very interested in less flashy but still very important changes that make running the database in production easier.</description></item><item><title>The MySQL Ecosystem in 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-colin-charles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-colin-charles/</guid><description>27 years of the MySQL ecosystem, not only is there the core product from Oracle, there is a branch from Percona and a fork from MariaDB. You&amp;rsquo;re a busy DBA having to maintain a mix of this. Or you&amp;rsquo;re a CIO planning to choose one branch/fork. How do you go about picking? How do you go about supporting multiple databases? Find out more in this talk.</description></item></channel></rss>