<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community Track on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/community-track/</link><description>Recent content in Community Track on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/community-track/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Twitter Runs Presto at Scale in the Cloud</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/7/</guid><description>Beinan Wang, Ph.D. - Twitter - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto is a widely adopted federated SQL engine for federated querying across multiple data sources. With Presto, you can perform ad hoc querying of data in place.
In this session, Twitter engineer Beinan Wang will share how they use Presto at scale with over 3K Presto workers and 10 million queries and a highly-scalable query predictor service. At Twitter, this service helps improve the performance of Presto clusters and provides expected execution statistics on Business Intelligence dashboards.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Architectures in a Nutshell</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/10/</guid><description>Kenny Gryp - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Following MySQL InnoDB Cluster as our first, fully integrated MySQL High Availability solution based on Group Replication, MySQL Shell 8.0.19 includes MySQL InnoDB ReplicaSet which delivers another complete solution, this time based on MySQL Replication.
The basic idea for InnoDB ReplicaSet is to do the same for classic MySQL Replication as InnoDB Cluster did for Group Replication. We take a strong technology that is very powerful but can be complex, and provide an easy-to-use AdminAPI for it in the MySQL Shell.</description></item><item><title>Presto and Apache Iceberg</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/6/</guid><description>Chunxu Tang - Twitter - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Apache Iceberg is an open table format for huge analytic datasets. At Twitter, engineers are working on the Presto-Iceberg connector, aiming to bring high-performance data analytics on Iceberg to the Presto ecosystem. In this session, Chunxu will share what they have learned during the development and the future work of interactive queries.</description></item><item><title>DBdeployer in Action - Optimised MySQL Sandboxes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/9/</guid><description>Giuseppe Maxia and Frédéric Descamps - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
The Data Charmer will show how to use dbdeployer in the wild by answering the questions of lefred. This session will mimic an Ask Me Anything session where all chapters will be an answer to a specic question. Throught this list of questions, the audience will learn how to start with dbdeployer but also discover more advanced featured.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Highly Available PostgreSQL With GKE</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/4/</guid><description>Christoph Bussler and Shashank Agarwal - Google - Percona Live 2021
When you have an application running in Google Kubernetes Engine, there are multiple options and considerations for how to deploy a database. In this session, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn some of the architectural considerations for choosing a database deployment option in GKE. We will demonstrate one of these options, as you learn how to configure PostgreSQL as a container in GKE based on regional persistent disks and PersistentVolumeClaims.</description></item><item><title>Running Presto on AWS With Ahana Cloud</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/5/</guid><description>Dipti Borkar (Ahana) and Gary Stafford (AWS) - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto, the fast-growing open source SQL query engine, disaggregates storage and compute and leverages all data within an organization for data-driven decision making. It is driving the rise of Amazon S3-based data lakes and on-demand cloud computing. In this session you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how Ahana Cloud, the only managed service for Presto, simplifies Presto deployment &amp;amp; management on AWS using Kubernetes so data platforms teams of any size can use it.</description></item><item><title>5 Ways Facebook’s Ludicrous Usage Drives Presto Innovation</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/4/</guid><description>Ariel Weisberg - Facebook - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto at Facebook has evolved significantly since its inception in 2012. In this session, Ariel will discuss this evolution including fundamental architectural improvements on scale and efficiency, the business cases that drive improvements like these, how the Presto use cases at Facebook have grown (and what they are), and how this all is balanced with features that the Presto community looks for.</description></item><item><title>How To Choose the Right Solution When Lifting and Shifting Your Database to the Cloud</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/3/</guid><description>Shachar Guz - Google - Percona Live 2021
Database migrations can be complex, time-consuming, and costly, increasing the risk of moving to the cloud. Enterprises need effective and reliable database migration tools that help automate this process for seamless cloud adoption. In this session, we will elaborate on the considerations to take into account when choosing database migration methods and technology, and the different aspects that can impact risk such as migration fidelity and downtime.</description></item><item><title>Validating JSON</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/8/</guid><description>Dave Stokes - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
JSON or JavaScript Object Notation has become the data interchange format of choice. Most relational databases have added a JSON data type (Oracle, Postgresql, MySQL) or some accommodation for JSON data (SQL Server, MariaDB). But the free form nature of JSON is problematic for relational databases resulting in compromises in speed, handling of key-value pairs, and general lack of the ability to validate data.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying Database Performance Issues With SQL Commenter and Cloud SQL Insights</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/2/</guid><description>Jan Kleinert - Google - Percona Live 2021
Have you ever tried to troubleshoot a database performance issue in an application that was built using an ORM? ORMs can simplify development of applications that communicate with databases, but since the ORMs are generating the SQL statements, it can be difficult to determine which application code is resulting in slow queries.
SQL Commenter is an open source library that enables ORMs to augment SQL statements with comments about the code that caused its execution, making it easier to correlate your application code with the SQL statements that were generated by the ORM.</description></item><item><title>PrestoDB Administration Fundamentals – Why, What and How</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/3/</guid><description>Ravi Shankar - PassionBytes - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
The session will discuss how to set up, run, and scale Presto at your organization. You will learn about configuring data sources, memory requirements and monitoring, in addition to how to access the metadata information and get run time information by queries as well as through the admin UI. In case you need to see the live plan, there will be methods shown and explained.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Presto: The SQL Engine for Data Platform Teams</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/2/</guid><description>Dipti Borkar (Ahana) and Tim Meehan (Facebook) - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto is an open source high performance, distributed SQL query engine. Born at Facebook in 2012, Presto was built to run interactive queries on large Hadoop-based clusters. Today it has grown to support many users and use cases including ad hoc query, data lake analytics, and federated querying. In this session, we will give an overview on Presto including architecture and how it works, the problems it solves, and most common use cases.</description></item><item><title>Successfully Run Your MySQL NDB Cluster in Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/7/</guid><description>Tiago Alves - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Fortunately, MySQL NDB Cluster already has auto-healing, data distribution, instant scaling and many other features built-in - making it a perfect t for Cloud Native. This session walks through the few steps necessary to deploy a distributed NDB setup in a Kubernetes cluster manually or with an operator.
NDB runs in Kubernetes serving mission critical microservices at the heart of Cloud Native production systems.</description></item><item><title>Working Effectively with Cloud SQL on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/1/</guid><description>Eno Compton - Google - Percona Live 2021
There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like about Kubernetes and Cloud SQL, but it&amp;rsquo;s not always clear how to use them together. This talk will be a deep-dive into Cloud SQL and how to work with it effectively on Kubernetes. The talk will be developer-centric and will start with the basics of connecting to Cloud SQL from Kubernetes. It will include how to run load tests and then size an instance.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Operator for Presto</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/1/</guid><description>Hemant Bhanawat - Yugabyte - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto Operator for Kubernetes is used to manage Presto clusters which are deployed as custom resources. In short, the task of configuring, creating and managing of Presto cluster(s) in a Kubernetes environment has been made simple, easy and quick with a Presto Operator.
This session will be a walkthrough of provisioning Presto in K8s using Presto Operator. The advanced features of Presto Operator like HTTPS support, additional volumes support, autoscaling and graceful shutdown of workers will also be discussed.</description></item><item><title>How Open Source Powers the Modern Data Stack</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/5/</guid><description>Michel Tricot - Airbyte - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
In this talk, we’ll describe how you can leverage 3 open-source standards - workflow management with Aifrow, EL with Airbyte, transformation with DBT - to build your organization&amp;rsquo;s modern data stack.
We’ll explain how to configure your Aifrow DAG to trigger Airbyte’s data replication jobs and DBT’s transformations with a concrete use case.</description></item><item><title>Migration From 5.6 to 8.xx.xx</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/6/</guid><description>Johannes Schlüter and Kenny Gryp - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Brand New Development announced at Percona Live !!
This talk is about something we cannot announce publicly now and will be exclusively announced during Percona Live.
This is something new, that will be released after the conference, don&amp;rsquo;t miss this session to discover new trendy stuff.
Brand New Development announced at Percona Live !!</description></item><item><title>Migration From 5.6 to 8.xx.xx</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/5/</guid><description>Luis Dias - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Intro I start working in a Belgium company that use Mysql 5.6. We use 6 production servers and we decide to migrate from this old version to mysql 8.0.19. All the servers have Centos 7 system (so RPM and YUM available)
The first test was done by devops team, they use mysqldump to make this job, but as each server is about 4T the down time was over 30 hours and it&amp;rsquo;s not acceptable for customer.</description></item><item><title>Towards a K8s Native Streaming Application</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/4/</guid><description>Jérémy Frénay (Babylon Health) and Francesco Nobilia (Nutmeg) - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
Starting from a simple application which can be deployed in every machine running Docker, we will go through all steps required to transform the simple app into a Kubernetes native streaming application. We will explain the theory and then exemplify the learnt concepts to dene a recipe for running streaming applications on Kubernetes. We will focus both on cultural and technical tricks to help you successfully adopt streaming applications at scale.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Shell for DBAs</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/4/</guid><description>Frédéric Descamps - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Get an overview of the possibilities offered by MySQL Shell for DBAs. How to deploy infrastructures (overview only), how to dump and load tables/schema/instances etc.. it&amp;rsquo;s time to t get more familiar with the util object. And finally see the possibility of User Defined Reports and Plugins for the MySQL Shell.
During the session we will cover the most useful plugins for general DBA tasks</description></item><item><title>Wrangling Data to Multiple Places With Fluent Bit</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/3/</guid><description>Anurag Gupta - Calyptia - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
As more and more users move to Kubernetes they also may start using multiple backends and analytic tools. How do you collect once and send everywhere? In this talk, Anurag will talk about a Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) graduated project Fluent Bit and how you can collect once, and send to all the backends you want. Additionally, Anurag will discuss some of Fluent Bit&amp;rsquo;s advanced capabilities such as enrichment, parsing, and data reduction that helps users get the most out of their backends.</description></item><item><title>Everything You Ever Wanted To Know About Databases but Were Too Afraid To Ask</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/2/</guid><description>Dr Gavin Mendel - TerminusDb - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
The talk does exactly what it says on the tin - everything you want to know about databases from somebody with decades of experience implementing, architecting, and building databases. Gavin will talk through the way he currently thinks about implementation - the problems he most cares about - and then will open up to your questions! In the absence of Stonebreaker, nobody is better placed to answer database Q&amp;amp;A.</description></item><item><title>Oracle MySQL Database Service with HeatWave for Real-Time Analytics</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/3/</guid><description>Carsten Thalheimer - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Since 2020 the MySQL development team is offering a fully managed database service of the MySQL Enterprise Edition. Traditionally MySQL InnoDB is designed for online transaction processing (OLTP) load. MySQL can cover online analytics processing (OLAP) load, but it is often rather slow and tricky. Beginning of December 2020, the MySQL team started a second MySQL Cloud offering called MySQL HeatWave for Real-time Analytics which is based on a new in-memory analytic accelerator which has been designed for extreme performance and cloud scale.</description></item><item><title>Insights Into the New Oracle MySQL Database Service</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/2/</guid><description>Carsten Thalheimer - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
Oracle MySQL Database Cloud Service 2021 - Where we are today&amp;hellip;
Early 2020 Oracle introduced the MySQL Database Service (MDS) built on Oracle Gen 2 Cloud Infrastructure and MySQL 8. It is 100% developed, managed, and supported by the Oracle MySQL team. The service is available as a fully-managed service in all commercial regions of the Oracle Cloud.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Server Component Manifest Files</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mysql-room/1/</guid><description>Georgi Kodinov - Oracle MySQL - MySQL Track Room - Percona Live 2021
MySQL configuration has traditionally been done via system variables with values coming from either command line, config files or SET commands. This can be a security issue since it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support a trust model rooted in some well known trusted state that cannot be modified by less trusted actors.
This is what the manifest le security model is aiming at solving.</description></item><item><title>Native Chaos Engineering in Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/data-on-kubernetes-room/1/</guid><description>Karthik Satchitanand - ChaosNative - Data on Kubernetes Track - Percona Live 2021
Chaos Engineering is revolutionizing testing means and doing it the cloud-native way is the best way in today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly changing world with a huge shift in the paradigm of Kubernetes resiliency. Karthik S, one of the maintainers for LitmusChaos would be introducing how to carry out Chaos Engineering, the cloud-native way. Further, he will touch upon how Chaos Engineering is carried out in Cloud-Native Databases with LitmusChaos.</description></item><item><title>Automating MariaDB Deployments With Ansible</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/6/</guid><description>Federico Razzoli - Vettabase - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
This demo shows how to deploy MariaDB with Ansible. We&amp;rsquo;ll look into the Ansible playbook and the Ansible commands to use to install MariaDB, upgrade MariaDB, and modify MariaDB configuration on any number of servers. The Playbook we&amp;rsquo;ll use is a realistic production installation: it includes scheduled backups and a PMM agent to monitor the server performance. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how using Ansible saves long work hours, makes operations virtually error-free, and provides a complete documentation of servers configuration.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB ColumnStore – A Columnar Storage Engine, First Class Citizen in MariaDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/5/</guid><description>Vicențiu Ciorbaru - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
MariaDB has had ColumnStore (a columnar storage engine) available for a while now. The problem was that ColumnStore (formerly known as InniDB) was coded in such a way that required a custom version of MariaDB to function. The installation was also non-trivial, with quite a set of dependencies needed. After a significant amount of work, both within MariaDB&amp;rsquo;s codebase and ColumnStore&amp;rsquo;s codebase, it is now possible with MariaDB 10.</description></item><item><title>Trino on Ice: Using Iceberg To Replace the Hive Table Format</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/10/</guid><description>Brian Olsen - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
Trino (formerly PrestoSQL) is a ludicrously fast query engine that evolved from the need to replace the slow query turnaround speeds of the Hive engine. Trino grew in popularity under the label of Presto for years as an interactive query engine that lives over your data lake. While this operation was certainly a step away from the initial big data days of waiting hours to days for queries to complete, there were still many tedious rules engineers had to follow in order to correctly create, manage, and use their data in the datalake due to the Hive table format.</description></item><item><title>Fun and Games: Why We Picked ClickHouse To Drive Gaming Analytics at GiG</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/9/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/9/</guid><description>Stephen Borg - Matthew Formosa - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
With such a saturated market for the iGaming industry, many technology providers are reviewing their architecture to provide a leaner, more sustainable platform. Complex architectures that involve heavy license and high maintenance costs were two of the rules to avoid when GiG kicked o R&amp;amp;D on what technology to choose at the heart of GiG Data. Tied with the necessity of good governance whilst empowering stakeholders needing real-time data, the list of databases became shorter and shorter.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Work and Leadership in the Time of Pandemics</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/4/</guid><description>Anna Widenius - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
Virtual work and leadership in the time of pandemics MariaDB Foundation has been a virtual organization long before the pandemic struck. That gave us a head start in finding ways to adapt team leadership and management to the new times. Team leadership and management are different in a virtual organization, and in this session, we will talk about best practices within development teams.</description></item><item><title>JSON Additions in MariaDB - Featuring JSON_TABLE</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/3/</guid><description>Vicențiu Ciorbaru - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
MariaDB has had JSON support for a while now. Released initially in 10.2, MariaDB tries to follow the SQL standard as close as possible. One of the new additions coming to MariaDB 10.6 is support for JSON_TABLE. In this talk we will go through the details of this new feature, as well use cases and interactions with JSON path.</description></item><item><title>I’ve Got a Fever and the Only Prescription is Apache Druid</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/8/</guid><description>Rachel Pedreschi - Imply - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
Digital transformation initiatives have unlocked large and fast-moving data sets including clickstreams, network telemetry, application monitoring and IoT devices. Analytics architectures have not kept pace, with most data still being run through existing “cold analytics” systems and tools designed for smaller and less time-sensitive workloads. “Hot analytics” denotes workloads where the responsiveness of the system is instantaneous and can support self-service data exploration, and where the data is extremely fresh, allowing for more informed decision-making.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration in Open Source: A Q&amp;A on Github, Jira, Zulip and Knowledgebase</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/2/</guid><description>Kaj Arnö, Ian Gilfillan, Robert Bindar, Vicențiu Ciorbaru, Anna Widenius - MariaDB Foundation - Percona Live 2021 - MariaDB Track Room
This is an extended, interactive panel / Q&amp;amp;A version of the 20 min talk on Collaboration in Open Source. Whereas the 20 min talk sets expectations, this session in the MariaDB Community Room goes in depth and solicits input from the audience. How can MariaDB Foundation improve its level of interactivity and collaboration with its developer community?</description></item><item><title>DuckDB: Embedded Analytics with Parallel/Vector/Columnar Performance</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/7/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/7/</guid><description>Jim Tommaney - Databricks - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
DuckDB is a project coming out of CWI in the Netherlands that combines vector, columnar, and parallel capabilities.
Highlights:
Great performance for analytic queries Fast batch load Near linear scaling Near-zero administration DuckDB is a SQLite replacement for analytics.
In this session you will learn about:
What is different about Embedded/Serverless data engines? Current performance and features of DuckDB Best practices using DuckDB</description></item><item><title>Something Went Wrong: Understanding Alerting and Anomaly Detection</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/5/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
Being informed of something going wrong after it has happened is never ideal. Setting up a system to monitor logs and metrics allows you to be proactive rather than reactive. This session will cover the differences between alerting and anomaly detection, how each works, and where they are best employed.</description></item><item><title>WarpSQL – A Distribution of MySQL 8 With Columnar Storage, Bitmap Indexing, and Parallel Query Execution</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/6/</guid><description>Justin Swanhart - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
WarpSQL is a distribution of MySQL 8 which includes the WARP storage engine and has parallel query execution features for queries that use WARP tables. The WARP storage engine features automatic creation of compressed bitmap indexes, which can be used to eciently execute complex queries that can not be executed eciently using traditional btree indexes, even over very large amounts of data.</description></item><item><title>Supporting Global Scale MySQL Applications With Amazon Aurora Global Database</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/3/</guid><description>Vijay Karumajj - AWS - Amazon Aurora Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Critical MySQL workloads with a global footprint, such as financial, travel, or gaming applications, have strict availability requirements and may need to tolerate a region-wide outage. Traditionally this required difficult tradeoffs between performance, availability, cost, and data integrity. In this session, learn how Amazon Aurora Global Database, which allows a single Amazon Aurora MySQL database to span multiple AWS regions, replicates your data with no impact on database performance, enables fast local reads with low latency in each region, and provides fast disaster recovery from region-wide outages.</description></item><item><title>A Tale of Two Communities: How Open Source, ClickHouse and Superset Help Visualize Your Data</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/5/</guid><description>Robert Hodges (Altinity) and Srini Kadamati (Preset.io) - Percona Live 2021 - Altinity Community Track
This talk consists of live lab exercises for the ClickHouse Developer Tutorial, Part 1. Please attend that talk and then join us for fun using ClickHouse. We have some puzzles for you to try that will test your ClickHouse knowledge. You can run all queries straight from your web browser, so there&amp;rsquo;s no preparation required. Join us for the fun!</description></item><item><title>Getting Your Mind Around OpenSearch Geospatial Data</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/4/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
Flat earthers need not attend! This session will go through the basics of geospatial data in general, then go deeper on how it works in (and inside of) OpenSearch. The session will explain how to get geospatial information into OpenSearch, then how to query and visualize the data.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Applications With Amazon RDS Proxy</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/2/</guid><description>Surendar Munimohan - AWS - Amazon Aurora Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Many applications, including those built on modern serverless architectures (https://aws.amazon.com/serverless/), can have a large number of open connections to the database server, and may open and close database connections at a high rate, exhausting database memory and compute resources. Amazon RDS Proxy allows applications to pool and share connections established with the database, improving database efficiency and application scalability.</description></item><item><title>ClickHouse Developer Tutorial, Part 2 - Lab Exercises</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/4/</guid><description>Robert Hodges and Alexander Zaitsev - Altinity - Altinity Community Track
This talk consists of live lab exercises for the ClickHouse Developer Tutorial, Part 1. Please attend that talk and then join us for fun using ClickHouse. We have some puzzles for you to try that will test your ClickHouse knowledge. You can run all queries straight from your web browser, so there&amp;rsquo;s no preparation required. Join us for the fun!</description></item><item><title>Hyperscaling Workloads With Amazon RDS MySQL and Amazon Aurora MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/aurora-room/1/</guid><description>Sai Kondapalli - AWS - Amazon Aurora Community Track - Percona Live 2021
When the right factors align, businesses can grow at a sudden, unanticipated and exponential rate. That&amp;rsquo;s a good thing, but an unexpected and dramatic spinke in users and transactions of your MySQL database can strain resources, potential database failure, and, as a result, a bad user or customer experience. In this session, learn strategies and best practices quickly growing your MySQL deployment to ensure high performance and an exceptional user experience while maintaing ACID compliance and rock solid security.</description></item><item><title>Securing OpenSearch</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/3/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
OpenSearch has a strong set of security features but not everyone takes advantage of them. This session will provide an overview of the features as well as show ways to apply these features for real world problems. The session will include demos of data masking, authentication, and authorization, as well as index, document, and eld level security.</description></item><item><title>ClickHouse Developer Tutorial, Part 1 - Intro to ClickHouse</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/3/</guid><description>Robert Hodges and Alexander Zaitsev - Intro to ClickHouse - Altinity Community Track
Heard about ClickHouse and been itching to try it out? This talk is for you! It&amp;rsquo;s a tutorial to get new ClickHouse developers up and running quickly. We&amp;rsquo;ll begin by summarizing practical differences between ClickHouse and row stores like MySQL or PostgreSQL. Next, we&amp;rsquo;ll show how to install ClickHouse and connect to it with popular client tools. We&amp;rsquo;ll then teach basics of ClickHouse SQL, focusing on commands to build reports and dashboards.</description></item><item><title>The Essentials of Search</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/2/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
The term ‘search engine’ is badly overloaded and can cause confusion for many folks. Is it a database? Is it a service to nd recipes for lasagna? Is it something else entirely? This session will teach you not only how to answer these questions but also what makes search distinct and so darn useful across so many domains.</description></item><item><title>ClickHouse 2021: New Features and Roadmap</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/2/</guid><description>Alexey Milovidov - Yandex - Percona Live ONLINE 2021 - Altinity Community Track
In 2021 the ClickHouse community is shipping the features that you probably always dreamed of. We are eliminating previously known limitations of ClickHouse. I will tell you and show demos about: replication without ZooKeeper; semistructured data; processing of frequent small INSERTs; support for transactions; window functions and projections and more and more&amp;hellip; We&amp;rsquo;re really excited about these features and hope they will make ClickHouse even better for your analytic applications.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.6 - What's New?</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/mariadb-room/1/</guid><description>Vicențiu Ciorbaru - MariaDB Foundation - MariaDB Community Track - Percona Live 2021
MariaDB&amp;rsquo;s 10.6 is coming with a lot of improvements, specifically centered around performance. Although the contents of this talk will depend on exactly what makes it into MariaDB 10.6 GA, the following topics will be covered.
Atomic DDL in MariaDB Optimizer changes InnoDB changes Oracle compatibility changes and parser changes</description></item><item><title>Projections in ClickHouse</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/altinity-room/1/</guid><description>Amos Bird - kuaishou.com - Percona Live - Altinity Community Track
Projections are collections of table columns with different physical layout to speed up queries. They are the main constructs of Vertica. At kuaishou.com we have implemented PROJECTIONs support for ClickHouse. It boosts our OLAP analytic capabilities by an order of magnitude. This talk will highlight the design considerations, some implementation details, how it is integrated into ClickHouse design. Examples and demo of the feature will be shown</description></item><item><title>What is OpenSearch?</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/1/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
You may have heard of OpenSearch, but what is it exactly and how did it come about? In this session, you’ll learn about the components of OpenSearch, what they do, and what problems they can solve. No prerequisites for this session, but it prepares you for other OpenSearch sessions.</description></item></channel></rss>