<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PMM on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/pmm/</link><description>Recent content in PMM on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/pmm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dashboard Story: How We Created PMM Dashboard for Highload</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/22/dashboard-story-how-we-created-pmm-dashboard-for-highload/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/22/dashboard-story-how-we-created-pmm-dashboard-for-highload/</guid><description>Let’s say you have highload instances. How do you monitor them? There are a lot of servers with 100, 200… 500+ nodes. How can we collect, check, and analyze metrics from all these servers? How can we understand what and where something happened? Scroll, scroll, scroll&amp;hellip; down? That was the task that we faced at Percona and successfully resolved.
Issue With Home Dashboard Percona Monitoring and Management dashboards are based on Grafana.</description></item><item><title>Testing Kubernetes with KUTTL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/16/testing-kubernetes-with-kuttl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/16/testing-kubernetes-with-kuttl/</guid><description>Automated testing is the only way to be sure that your code works. Enabling automated testing can be hard and we say a lot of tools to write automated tests in the industry since the beginning. Some veterans in the industry may remember Selenium, Cucumber frameworks that help automate testing in the browser. However, testing in Kubernetes can be hard.
In Percona we deal with Kubernetes and have different operators to automate the management of databases.</description></item><item><title>How Do We Develop Code? Live Coding Session Into Our DBaaS Controller- October 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-10-27-develop-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-10-27-develop-code/</guid><description>Have you always wanted to know what and how a developer is working? What do they do, how do they start looking into issues and how do they finally turn that into code? It’s your time to get a behind the scenes view into the daily life of a developer from Percona!
In this session, Andrew is going to implement the db engine configuration support for the PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management) API and will implement that into the DBaaS controller.</description></item><item><title>Hacktoberfest with Percona - We Want You! - September 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>October is close, and it is time for Hacktoberfest! Join our stream to talk online about this fantastic challenge at 2:30 UTC on Wednesday, September 28th. And yes, you can be a part of the conversation with experts and jump into the stream to address the audience!
If you love open source as much as we do, Hacktoberfest is created for you. It is a unique opportunity to be a part of a great open source community.</description></item><item><title>Running PMM with Docker on Ubuntu 20.04</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/installing-pmm-with-docker-on-ubuntu-20/</guid><description>I started at Percona a few weeks ago and was looking for a quick way to learn about PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management), which is one of my favorite technologies within Percona to monitor the health of our database infrastructure, explore new patterns in the database behavior, manage and improve the performance of our databases, all with customizable dashboards and real-time alerts using Grafana and VictoriaMetrics.
The best of all is that PMM is Open Source, you can check the PMM repository in case you want to contribute.</description></item><item><title>Setting up PMM for monitoring MySQL on a local environment</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-mysql-on-a-local-environment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/08/05/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-mysql-on-a-local-environment/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) is an open source database monitoring, observability, and management tool that can be used for monitoring the health of your database infrastructure, exploring new patterns in database behavior, and managing and improving the performance of your databases no matter where they are located or deployed.
PMM is designed to work with MySQL (including Percona Server for MySQL, Percona XtraDB Cluster, Oracle MySQL Community Edition, Oracle MySQL Enterprise Edition, and MariaDB), PostgreSQL (including Percona Distribution for PostgreSQL), MongoDB (including Percona Server for MongoDB), Amazon RDS, Amazon Aurora, Proxy SQL, and Percona XtraDB Cluster.</description></item><item><title>How and Why Contribute to Communities</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/30/csi-minikube-multinode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/30/csi-minikube-multinode/</guid><description>Why Lets start with a simple question &amp;ldquo;Why to contribute?&amp;rdquo;.
In our day to day development&amp;rsquo;s and user&amp;rsquo;s life we use tons of OSS (open source) software. Ppl develop that software together to have ability to use them in more standard and open way, so they spend less time negotiating on interfaces and tools (and that is not the main reason, one of the reasons for OSS).
As any sustainable process, OSS development also needs not only users but contributors to be able to move project forward as well as to sustain bugs, time and new tech trends.</description></item><item><title>How long do you keep the metrics in PMM?</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/02/11/poll-metrics-keep/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/02/11/poll-metrics-keep/</guid><description>Hello everyone! We are indeed excited to announce that the new release of VictoriaMetrics has many exciting features, one of them being downsampling.
Downsampling helps to reduce disk space usage and improves query performance in a big and long time series if applied independently per each time series. However, this feature works only with a large number of samples per series.
As we are keen on implementing downsampling in our future releases, we would like to understand how long you keep your metrics in PMM.</description></item><item><title>How to Publish a Blog Post</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/02/10/how-to-publish-blog-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/02/10/how-to-publish-blog-post/</guid><description>If you write technical content or just want to become an author, this blog is open to you! We accept any technical articles about databases and open source technologies. Also, we have no requirements for the uniqueness of the article. If your post is published on another resource, you can duplicate it here and get more attention.
In this post, I will explain step by step how to publish a post in our Community Blog.</description></item><item><title> Comunity MeetUp - Installation of the main part of Percona products - February 9th, 2022 at 10:00 am EST</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</guid><description>This video and its transcript are from the Percona Commmunity Meetup that we had with Evgeniy Patlan last February 9th, 2022. We have talked how to install Percona&amp;rsquo;s various components, the different software that we have, specifically looking at our server software in Postgres, MySQL, and MongoDB. We tackle how to install from a repository and what are the different install options that we have?
Video Link: https://youtu.be/LkmbEql9Mj8
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:</description></item><item><title>PMM 2.26.0 Preview Release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/01/27/preview-release-2-26/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/01/27/preview-release-2-26/</guid><description>PMM 2.26.0 Preview Release Percona Monitoring and Management 2.26.0 is now available as a Preview Release.
PMM team really appreciates your feedback!
We encourage you to try this PMM Preview Release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
Release Notes can be found here
PMM server docker Instructions</description></item><item><title>How to replace `docker` with `podman` for PMM development</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/27/replace-docker-with-podman-for-pmm-dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/27/replace-docker-with-podman-for-pmm-dev/</guid><description>What is Podman? Podman is a daemonless container engine for developing, managing, and running OCI (Open Container Initiative) Containers on your Linux System. Containers can either be run as root or in rootless mode. More details here.
Check out also Kubernetes Podcast to learn more about podman and listen to it&amp;rsquo;s creators.
Why to replace? Especially in development I need simplest possible solution, I don&amp;rsquo;t need additional daemon running or allowing something to run with elevated privileges.</description></item><item><title>Percona Supports Community Events - Organize Yours With Us!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</guid><description>One of the things we love doing in Percona is participating in community events and inspiring people to stay connected in the changing world. We have experience in organizing community dinners, meetups, lectures at universities, booths, and even conferences both in-person and virtually. Percona speakers give talks on events all around the globe.
Have you ever thought about organizing a themed meeting for your local open source community? It may harbor many possibilities for you.</description></item><item><title>PMM development and testing with help of minikube</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</guid><description>Why Some time ago I needed to test PG14 with the new pg_stat_monitor version that wasn&amp;rsquo;t released. I decided to log my journey so I would spend less effort next time to replicate it.
I do use podman and run PMM with its help but I also like to hack PMM DBaaS features and think that k8s and minikube are perfect and better scalable solutions for the different development environments and especially for the number of clusters and DBs.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for Percona Monitoring and Management PMM Dec 1st, 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-december-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-december-2021/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) is designed and constantly updated with useful features for monitoring and optimizing your database performance. The Community MeetUp for PMM of last Dec 1st, 2021 was live streaming from AWS re:Invent with Michael Coburn, hosted by Matt Yonkovit. Together, they have resolved database performance issues and stump the expert.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/Ax5McTZifmw
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hello, everybody, and welcome to another Percona meetup. I am Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS at Percona, and we have Michael Coburn once again, joining us for his monthly slot to talk about PMM.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PMM Oct 27th, 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-october-2021/</guid><description>Percona Community Team orgnize Community MeetUp for Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) every month to introduce some features that help optimizing performance, and improve the security of your open-source database environments. Here is the full video recording of the live-streamed Community MeetUp for PMM of last Oct 27th, 2021. Matt Yonkovit and Michael Coburn make a demo of the dashboard and some of the more incremental changes.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/7_BF0-1o0WU</description></item><item><title>Going back to the original node_exporter in PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/10/21/going-back-to-original-pmm-node-exporter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/10/21/going-back-to-original-pmm-node-exporter/</guid><description>This is my first (I hope) post about something no so usual in our regular posts about technology.
Usually we discuss new features, talk about how to do something but even for me, a Percona developer, sometimes it is hard to know where and what to touch in PMM. There are many components, many abstractions, parts that send messages to remote APIs or agents, the PMM agent, the PMM API (pmm-managed), the command line client (pmm-admin) and all the external exporters.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PMM Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</guid><description>The Community MeetUp for PMM was an extraordinary one-hour Live Broadcast MeetUp from the OSS Summit on last Sept 29th, to talk about open source databases, observability and monitoring MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL with PMM. Percona experts Matt Yonkovit and Michael Coburn has made a PMM Demo. Check the the full recording by clicking the video here:
Video Link: https://youtu.be/2WSsmhzsVXg
Transcript Matt Yonkovit
Everybody, welcome to the OSS summit. We&amp;rsquo;re here for our PMM meetup.</description></item><item><title>Exporters Roadmap</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/11/exporters-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/11/exporters-roadmap/</guid><description>Exporters Roadmap Goals Prometheus exports as a part of PMM are a big and valuable component.
According to the goal to involve open source contributors to contribute to PMM and Percona to contribute to open source. As the main focus, it was decided to start from the exporter.
For now PMM use the next exporters:
https://github.com/percona/node_exporter https://github.com/percona/mysqld_exporter https://github.com/percona/mongodb_exporter https://github.com/percona/postgres_exporter https://github.com/Percona-Lab/clickhouse_exporter https://github.com/percona/proxysql_exporter https://github.com/percona/rds_exporter https://github.com/percona/azure_metrics_exporter Groups We can split them into three groups.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code Refactor PMM Framework Project with Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:08:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</guid><description>I am Meet Patel, 2nd year undergraduate at DAIICT, Gandhinagar, India; pursuing a bachelor’s degree in Information and Communication Technology with a minor in Computational Science.
I am proud to be selected for the Google Summer of Code program under an open source organization as big and impactful as Percona. As we head towards the end of this amazing program, I’ll try to share a general overview of what and how all of it has been implemented.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Projects for Google Summer of Code - 2020</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that Percona was selected as a participating organization for the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2020 program, this is our second year as a participating org with the GSoC program.
GSoC is a great program to involve young student developers in open source projects. We participated in the program in 2019 for the first time and we were really happy and satisfied with the results.</description></item><item><title>How do We Keep Metrics for a Long Time in VictoriaMetrics</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-anton-bystrov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-anton-bystrov/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
What is VictoriaMetrics? Why we choose it. Some data with compare VM and Prometheus. What is TSDB? How tuneup VM for preventing crash. What is deduplication, dawnsampling. How it works?
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/SGZjY7xgDwE
Transcript</description></item><item><title>PMM Development Process</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko2/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
I would discuss how to contribute to the PMM project, what process we use and show example of code contribution to the parts of PMM.
Watch Video Here Transcript</description></item><item><title>PMM on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-denys-kondratenko/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
How to run PMM on Kubernetes, demonstration and discussion of technology choices. Tip and tricks and relation to DBaaS. Q&amp;amp;A
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/bqvE_5tcL5M
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Using PMM Alerting in Production</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-francisco-bordenave/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-francisco-bordenave/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Now that you&amp;rsquo;re using PMM to identify slow queries and chart your database activity, what PMM can do for you to avoid problems? PMM is getting more and more popular for monitoring databases while features are increasing and allowing us to do more with less effort. In this talk we will show you how PMM can help you on your day to day operational tasks to prevent issues by setting up alerts.</description></item></channel></rss>