<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PMM on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/pmm/</link><description>Recent content in PMM on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/pmm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> Comunity MeetUp - The installation of the main part of Percona products - February 9th, 2022 at 10:00 am EST</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</guid><description>We will meet in The Percona Community MeetUp. Evgeniy will be joining us and talk more about the installation of main part of Percona products . Join us and ask questions and receive an answer right away.
Join us in Community MeetUp for Percona Product Day: February 9th, 2022 at 10:00 am EST (4:00 pm CET or 8:30 pm IST) Live stream on YouTube and Twitch Live chat on Discord Add this event to your Google Calendar Topic The installation of the main part of Percona products with Evgeniy Patlan and Matt Yonkovit</description></item><item><title>PMM 2.26.0 Preview Release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/01/27/preview-release-2-26/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/01/27/preview-release-2-26/</guid><description>PMM 2.26.0 Preview Release Percona Monitoring and Management 2.26.0 is now available as a Preview Release.
PMM team really appreciates your feedback!
We encourage you to try this PMM Preview Release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
Release Notes can be found here
PMM server docker Instructions</description></item><item><title>How to replace `docker` with `podman` for PMM development</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/27/replace-docker-with-podman-for-pmm-dev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/27/replace-docker-with-podman-for-pmm-dev/</guid><description>What is Podman? Podman is a daemonless container engine for developing, managing, and running OCI (Open Container Initiative) Containers on your Linux System. Containers can either be run as root or in rootless mode. More details here.
Check out also Kubernetes Podcast to learn more about podman and listen to it&amp;rsquo;s creators.
Why to replace? Especially in development I need simplest possible solution, I don&amp;rsquo;t need additional daemon running or allowing something to run with elevated privileges.</description></item><item><title>Percona Supports Community Events - Organize Yours With Us!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</guid><description>One of the things we love doing in Percona is participating in community events and inspiring people to stay connected in the changing world. We have experience in organizing community dinners, meetups, lectures at universities, booths, and even conferences both in-person and virtually. Percona speakers give talks on events all around the globe.
Have you ever thought about organizing a themed meeting for your local open source community? It may harbor many possibilities for you.</description></item><item><title>PMM development and testing with help of minikube</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</guid><description>Why Some time ago I needed to test PG14 with the new pg_stat_monitor version that wasn&amp;rsquo;t released. I decided to log my journey so I would spend less effort next time to replicate it.
I do use podman and run PMM with its help but I also like to hack PMM DBaaS features and think that k8s and minikube are perfect and better scalable solutions for the different development environments and especially for the number of clusters and DBs.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for Percona Monitoring and Management PMM Dec 1st, 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-december-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-december-2021/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) is designed and constantly updated with useful features for monitoring and optimizing your database performance. The Community MeetUp for PMM of last Dec 1st, 2021 was live streaming from AWS re:Invent with Michael Coburn, hosted by Matt Yonkovit. Together, they have resolved database performance issues and stump the expert.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/Ax5McTZifmw
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hello, everybody, and welcome to another Percona meetup. I am Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS at Percona, and we have Michael Coburn once again, joining us for his monthly slot to talk about PMM.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PMM Oct 27th, 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-october-2021/</guid><description>Percona Community Team orgnize Community MeetUp for Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) every month to introduce some features that help optimizing performance, and improve the security of your open-source database environments. Here is the full video recording of the live-streamed Community MeetUp for PMM of last Oct 27th, 2021. Matt Yonkovit and Michael Coburn make a demo of the dashboard and some of the more incremental changes.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/7_BF0-1o0WU</description></item><item><title>Going back to the original node_exporter in PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/10/21/going-back-to-original-pmm-node-exporter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/10/21/going-back-to-original-pmm-node-exporter/</guid><description>This is my first (I hope) post about something no so usual in our regular posts about technology.
Usually we discuss new features, talk about how to do something but even for me, a Percona developer, sometimes it is hard to know where and what to touch in PMM. There are many components, many abstractions, parts that send messages to remote APIs or agents, the PMM agent, the PMM API (pmm-managed), the command line client (pmm-admin) and all the external exporters.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PMM Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</guid><description>The Community MeetUp for PMM was an extraordinary one-hour Live Broadcast MeetUp from the OSS Summit on last Sept 29th, to talk about open source databases, observability and monitoring MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL with PMM. Percona experts Matt Yonkovit and Michael Coburn has made a PMM Demo. Check the the full recording by clicking the video here:
Video Link: https://youtu.be/2WSsmhzsVXg
Transcript Matt Yonkovit
Everybody, welcome to the OSS summit. We&amp;rsquo;re here for our PMM meetup.</description></item><item><title>Exporters Roadmap</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/11/exporters-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/11/exporters-roadmap/</guid><description>Exporters Roadmap Goals Prometheus exports as a part of PMM are a big and valuable component.
According to the goal to involve open source contributors to contribute to PMM and Percona to contribute to open source. As the main focus, it was decided to start from the exporter.
For now PMM use the next exporters:
https://github.com/percona/node_exporter https://github.com/percona/mysqld_exporter https://github.com/percona/mongodb_exporter https://github.com/percona/postgres_exporter https://github.com/Percona-Lab/clickhouse_exporter https://github.com/percona/proxysql_exporter https://github.com/percona/rds_exporter https://github.com/percona/azure_metrics_exporter Groups We can split them into three groups.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code Refactor PMM Framework Project with Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:08:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</guid><description>I am Meet Patel, 2nd year undergraduate at DAIICT, Gandhinagar, India; pursuing a bachelor’s degree in Information and Communication Technology with a minor in Computational Science.
I am proud to be selected for the Google Summer of Code program under an open source organization as big and impactful as Percona. As we head towards the end of this amazing program, I’ll try to share a general overview of what and how all of it has been implemented.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Projects for Google Summer of Code - 2020</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that Percona was selected as a participating organization for the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2020 program, this is our second year as a participating org with the GSoC program.
GSoC is a great program to involve young student developers in open source projects. We participated in the program in 2019 for the first time and we were really happy and satisfied with the results.</description></item></channel></rss>