<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Event on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/event/</link><description>Recent content in Event on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Road to Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/road-to-percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/road-to-percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Percona Live 2022 is coming soon! Get to know the talk of the amazing speakers and best-of-breed open source database experts, who will come to Austin to present for you this year. Matt Yonkovit, the Percona’s HOSS, met some of them virtually and recorded small previews of their talks. Watch them, find out more details about the upcoming presentations and choose which ones to join during the event.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp Queretaro 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/meetup-queretaro-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/meetup-queretaro-2022/</guid><description>On May 6th, Percona together with MedTrainer organized a meetup for the local community in Queretaro, Mexico. It took place in a wonderful location - Holiday Inn Zona Krystal Meeting Room.
Five experts and engineers presented talks on all kinds of topics from the open source world and databases:
Opening presentation by Peter Zaitsev (CEO, Percona);
Patroni, a High Availability solution for PostgreSQL by David González (PostgreSQL DBA, Percona);</description></item><item><title>Percona Community Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/</guid><description>Good news! We are happy to announce a new 100% virtual event coming up this summer - Percona Community Live!
It will take place on June 21-23 online and will be live-streamed on YouTube, LinkedIn, and Twitch. It is an excellent opportunity to learn from the best-of-breed experts directly from your home! We will focus on the latest trends in the database world, and secret tricks from the open source stars.</description></item><item><title>Percona Roadshow Coming to Your City!</title><link>https://percona.community/events/roadshow-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/roadshow-2022/</guid><description>We are pleased to invite you to a one day event as part of our 2022 Road Show around Europe and Asia.
In these sessions, our Percona experts and engineers will walk you through a broad range of topics around the open source industry, such as Percona Monitoring and Management, Percona Kubernetes Operators, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL and Percona Platform. Join us for demos, customer stories, industry news, trend analysis, and Q&amp;amp;A sessions.</description></item><item><title>Postgres Conference Silicon Valley 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2022/</guid><description>This time Percona Team flew to San Jose to participate in the Postgres Conference Silicon Valley from April 7th to 8th. This is a significant event for the Postgres Community on the West Coast.
Percona sponsored the event on the Gold level and had a huge presence there. 4 recognized database experts gave 5 stunning talks:
PostgreSQL Replication Conflicts: Avoiding Pitfalls by Hamid Akhtar (Technical Product Manager for PostgreSQL); Tune PostgreSQL for Read/Write Scalability and A Deep Dive into PostgreSQL Indexing by Ibrar Ahmed (Senior Software Architect); How Users Will Dictate and Change the Next 20 Years of PostgreSQL by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy); PL/Java - Extend the Power of Your Database by Charly Batista (PostgreSQL Tech Lead).</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2022/</guid><description>Percona Team actively participated in FOSDEM 2022. It is a large, non-commercial free event for thousands of developers of free and open-source software from all over the world to meet, share ideas and collaborate. Traditionally held in the beautiful city of Brussels (Belgium), it took place online this year on February 5-6. FOSDEM is widely recognized as the best such conference in Europe organized by the community for the community.</description></item><item><title>Chernihiv.IT Cluster Sponsorship</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-cluster/</guid><description>Percona is thrilled to support Chernihiv.IT Cluster and help to develop the local IT community in Chernihiv, Ukraine. The cluster was founded in 2017 and it unites the efforts of 11 IT companies. Percona&amp;rsquo;s engineers Evgeniy Patlan, Serhii Stasiuk, Mykola Marzhan, Maxim Kondratenko, and other Perconians in the city eagerly participate in Cluster&amp;rsquo;s activities, both online and in-person, and willingly share their knowledge and experience with others.
CHERNIHIV.IT DevOps Crash Course</description></item><item><title>PGConf NYC 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</guid><description>On December 2th-3th, Percona Team was in New York on an important event in the PostgreSQL world - PGConf NYC. It is a non–profit, community-run conference, focused on business users, database professionals, and developers of PostgreSQL. Percona was thrilled to participate in it as a Platinum sponsor this year.
Speakers from Percona gave several amazing talks at the conference:
Postgres and Json - How to get the best of them?</description></item><item><title>Balalaika Meetup With Local Community in Ulyanovsk</title><link>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</guid><description>On November 15th, Percona organized a meetup with the local community in Ulyanovsk (Russia). From Percona, there were Peter Zaitsev (CEO), Maria Azizova (Staff Executive), and Aleksandra Abramova (Community Specialist). They had a chance to meet engineers from different IT companies who live nearby.
The event took place in an interesting location. It was a private Balalaika&amp;rsquo;s Museum. It is a Russian national musical instrument. If you wonder how it sounds like, there are some examples on YouTube like this one.</description></item><item><title>Merge Conf 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/mergeconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/mergeconf-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team members visited Merge Conf 2021 in Innopolis, Russia, on November 13-14.
Percona speakers gave 2 talks on the Open Source track.
Technologies and Trends in the World of Open Source Databases in 2021 by Peter Zaitsev (CEO, Percona). Peter talked about all the main open source databases and their versatility, considered specific solutions for different situations and provided information on the changes in open source licenses and what can be expected next year.</description></item><item><title>Online Public Lecture “What is DevOps?”</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</guid><description>Percona’s Evgeniy Patlan (Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering) and Serhii Stasiuk (Build/Release Engineer) participated in an online public meetup “What is DevOps?” for students of Chernihiv Polytechnic National University. Together with Volodymyr Rudiy (CEO, Agilevision.io) and Volodymyr Bazilevich (Academic, Chernihiv Polytechnic National University), they discussed the modern views on DevOps methodology, practices and people who do this job nowadays, tasks and challenges that they face and what is expected of them on the modern labor market.</description></item><item><title>Nerdearla 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/nerdearla-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/nerdearla-2021/</guid><description>One of the virtual events Percona was happy to support this year was Nerdearla 2021, the most important IT conference in the Latin American region.
Ivan Groenewold (Architect, Percona) presented his talk “Deployando MongoDB sharded con Terraform y Ansible” (Deploying MongoDB Sharded Clusters With Terraform and Ansible”.
Link: https://youtu.be/okCaeIHa4cY
We also welcomed people to our virtual booth and distributed some white paper collateral.
Though it was lots of fun virtually, we hope that in the future we will be able to meet in person again!</description></item><item><title>National University "Chernihiv Polytechnic"</title><link>https://percona.community/events/national_university_chernihiv_polytechnic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/national_university_chernihiv_polytechnic/</guid><description>Percona encourages its staff members to actively collaborate with universities and local communities. Evgeniy Patlan (Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering) is one of those who enjoy active communication with local students and those who would like to become more familiar with modern open source technologies. In October, he participated in the student training which took place in the Ukrainian National University &amp;ldquo;Chernihiv Polytechnic&amp;rdquo;.
The mission of the National University &amp;ldquo;Chernihiv Polytechnic&amp;rdquo; is the development of society through education and research to build leadership and address global challenges in a changing world.</description></item><item><title>All Things Open 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in ATO (All Things Open) in Raleigh Convention Center on October 17th - 19th.
Percona speakers gave 4 talks during the conference:
The PostgreSQL Twin Bill: The 7 Deadly PostgreSQL Mistakes &amp;amp; Review of what&amp;rsquo;s new in PostgreSQL 14 by Matt Yonkovit (HOSS) and Barrett Chambers (Sr. Manager, Solutions Engineering). Distributed Storage in the Cloud by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Deploying MongoDB sharded clusters easily with Terraform and Ansible by Ivan Groenewold (Architect).</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit Seattle 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in the OSS event organized by Linux Foundation in Seattle in Hyatt Regency Hotel on September 27-30. It was really exciting for all of us to start meeting in person with customers, community members, and teammates as well!
Percona speakers gave 3 talks during the conference: From a database in container to DBaaS on Kubernetes by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Default to Open - Steps and Traps by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy).</description></item><item><title>OSDN Conf Kyiv 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</guid><description>Percona sponsored the OSDN Conf Kyiv which was held in person in the Nivki-hal on September 18th. It was a one-day non-commercial, volunteer-organized event centered on free and open-source software. Mykola Marzhan (Director of Server Engineering, Percona) and Evgeniy Patlan (Manager of Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering, Percona) are the main organizers of the conference.
During the event, 400 attendees had the opportunity to visit presentations by the open-source community leaders, meet each other and chat during lunch and coffee breaks, discuss the latest trends with representatives on booths.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native Data Management Day</title><link>https://percona.community/events/cloud-native-data-management-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/cloud-native-data-management-day/</guid><description>MongoDB on Kubernetes with GitOps by Sergey Pronin GitOps quickly found its way into DevOps and developer’s hearts as it greatly simplifies the application delivery pipeline. GitOps can be also used to deploy and more importantly - manage - MongoDB on Kubernetes. In this video, Sergey Pronin explains how MongoDB users can benefit from the collaboration of Kubernetes and GitOps and shows a quick demo of the example.
Video</description></item><item><title>HighLoad++ Spring 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</guid><description>Percona team participated in the HighLoad ++ Spring conference in Moscow on May 17-18, 2021. It is the most famous IT conference in Russia for developers of highload projects. This year it brought together 2000 participants offline and 2000 online running 8 parallel tracks and having 20+ company stands for networking.
On the conference, Percona speakers presented 4 talks:
MySQL 8 Observability and Query Analysis with PMM by Peter Zaitsev (CEO) Comparison of Kubernetes Operators for MySQL by Sergey Pronin (Product Owner) Migrations between schemas and updates in MySQL: mechanisms, locks, loads by Nikolay Ihalainen (Senior Support Engineer) Anatomy of a Kubernetes Operator for a database by Peter Zaitsev and Sergey Pronin.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team actively participated in FOSDEM 2021. It is a large, non-commercial free event for thousands of developers of free and open-source software from all over the world to meet, share ideas and collaborate. Traditionally held in the beautiful city of Brussels (Belgium), it took place online this year on February 6-7. FOSDEM is widely recognized as the best such conference in Europe organized by the community for the community.</description></item></channel></rss>