<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Event on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/event/</link><description>Recent content in Event on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Live Chat &amp; Demo: JS Stored Programs in Percona Server for MySQL – April 14, 2025</title><link>https://percona.community/events/2024-04-js-stored-programs-percona-server-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/2024-04-js-stored-programs-percona-server-for-mysql/</guid><description>Join the Online Stream Percona invites you to a Live Chat &amp;amp; Demo showcasing the public prototype of JS stored programs in Percona Server for MySQL!
Learn about the architecture and inner workings of stored procedures that deliver execution speeds up to 100x faster compared to traditional SQL-based procedures. Discover the current state of this feature, its architecture, practical applications, and security aspects.
Attendees will have the opportunity to ask questions and receive answers directly from the presenters and development team.</description></item><item><title>Online Stream – Removing Offensive Language from Percona Toolkit - March 27th at 13:30 pm GMT</title><link>https://percona.community/events/2025-03-sveta-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/2025-03-sveta-toolkit/</guid><description>Join Our Online Stream: War story. Removing Offensive Language from Percona Toolkit
Date: March 27, 2025
Time: 13:30 GMT / 9:30 ET Streaming Live on: LinkedIn and YouTube
About the Event We invite you to join our online stream, perfect for developers, DBAs, and anyone interested in databases and the latest advancements in MySQL and Percona Toolkit. Our featured speaker, Sveta Smirnova, is the Principal Support Engineering Coordinator at Percona. Sveta is an expert in MySQL and Percona Toolkit, an accomplished author, and a speaker at international conferences on development and databases.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Delhi 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-delhi-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-delhi-2024/</guid><description>Percona Universities are was designed to help attendees dive deep into the latest advancements in database technology. On June 21st, 2024, database enthusiasts gathered in Gurgaon to talk all things databases.
The event took place at The Circle Work Huda City Center co-working space. The location was perfect eith easy access from the metro station.
Throughout the day, various talks and sessions allowed participants to gain new insights and exchange ideas.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Limassol 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-limassol-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-limassol-2024/</guid><description>On April 20th, 2024, people who love working with databases came together in Cyprus for something special - the Percona University Limassol. Percona put on this event to help folks dive deep into the latest database tech.
The meetup was all about sharing knowledge. Percona brought in international and local experts in a database space. These experts talked about the newest trends, best ways to manage databases, and cool new solutions.</description></item><item><title>Postgres Conference 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2024/</guid><description>In April 2024, the Percona Team journeyed to San Jose for the Postgres Conference in San Jose, CA, taking place from April 17th to 19th.
This conference holds great importance for the thriving Postgres Community on the West Coast.
Percona proudly sponsored the event at the Partner level. Percona experts also gave many talks at the conference:
Reducing Costs and Improving Performance With Data Modeling in Postgres by Charly Batista. Monitoring PostgreSQL: Navigating the Landscape of Metrics, OS and Hardware Relationships, and Toolsets by Charly Batista.</description></item><item><title>PGConf India 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-india-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-india-2024/</guid><description>PGConf India 2024 took place in Bengaluru at February 28 - March 01, 2024. With about 400 conference attendees, it is the biggest Postgres event in India. This conference is part of efforts to grow the PostgreSQL community by increasing awareness and providing the appropriate training and resources to further PostgreSQL adoption in India.
Participants from 61 different cities and 10 countries gathered together in Radisson Blu Bengaluru Outer Ring Road Hotel for a 3 day event.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Meetup Brazil 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/mysql-meetup-brazil-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/mysql-meetup-brazil-2023/</guid><description>Percona co-organized a MySQL Meetup with Oracle in São Paulo on December 2nd.
We had a full day of talks on the most diverse topics about MySQL, ranging from open source tools to the Oracle cloud, and networking.
Talks will be presented in Portuguese. Below is the event agenda:
Evaluating Large Data Loads and Analysis with MySQL HeatWave Lakehouse by Narciso Oliveira Júnior (Oracle) As the number of data and connected devices grows, the demand for a better user experience and value-added services increases.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Athens 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-athens-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-athens-2023/</guid><description>Percona University Athens took place on November 7th. The event in Athens was organised with the help and sponsorship of FerretDB.
Attendees of the event had a chance to interact with recognised database experts and each other.
Speakers from different countries and companies participated in this event. Click on the links below to view the slides:
Cloud of Serfdom vs Cloud of Freedom: Why Open Source Will Win in the Cloud Age by Peter Zaitsev (Founder, Percona)</description></item><item><title>Percona University Buenos Aires 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-buenos-aires-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-buenos-aires-2023/</guid><description>Percona University came to Buenos Aires on October 20th. Percona University is a series of database meetups that we organize worldwide in different locations.
It is a wonderful opportunity to discover more about open source software, databases, and services, and speak to recognised experts and featured speakers. Build your knowledge and get up to speed on hot database topics.
Agenda included talks both in English and Spanish. Click on the talk&amp;rsquo;s titles to look through slides.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Montevideo 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-montevideo-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-montevideo-2023/</guid><description>We bring international speakers and invite local ones to help you to build your knowledge and get up to speed on hot database topics.
Percona University came to in Montevideo at October 24th. Percona University is a free database meetup open to everyone in the community.
This time agenda included talks both in English and Spanish:
Cloud of Serfdom vs Cloud of Freedom: Why Open Source Will Win in the Cloud Age by Peter Zaitsev (Founder, Percona)</description></item><item><title>HighLoad++ Serbia 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2023/</guid><description>This summer Percona Team traveled to Belgrade in Serbia to participate in 2 events - Highload++ Serbia 2023 and Percona University Belgrade.
The journey started with team building for those who arrived early. They went to a segway tour around the city and visited Belgrade Fortress with Kalemegdan park with an amazing guide who told them a lot about Serbia history. They also ride segways in the city center to get acquainted with the main tourist attractions.</description></item><item><title>PGConf Germany 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-germany-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-germany-2023/</guid><description>The PGConf Germany 2023 took place in the Haus der Technik in Essen, Germany, on June 27, 2023. It had a record-breaking registration with above 250 people.
The sessions weren’t recorded but many speakers added their slide decks to their talks, so check out the schedule if you’re interested to learn more about a specific talk.
Kai Wagner and Dimitri Vanoverbeke from Percona participated in the event and worked on Percona booth.</description></item><item><title>State of Open Con 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/sooc-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/sooc-2023/</guid><description>The State of Open Con is the UK&amp;rsquo;s open source technology conference. This year, it took place at Queen Elizabeth II Centre in London, last Feb 7-8, 2023.
SOOC23 is an excellent opportunity to meet community and industry members in Open Source Software, Open Hardware &amp;amp; Open Data. This event was organized for OpenUK, which is a not-for-profit company to develop UK Leadership &amp;amp; Global Collaboration in Open Technology. Amanda Brock inaugurated the occasion with this fantastic keynote.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2023/</guid><description>FOSDEM is very special: people from all over the world come to Brussels to participate in the biggest open source event in Europe. How many people? FOSDEM attracts more than 5000 attendees to the ULB Solbosch campus.
Many open source projects have stands at the event that are provided to them free of charge by the organizers. It is a perfect opportunity not only to collect some swag with the logo of your favorite project, but also to chat with its representatives and maybe even core developers and ask your questions in person.</description></item><item><title>PGConf India 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-india-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-india-2023/</guid><description>PGConf India 2023 started on a fresh note after 2 years of gap due to the pandemic. With 400+ conference attendees and 150+ attendees for the training program, it was a great event.
There were three parallel tracks for the presentations. Jobin Augustine, PostgreSQL Escalation Specialist from Percona, gave 2 talks during the event:
Reducing PostgreSQL Costs in the Cloud In the face of economic uncertainty and a possible recession, many companies are trimming expenses, freezing hiring, and, in some cases, laying off staff.</description></item><item><title>preFOSDEM MySQL Days 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/prefosdem-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/prefosdem-2023/</guid><description>Two days before the main FOSDEM event, MySQL enthusiasts all over the world gather together for learning and networking at preFOSDEM MySQL Days in Brussels. This time the event took place at the same building where it was interrupted by COVID - ICAB Incubator. The event was free but required registration due to limited capacity. A couple of weeks before the event, all available tickets were sold out.
The room was almost full.</description></item><item><title>International Day of Computer Security 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/international-day-of-computer-security-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/international-day-of-computer-security-2022/</guid><description>On November 30th, Percona&amp;rsquo;s Technical Evangelists Edith Puclla and Mario García participated in the International Day of Computer Security. An event organized by Comunidad Tecnológica Tapachula together with Universidad Filantrópica Internacional, in Tapachula, Mexico.
Two talks in Spanish were presented at this event:
Docker: Basic Hands-On by Edith Puclla;
Slides Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) for Novices by Mario García.
Slides The event lasted 2 and a half hours, with two in-person speakers (including Mario) and three speakers who joined the event virtually (including Edith).</description></item><item><title>Percona University Istanbul 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2022/</guid><description>Percona University is a series of database meetups that we organize worldwide in different locations. November 5th we came to Istanbul, economical, cultural and historical heart of Turkiye. HostedPMM and FerretDB supported us during this meetup and sponsored it.
It was a wonderful sunny day in Istanbul. We gathered together early in the morning at Kolektif House. It is an awesome coworking place with wonderful inhabitants and all the necessary equipment to hold an event.</description></item><item><title>Chernihiv.IT Conf: Tech Front</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-conf-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-conf-2022/</guid><description>Percona sponsored an amazing event organized by Chernihiv.IT Cluster - Chernihiv.IT Conf: Tech Front. It was an online event organized in support to Chernihiv and IT industry in this city. It was an online event and it attackted a lot of attendees from Chernihiv and all over Ukraine.
Evgeniy Patlan, Manager in Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering, was in the role of the host greeting speakers, communicating with them and asking questions.</description></item><item><title>FTD Data 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</guid><description>A big part of the Percona Brazilian team gathered together in Florianópolis to participate in a special edition of the Floripa Tech Day (FTD), focused on DATA. The agenda included talks on various technologies: MongoDB, MS-SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, and PostgreSQL.
It was a 1-day event with 13 talks from early morining till late evening. Three of them were deliverd by Percona speakers:
Online Backup in MySQL with XtraBackup by Marcelo Altmann (Software Engineer).</description></item><item><title>PGConf NYC 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pfcong-nyc-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pfcong-nyc-2022/</guid><description>The PostgreSQL NYC is a PostgreSQL community conference that was held in the last week of September 2022. It is a non–profit, community-run conference. About 140+ attendees participated in the event. Percona supported the conference on a Broze level and also provided additional support, for example, sponsoring speaker/stuff dinner.
Two speakers from Percona gave amazing talks:
A Deep Dive Into PostgreSQL Indexing by Ibrar Ahmed. Abstract: Indexes are a fundamental feature of relational databases, and PostgreSQL offers developers and designers a rich collection of options.</description></item><item><title>Elisa Usai at POUG 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/elisa-pmm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/elisa-pmm/</guid><description>Elisa Usai from dbi participated in POUG 2022 and gave a talk about Percona Monitoring and Management. POUG (Polish Oracle User Group) organizes as usual his annual conference in Poland in September to discuss about Oracle topics. The 7th edition of 2022 took place in Wrocław on September 9 and 10.
Elisa is an amazing speaker. She give an overview of the tool, explained how easy it is to install and turn on monitoring and show the some features such as integrated alerting, Query Analytics to get performance metrics over a period of time, Advisors checks to perform some security checks on databases, and more!</description></item><item><title>PGConf Brazil 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconfbrazil-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconfbrazil-2022/</guid><description>Percona supports events all over the globe. We were so happy to participate in a big (maybe even the largest!) Postgres event in Brazil - PGConf Brazil 2022. It is a world-class conference, which builds on the efforts of professionals and enthusiasts to expand the community of PostgreSQL, enabling participants to develop new knowledge through lectures and training.
Since the pandemic has slowed down a bit and allowed all of us to gather together safely again, we take part in offline events again and this is super exciting.</description></item><item><title>SCaLE 19X 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/scale19x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/scale19x/</guid><description>This July, Percona Team met in Los Angeles. We participated in the Scale 19x from July 28th to 31st. SCaLE is the largest community-run open-source and free software conference in North America. It is held annually in the greater Los Angeles area. It was a big event with many sponsors this year.
Percona sponsored the event on the Silver level and had a huge presence there. 5 experienced Percona experts gave several talks:</description></item><item><title>Percona Community Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/</guid><description>Good news! We are happy to announce a new 100% virtual event coming up this summer - Percona Community Live!
Agenda is ready and published here Links to the streaming here It will take place on June 21-23 online and will be live-streamed on YouTube, LinkedIn, and Twitch. It is an excellent opportunity to learn from the best-of-breed experts directly from your home! We will focus on the latest trends in the database world, and secret tricks from the open source stars.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Links Percona Live 2022 was an amazing 3-day event of keynotes, educational sessions, hands-on activities, and more. It took place in Austin, TX on May 16th-18th. Attendees could hear the biggest names in the industry, discuss their experience, dive deep into software, and offer actionable advice. They also learned about how open source database technology can power applications, improve websites, secure data, and solve critical database issues. On this page, you can find the list of presentations from Percona Live 2022.</description></item><item><title>Road to Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/road-to-percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/road-to-percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Percona Live 2022 is coming soon! Get to know the talk of the amazing speakers and best-of-breed open source database experts, who will come to Austin to present for you this year. Matt Yonkovit, the Percona’s HOSS, met some of them virtually and recorded small previews of their talks. Watch them, find out more details about the upcoming presentations and choose which ones to join during the event.
This page is constantly updated.</description></item><item><title>DoK Istanbul Meetup 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dok-istanbul-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dok-istanbul-2022/</guid><description>Ege Güneş, Percona&amp;rsquo;s Software Engineer, participated in the first DoK Istanbul Meetup on May 12th. It took place at the TurkNet office.
Several talks were presented that day:
Alkin Tezuysal, EVP at ChistaDATA Inc., gave an intro about the Data on Kubernetes Community, what he&amp;rsquo;s doing at ChistaDATA with Clickhouse, and an update about his book. Ege Gunes wtold everyone about Percona Operators- current features, roadmap, and demos. Murat from Turknet gave a talk about how TurkNet does DevOps.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp Queretaro 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/meetup-queretaro-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/meetup-queretaro-2022/</guid><description>On May 6th, Percona together with MedTrainer organized a meetup for the local community in Queretaro, Mexico. It took place in a wonderful location - Holiday Inn Zona Krystal Meeting Room.
Five experts and engineers presented talks on all kinds of topics from the open source world and databases:
Opening presentation by Peter Zaitsev (CEO, Percona);
Patroni, a High Availability solution for PostgreSQL by David González (PostgreSQL DBA, Percona);</description></item><item><title>Percona Roadshow Coming to Your City!</title><link>https://percona.community/events/roadshow-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/roadshow-2022/</guid><description>We are pleased to invite you to a one day event as part of our 2022 Road Show around Europe and Asia.
In these sessions, our Percona experts and engineers will walk you through a broad range of topics around the open source industry, such as Percona Monitoring and Management, Percona Kubernetes Operators, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL and Percona Platform. Join us for demos, customer stories, industry news, trend analysis, and Q&amp;amp;A sessions.</description></item><item><title>Postgres Conference Silicon Valley 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2022/</guid><description>This time Percona Team flew to San Jose to participate in the Postgres Conference Silicon Valley from April 7th to 8th. This is a significant event for the Postgres Community on the West Coast.
Percona sponsored the event on the Gold level and had a huge presence there. 4 recognized database experts gave 5 stunning talks:
PostgreSQL Replication Conflicts: Avoiding Pitfalls by Hamid Akhtar (Technical Product Manager for PostgreSQL); Tune PostgreSQL for Read/Write Scalability and A Deep Dive into PostgreSQL Indexing by Ibrar Ahmed (Senior Software Architect); How Users Will Dictate and Change the Next 20 Years of PostgreSQL by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy); PL/Java - Extend the Power of Your Database by Charly Batista (PostgreSQL Tech Lead).</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2022/</guid><description>Percona Team actively participated in FOSDEM 2022. It is a large, non-commercial free event for thousands of developers of free and open-source software from all over the world to meet, share ideas and collaborate. Traditionally held in the beautiful city of Brussels (Belgium), it took place online this year on February 5-6. FOSDEM is widely recognized as the best such conference in Europe organized by the community for the community.</description></item><item><title>Chernihiv.IT Cluster Sponsorship</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-cluster/</guid><description>Percona is thrilled to support Chernihiv.IT Cluster and help to develop the local IT community in Chernihiv, Ukraine. The cluster was founded in 2017 and it unites the efforts of 11 IT companies. Percona&amp;rsquo;s engineers Evgeniy Patlan, Serhii Stasiuk, Mykola Marzhan, Maxim Kondratenko, and other Perconians in the city eagerly participate in Cluster&amp;rsquo;s activities, both online and in-person, and willingly share their knowledge and experience with others.
CHERNIHIV.IT DevOps Crash Course</description></item><item><title>PGConf NYC 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</guid><description>On December 2th-3th, Percona Team was in New York on an important event in the PostgreSQL world - PGConf NYC. It is a non–profit, community-run conference, focused on business users, database professionals, and developers of PostgreSQL. Percona was thrilled to participate in it as a Platinum sponsor this year.
Speakers from Percona gave several amazing talks at the conference:
Postgres and Json - How to get the best of them? by Charly Batista (PostgreSQL Tech Lead).</description></item><item><title>Balalaika Meetup With Local Community in Ulyanovsk</title><link>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</guid><description>On November 15th, Percona organized a meetup with the local community in Ulyanovsk (Russia). From Percona, there were Peter Zaitsev (CEO), Maria Azizova (Staff Executive), and Aleksandra Abramova (Community Specialist). They had a chance to meet engineers from different IT companies who live nearby.
The event took place in an interesting location. It was a private Balalaika&amp;rsquo;s Museum. It is a Russian national musical instrument. If you wonder how it sounds like, there are some examples on YouTube like this one.</description></item><item><title>Merge Conf 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/mergeconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/mergeconf-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team members visited Merge Conf 2021 in Innopolis, Russia, on November 13-14.
Percona speakers gave 2 talks on the Open Source track.
Technologies and Trends in the World of Open Source Databases in 2021 by Peter Zaitsev (CEO, Percona). Peter talked about all the main open source databases and their versatility, considered specific solutions for different situations and provided information on the changes in open source licenses and what can be expected next year.</description></item><item><title>Online Public Lecture “What is DevOps?”</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</guid><description>Percona’s Evgeniy Patlan (Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering) and Serhii Stasiuk (Build/Release Engineer) participated in an online public meetup “What is DevOps?” for students of Chernihiv Polytechnic National University. Together with Volodymyr Rudiy (CEO, Agilevision.io) and Volodymyr Bazilevich (Academic, Chernihiv Polytechnic National University), they discussed the modern views on DevOps methodology, practices and people who do this job nowadays, tasks and challenges that they face and what is expected of them on the modern labor market.</description></item><item><title>Nerdearla 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/nerdearla-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/nerdearla-2021/</guid><description>One of the virtual events Percona was happy to support this year was Nerdearla 2021, the most important IT conference in the Latin American region.
Ivan Groenewold (Architect, Percona) presented his talk “Deployando MongoDB sharded con Terraform y Ansible” (Deploying MongoDB Sharded Clusters With Terraform and Ansible”.
Link: https://youtu.be/okCaeIHa4cY
We also welcomed people to our virtual booth and distributed some white paper collateral.
Though it was lots of fun virtually, we hope that in the future we will be able to meet in person again!</description></item><item><title>National University "Chernihiv Polytechnic"</title><link>https://percona.community/events/national_university_chernihiv_polytechnic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/national_university_chernihiv_polytechnic/</guid><description>Percona encourages its staff members to actively collaborate with universities and local communities. Evgeniy Patlan (Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering) is one of those who enjoy active communication with local students and those who would like to become more familiar with modern open source technologies. In October, he participated in the student training which took place in the Ukrainian National University &amp;ldquo;Chernihiv Polytechnic&amp;rdquo;.
The mission of the National University &amp;ldquo;Chernihiv Polytechnic&amp;rdquo; is the development of society through education and research to build leadership and address global challenges in a changing world.</description></item><item><title>All Things Open 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in ATO (All Things Open) in Raleigh Convention Center on October 17th - 19th.
Percona speakers gave 4 talks during the conference:
The PostgreSQL Twin Bill: The 7 Deadly PostgreSQL Mistakes &amp;amp; Review of what&amp;rsquo;s new in PostgreSQL 14 by Matt Yonkovit (HOSS) and Barrett Chambers (Sr. Manager, Solutions Engineering). Distributed Storage in the Cloud by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Deploying MongoDB sharded clusters easily with Terraform and Ansible by Ivan Groenewold (Architect).</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit Seattle 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in the OSS event organized by Linux Foundation in Seattle in Hyatt Regency Hotel on September 27-30. It was really exciting for all of us to start meeting in person with customers, community members, and teammates as well!
Percona speakers gave 3 talks during the conference: From a database in container to DBaaS on Kubernetes by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Default to Open - Steps and Traps by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy).</description></item><item><title>OSDN Conf Kyiv 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</guid><description>Percona sponsored the OSDN Conf Kyiv which was held in person in the Nivki-hal on September 18th. It was a one-day non-commercial, volunteer-organized event centered on free and open-source software. Mykola Marzhan (Director of Server Engineering, Percona) and Evgeniy Patlan (Manager of Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering, Percona) are the main organizers of the conference.
During the event, 400 attendees had the opportunity to visit presentations by the open-source community leaders, meet each other and chat during lunch and coffee breaks, discuss the latest trends with representatives on booths.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native Data Management Day</title><link>https://percona.community/events/cloud-native-data-management-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/cloud-native-data-management-day/</guid><description>MongoDB on Kubernetes with GitOps by Sergey Pronin GitOps quickly found its way into DevOps and developer’s hearts as it greatly simplifies the application delivery pipeline. GitOps can be also used to deploy and more importantly - manage - MongoDB on Kubernetes. In this video, Sergey Pronin explains how MongoDB users can benefit from the collaboration of Kubernetes and GitOps and shows a quick demo of the example.
Video Link: https://www.</description></item><item><title>HighLoad++ Spring 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</guid><description>Percona team participated in the HighLoad ++ Spring conference in Moscow on May 17-18, 2021. It is the most famous IT conference in Russia for developers of highload projects. This year it brought together 2000 participants offline and 2000 online running 8 parallel tracks and having 20+ company stands for networking.
On the conference, Percona speakers presented 4 talks:
MySQL 8 Observability and Query Analysis with PMM by Peter Zaitsev (CEO) Comparison of Kubernetes Operators for MySQL by Sergey Pronin (Product Owner) Migrations between schemas and updates in MySQL: mechanisms, locks, loads by Nikolay Ihalainen (Senior Support Engineer) Anatomy of a Kubernetes Operator for a database by Peter Zaitsev and Sergey Pronin.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team actively participated in FOSDEM 2021. It is a large, non-commercial free event for thousands of developers of free and open-source software from all over the world to meet, share ideas and collaborate. Traditionally held in the beautiful city of Brussels (Belgium), it took place online this year on February 6-7. FOSDEM is widely recognized as the best such conference in Europe organized by the community for the community.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/</guid><description>Percona Live Community Rooms Percona Community worked together with other communities to organize Community Tracks at Percona Live.
Select a room to watch the content.
Full list of speakers on the Speakers page.</description></item></channel></rss>