<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MongoDB on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/mongodb/</link><description>Recent content in MongoDB on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/mongodb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> Installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes Operator - Community MeetUp - March 10th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-10-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-10-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</guid><description>Check this full recording of the Percona Community MeetUp of March 10th hosted and learn more about installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes operator. Matt Yonkovit, the Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona, and Sergey Pronin, Product Owner at Percona, took us through the step-by-step setup to get us started with a new MongoDB cluster.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/HZ9yaS-ZS48
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Helloб everyone out there in the stream land.</description></item><item><title> Community MeetUp - Installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes Operator - POSTPONED</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-24-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-24-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</guid><description>Hello,
We are sorry to inform you that we have to POSTPONE our Community MeetUp of Today Thursday, Feb 24th, 11 am EST (5:00 pm CEST / 9:30 pm IST). A new schedule of the meeting will be announced soon.
Thank you for your understanding.
Percona Community Team
Join us in The Percona Community MeetUp and walk with us through the installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes operator.</description></item><item><title> Comunity MeetUp - Installation of the main part of Percona products - February 9th, 2022 at 10:00 am EST</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</guid><description>This video and its transcript are from the Percona Commmunity Meetup that we had with Evgeniy Patlan last February 9th, 2022. We have talked how to install Percona&amp;rsquo;s various components, the different software that we have, specifically looking at our server software in Postgres, MySQL, and MongoDB. We tackle how to install from a repository and what are the different install options that we have?
Video Link: https://youtu.be/LkmbEql9Mj8
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:</description></item><item><title>Percona Supports Community Events - Organize Yours With Us!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</guid><description>One of the things we love doing in Percona is participating in community events and inspiring people to stay connected in the changing world. We have experience in organizing community dinners, meetups, lectures at universities, booths, and even conferences both in-person and virtually. Percona speakers give talks on events all around the globe.
Have you ever thought about organizing a themed meeting for your local open source community? It may harbor many possibilities for you.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MongoDB Oct 20th, 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-october-2021/</guid><description>This video from Percona MeetUp for MongoDB of October 20th talk about backups, scalability, security, MongoDB 5.0, and more. Full recording with Andrew Pogrebnoi, Principal Software Engineer at Percona, and Kimberly Wilkins, MongoDB Technical Lead at Percona, hosted by Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/YnQu2Ock2d8
Transcript Matt Yonkovit
Hello everyone. Welcome to another Percona meetup this week is our MongoDB meetup week. So, glad to have everyone with us.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MongoDB Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-september-2021/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit hosted the Percona MeetUp for MongoDB on September 22nd with Vinodh Krishnaswamy, Support Engineer at Percona, to talk about &amp;ldquo;MongoDB sharded Cluster- best practices&amp;rdquo; and Ege Güneş, Software Engineer at Percona, to discuss &amp;ldquo;Cross-regional replication for MongoDB with Kubernetes&amp;rdquo;. Check full video on youtube by clicking the link below :
Video Link: https://youtu.be/s7v8hAC55iw
Transcript Matt Yonkovit Good amazing that&amp;rsquo;s a cool whoa
Hello everybody welcome to another Зercona live streamб we are at the top of the hour so thank you for joining us today I&amp;rsquo;ve got Ege and Vinodh with me from Team Perconaю So hello guys I&amp;rsquo;m gonna go ahead and I&amp;rsquo;m gonna turn on the chat so we can see anybody who pops in here and asks us some questions.</description></item><item><title>IoT Performance Bottlenecks &amp; Open Source Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</guid><description>The Internet of Things (IoT), in essence, is all about everyday devices that are readable, recognizable, trackable, and/or controllable via the Internet, regardless of the communication means — RFID, wireless LAN, and so on. The total installed base of IoT connected devices is projected to amount to 21.5 billion units worldwide by 2025. Thanks to IoT, the proliferation of data can be quite daunting. Hence, businesses should effectively organize and work with this enormous amount of valuable data.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe '19: MongoDB 4.2</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/18/percona-live-europe-19-mongodb-4-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 15:22:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/18/percona-live-europe-19-mongodb-4-2/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s all about MongoDB® 4.2 this time. MongoDB 4.2 released like a month ago (still newborn) and I am going to cover what&amp;rsquo;s new in three different areas: sharding, indexing, and the aggregation framework. I can promise you this, there are a lot of new features and improvements in MongoDB 4.2 and I am thrilled to present those to you. Join me at Percona Live Europe, and discover how distributed transactions, wildcard indexes and materialized views (plus many other new features) actually work and fit on your workload.</description></item><item><title>The Concept of Materialized Views in MongoDB Sharded Clusters</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/16/concept-materialized-views-mongodb-sharded-clusters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 10:14:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/16/concept-materialized-views-mongodb-sharded-clusters/</guid><description>In one of my past blogs I explained the contribution of MongoDB® views in organization security. In this blog, I will take it one step further and I will try to approach the concept of a materialized view in MongoDB. In computing, a materialized view is a database object that contains the results of a query (definition taken from Wikipedia). If you are already familiar with MongoDB views (or you read my blog), you are now probably wondering why I am calling the MongoDB views materialized while it&amp;rsquo;s well known that they are computed on the fly?</description></item><item><title>London Open Source Database Community Meetup</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 09:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</guid><description>I strongly believe in the community.
Communities are the real strength of open source. Not just the theoretical ability to study, modify and share code – but the fact that other people out there are doing these things. Creating a base of knowledge and a network of relations.These can become work relationships, valuable discussions, open source tools, or even friendships.
That is why, when I heard that several people from the Percona support team will soon be in London, I badly wanted to organise an event.</description></item><item><title>An Introduction To MongoDB Replication</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/01/14/introduction-mongodb-replication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 11:21:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/01/14/introduction-mongodb-replication/</guid><description>MongoDB® is database software that stores data in the same format as JSON. The data structure of the database can be changed when required. The performance of the database is good and developers can easily use to it to connect their code to the database.
The database, MongoDB is platform independent and runs in the same way on all platforms. It is an open source database and is based on a document-oriented database model.</description></item><item><title>Export to JSON from MySQL All Ready for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/export-to-json-from-mysql-all-ready-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 15:18:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/16/export-to-json-from-mysql-all-ready-for-mongodb/</guid><description>This post walks through how to export data from MySQL® into JSON format, ready to ingest into MongoDB®. Starting from MySQL 5.7+, there is native support for JSON. MySQL provides functions that actually create JSON values, so I will be using these functions in this article to export to JSON from MySQL:
JSON_OBJECT JSON_ARRAY These functions make it easy to convert MySQL data to JSON e.g.
mysql&amp;gt; SELECT json_object(&amp;#39;employee_id&amp;#39;, emp_no, &amp;#39;first_name&amp;#39;, first_name ) AS &amp;#39;JSON&amp;#39; FROM employees LIMIT 2; +------------------------------------------------+ | JSON | +------------------------------------------------+ | {&amp;#34;first_name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Aamer&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;employee_id&amp;#34;: 444117} | | {&amp;#34;first_name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Aamer&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;employee_id&amp;#34;: 409151} | +------------------------------------------------+ 2 rows in set (0.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Elasticsearch 101</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 07:17:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/03/percona-live-tutorial-elasticsearch-101/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe, I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting the tutorial Elasticsearch 101 alongside my colleagues and fellow presenters from ObjectRocket Alex Cercel, DBA, and Mihai Aldoiu, Data Engineer. Here&amp;rsquo;s a brief overview of our tutorial.
Elasticsearch® is well known as a highly scalable search engine that stores data in a structure optimized for language based searches but its capabilities and use cases don’t stop there. In this tutorial, we’ll give you a hands-on introduction to Elasticsearch and give you a glimpse at some of the fundamental concepts.</description></item><item><title>7 Checks to Successfully Upgrade MongoDB Replica Set in Production</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/29/7-checks-successfully-upgrade-mongodb-replica-set-production/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:23:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/29/7-checks-successfully-upgrade-mongodb-replica-set-production/</guid><description>MongoDB ships powerful features in each release. The new release brings new features while revisions add bug fixes, security patches or improvements to existing features. To bring most out these releases to your plate you should always consider upgrading your MongoDB deployments.
Planning your database upgrade can avoid the nightmares caused due to database-upgrade-gone-wrong or avoid not-so-simple rollbacks in your production database. Grab a cup of coffee and sit back.</description></item><item><title>Physical Backups with Percona Backup for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-sergey-pronin2/</guid><description>Reduce Recovery Time Objective with new Physical Backups functionality in Percona Backup for MongoDB (PBM). We will explain the value, the limitations of our solution and go deeper into the mechanics of how it works.</description></item><item><title>Walking Through Identifying and Drilling Into a Slow Down in MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-divyanshu-soni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-divyanshu-soni/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>