<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Monitoring on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/monitoring/</link><description>Recent content in Monitoring on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/monitoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0-Beta - Tech Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/12/02/percona-monitoring-management-technical-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/12/02/percona-monitoring-management-technical-preview/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0 Beta - Tech Preview We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the Tech Preview (Beta) release of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 3.0.0-Beta.
This release is intended for testing environments only, as it&amp;rsquo;s not yet production-ready. The GA (General Availability) release will be available through standard channels in the upcoming months.
Release notes To see the full list of changes, check out the 3.0.0-Beta - Tech Preview Release Notes</description></item><item><title>Dolphie, your real-time MySQL monitoring assistant</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/22/dolphie-your-real-time-mysql-monitoring-assistant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/22/dolphie-your-real-time-mysql-monitoring-assistant/</guid><description>For as long as I can remember, Innotop has been the go-to terminal tool for real-time MySQL monitoring. It is an invaluable addition to any DBA&amp;rsquo;s toolkit, but unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s not really actively maintained these days, except for addressing critical issues, and it hasn&amp;rsquo;t kept pace with the evolving capabilities of modern terminals. With no viable alternatives except for InnotopGo, which is also no longer actively maintained and limited to MySQL 8 (while many still use 5.</description></item><item><title>PMM Client on Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/15/pmm-client-on-raspberry-pi-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/15/pmm-client-on-raspberry-pi-4/</guid><description>This will be the third in my series of Percona Products on a Raspberry Pi. My previous posts:
How to Build a Percona Server &amp;ldquo;Stack&amp;rdquo; on a Raspberry Pi 3+ Raspberry Pi Bullseye Percona Server 64bit Before I get started I would like to thank guriandoro, for the work he did in compiling the PMM Client tools in his 2021 blog.
My regular readers know how much I love the Raspberry Pi and MySQL.</description></item><item><title>How a Database Monitoring Tool Can Help a Developer. The Story of One Mistake.</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/07/how-a-database-monitoring-tool-can-help-a-developer.-the-story-of-one-mistake./</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/07/how-a-database-monitoring-tool-can-help-a-developer.-the-story-of-one-mistake./</guid><description>I will tell you the real story of using database monitoring tools when developing an application. I will show you an example of how I managed to detect and fix a problem in the application.
A small clarification, the real story from my development practice happened a little more than a week ago, but for the article I took graphs of final debugging, so that the graphs show the correct sequence and fit into the available for explanation and demonstration.</description></item><item><title>Node metrics available inside of a container</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/06/node-metrics-container/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/06/node-metrics-container/</guid><description>Several people asked me this question: Could we get Node metrics inside of a container?
Usually, this comes from the fact that PMM or standalone people run node_exporter inside a container. PMM does it as a sidecar along with many other exporters to monitor DBs, and node_exporter comes out of the box as a default one. So people could see accurate data on dashboards, like Memory and CPU, that node_exporter reads inside the container.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up PMM For Monitoring Your Databases on Windows</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/16/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-your-databases-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/16/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-your-databases-on-windows/</guid><description>Before deploying Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) in production, you might want to test it or set up a development instance locally. Since many developers and DBAs have Windows desktops, I wanted to demonstrate how to set up PMM on Windows for an easy test environment. In this post, I’ll walk you through setting up PMM with Docker and WSL.
If you’re a Linux user, check the blog post I wrote on Setting up PMM for monitoring MySQL in a local environment.</description></item><item><title>Dashboard Story: How We Created PMM Dashboard for Highload</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/22/dashboard-story-how-we-created-pmm-dashboard-for-highload/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/22/dashboard-story-how-we-created-pmm-dashboard-for-highload/</guid><description>Let’s say you have highload instances. How do you monitor them? There are a lot of servers with 100, 200… 500+ nodes. How can we collect, check, and analyze metrics from all these servers? How can we understand what and where something happened? Scroll, scroll, scroll&amp;hellip; down? That was the task that we faced at Percona and successfully resolved.
Issue With Home Dashboard Percona Monitoring and Management dashboards are based on Grafana.</description></item><item><title>Exporters Roadmap</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/11/exporters-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/11/exporters-roadmap/</guid><description>Exporters Roadmap Goals Prometheus exports as a part of PMM are a big and valuable component.
According to the goal to involve open source contributors to contribute to PMM and Percona to contribute to open source. As the main focus, it was decided to start from the exporter.
For now PMM use the next exporters:
https://github.com/percona/node_exporter https://github.com/percona/mysqld_exporter https://github.com/percona/mongodb_exporter https://github.com/percona/postgres_exporter https://github.com/Percona-Lab/clickhouse_exporter https://github.com/percona/proxysql_exporter https://github.com/percona/rds_exporter https://github.com/percona/azure_metrics_exporter Groups We can split them into three groups.</description></item><item><title>On the Observability of Outliers</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/11/23/on-the-observability-of-outliers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 17:41:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/11/23/on-the-observability-of-outliers/</guid><description>At work, I am in an ongoing discussion with a number of people on the Observability of Outliers. It started with the age-old question “How do I find slow queries in my application?” aka “What would I want from tooling to get that data and where should that tooling sit?”
As a developer, I just want to automatically identify and isolate slow queries!
Where I work, we do have SolarWinds Database Performance Monitor aka Vividcortex to find slow queries, so that helps.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0-GA - Tech Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/1/01/01/percona-monitoring-management-technical-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/1/01/01/percona-monitoring-management-technical-preview/</guid><description>Percona Monitoring and Management 3.0.0 GA - Tech Preview We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce the Tech Preview release of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) 3.0.0 (GA).
This release is intended for testing environments only, as it&amp;rsquo;s not yet production-ready. The public release will be available through standard channels in upcoming days.
Release notes To see the full list of changes, check out the 3.0.0-GA - Tech Preview Release Notes
Installation options PMM Server Docker Server image: docker pull perconalab/pmm-server:3.</description></item></channel></rss>