<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Take a Clone it will last longer</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/02/take-a-clone-it-will-last-longer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/02/take-a-clone-it-will-last-longer/</guid><description>So cloning is a great subject. I mean we clone sheep, we can clone human organs in time we might be able to clone humans, but thats a topic for scientist and philosophers.
What is MySQL Replicaion:
The MySQL clone plugin can be used to replicate data from a MySQL server to another MySQL server, and it supports replication. The cloning process creates a physical snapshot of the data, including tables, schemas, tablespaces, and data dictionary metadata.</description></item><item><title>Open Source And Recession – An Economic Outlook</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/09/14/open-source-and-recession-an-economic-outlook/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/09/14/open-source-and-recession-an-economic-outlook/</guid><description>Initially, I dropped an idea of writing this blog by reckoning the amount of time and energy required to perform research. However, my mentor Ramona Gerum motivated me and provided inputs to write this blog. This would not have been possible without her help. Thank you very much Ramona.
Introduction In October 2022, the term recession gained popularity on Google trends. This happened as many economists already predicted a slowdown, and it started flashing on news channels world-wide.</description></item><item><title>Nurturing, Motivating and Recognizing Non-Code Contributions</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/08/nurturing-motivating-and-recognizing-non-code-contributions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/08/nurturing-motivating-and-recognizing-non-code-contributions/</guid><description>When discussing contributions, we still see a lot of emphasis on the code contributions into project repositories. But the open source world is extensive and diverse, and everyone can find their place there. Your project will benefit from various experiences that non-coders can bring to the table. Isn’t that cool when you receive an issue with an interesting bug from the community, read about a user case in a blog or a review, or someone makes a video guide for your product?</description></item><item><title>Open Source for Non-Techs - Find Your Way to Contribute!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/09/29/open-source-for-non-techs-find-your-way-to-contribute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/09/29/open-source-for-non-techs-find-your-way-to-contribute/</guid><description>When we talk about open source contributing, we often associate it with only and exclusively code contributions made by engineers. But the open source world is extensive and diverse, and everyone can find their place there. Even if you don’t feel confident with coding, you can have a lot of things to keep you busy! What can it give back to you? Lots of stuff: sharping your professional skills and obtaining diversified experience, enriching your portfolio, connecting with open source community and passionate people, and last but not the least - definitely lots of fun.</description></item><item><title>Monthly Percona Developer Meetup</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/09/26/monthly-percona-developer-meetup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/09/26/monthly-percona-developer-meetup/</guid><description>What is this? This new meetup is your chance to get a behind-the-scenes view and to interact directly in person with our engineers. You can jump into the session and discuss with our engineers without any barriers in between. If you do have questions, new ideas, enhancements, or are just curious to learn more, you’re welcome to join our call.
We’ll discuss development practices, tools, projects, frameworks, and many more engineering-focused topics we are working on at Percona.</description></item><item><title>Percona Projects for Google Summer of Code - 2020</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that Percona was selected as a participating organization for the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2020 program, this is our second year as a participating org with the GSoC program.
GSoC is a great program to involve young student developers in open source projects. We participated in the program in 2019 for the first time and we were really happy and satisfied with the results.</description></item></channel></rss>