<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Featured on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/featured/</link><description>Recent content in Featured on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learn PostgreSQL and SQL Quickly and Free</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/20/learn-postgresql-and-sql-quickly-and-free/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/20/learn-postgresql-and-sql-quickly-and-free/</guid><description>Learn PostgreSQL and SQL Quickly and Free
Want to learn PostgreSQL? What if you could learn PostgreSQL without having to install the database, load data, find sample data, and it was free? PGExamples.com is what you are looking for.
First, let me state that I have no connection to the website or its author. I discovered PgExercises.com by accident and was impressed by its quality and completeness. I am so impressed that I am exploring a video series on it.</description></item><item><title>How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes with Percona Everest Summary</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</guid><description>Kubernetes continues evolving, and the complexity of deploying and managing databases within the ecosystem is a topic of considerable discussion and importance these days. This article summarizes a detailed discussion between Piotr Szczepaniak and Diogo Recharte, who offer insights and live demonstrations to simplify database operations on Kubernetes with a new technology for cloud-native applications: Percona Everest. If you want to watch the full video, check out How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes Webinar.</description></item><item><title>Open Door MongoDB Chats</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/26/open-door-mongodb-chats/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/26/open-door-mongodb-chats/</guid><description>Let’s talk about MongoDB! This week, Jan Wieremjewicz, Senior Product Manager, and Michal Nosek, Pre-Sales Enterprise Architect at Percona, made two series of videos covering basic to advanced concepts in MongoDB and backups. Le’s explore them together!
Enterprise Scale Backups for MongoDB with Open Source Software In the first video about enterprise-scale backups for MongoDB using open-source software, Jan and Michal discuss the challenges and solutions associated with backing up large datasets in MongoDB.</description></item></channel></rss>