<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Source Databases on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/open-source-databases/</link><description>Recent content in Open Source Databases on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:33:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/open-source-databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Embracing the Stream</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/10/embracing-the-stream/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:33:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/10/embracing-the-stream/</guid><description>So this happened: CentOS Project shifts focus to CentOS Stream
The future of the CentOS Project is CentOS Stream, and over the next year we’ll be shifting focus from CentOS Linux, the rebuild of Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), to CentOS Stream, which tracks just ahead of a current RHEL release. CentOS Linux 8, as a rebuild of RHEL 8, will end at the end of 2021. CentOS Stream continues after that date, serving as the upstream (development) branch of Red Hat Enterprise Linux.</description></item><item><title>Not JOINing on PERFORMANCE_SCHEMA</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/01/not-joining-on-performance_schema/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 19:22:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/01/not-joining-on-performance_schema/</guid><description>The tables in PERFORMANCE_SCHEMA (P_S) are not actually tables. You should not think of them as tables, even if your SQL works on them. You should not JOIN them, and you should not GROUP or ORDER BY them.
Unlocked memory buffers without indexes The stuff in P_S has been created with “keep the impact on production small” in mind. That is, from a users point of view, you can think of them as unlocked memory buffers - the values in there change as you look at them, and there are precisely zero stability guarantees.</description></item><item><title>On the Observability of Outliers</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/11/23/on-the-observability-of-outliers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 17:41:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/11/23/on-the-observability-of-outliers/</guid><description>At work, I am in an ongoing discussion with a number of people on the Observability of Outliers. It started with the age-old question “How do I find slow queries in my application?” aka “What would I want from tooling to get that data and where should that tooling sit?”
As a developer, I just want to automatically identify and isolate slow queries!
Where I work, we do have SolarWinds Database Performance Monitor aka Vividcortex to find slow queries, so that helps.</description></item><item><title>How to build a high-performance application on Tarantool from scratch</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</guid><description>I came to Mail.ru Group in 2013, and I required a queue for one task. First of all, I decided to check what the company had already got. They told me they had this Tarantool product, and I checked how it worked and decided that adding a queue broker to it could work perfectly well. I contacted Kostja Osipov, the senior expert in Tarantool, and the next day he gave me a 250-string script that was capable of managing almost everything I needed.</description></item><item><title>Mayastor: Lightning Fast Storage for Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/23/mayastor-lightning-fast-storage-for-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 14:03:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/23/mayastor-lightning-fast-storage-for-kubernetes/</guid><description>At MayaData we like new tech. Tech that makes our databases perform better. Tech like lockless ring buffers, NVMe-oF, and Kubernetes. In this blog post we’re going to see those technologies at work to give us awesome block storage performance with flexibility and simple operations.
Mayastor + SPDK + NVMe = fast databases Mayastor is new tech, it’s fast, and it’s based on SPDK. Why is SPDK exciting? It’s a new generation in storage software, designed for super high speed low latency NVMe devices.</description></item><item><title>NoSQL Endgame – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/05/nosql-endgame-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 01:08:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/05/nosql-endgame-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 3:00 p.m. • London 8:00 p.m. • New Delhi 12:30 a.m. (next day) • Singapore 3:00 a.m.
Abstract The amount of data collected by applications nowadays is growing at a scary pace. Many of them need to handle billions of users generating and consuming data at an incredible speed. Maybe you are wondering how to create an application like this?</description></item><item><title>Kunlun Distributed DB Cluster Intro – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 22:25:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 9:30 p.m. • London 02:30 a.m. (next day) • New Delhi 7:00 a.m. • Singapore 09:30 a.m.
Abstract Kunlun Distributed Database Cluster is a distributed DBMS that aims to combine the best of both MySQL and PostgreSQL for a highly performant, highly available, highly scalable and fault-tolerant, easy to use and manage database system that requires minimal human maintenance. It enables users to define table sharding rules so that it automatically distributes tables properly to available storage shards; implements the two-phase commit protocol to do distributed transaction commit; uses MySQL group replication for high availability in storage shards; fixes a series of MySQL XA bugs to make distributed transactions highly reliable, among many other enhancements.</description></item><item><title>How to Write Your Index in Tarantool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 17:23:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</guid><description>Tarantool is an application server and a database. The server part is written in C, and the user is provided with a Lua interface to use it. Then, Tarantool is an open-source product with its source code in open access, and anyone can develop and distribute Tarantool-based software freely.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you about an attempt to write my own data structure for the search (the Z-order curve) and build it into the Tarantool ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code Refactor PMM Framework Project with Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:08:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/07/google-summer-of-code-refactor-pmm-framework-project-with-percona/</guid><description>I am Meet Patel, 2nd year undergraduate at DAIICT, Gandhinagar, India; pursuing a bachelor’s degree in Information and Communication Technology with a minor in Computational Science.
I am proud to be selected for the Google Summer of Code program under an open source organization as big and impactful as Percona. As we head towards the end of this amazing program, I’ll try to share a general overview of what and how all of it has been implemented.</description></item><item><title>Two weeks to MariaDB Server Fest</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 09:34:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/04/two-weeks-to-mariadb-server-fest/</guid><description>There is still time to register for the MariaDB Server Fest 2020!
MariaDB Fest 2020[/caption]
Our Fest is the opportunity to have live interactions with the key players on MariaDB Server: the developers of MariaDB Server, the service providers, the experts, the system integrators, and – perhaps most importantly – your fellow users!
Interactivity happens all the time, with the presenters being cloned and available for answering questions throughout the presentation.</description></item><item><title>IoT Performance Bottlenecks &amp; Open Source Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 17:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/03/iot-performance-bottlenecks-and-open-source-databases/</guid><description>The Internet of Things (IoT), in essence, is all about everyday devices that are readable, recognizable, trackable, and/or controllable via the Internet, regardless of the communication means — RFID, wireless LAN, and so on. The total installed base of IoT connected devices is projected to amount to 21.5 billion units worldwide by 2025. Thanks to IoT, the proliferation of data can be quite daunting. Hence, businesses should effectively organize and work with this enormous amount of valuable data.</description></item><item><title>IIoT platform databases - How Mail.ru Cloud Solutions deals with petabytes of data coming from a multitude of devices</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:11:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</guid><description>Hello, my name is Andrey Sergeyev and I work as a Head of IoT Solution Development at Mail.ru Cloud Solutions. We all know there is no such thing as a universal database. Especially when the task is to build an IoT platform that would be capable of processing millions of events from various sensors in near real-time.
Our product Mail.ru IoT Platform started as a Tarantool-based prototype. I’m going to tell you about our journey, the problems we faced and the solutions we found.</description></item><item><title>Cassandra Where and How by John Schulz</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</guid><description>If Percona Live ONLINE had graded its talks by skill level this year, John Schulz’s talk would have been essential viewing in the Beginners track. (You can watch all the event’s presentations now on Percona’s YouTube channel.) This talk was a good overview and meant for anyone who had heard of the Apache Cassandra distributed database but wasn’t sure whether it would be suitable for their project or not.
Database-veteran, John Schulz has been tinkering with Cassandra for about a decade and to help anyone get started he gave a whistle-stop tour of the Cassandra ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Making a Tarantool-Based Investment Business Core for Alfa-Bank</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/19/making-a-tarantool-based-investment-business-core-for-alfa-bank/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 13:23:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/19/making-a-tarantool-based-investment-business-core-for-alfa-bank/</guid><description>A still from &amp;ldquo;Our Secret Universe: The Hidden Life of the Cell&amp;rdquo;
Investment business is one of the most complex domains in the banking world. It&amp;rsquo;s about not just credits, loans, and deposits — there are also securities, currencies, commodities, derivatives, and all kinds of complex stuff like structured products.
Recently, people have become increasingly aware of their finances. More and more get involved in securities trading. Individual investment accounts have emerged not so long ago.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Projects for Google Summer of Code - 2020</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that Percona was selected as a participating organization for the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2020 program, this is our second year as a participating org with the GSoC program.
GSoC is a great program to involve young student developers in open source projects. We participated in the program in 2019 for the first time and we were really happy and satisfied with the results.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE: MySQL on Google Cloud: War and Peace! by Akshay Suryawanshi &amp; Jeremy Cole</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:12:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</guid><description>This session at Percona Live ONLINE was presented by Akshay Suryawanshi, Senior Production Engineer at Shopify, and Jeremy Cole, Senior Staff Production Engineer - Datastores at Shopify. Shopify is an online and on-premise commerce platform, founded in 2006.
Shopify is used by more than a million merchants, and hundreds of billions of dollars of sales have happened on the platform since its inception. The company is a large user of MySQL, and the Black Friday and Cyber Monday weekends are their peak dates during the year, handling hundreds of billions of queries with MySQL.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Enhancing MySQL security at LinkedIn by Karthik Appigatla</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/01/percona-live-online-talk-enhancing-mysql-security-at-linkedin-by-karthik-appigatla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 08:01:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/01/percona-live-online-talk-enhancing-mysql-security-at-linkedin-by-karthik-appigatla/</guid><description>MySQL, arguably the most popular relational database, is used pretty extensively at the popular professional social network LinkedIn. At Percona Live ONLINE 2020, the company’s flagship event held online for the first time due to the Covid-19 pandemic, Karthik Appigatla from LinkedIN’s database SRE team discussed the company’s approach to securing their database deployment without introducing operational hiccups or adversely affecting performance.
Instead of just performing admin duties, Karthik’s team builds automated tools to scale their infrastructure, and he talked about some of these tailored tools in his presentation.</description></item><item><title>Join ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona on June 4th, 2020!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</guid><description>Long months of the pandemic lockdown have brought to life many great online events enabling the MySQL community to get together and stay informed about the very recent developments and innovations available to MySQL users. It isn’t over yet! Next Thursday, June 4th, Percona &amp;amp; ProxySQL are co-hosting the ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona virtual meetup covering ProxySQL, MySQL and Percona XtraDB Cluster.
The attendees are invited to participate in the two-hour deep-dive event with plenty of time for questions and answers (we will have two 40-minute sessions + 20 minutes allocated for Q&amp;amp;A).</description></item><item><title>How to contribute Dashboards to PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 14:54:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</guid><description>Have you already contributed to Percona’s open-source products or perhaps you wanted to try doing so?
I will tell you how to become a contributor to the popular open-source product from Percona in just a few hours. You don&amp;rsquo;t need any serious developer skills.
We earlier explained how to contribute to PMM documentation in our last post. Now we will contribute to PMM itself, namely to Dashboards. Dashboards are an important part of PMM, they are seen and used by thousands of users, so your contribution may be of benefit to many others.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Tarantool Cartridge Applications with Zero Effort (Part 2)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/01/deploying-tarantool-cartridge-applications-with-zero-effort-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 11:04:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/01/deploying-tarantool-cartridge-applications-with-zero-effort-part-2/</guid><description>We have recently talked about how to deploy a Tarantool Cartridge application. However, an application&amp;rsquo;s life doesn&amp;rsquo;t end with deployment, so today we will update our application and figure out how to manage topology, sharding, and authorization, and change the role configuration.
Feeling interested? Please continue reading under the cut.
Where did we leave off? Last time, we set up the following topology: The sample repository has changed a bit: there are new files called getting-started-app-2.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Tarantool Cartridge Applications with Zero Effort (Part 1)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/03/24/deploying-tarantool-cartridge-applications-with-zero-effort-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 14:04:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/03/24/deploying-tarantool-cartridge-applications-with-zero-effort-part-1/</guid><description>Tarantool is an open-source in-memory DB with a Lua application server on board. It&amp;rsquo;s best used for apps that require high performance and horizontal scaling. Out of the box we support horizontal scaling via the vshard module. There are quite a few things that you have to keep in mind when you work on your business logic, though. Not ideal.
We made it easier. All the lessons learned from creating distributed apps resulted in a framework called Tarantool Cartridge.</description></item><item><title>How To Contribute to PMM Documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 16:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;d love to see more contributions towards the development and improvement of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM), one of Percona&amp;rsquo;s most valued projects. Like all of Percona&amp;rsquo;s software, PMM is free and open-source. An area where we&amp;rsquo;d dearly love to see some community provided enhancement is in its documentation. In future blog posts, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide some insight on how to contribute to our software but&amp;hellip; the beauty of documentation is that it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to maintain, and you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to be a programmer to be able to provide valuable corrections and enhancements.</description></item><item><title>Disk of Yesteryear Compared to Today’s SSD Drives</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/17/disk-of-yesteryear-compared-to-todays-ssd-drives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/17/disk-of-yesteryear-compared-to-todays-ssd-drives/</guid><description>In my [last blog post](https://www.percona.com/ community-blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/) I showed you how to get the entire Percona “Stack&amp;quot; up and running on a Raspberry Pi. This time around, I would like to show the impact on performance between using an SSD hard disk and a standard hard disk.
Disk performance is a key factor in Percona Server for MySQL (or any RDB platform) performance on a Raspberry Pi 4.
Test set up Each test below was run three times per Hard Disk and I took the best of the three for comparison.</description></item><item><title>Impact of innodb_file_per_table Option On Crash Recovery Time</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/23/impact-of-innodb_file_per_table-option-on-crash-recovery-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 13:34:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/07/23/impact-of-innodb_file_per_table-option-on-crash-recovery-time/</guid><description>Starting at version MySQL5.6+ by default innodb_file_per_table is enabled and all data is stored in separate tablespaces. It provides some advantages.
I will highlight some of them:
You can reclaim disk space when truncating or dropping a table stored in a file-per-table tablespace. Truncating or dropping tables stored in the shared system tablespace creates free space internally in the system tablespace data files (ibdata files) which can only be used for new InnoDB data.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Globalizing Player Accounts with MySQL at Riot Games</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/28/percona-live-presents-globalizing-player-accounts-mysql-riot-games/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:48:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/28/percona-live-presents-globalizing-player-accounts-mysql-riot-games/</guid><description>During my presentation at Percona Live 2019, I’ll be talking about how Riot Games, the company behind League of Legends, migrated hundreds of millions of player accounts to unlock opportunities for us to delight players. This meant moving ten geographically distributed databases into a single global database replicated into four AWS regions. I’ll talk about some of the technical decisions we made, the expected vs actual outcomes, and lessons we learned along the way.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The State of Databases in 2019</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</guid><description>At this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live I am talking about The State of Databases in 2019. As a Software Engineer in the thick of the Database landscape, there are two problems that I see repeatedly.
Due to the massive explosion of database solutions, it has become very difficult to evaluate what database solution will serve the best for one’s use case, and
The constant tug of war between database operators and users.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The First Ever TiDB Track</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 20:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</guid><description>The PingCAP team has always been a strong supporter of Percona and the wider open source database community. As the people who work day in and day out on TiDB, an open source NewSQL database with MySQL compatibility, open source database is what gets us in the morning, and there’s no better place to share that passion than Percona Live.
At this year’s Percona Live Open Source Database Conference in Austin, Texas, we are particularly excited to bring you a full track of talks and demo on the latest development in TiDB during Day 1 of the conference.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Query Optimization and TLS at Large Scale</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 14:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe this year, I got accepted a workshop on query optimization and a 50-minute talk covering TLS for MySQL at Large Scale, talking about our experiences at the Wikimedia Foundation.
Workshop The 3-hour workshop on Monday, titled Query Optimization with MySQL 8.0 and MariaDB 10.3: The Basics is a beginners' tutorial–though dense in content. It&amp;rsquo;s for people who are more familiar with database storage systems other than InnoDB for MySQL, MariaDB or Percona Server.</description></item><item><title>Multi-master with MariaDB 10 - a tutorial</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:57:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/09/10/multi-master-with-mariadb-10-tutorial/</guid><description>The goal of this tutorial is to show you how to use multi-master to aggregate databases with the same name, but different data from different masters, on the same slave.
Example:
master1 =&amp;gt; a French subsidiary master2 =&amp;gt; a British subsidiary Both have the same database PRODUCTION but the data are totally different.
This screenshot is made from my own monitoring tool: PmaControl. You have to read 10.</description></item><item><title>7 Checks to Successfully Upgrade MongoDB Replica Set in Production</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/29/7-checks-successfully-upgrade-mongodb-replica-set-production/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:23:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/29/7-checks-successfully-upgrade-mongodb-replica-set-production/</guid><description>MongoDB ships powerful features in each release. The new release brings new features while revisions add bug fixes, security patches or improvements to existing features. To bring most out these releases to your plate you should always consider upgrading your MongoDB deployments.
Planning your database upgrade can avoid the nightmares caused due to database-upgrade-gone-wrong or avoid not-so-simple rollbacks in your production database. Grab a cup of coffee and sit back.</description></item><item><title>Easy and Effective Way of Building External Dictionaries for ClickHouse with Pentaho Data Integration Tool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 16:09:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/08/02/easy-effective-building-external-dictionaries-clickhouse-pentaho-data-integration-tool/</guid><description>In this post, I provide an illustration of how to use Pentaho Data Integration (PDI) tool to set up external dictionaries in MySQL to support ClickHouse. Although I use MySQL in this example, you can use any PDI supported source.
ClickHouse ClickHouse is an open-source column-oriented DBMS (columnar database management system) for online analytical processing. Source: wiki.
Pentaho Data Integration Information from the Pentaho wiki: Pentaho Data Integration (PDI, also called Kettle) is the component of Pentaho responsible for the Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) processes.</description></item><item><title>TiSpark: More Data Insights, No More ETL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/18/tispark-data-insights-no-etl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 13:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/18/tispark-data-insights-no-etl/</guid><description>When we released TiDB 2.0 in April, part of that announcement also included the release of TiSpark 1.0&amp;ndash;an integral part of the TiDB platform that makes complex analytics on “fresh” transactional data possible. Since then, many people in the TiDB community have been asking for more information about TiSpark. In this post, I will explain the motivation, inner workings, and future roadmap of this project.
Motivation The motivation behind building TiSpark was to enable real-time analytics on TiDB without the delay and challenges of ETL.</description></item></channel></rss>