<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mongo on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/mongo/</link><description>Recent content in Mongo on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/mongo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> Installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes Operator - Community MeetUp - March 10th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-10-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-10-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</guid><description>Join us in The Percona Community MeetUp and walk with us through the installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes operator. Sergey Pronin will take us through all steps of the setup to get us started with a new MongoDB Cluster. Stop by and ask your questions and receive an answer right away.
Join us in Community MeetUp for MongoDB Day: Thursday, Mar 10th, 11 am EST (5:00 pm CEST / 9:30 pm IST) Live stream on YouTube and Twitch Live chat on Discord Add this event to your Google Calendar We Will Talk About: Installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes operator, with Sergey Pronin and Matt Yonkovit</description></item><item><title> Community MeetUp - Installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes Operator - POSTPONED</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-24-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-24-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</guid><description>Hello,
We are sorry to inform you that we have to POSTPONE our Community MeetUp of Today Thursday, Feb 24th, 11 am EST (5:00 pm CEST / 9:30 pm IST). A new schedule of the meeting will be announced soon.
Thank you for your understanding.
Percona Community Team
Join us in The Percona Community MeetUp and walk with us through the installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes operator.</description></item></channel></rss>