<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mongo on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/mongo/</link><description>Recent content in Mongo on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/mongo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> Installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes Operator - Community MeetUp - March 10th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-10-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-10-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</guid><description>Check this full recording of the Percona Community MeetUp of March 10th hosted and learn more about installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes operator. Matt Yonkovit, the Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona, and Sergey Pronin, Product Owner at Percona, took us through the step-by-step setup to get us started with a new MongoDB cluster.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/HZ9yaS-ZS48
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Helloб everyone out there in the stream land. Welcome to another Percona Livestream.</description></item><item><title> Community MeetUp - Installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes Operator - POSTPONED</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-24-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-24-percona-meetup-for-mongodb/</guid><description>Hello,
We are sorry to inform you that we have to POSTPONE our Community MeetUp of Today Thursday, Feb 24th, 11 am EST (5:00 pm CEST / 9:30 pm IST). A new schedule of the meeting will be announced soon.
Thank you for your understanding.
Percona Community Team
Join us in The Percona Community MeetUp and walk with us through the installation of MongoDB via a Kubernetes operator. Sergey Pronin will take us through all steps of the setup to get us started with a new MongoDB Cluster.</description></item></channel></rss>