<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lua on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/lua/</link><description>Recent content in Lua on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 14:44:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/lua/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to build a high-performance application on Tarantool from scratch</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</guid><description>I came to Mail.ru Group in 2013, and I required a queue for one task. First of all, I decided to check what the company had already got. They told me they had this Tarantool product, and I checked how it worked and decided that adding a queue broker to it could work perfectly well. I contacted Kostja Osipov, the senior expert in Tarantool, and the next day he gave me a 250-string script that was capable of managing almost everything I needed.</description></item><item><title>IIoT platform databases - How Mail.ru Cloud Solutions deals with petabytes of data coming from a multitude of devices</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 14:11:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/07/24/iiot-platform-databases-how-mail-ru-cloud-solutions-deals-with-petabytes-of-data-coming-from-a-multitude-of-devices/</guid><description>Hello, my name is Andrey Sergeyev and I work as a Head of IoT Solution Development at Mail.ru Cloud Solutions. We all know there is no such thing as a universal database. Especially when the task is to build an IoT platform that would be capable of processing millions of events from various sensors in near real-time.
Our product Mail.ru IoT Platform started as a Tarantool-based prototype. I’m going to tell you about our journey, the problems we faced and the solutions we found.</description></item><item><title>The Anatomy of LuaJIT Tables and What's Special About Them</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/29/the-anatomy-of-luajit-tables-and-whats-special-about-them/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 13:18:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/29/the-anatomy-of-luajit-tables-and-whats-special-about-them/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but I really like to get inside all sorts of systems. In this article, I’m going to tell you about the internals of Lua tables and special considerations for their use. Lua is my primary professional programming language, and if one wants to write good code, one needs at least to peek behind the curtain. If you are curious, follow me.
Lua has several implementations and several versions.</description></item></channel></rss>