<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>author_federico on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/author_federico/</link><description>Recent content in author_federico on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 09:24:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/author_federico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>London Open Source Database Community Meetup</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 09:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</guid><description>I strongly believe in the community.
Communities are the real strength of open source. Not just the theoretical ability to study, modify and share code – but the fact that other people out there are doing these things. Creating a base of knowledge and a network of relations.These can become work relationships, valuable discussions, open source tools, or even friendships.
That is why, when I heard that several people from the Percona support team will soon be in London, I badly wanted to organise an event.</description></item><item><title>Some Notes on MariaDB system-versioned Tables</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/14/notes-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 14:53:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/14/notes-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</guid><description>As mentioned in a previous post, I gave a talk at Percona Live Europe 2018 about system-versioned tables. This is a new MariaDB 10.3 feature, which consists of preserving old versions of a table rows. Each version has two timestamps that indicate the start (INSERT,UPDATE) of the validity of that version, and its end (DELETE, UPDATE). As a result, the user is able to query these tables as they appear at a point in the past, or how data evolved in a certain time range.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: MariaDB System-Versioned Tables</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/17/percona-live-europe-presents-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 16:14:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/17/percona-live-europe-presents-mariadb-system-versioned-tables/</guid><description>System-versioned tables, or temporal tables, are a typical feature of proprietary database management systems like DB2, Oracle and SQL Server. They also appeared at some point in PostgreSQL, but only as an extension; and also in CockroachDB, but in a somewhat limited fashion.
The MariaDB® implementation is the first appearance of temporal tables in the MySQL ecosystem, and the most complete implementation in the open source world.
My presentation will be useful for analysts, and some managers, who will definitely benefit from learning how to use temporal tables.</description></item></channel></rss>