<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DBA Tools on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/dba-tools/</link><description>Recent content in DBA Tools on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/dba-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Join ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona on June 4th, 2020!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</guid><description>Long months of the pandemic lockdown have brought to life many great online events enabling the MySQL community to get together and stay informed about the very recent developments and innovations available to MySQL users. It isn’t over yet! Next Thursday, June 4th, Percona &amp;amp; ProxySQL are co-hosting the ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona virtual meetup covering ProxySQL, MySQL and Percona XtraDB Cluster.
The attendees are invited to participate in the two-hour deep-dive event with plenty of time for questions and answers (we will have two 40-minute sessions + 20 minutes allocated for Q&amp;amp;A).</description></item><item><title>Minimalist Tooling for MySQL/MariaDB DBAs</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/14/minimalist-tooling-for-mysql-mariadb-dbas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 14:21:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/14/minimalist-tooling-for-mysql-mariadb-dbas/</guid><description>In my roles as a DBA at various companies, I generally found the tooling to be quite lacking. Everything from metrics collection, alerting, backup management; they were either missing, incomplete or implemented poorly. DBA-Tools was born from a desire to build backup tools that supported my needs in smaller/non-cloud environments. As BASH is easily the most common shell available out there on systems running MySQL® or MariaDB®, it was an easy choice.</description></item></channel></rss>