<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PMM_prev on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/pmm_prev/</link><description>Recent content in PMM_prev on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/pmm_prev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2.23.0 Preview Release(Updated!)</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/10/15/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/10/15/preview-release/</guid><description>Update Percona Monitoring and Management 2.23.0 is now available as a Public Release!
Release notes for Percona Monitoring and Management 2.23.0 Public Release can be found here
2.23.0 Preview Release Percona Monitoring and Management 2.23.0 is released today as a Preview Release.
PMM team really appreciates your feedback!
We encourage you to try this PMM Internal Release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.</description></item><item><title>2.22.0 Preview Release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/16/preview-release/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/09/16/preview-release/</guid><description>2.20.0 Preview Release Percona Monitoring and Management 2.22.0 is released today as a Preview Release.
PMM team really appreciates your feedback!
We encourage you to try this PMM Preview Release in testing environments only, as these packages and images are not fully production-ready. The final version is expected to be released through the standard channels in the coming week.
Known issue:
PMM-8829 - &amp;ldquo;Missing Listen Port&amp;rdquo; error for external exporters after restart Release notes: Release Notes Preview found here</description></item></channel></rss>