<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PerconaLive2022 on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/perconalive2022/</link><description>Recent content in PerconaLive2022 on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/perconalive2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dave Stokes talks open - Stoking the flames of open source - Episode 2 - Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-2/</guid><description>Bruce Momjian, VP, Postgres Evangelist at EDB, and Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona joined Dave Stokes, Technical Evangelist at Percona Live 2022. This is the recording of their talk on all things Postgres-related and OpenSource technologies.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/dcoQmgV2kBA</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes talks open - Stoking the flames of open source - Episode 1 - Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/dave-stokes-talks-open-1/</guid><description>Listen to the interviews from PerconaLive 2022. David Stokes invited amazing guests to talk to him about open source technologies.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/cOK4hzRLszo</description></item><item><title>Dave Stokes Talks Open on Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/dave-stokes-talks-open-percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Dave Stokes Talks Open on Percona Live 2022 During the Percona Live 2022 in Austin, David Stokes, Percona’s Technical Evangelist, invited amazing event guests and speakers to talk to him about open source technologies and trends and record a podcast. Watch these videos to find out the latest news in the world of open source databases, cloud technologies, DevOps tools, and monitoring and hear from the outstanding experts. Don’t forget to like and share them with your friends!</description></item><item><title>Liquibase Data is Git for Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/25/liquibase-data-is-git-for-databases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/25/liquibase-data-is-git-for-databases/</guid><description>Author&amp;rsquo;s Note: Robert will be demoing Liquibase Data at Percona Live 2022 on Wednesday, May 18 at 11:50am. Add this presentation to your schedule.
Git is an amazing tool for collaboration — developers can work together to build better software faster. However, the usual Git workflow neglects the database. With Liquibase Data we’re bringing git to the database so you can easily version containerized databases, share changes with team members, store versions in remote locations, and tag versions.</description></item><item><title>A Quick Guide To Austin For Percona Live 2022 Attendees</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/11/percona-live-austin-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/11/percona-live-austin-guide/</guid><description>Percona Live returns again to Austin May 16th through the 18th will find the city vibrant, charming, and weird. The semi-official motto for the city is ‘Keep Austin Weird’ and during your visit you will indeed see many of the residents working hard to do just that. Not in a bad way. Austin is at the intersection of so many cultural, artistic, and lifestyle modes that there are a fair amount of many different things happening at the same time to ensure that any dull moments you have will have to be an active choice on your part.</description></item></channel></rss>