<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PostgreSQL on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/categories/postgresql/</link><description>Recent content in PostgreSQL on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/categories/postgresql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Progress report on pg_tde - GA extension is nearer every day!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/05/08/progress-report-on-pg_tde-ga-extension-is-nearer-every-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/05/08/progress-report-on-pg_tde-ga-extension-is-nearer-every-day/</guid><description>Another week, another blogpost about the state of open source Transparent Data Encryption (TDE) for PostgreSQL.
First off, thank you for all the feedback shared so far!
Whether it&amp;rsquo;s reports about deployment issues with pg_tde, integration with KMS, missing features or gaps in our documentation, we truly appreciate it! Your input helps us build a better, more complete solution and to properly prioritize what&amp;rsquo;s next.
What’s the word? We know many of you are eagerly waiting for a production-ready release of pg_tde, and today we’ve got some good news!</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: October 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Percona Joins Community Over Code 2024 in Bratislava, Slovakia</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/21/percona-joins-community-over-code-2024-in-bratislava-slovakia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/21/percona-joins-community-over-code-2024-in-bratislava-slovakia/</guid><description>Last week, I participated as a speaker for the first time at Community Over Code 2024.
Community Over Code Community Over Code is a key principle at Apache, highlighting the importance of having a solid and collaborative community rather than just focusing on the code. While good code is essential, the community&amp;rsquo;s strength and resilience keep a project going and growing. I love how this is expressed in the &amp;ldquo;Apache Way.</description></item><item><title>Let's take a look at Percona Everest 1.0.0 RC</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/14/lets-take-a-look-at-percona-everest-1.0.0-rc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/14/lets-take-a-look-at-percona-everest-1.0.0-rc/</guid><description>Hi, the Percona Everest 1.0.0-rc1 release was published on GitHub.
Percona Everest is the first open source cloud-native platform for provisioning and managing PostgreSQL, MongoDB and MySQL database clusters.
I want to tell you how to install it so you can try it out.
RC builds aren&amp;rsquo;t meant for the general public; we don&amp;rsquo;t support upgrading from RC to stable versions. This means that this is only for testing and familiarizing yourself with the features.</description></item><item><title>Learn PostgreSQL and SQL Quickly and Free</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/20/learn-postgresql-and-sql-quickly-and-free/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/20/learn-postgresql-and-sql-quickly-and-free/</guid><description>Learn PostgreSQL and SQL Quickly and Free
Want to learn PostgreSQL? What if you could learn PostgreSQL without having to install the database, load data, find sample data, and it was free? PGExamples.com is what you are looking for.
First, let me state that I have no connection to the website or its author. I discovered PgExercises.com by accident and was impressed by its quality and completeness. I am so impressed that I am exploring a video series on it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: April 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Standby Cluster With the Percona Operator for PostgreSQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/27/creating-a-standby-cluster-with-the-percona-operator-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/27/creating-a-standby-cluster-with-the-percona-operator-for-postgresql/</guid><description>In this video, Nickolay Ihalainen, a Senior Scaling Specialist at Percona Global Services, explains how to set up replication with standby clusters for Kubernetes databases using Percona&amp;rsquo;s open-source tools, including the Percona Operator for PostgreSQL
A Standby Cluster is a backup version of your main database. It&amp;rsquo;s there to keep your data safe and make sure your database can keep running even if something goes wrong with the main one.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup March 18, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/18/release-roundup-march-18-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/18/release-roundup-march-18-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates March 5 - March 18, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>Release Roundup March 4, 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/04/release-roundup-march-4-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/04/release-roundup-march-4-2024/</guid><description>Percona software releases and updates February 21 - March 4, 2024.
Percona is a leading provider of unbiased, performance-first, open source database solutions that allow organizations to easily, securely, and affordably maintain business agility, minimize risks, and stay competitive, free from vendor lock-in. Percona software is designed for peak performance, uncompromised security, limitless scalability, and disaster-proofed availability.
Our Release Roundups showcase the latest Percona software updates, tools, and features to help you manage and deploy our software.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL: Query Optimization With Python and PgBouncer</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/25/postgresql-query-optimization-with-python-and-pgbouncer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/25/postgresql-query-optimization-with-python-and-pgbouncer/</guid><description>Database application by Nick Youngson CC BY-SA 3.0 Pix4free A few months ago I wrote a few blog posts on how to generate test data for your database project using Python, which you can find on the Percona blog and the Community blog:
How To Generate Test Data for MySQL with Python How To Generate Test Data for MongoDB With Python How To Generate Test Data for Your Database Project With Python The basic idea is to create a script that uses Faker, a Python library for generating fake data, and what the script does is</description></item><item><title>FerretDB - A Quick Look</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/12/ferretdb-a-quick-look/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/04/12/ferretdb-a-quick-look/</guid><description>There is an old saying that what looks like a duck and quacks like a duck is probably a duck. But what looks like MongoDB and acts like MongoDB could be FerretDB! To greatly simplify the technology behind this project, FerretDB speaks, or quacks, MongoDB but stores the data in PostgreSQL. PostgreSQL has had a rich JSON data environment for years and FerrtDB takes advantage of this capability. This is a truly Open Source MongoDB alternative and was released under the Apache 2.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up PMM For Monitoring Your Databases on Windows</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/16/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-your-databases-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/16/setting-up-pmm-for-monitoring-your-databases-on-windows/</guid><description>Before deploying Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) in production, you might want to test it or set up a development instance locally. Since many developers and DBAs have Windows desktops, I wanted to demonstrate how to set up PMM on Windows for an easy test environment. In this post, I’ll walk you through setting up PMM with Docker and WSL.
If you’re a Linux user, check the blog post I wrote on Setting up PMM for monitoring MySQL in a local environment.</description></item><item><title>How To Generate Test Data for Your Database Project With Python</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/09/how-to-generate-test-data-for-your-database-project-with-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/09/how-to-generate-test-data-for-your-database-project-with-python/</guid><description>If you need test data for the database of your project, you can get a dataset from Kaggle or use a data generator. In the first case, if you need to process the data before inserting it into the database, you can use Pandas, a widely used Python library for data analysis. This library supports different formats, including CSV and JSON, and it also provides a method for inserting data into a SQL database.</description></item><item><title>How To Generate Data With Pagila in Percona Distribution for PostgreSQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/13/how-to-generate-data-with-pagila-in-percona-distribution-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/12/13/how-to-generate-data-with-pagila-in-percona-distribution-for-postgresql/</guid><description>Have you ever faced the need to generate test data for your Postgres database? I am sure you have! This blog post will guide you step-by-step through one of the many ways to get it fast and easy. That will leave you plenty of time to focus on queries. No need to spend time creating your data generation scripts!
For this guide, we will use Pagila, a tool that provides a standard schema that we can use for examples in books, tutorials, articles, samples, etc.</description></item><item><title>Announcing the release of pg_stat_monitor 1.1.0</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/09/22/announcing-the-release-of-pg_stat_monitor-1.1.0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/09/22/announcing-the-release-of-pg_stat_monitor-1.1.0/</guid><description>Percona is happy to announce the 1.1.0 release of pg_stat_monitor. You can install it from the Percona repositories following the installation instructions.
pg_stat_monitor is a Query Performance Monitoring tool for PostgreSQL. It attempts to provide a more holistic picture by providing much-needed query performance insights in a single view.
pg_stat_monitor provides improved insights that allow database users to understand query origins, execution, planning statistics and details, query information, and metadata. This significantly improves observability, enabling users to debug and tune query performance.</description></item><item><title>The Ins and Outs of PostgreSQL Default Configuration Tuning</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/03/31/the-ins-and-outs-of-postgresql-default-configuration-tuning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/03/31/the-ins-and-outs-of-postgresql-default-configuration-tuning/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what the optimal settings for a newly installed Postgres database are, here are some simple steps to take to tune it right from the start. Matt Yonkovit discussed them with Charly Batista, Postgres Tech Lead at Percona during the live-streamed meetup. Watch the recording to see how Charly tunes a default installation of Percona Distribution for PostgreSQL 13.
Most of the default settings have been defined long, long time ago, where one gigabyte of RAM was very expensive.</description></item><item><title>PMM development and testing with help of minikube</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</guid><description>Why Some time ago I needed to test PG14 with the new pg_stat_monitor version that wasn&amp;rsquo;t released. I decided to log my journey so I would spend less effort next time to replicate it.
I do use podman and run PMM with its help but I also like to hack PMM DBaaS features and think that k8s and minikube are perfect and better scalable solutions for the different development environments and especially for the number of clusters and DBs.</description></item><item><title>Fixing Common PostgreSQL Performance Bottlenecks</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/04/fixing-common-postgresql-performance-bottlenecks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 20:26:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/04/fixing-common-postgresql-performance-bottlenecks/</guid><description>Overview In this article, I look at how poorly designed sharding systems and replication systems in PostgreSQL affect query performance in high volume situations, and how to ensure data consistency across many servers. I also discuss how excessive vacuuming generates I/O traffic, and how connection pooling is used to improve transaction throughput by caching connections from clients. I also cover how insufficient memory could affect PostgreSQL performance. These are key problems I have encountered as a database consultant, and how I&amp;rsquo;ve overcome them.</description></item><item><title>Database Schema Management Via Liquibase</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 22:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</guid><description>Creating the database for an application is simple and easy. However, database script management gets complicated in a hurry when you need to support multiple versions, work with multiple teams, and apply the same changes to multiple types of databases. One open-source tool that helps teams track, version, and deploy database schema changes is Liquibase. It executes database scripts sequentially, allows for the automatic creation and execution of rollback scripts for failed updates, and provides an easy way to use the same scripts and apply them to different types of databases.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Gonymizer, A Tool to Anonymize Sensitive PostgreSQL Data Tables for Use in QA and Testing</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/17/percona-live-gonymizer-tool-anonymize-sensitive-postgresql-data-testing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 11:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/17/percona-live-gonymizer-tool-anonymize-sensitive-postgresql-data-testing/</guid><description>SmithRX is a next generation pharmacy benefit platform that is using the latest technology to radically reshape the prescription benefit management industry. To move quickly, we require the ability to iterate and test new versions of our software using production like data without violating Health Information Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) regulations.
At Percona Live 2019, we are introducing a project we open sourced to anonymize our sensitive production data for use in rapid QA and testing of our software.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: pg_chameleon MySQL to PostgreSQL Replica Made Easy</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 14:42:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</guid><description>What excites me is the possibility that this tool is giving to other people. Also, the challenges I’ve faced and the new ideas for the future releases are always source of interest that keep me focused on the project. So I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to sharing this with the conference delegates.
pg_chameleon can achieve two tasks in a very simple way. It can setup a permanent replica between MySQL and PostgreSQL, giving the freedom of choice for the right tool for the right job, or can migrate multiple schemas to a PostgreSQL database.</description></item></channel></rss>