<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create your own Exporter in Go!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/21/create-your-own-exporter-in-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/21/create-your-own-exporter-in-go/</guid><description>Overview Hi, it’s too hot summer in Korea. Today I want to talk about an interesting and exciting topic. Try to making your own exporter in Go language.
If you register a specific query, it is a simple program that shows the result of this query as an exporter result metrics. Some of you may still be unfamiliar with what Expoter is.
I will explain about Exporter step by step in today’s post.</description></item><item><title>How to build a high-performance application on Tarantool from scratch</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/30/how-to-build-a-high-performance-application-on-tarantool-from-scratch/</guid><description>I came to Mail.ru Group in 2013, and I required a queue for one task. First of all, I decided to check what the company had already got. They told me they had this Tarantool product, and I checked how it worked and decided that adding a queue broker to it could work perfectly well. I contacted Kostja Osipov, the senior expert in Tarantool, and the next day he gave me a 250-string script that was capable of managing almost everything I needed.</description></item></channel></rss>