<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amazon OpenSearch Room on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon OpenSearch Room on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Something Went Wrong: Understanding Alerting and Anomaly Detection</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/5/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
Being informed of something going wrong after it has happened is never ideal. Setting up a system to monitor logs and metrics allows you to be proactive rather than reactive. This session will cover the differences between alerting and anomaly detection, how each works, and where they are best employed.</description></item><item><title>Getting Your Mind Around OpenSearch Geospatial Data</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/4/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
Flat earthers need not attend! This session will go through the basics of geospatial data in general, then go deeper on how it works in (and inside of) OpenSearch. The session will explain how to get geospatial information into OpenSearch, then how to query and visualize the data.</description></item><item><title>Securing OpenSearch</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/3/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
OpenSearch has a strong set of security features but not everyone takes advantage of them. This session will provide an overview of the features as well as show ways to apply these features for real world problems. The session will include demos of data masking, authentication, and authorization, as well as index, document, and eld level security.</description></item><item><title>The Essentials of Search</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/2/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
The term ‘search engine’ is badly overloaded and can cause confusion for many folks. Is it a database? Is it a service to nd recipes for lasagna? Is it something else entirely? This session will teach you not only how to answer these questions but also what makes search distinct and so darn useful across so many domains.</description></item><item><title>What is OpenSearch?</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/opensearch-room/1/</guid><description>Kyle Davis - AWS - Percona Live 2021
You may have heard of OpenSearch, but what is it exactly and how did it come about? In this session, you’ll learn about the components of OpenSearch, what they do, and what problems they can solve. No prerequisites for this session, but it prepares you for other OpenSearch sessions.</description></item></channel></rss>