<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opensource on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/opensource/</link><description>Recent content in opensource on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/opensource/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chernihiv.IT Cluster Sponsorship</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-it-cluster/</guid><description>Percona is thrilled to support Chernihiv.IT Cluster and help to develop the local IT community in Chernihiv, Ukraine. The cluster was founded in 2017 and it unites the efforts of 11 IT companies. Percona&amp;rsquo;s engineers Evgeniy Patlan, Serhii Stasiuk, Mykola Marzhan, Maxim Kondratenko, and other Perconians in the city eagerly participate in Cluster&amp;rsquo;s activities, both online and in-person, and willingly share their knowledge and experience with others.
CHERNIHIV.IT DevOps Crash Course</description></item><item><title>PGConf NYC 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</guid><description>On December 2th-3th, Percona Team was in New York on an important event in the PostgreSQL world - PGConf NYC. It is a non–profit, community-run conference, focused on business users, database professionals, and developers of PostgreSQL. Percona was thrilled to participate in it as a Platinum sponsor this year.
Speakers from Percona gave several amazing talks at the conference:
Postgres and Json - How to get the best of them?</description></item><item><title>Balalaika Meetup With Local Community in Ulyanovsk</title><link>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</guid><description>On November 15th, Percona organized a meetup with the local community in Ulyanovsk (Russia). From Percona, there were Peter Zaitsev (CEO), Maria Azizova (Staff Executive), and Aleksandra Abramova (Community Specialist). They had a chance to meet engineers from different IT companies who live nearby.
The event took place in an interesting location. It was a private Balalaika&amp;rsquo;s Museum. It is a Russian national musical instrument. If you wonder how it sounds like, there are some examples on YouTube like this one.</description></item><item><title>Merge Conf 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/mergeconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/mergeconf-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team members visited Merge Conf 2021 in Innopolis, Russia, on November 13-14.
Percona speakers gave 2 talks on the Open Source track.
Technologies and Trends in the World of Open Source Databases in 2021 by Peter Zaitsev (CEO, Percona). Peter talked about all the main open source databases and their versatility, considered specific solutions for different situations and provided information on the changes in open source licenses and what can be expected next year.</description></item><item><title>Online Public Lecture “What is DevOps?”</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</guid><description>Percona’s Evgeniy Patlan (Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering) and Serhii Stasiuk (Build/Release Engineer) participated in an online public meetup “What is DevOps?” for students of Chernihiv Polytechnic National University. Together with Volodymyr Rudiy (CEO, Agilevision.io) and Volodymyr Bazilevich (Academic, Chernihiv Polytechnic National University), they discussed the modern views on DevOps methodology, practices and people who do this job nowadays, tasks and challenges that they face and what is expected of them on the modern labor market.</description></item><item><title>Nerdearla 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/nerdearla-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/nerdearla-2021/</guid><description>One of the virtual events Percona was happy to support this year was Nerdearla 2021, the most important IT conference in the Latin American region.
Ivan Groenewold (Architect, Percona) presented his talk “Deployando MongoDB sharded con Terraform y Ansible” (Deploying MongoDB Sharded Clusters With Terraform and Ansible”.
Link: https://youtu.be/okCaeIHa4cY
We also welcomed people to our virtual booth and distributed some white paper collateral.
Though it was lots of fun virtually, we hope that in the future we will be able to meet in person again!</description></item><item><title>National University "Chernihiv Polytechnic"</title><link>https://percona.community/events/national_university_chernihiv_polytechnic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/national_university_chernihiv_polytechnic/</guid><description>Percona encourages its staff members to actively collaborate with universities and local communities. Evgeniy Patlan (Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering) is one of those who enjoy active communication with local students and those who would like to become more familiar with modern open source technologies. In October, he participated in the student training which took place in the Ukrainian National University &amp;ldquo;Chernihiv Polytechnic&amp;rdquo;.
The mission of the National University &amp;ldquo;Chernihiv Polytechnic&amp;rdquo; is the development of society through education and research to build leadership and address global challenges in a changing world.</description></item><item><title>All Things Open 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in ATO (All Things Open) in Raleigh Convention Center on October 17th - 19th.
Percona speakers gave 4 talks during the conference:
The PostgreSQL Twin Bill: The 7 Deadly PostgreSQL Mistakes &amp;amp; Review of what&amp;rsquo;s new in PostgreSQL 14 by Matt Yonkovit (HOSS) and Barrett Chambers (Sr. Manager, Solutions Engineering). Distributed Storage in the Cloud by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Deploying MongoDB sharded clusters easily with Terraform and Ansible by Ivan Groenewold (Architect).</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit Seattle 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in the OSS event organized by Linux Foundation in Seattle in Hyatt Regency Hotel on September 27-30. It was really exciting for all of us to start meeting in person with customers, community members, and teammates as well!
Percona speakers gave 3 talks during the conference: From a database in container to DBaaS on Kubernetes by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Default to Open - Steps and Traps by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy).</description></item><item><title>OSDN Conf Kyiv 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</guid><description>Percona sponsored the OSDN Conf Kyiv which was held in person in the Nivki-hal on September 18th. It was a one-day non-commercial, volunteer-organized event centered on free and open-source software. Mykola Marzhan (Director of Server Engineering, Percona) and Evgeniy Patlan (Manager of Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering, Percona) are the main organizers of the conference.
During the event, 400 attendees had the opportunity to visit presentations by the open-source community leaders, meet each other and chat during lunch and coffee breaks, discuss the latest trends with representatives on booths.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item></channel></rss>