<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opensource on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/opensource/</link><description>Recent content in opensource on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/opensource/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Online Public Lecture “What is DevOps?”</title><link>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/chernihiv-polytechnic-what-is-devops/</guid><description>Percona’s Evgeniy Patlan (Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering) and Serhii Stasiuk (Build/Release Engineer) participated in an online public meetup “What is DevOps?” for students of Chernihiv Polytechnic National University. Together with Volodymyr Rudiy (CEO, Agilevision.io) and Volodymyr Bazilevich (Academic, Chernihiv Polytechnic National University), they discussed the modern views on DevOps methodology, practices and people who do this job nowadays, tasks and challenges that they face and what is expected of them on the modern labor market.</description></item><item><title>National University "Chernihiv Polytechnic"</title><link>https://percona.community/events/national_university_chernihiv_polytechnic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/national_university_chernihiv_polytechnic/</guid><description>Percona encourages its staff members to actively collaborate with universities and local communities. Evgeniy Patlan (Manager, Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering) is one of those who enjoy active communication with local students and those who would like to become more familiar with modern open source technologies. In October, he participated in the student training which took place in the Ukrainian National University &amp;ldquo;Chernihiv Polytechnic&amp;rdquo;.
The mission of the National University &amp;ldquo;Chernihiv Polytechnic&amp;rdquo; is the development of society through education and research to build leadership and address global challenges in a changing world.</description></item><item><title>All Things Open 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in ATO (All Things Open) in Raleigh Convention Center on October 17th - 19th.
Percona speakers gave 4 talks during the conference:
The PostgreSQL Twin Bill: The 7 Deadly PostgreSQL Mistakes &amp;amp; Review of what&amp;rsquo;s new in PostgreSQL 14 by Matt Yonkovit (HOSS) and Barrett Chambers (Sr. Manager, Solutions Engineering). Distributed Storage in the Cloud by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Deploying MongoDB sharded clusters easily with Terraform and Ansible by Ivan Groenewold (Architect).</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit Seattle 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in the OSS event organized by Linux Foundation in Seattle in Hyatt Regency Hotel on September 27-30. It was really exciting for all of us to start meeting in person with customers, community members, and teammates as well!
Percona speakers gave 3 talks during the conference: From a database in container to DBaaS on Kubernetes by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Default to Open - Steps and Traps by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy).</description></item><item><title>OSDN Conf Kyiv 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</guid><description>Percona sponsored the OSDN Conf Kyiv which was held in person in the Nivki-hal on September 18th. It was a one-day non-commercial, volunteer-organized event centered on free and open-source software. Mykola Marzhan (Director of Server Engineering, Percona) and Evgeniy Patlan (Manager of Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering, Percona) are the main organizers of the conference.
During the event, 400 attendees had the opportunity to visit presentations by the open-source community leaders, meet each other and chat during lunch and coffee breaks, discuss the latest trends with representatives on booths.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item></channel></rss>