<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community MeetUps on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/</link><description>Recent content in Percona Community MeetUps on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PostgreSQL October 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-october-2021/</guid><description>The next Community MeetUp for PostgreSQL will be dedicated to Performance and Troubleshooting PostgreSQL. Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy (HOSS) at Percona, is hosting the talk with Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona, for one hour live streaming followed by Q&amp;amp;A. This is a part of our regular monthly event to talk about databases.
Join us for an hour MeetUp for PostgreSQL
Date: Wednesday Oct 13th, 2021 at 11:00am EST</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MongoDB Oct 20th, 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-october-2021/</guid><description>Now that MongoDB 5.0 is out, the Percona Community MeetUp for MongoDB in October will highlight new features of this release. We will also talk about backups, scalability, and security. Our experts, Andrew Pogrebnoi, Principal Software Engineer at Percona, and Kimberly Wilkins, MongoDB Technical Lead at Percona, will join Matt Yonkovit, The HOSS at Percona, to answer all your questions.
Join us for an-hour MeetUp for MongoDB:</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MySQL Oct 6th 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-october-2021/</guid><description>Percona Community Team organizes the MeetUp for MySQL every first week of the month. It is an hour of live streaming dedicated to experts and users to discuss MySQL databases. Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy (HOSS), invites experts to share their knowledge. Come up with your questions as they like to find those tough database problems.
Join for an hour MeetUp for MySQL
Day: Wednesday Oct 6th at 11:00 am EDT/ 5:00 pm CEST/ 8:30pm IST</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PMM Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</guid><description>The Community MeetUp for PMM was an extraordinary one-hour Live Broadcast MeetUp from the OSS Summit on last Sept 29th, to talk about open source databases, observability and monitoring MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL with PMM. Percona experts Matt Yonkovit and Michael Coburn has made a PMM Demo. Check the the full recording by clicking the video here:
Video Link: https://youtu.be/2WSsmhzsVXg
Transcript Matt Yonkovit, The HOSS at Percona, will host the Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) from the Open Source Summit in Seattle.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MongoDB Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-september-2021/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit hosted the Percona MeetUp for MongoDB on September 22nd with Vinodh Krishnaswamy, Support Engineer at Percona, to talk about &amp;ldquo;MongoDB sharded Cluster- best practices&amp;rdquo; and Ege Güneş, Software Engineer at Percona, to discuss &amp;ldquo;Cross-regional replication for MongoDB with Kubernetes&amp;rdquo;. Check full video on youtube by clicking the link below :
Video Link: https://youtu.be/s7v8hAC55iw
Transcript Matt Yonkovit Good amazing that&amp;rsquo;s a cool whoa
Hello everybody welcome to another Зercona live streamб we are at the top of the hour so thank you for joining us today I&amp;rsquo;ve got Ege and Vinodh with me from Team Perconaю So hello guys I&amp;rsquo;m gonna go ahead and I&amp;rsquo;m gonna turn on the chat so we can see anybody who pops in here and asks us some questions.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PostgreSQL Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-september-2021/</guid><description>Full video recording of the live-streamed Community MeetUp for postgreSQL we held on September 15th, 2021. Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS, sat down with Jobin Augustine, PostgreSQL Escalation Specialist in Support at Percona, and Ibrar Ahmed, Senior Software Architect at Percona to talk about “PostgreSQL Data and Database Security” and &amp;ldquo;Driving factors for increased PostgreSQL adoptions&amp;rdquo;.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/B_U3rYue0iQ
Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hey everybody, welcome to another Percona live stream. We are here with Ibrar and Jobin today.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MySQL Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-september-2021/</guid><description>Watch the video record of the live-streamed Community MeetUp for MySQL we held on September 8, 2021. Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS, sat down with 2 MySQL experts, Nando Camargos and Marcos Albe, and discusses the ways you REALLY can make your database faster. They touched query optimization, indexes, the art of database design, hiding columns, and things that occupy Matt’s thoughts when he wakes up at 3 AM.
Video Link: https://youtu.</description></item></channel></rss>