<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community MeetUps on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/</link><description>Recent content in Percona Community MeetUps on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PMM Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, The HOSS at Percona, will host the Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) from the Open Source Summit in Seattle. We will talk about database monitoring, discuss PMM in detail and also do a tour of the Summit during a one hour live stream with Michael Coburn, Principal Architect at Percona. You can ask questions in-person or virtually and get help.
Join us for an hour MeetUp for PMM</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MongoDB Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-september-2021/</guid><description>MongoDB is a database which came into light around the mid-2000s used by companies and development teams of all sizes. The Percona Head of Open Source Strategy - HOSS - and experts organize a series of regular live online streaming Community MeetUp for MongoDB to share their knowledge and to answer attendees' questions.
Join for an hour MeetUp for MongoDB
Day: Wednesday Sept 22nd, 2021 at 11:00am EDT (5:00 pm CEST or 8:30 pm IST) Location: Discord Live streaming on YouTube and Twitch Add this event to your Google Calendar</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MySQL Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-september-2021/</guid><description>The Percona Community MeetUp for MySQL is a great opportunity for experts to share their knowledge and to the attendees to ask questions. This event is a part of a series of regular live online streaming with Matt Yonkovit, The Head of OpenSource Strategy (HOSS) dedicated to experts and users of database.
Join the Percona MeetUp for MySQL
Day: Wednesday Sept 8th, 2021 at 11:00am EST</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PostgreSQL Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-september-2021/</guid><description>PostgreSQL counts more than 20 years of community development.The Percona Community MeetUp for PostgreSQL is an hour-long talk hosted by Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy (HOSS) at Percona with experts to talk database. It is a series of regular live online streaming where users can ask any question.
Join for an hour MeetUp for PostgreSQL
Day: Wednesday Sept 15th, 2021 at 11:00am EST</description></item></channel></rss>