<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meetup on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/meetup/</link><description>Recent content in Meetup on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MySQL Oct 6th 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-october-2021/</guid><description>Percona Community Team organizes the MeetUp for MySQL every first week of the month. It is an hour of live streaming dedicated to experts and users to discuss MySQL databases. Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy (HOSS), invites experts to share their knowledge. Come up with your questions as they like to find those tough database problems.
Join for an hour MeetUp for MySQL
Day: Wednesday Oct 6th at 11:00 am EDT/ 5:00 pm CEST/ 8:30pm IST</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PostgreSQL October 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-october-2021/</guid><description>The next Community MeetUp for PostgreSQL will be dedicated to Performance and Troubleshooting PostgreSQL. Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy (HOSS) at Percona, is hosting the talk with Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona, for one hour live streaming followed by Q&amp;amp;A. This is a part of our regular monthly event to talk about databases.
Join us for an hour MeetUp for PostgreSQL
Date: Wednesday Oct 13th, 2021 at 11:00am EST</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PMM Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-pmm-september-2021/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, The HOSS at Percona, will host the Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) from the Open Source Summit in Seattle. We will talk about database monitoring, discuss PMM in detail and also do a tour of the Summit during a one hour live stream with Michael Coburn, Principal Architect at Percona. You can ask questions in-person or virtually and get help.
Join us for an hour MeetUp for PMM</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MongoDB Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mongodb-september-2021/</guid><description>MongoDB is a database which came into light around the mid-2000s used by companies and development teams of all sizes. The Percona Head of Open Source Strategy - HOSS - and experts organize a series of regular live online streaming Community MeetUp for MongoDB to share their knowledge and to answer attendees' questions.
Join for an hour MeetUp for MongoDB
Day: Wednesday Sept 22nd, 2021 at 11:00am EDT (5:00 pm CEST or 8:30 pm IST) Location: Discord Live streaming on YouTube and Twitch Add this event to your Google Calendar</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PostgreSQL Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-september-2021/</guid><description>PostgreSQL counts more than 20 years of community development.The Percona Community MeetUp for PostgreSQL is an hour-long talk hosted by Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy (HOSS) at Percona with experts to talk database. It is a series of regular live online streaming where users can ask any question.
Join for an hour MeetUp for PostgreSQL
Day: Wednesday Sept 15th, 2021 at 11:00am EST</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for MySQL Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-mysql-september-2021/</guid><description>Watch the video record of the live-streamed Community MeetUp for MySQL we held on September 8, 2021. Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS, sat down with 2 MySQL experts, Nando Camargos and Marcos Albe, and discusses the ways you REALLY can make your database faster. They touched query optimization, indexes, the art of database design, hiding columns, and things that occupy Matt’s thoughts when he wakes up at 3 AM.
Video Link: https://youtu.</description></item></channel></rss>