<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>author_jaime on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/author_jaime/</link><description>Recent content in author_jaime on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/author_jaime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Are your Database Backups Good Enough?</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</guid><description>In the last few years there have been several examples of major service problems affecting businesses data: outages causing data inconsistencies; unavailability or data loss, and worldwide cyberattacks encrypting your files and asking for a ransom.
Database-related incidents are a very common industry issue- even if the root cause is not the database system itself. No matter if your main relational system is MySQL, MariaDB, PostgresQL or AWS Aurora -there will be a time where you will need to make use of backups to recover to a previous state.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Tutorial: Query Optimization and TLS at Large Scale</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 14:05:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/15/percona-live-europe-tutorial-query-optimization-workshop-tls-large-scale-session/</guid><description>For Percona Live Europe this year, I got accepted a workshop on query optimization and a 50-minute talk covering TLS for MySQL at Large Scale, talking about our experiences at the Wikimedia Foundation.
Workshop The 3-hour workshop on Monday, titled Query Optimization with MySQL 8.0 and MariaDB 10.3: The Basics is a beginners' tutorial–though dense in content. It&amp;rsquo;s for people who are more familiar with database storage systems other than InnoDB for MySQL, MariaDB or Percona Server.</description></item></channel></rss>