<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authors on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/authors/</link><description>Recent content in Authors on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/aftab_khan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/aftab_khan/</guid><description>IT professional with 10+ years experience, mainly in large commercial environments. Expertise in MySQL, MariaDB, Big Data, Bash , Unix systems and Python development. Aftab&amp;rsquo;s LinkedIn Profile</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/aleksandar_aleksandrov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/aleksandar_aleksandrov/</guid><description>Aleksandar is a Data Engineer at MessageBird, an IT Telecom Startup based in Amsterdam. His mission is to bring accessible data to every nook and cranny in the business. In the data team in MessageBird he is working on designing, building and maintaining the data infrastructure with a focus on scaling it as the business grows.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/aleksandra_abramova/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/aleksandra_abramova/</guid><description>Aleksandra joined Percona Community Team in 2021 as a Community Specialist. Before joining Percona, she worked as a support specialist and as a technical writer in Simtech Development. She is now focusing on communicating with the opensource community, building awareness about Percona products and services, and event organizing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/alexander_rubin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/alexander_rubin/</guid><description>Alexander has worked with MySQL since 2000 as a DBA and Application Developer. He has performed MySQL consulting as a principal consultant/architect for over 13 years, starting with MySQL AB in 2006, then Sun Microsystems, then Oracle and then Percona. Alex has helped many customers design large, scalable, and highly available MySQL systems and optimize MySQL performance. He has also helped customers design Big Data stores with Apache Hadoop and related technologies.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/alexandre_vaniachine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/alexandre_vaniachine/</guid><description>Alexandre is an Open Source enthusiast experienced in troubleshooting and resolving scalability issues across the full software stack. In industry and academia, he scaled up data processing from terabytes to petabytes, while minimizing data losses below acceptable level. Early in his career Alexandre pioneered deployment of MySQL databases on Virtual Machines. Alexandre is a Senior MySQL DBA at VirtualHealth</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/alexey_mikotkin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/alexey_mikotkin/</guid><description>Alexey Mikotkin is a software engineer at Devart. He leads a team that develops SQL Server, MySQL, and Oracle tools. The team&amp;rsquo;s main development environment is .NET. Alexey has a great experience in development of applications (backend/frontend). New technologies are the focus of Alexey&amp;rsquo;s interest.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/andrey_sergeev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/andrey_sergeev/</guid><description>Team lead and developer working on various e-commerce and IOT products. Over 3 years of experience in Lamoda, one of the largest e-commerce site in Russia. Current project is a new IOT platform for rapid development fast effective scalable IOT and IIOT solutions.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/andrii_skomorokhov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/andrii_skomorokhov/</guid><description>Software Engineer, PMM</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/anton_bystrov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/anton_bystrov/</guid><description>Dashboards engineer, Percona Monitoring and Management.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/antonios_giannopoulos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/antonios_giannopoulos/</guid><description>Antonios Giannopoulos is a Senior Database Administrator at ObjectRocket supporting MongoDB, Elastic and CockroachDB. Antonios has 18 years of experience in databases and system engineering. He really enjoys challenges in sharding and schema design and loves migrations from Relational to NoSQL world.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/arjen_lentz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/arjen_lentz/</guid><description>Making stuff work. Solving problems. Organising things. Connecting people. Coming up with new angles.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/art_vanscheppingen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/art_vanscheppingen/</guid><description>Art van Scheppingen is a Senior Database Engineer at MessageBird with focus on database scalability and reliability. He&amp;rsquo;s a pragmatic MySQL and Database expert with over 20 years experience in web development. He previously worked in various database architectural roles and as Senior Support Engineer at Severalnines. He has experience with a broad spectrum of (open source) databases: from MySQL to MongoDB, Cassandra to Hadoop and from Sphinx Search to SOLR.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/atish_a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/atish_a/</guid><description>Atish is a Distributed Database Systems Engineer, and works in a DevOps team focusing on operational Databases and Data Infrastructure. He is passionate about highly available, scalable database systems &amp;amp; data pipelines. He&amp;rsquo;s a data engineering enthusiast and a MongoDB certified professional.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/aurelien_lequoy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/aurelien_lequoy/</guid><description>Founder &amp;amp; CEO at 68 Koncept Inc, MySQL Expert, Entrepreneur, Author of Glial (PHP framework) &amp;amp; PmaControl (MySQL Tools)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/brian_matheson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/brian_matheson/</guid><description>Technical Account Management, MayaData. Brian Matheson helps enterprise PaaS teams turn Kubernetes into a Data Plane for hosting Stateful Applications. A serial entrepreneur with an intense customer focus, Brian has helped a number of startups in a technical capacity, and is currently @ MayaData. Twitter @brian_matheson.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/carlos_salguero/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/carlos_salguero/</guid><description>Software Engineer, PMM, Percona Toolkit</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/cate_lawrence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/cate_lawrence/</guid><description>I’m a tech journalist and reporter, who has experience in marketing and content strategy, and I have undertaken multiple projects internationally for enterprise clients.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/colin_charles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/colin_charles/</guid><description>Businessperson, open source consultant, technical architect, experienced community builder based in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/daniel_black/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/daniel_black/</guid><description>After a reasonable amount of time doing development and IT security work, Daniel landed a DBA Consultant job and loved it.
After writing a few too many bug fixes without a client to bill them to, he joined IBM to make MariaDB and MySQL scale on IBM POWER.
The love for the community brought him to MariaDB Foundation where he embraces the innovation of contributors and users to make</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/daniil_bazhenov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/daniil_bazhenov/</guid><description>I am proud to work for the Percona Community Team.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/danish_wadhwa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/danish_wadhwa/</guid><description>Danish Wadhwa is a doyen of governing the digital content to assemble good relationships for enterprises or individuals. He is specialized in digital marketing, cloud computing, web designing and offers other valuable IT services for organizations, eventually enhancing their shape by delivering stupendous solutions to their business problems.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/dave_cohen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/dave_cohen/</guid><description>Dave Cohen is the Storage Solutions CTO in Intel&amp;rsquo;s Non-Volatile Memory and Storage (NVMS) Group and the Chief Architect of Intel&amp;rsquo;s Data Management Platform. This is a rack-centric, physical cluster that builds on the Intel Rack Scale Design (RSD). Dave has been at Intel for five years working on a variety of network and storage related solutions. His career spans over 30 years working on large scale, distributed systems for Fortune 500 companies across several industry segments.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/david_berube/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/david_berube/</guid><description>David Berube is a freelance Ruby on Rails developer and MySQL performance consultant. He specializes in maintaining legacy systems. He authored the books “Practical Rails Gems” and “Practical Reporting with Ruby and Rails”, and co-authored the book “Practical Rails Plugins,&amp;quot; and he&amp;rsquo;s written for venues like Dr. Dobb&amp;rsquo;s Journal, Linux Pro Magazine, and IBM DeveloperWorks. Website: berubeconsulting.com</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/david_zhao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/david_zhao/</guid><description>Founder of Kunlun Distributed DBMS. Formerly worked in Oracle Berkeley DB and MySQL teams from 2007 to 2015 as database kernel developer. Since October 2015, worked in TDSQL team of Tencent as database kernel developer, took the initiative to design and implement the distributed transaction processing and distributed query processing features of TDSQL. Left Tencent in July 2019 and started working on Kunlun distributed DBMS.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/denys_kondratenko/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/denys_kondratenko/</guid><description>Engineering Manager, PMM</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/dinesh_joshi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/dinesh_joshi/</guid><description>Dinesh is a Committer on the Apache Cassandra project. Dinesh has been a professional Software Engineer for over a decade building highly scalable realtime Web Services and Distributed Streaming Data Processing Architectures serving over 1 billion devices. He has a Masters degree in Computer Science (Distributed Systems &amp;amp; Databases) from Georgia Tech, Atlanta, USA.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/donatas_abraitis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/donatas_abraitis/</guid><description>I’m a Systems engineer at Hostinger. I love solving non-trivial issues. You can find more posts I wrote on</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/dongchan_sung/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/dongchan_sung/</guid><description>MySQL DBA, KakaoBank
Dongchan is DBA at KakaoBank, the Korean internet bank. He is very interested in data efficient processing and automation. His final goal is building unbreakable data system. He is interested in all elements (monitoring, automation) for a stable system configuration. https://gywn.blog</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/elizaveta_dokshina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/elizaveta_dokshina/</guid><description>Developer working on Tarantool. Several years of experience in solution implementation, focused in high performance tasks. Current projects include Tarantool Cartridge (a framework for creating distributed apps), an Ansible role for it to deploy these apps, and a command-line utility for the framework.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/emily_gorcenski/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/emily_gorcenski/</guid><description>Emily Gorcenski is Head of Data for ThoughtWorks, Germany.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/federico_campoli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/federico_campoli/</guid><description>Federico is the author of pg_chameleon a replication tool from MySQL to PostgreSQL developed in Python 3.3+</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/federico_razzoli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/federico_razzoli/</guid><description>Relational databases lover and open source supporter. I wrote &amp;ldquo;Mastering MariaDB&amp;rdquo; in 2014, and I was a MariaDB Community Ambassador. I am an independent consultant based in London</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/felix_mattrat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/felix_mattrat/</guid><description>Félix is a Data Engineer at MessageBird, an IT Telecom Startup based in Amsterdam. With the data team of MessageBird he is working on building and managing various data pipelines with a focus on scalability and real-time. He also worked on designing and deploying the ClickHouse cluster and now is busy with running and scaling.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/flavius_mecea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/flavius_mecea/</guid><description>Flavius Mecea is a software and operations engineer at Presslabs. A vivid builder and avid reader, Flavius is always up to something—exploring untapped possibilities using Kubernetes &amp;amp; Go, mentoring students into the secrets of algorithms and DevOps or playing with hardware and machine learning. He’s a high-spirited person and an all-time helper that always meets a new day with curiosity.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/francisco_miguel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/francisco_miguel/</guid><description>Principal Data Engineer at UnitedHealth Group, for Oracle and MySQL. When he is not working or coding, Fran likes to backpack visiting new places and experiencing different cultures.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/gaurav_belani/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/gaurav_belani/</guid><description>Gaurav Belani is a senior SEO and content marketing analyst at Growfusely, a content marketing agency that specializes in data-driven SEO. He has more than seven years of experience in digital marketing and loves to read and write about AI, machine learning, data science, and other emerging technologies. In his spare time, he enjoys watching movies and listening to music. Connect with him Linkedin and Twitter at @belanigaurav</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/geoff_winans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/geoff_winans/</guid><description>I have held the role of MySQL DBA for the last eight years. Prior to 2012, I was a Linux admin who worked with RHEL and CentOS. Today, I work for CVS as part of their Open Source team, specifically the lead engineer for MySQL/MariaDB.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/giuseppe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/giuseppe/</guid><description>Software Explorer and creator of tools. Formerly at MySQL AB, and then through acquisitions at Sun Microsystems and Oracle, and currently at VMware through a merge. I am an active member of the MySQL community and long timer open source enthusiast. During the past decades, I have worked in various IT related fields, with a focus on databases, software development, quality assurance, and system administration. Fluent in Italian, English, Go, Spanish, SQL, Bash, and good speaker of C, French, and Perl.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/gurnish_anand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/gurnish_anand/</guid><description>Gurnish&amp;rsquo;s career has been with Oracle, in Technical Management, and now with MySQL. On the personal front, I live/work in San Francisco, and in my free time I zip around in single engine airplanes around the bay!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/jaime_crespo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/jaime_crespo/</guid><description>Jaime is the Senior DBA of the Wikimedia Foundation, managing Wikipedia databases.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/jeff_gagne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/jeff_gagne/</guid><description>Jean-François (J-F, JF or Jeff for short, not just Jean please) is a System/Infrastructure Engineer and a MySQL Expert. In July 2018, he joined MessageBird, an IT telco startup in Amsterdam, with the mission of scaling the MySQL infrastructure. Before that, J-F worked for five years on growing the Booking.com MySQL and MariaDB installations, including dealing with replication bottlenecks (he also works on many other non MySQL related projects that are less relevant here).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/jorge_torres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/jorge_torres/</guid><description>Jorge Torres is the Co-founder &amp;amp; CEO of MindsDB. He is also a visiting scholar at UC Berkeley researching machine learning automation and explainability. Prior to founding MindsDB, he worked for a number of data-intensive start-ups, most recently working with Aneesh Chopra (the first CTO in the US government) building data systems that analyze billions of patients records and lead to highest savings for millions of patients. He started his work on scaling solutions using machine learning in early 2008 while working as first full time engineer at Couchsurfing where he helped grow the company from a few thousand users to a few million.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/kaj_arno/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/kaj_arno/</guid><description>Kaj Arnö is CEO of the MariaDB Foundation. He is a software industry generalist, having served as VP Professional Services, VP Engineering, CIO and VP Community Relations of MySQL AB prior to the acquisition by Sun Microsystems. At Sun, Kaj served as MySQL Ambassador to Sun and Sun VP of Database Community. Board member at Footbalance Systems Oy (Helsinki, Finland). Past founder, CEO and 14 year main entrepreneur of Polycon Ab (Finland).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/koehntopp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/koehntopp/</guid><description>Senior Scalability Engineer at Booking.com.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/krunal_bauskar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/krunal_bauskar/</guid><description>Krunal has been actively working in MySQL space for over a decade. He is currently driving the adaption of the ARM ecosystem for MySQL/MariaDB/Percona through his #mysqlonarm initiative working at Huawei. In the past he has worked on multiple MySQL projects viz. undo log truncate, atomic truncate temp table work, Percona XtraDB Cluster performance, PXC-5.7/8.0 features as part of his tenure at MySQL/Oracle (as InnoDB developer) and Percona (as PXC product lead).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/lefred/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/lefred/</guid><description>@lefred has been consulting OpenSource and MySQL for almost 20 years. After graduating in Management Information Technology, Frédéric Descamps started his career as a developer for an ERP under HPUX. He will then opt for a career in the world of open-source by joining one of the first Belgian start-up dedicated 100% to free projects around GNU/Linux. It is in 2011 that lefred joined Percona, one of the leading MySQL-based specialists.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/levi_junkert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/levi_junkert/</guid><description>Levi is an infrastructure engineer who works at SmithRx creating HIPAA compliant infrastructure and software for the prescription benefits management industry. He has been building automated systems for over 10 years and working with MySQL and PostgreSQL database management systems for the past 18 years. Previous to SmithRx software that Levi has written can be found at companies such as: Facebook, Cisco, Oracle, JPL-NASA, and other small start-ups in The Bay area.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/lorraine_pocklington/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/lorraine_pocklington/</guid><description>Community Manager for Percona</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/mayank_sharma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/mayank_sharma/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/meet_patel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/meet_patel/</guid><description>I am Meet Patel, 2nd year undergraduate at DAIICT, Gandhinagar, India; pursuing a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Information and Communication Technology with a minor in Computational Science. I am an open open source enthusiast and who is always eager to learn about experimenting with new tools and technologies!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/michael_aboagye/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/michael_aboagye/</guid><description>Michael is a freelance database consultant, back-end data engineer and founder of technical writing firm @BytesDaten. He is based in Accra, Ghana and has worked with startups in the eCommerce and healthcare industry. His tech stack includes but not limited to Kafka, Hadoop, Storm, Python, Rails, Cassandra, Postgres, Elastic Search, Redis and Zookeeper. Follow him on twitter @kwaku_mikey</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/mons_anderson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/mons_anderson/</guid><description>Architect of the S3 compatible object storage by Mail.ru Cloud Solutions. Technical product manager at Tarantool. 20+ years of experience in programming, 8+ years in high-performance applications based on Tarantool.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/oleg_babin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/oleg_babin/</guid><description>Tarantool Solution Engineer. Last several years I develop high-performance applications based on Tarantool. Developer of Tarantool Data Grid - the platform for developing distributed applications with a fast persistent in-memory storage. Also, I participate in developing of some Tarantool open source projects.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/oystein_grovlen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/oystein_grovlen/</guid><description>Øystein Grøvlen is a Senior Staff Engineer in Alibaba Cloud, where he works in the Database Products Group. Before joining Alibaba, Øystein worked for 10 years in the MySQL optimizer team at Sun/Oracle. At Sun Microsystems, he was also a contributor on the Apache Derby project and Sun&amp;rsquo;s Architectural Lead on Java DB. Prior to that, he worked for 10 years on development of Clustra, a highly available DBMS. Øystein has been talking about the MySQL Optimizer at several conferences over the years.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/pingcap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/pingcap/</guid><description>PingCAP is building an open source distributed NewSQL hybrid transactional and analytical processing (HTAP) database. Its flagship open source database project, TiDB, is a cloud-native distributed SQL layer with MySQL compatibility. TiDB’s sister project, TiKV, is a cloud-native distributed Key-Value store and also growing rapidly.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/puneet_kala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/puneet_kala/</guid><description>Frontend Web Automation Quality Assurance at Percona</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/raghavendra_prabhu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/raghavendra_prabhu/</guid><description>Raghavendra works as a Senior Software Engineer in the Database Reliability Engineering team at Yelp&amp;rsquo;s London office, dealing with datastores such as Cassandra and MySQL. Prior to that, he worked at Percona as the Product Lead of Percona XtraDB Cluster (PXC) and at Yahoo as a Systems Engineer. His main interests include distributed systems, databases, operating systems, and virtualization. He blogs at http://blog.rdprabhu.com/ and tweets @randomsurfer.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/rasika/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/rasika/</guid><description>Technical Writer, PMM</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/renato_losio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/renato_losio/</guid><description>Renato Losio is a software and cloud architect, a digital nomad and an accidental speaker. He has many years of experience as a software engineer, tech lead and cloud services specialist in Italy, UK, Portugal and Germany. He currently lives in Berlin and works remotely as principal cloud architect for Funambol inc. Location-based services and relational databases are his main working interests. A certified AWS professional, he holds an MSc degree in Physics and an MSc in Computing Science.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/rene_cannao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/rene_cannao/</guid><description>René founded ProxySQL in 2016 after developing it since 2013. He has over 15 years of experience as Database Administrator mostly on MySQL, working as Senior MySQL Support Engineer at Sun/Oracle, Senior Operational DBA at Blackbird, and consulting for small and large companies like Dropbox. In this period he build an analytic and problem-solving mindset, he is always eager to take on new challenges, especially if they are related to high performance.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/roman_proshkin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/roman_proshkin/</guid><description>Roman Proskin, senior developer at Mail.ru Group. For the last few years I am working on Tarantool — an in-memory computing platform. I have developed and deployed to production several projects focused on high availability and performance. My current project involves a major commercial bank, where I manage everything from monitoring and logging to CI/CD.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/ronak_rahman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/ronak_rahman/</guid><description>Liquibase Developer Advocate. Background in DevOps, Customer Success, and Solution Architecture. Current project: Supporting and organizing the Liquibase community answering questions. Follow Ronak on Twitter or LinkedIn.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/shlomi_noach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/shlomi_noach/</guid><description>Engineer and database geek, working at PlanetScale on both open source Vitess as well as PlanetScaleDB. Interested in database infrastructure solutions such as high availability, reliability, enablement, automation and testing. Shlomi is an active MySQL community member, authors orchestrator, gh-ost, common_schema and other open source tools, and blogs at http://openark.org. He is the recipient of MySQL Community Member of the Year, Oracle ACE (Alumni) &amp;amp; Oracle Technologist of the Year awards.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/stacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/stacy/</guid><description>Anastasia &amp;lsquo;Stacy&amp;rsquo; Rostova (Raspopina) is now a Communications Manager at ProxySQL, the company developing an open source HA protocol aware proxy for MySQL and its forks (Percona Server, MariaDB). Previously she worked at Percona as a Marketing Specialist responsible for internal company communications, event management, promotional activities, content generation and other special projects. Prior to this Stacy was in charge of HighLoad++ and RIT++, large tech conferences in Russia boasting thousands of attendees.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/sugu_sougoumarane/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/sugu_sougoumarane/</guid><description>Sugu is the co-creator of Vitess, and has been working on it since 2010. Prior to Vitess, Sugu worked on scalability at YouTube and was also part of PayPal in the early days. His recent interest is in distributed systems and consensus algorithms. He occasionally shares his thoughts on his blog ssougou.blogspot.com.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/taras_kozub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/taras_kozub/</guid><description>Agile Facilitator, PMM</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/thodoris_bais/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/thodoris_bais/</guid><description>Thodoris Bais works as a Scrum Master for ABN Amro bank and contributes to the prosperity of the IT community in several ways. He is the Founder &amp;amp; Leader of Utrecht Java User Group, which counts around 2500 members and has hosted exceptional speakers (among others, James Gosling and Uncle Bob). Besides, he helps new communities making their first steps. Thodoris serves the Expert Group of JSR-385 and helps developers to grow their career.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/tiago_jorge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/tiago_jorge/</guid><description>Tiago is a Senior Software Developer at Oracle and Technical Lead for Group Communication System in Group Replication.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/timur_solodovnikov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/timur_solodovnikov/</guid><description>For the last 10 years, Timur has worked in various telco companies. He has hands-on experience in databases, system and network engineering. Currently Timur works as a Senior DBA for Five9, Inc., the leading provider of cloud contact center software. He lives in California, US with wife and daughter.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/tom_basil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/tom_basil/</guid><description>Tom Basil is Chief of Staff at Percona.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/tyler_turk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/tyler_turk/</guid><description>Tyler is an engineer on the player accounts team at Riot Games. The Player Accounts team is responsible for every player&amp;rsquo;s ability to log in and manage account data. In 2018, we re-architected our systems to become GDPR compliant, provide a better player experience, and enable Riot to become a multi-game company in the future.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/valeriy_kravchuk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/valeriy_kravchuk/</guid><description>Valeriy Kravchuk has supported MySQL users since 2005, in MySQL AB, Sun, Oracle, Percona and (since 2016) MariaDB Corporation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/vicen%C8%9Biu_ciorbaru/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/vicen%C8%9Biu_ciorbaru/</guid><description>Vicențiu works at the MariaDB Foundation as a Software Engineer. He focuses on Optimizer development, but has also worked on other parts of the MariaDB Server. Notable projects include: Window Functions in MariaDB, Custom Aggregate Functions in MariaDB, Roles in MariaDB</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/vladimir_drynkin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/vladimir_drynkin/</guid><description>Team lead and developer working on investment banking solutions. Over four years of experience in Alfa-bank, the largest commercial bank in Russia. The current project is a new distributed core system for the corporate investment bank based on the Tarantool in-memory database and application server.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/wayne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/wayne/</guid><description>When I&amp;rsquo;m not working with MySQL or other Open-source software packages. I like to do woodworking, 3D design and Printing, listening to all forms of Metal music and electronic projects with Raspberry PI, Arduino. Wayne lives in Powell Ohio, with his wife, daughter, 6 cats and 2 dogs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/werner_keil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/werner_keil/</guid><description>Werner Keil is a Cloud Architect, Eclipse RCP and Microservice expert for a large bank. Helping Global 500 Enterprises across industries and leading IT vendors. He worked for over 30 years as IT Manager, PM, Coach, SW architect and consultant for Finance, Mobile, Media, Transport and Public sector. Werner develops enterprise systems using Java, Java/Jakarta EE, Oracle, IBM, Spring or Microsoft technologies, JavaScript, Node, Angular, dynamic or functional languages. Werner is Committer at Apache Foundation, Eclipse Foundation, Babel Language Champion, UOMo Project Lead and active member of the Java Community Process.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/yahav_biran/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/yahav_biran/</guid><description>Yahav is a Senior Solutions Architect in Amazon Web Services Game-Tech. Dr. Biran designs reliable, resilient, and secured cloud-based information systems for AWS Cloud customers. He received his Ph.D. (Systems Engineering) from Colorado State University in 2017. He was previously a Technical Program Manager at Microsoft Azure; there he built Azure Compute Services. He has more than fifteen years of professional experience in information systems. His research seeks an objective and overall higher fidelity approach to optimize large scale game-tech scenarios.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/yaroslav_dynnikov/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/yaroslav_dynnikov/</guid><description>Tarantool Solution Engineer and Software Developer. I have used Lua since 2007. For the last three years this has been my primary programming language professionally. I used it for video streaming business logic and now within Tarantool to develop an in-memory database and a Lua application server.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://percona.community/authors/yoav_eilat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/authors/yoav_eilat/</guid><description>Yoav is Senior Product Manager for Amazon Relational Database Service and Amazon Aurora. He joined AWS in 2016 after holding product roles for several years at Oracle and other technology companies. At AWS, he managed the launches of Aurora PostgreSQL, Aurora Serverless, Aurora Global Database, and other major features. Yoav currently focuses on new capabilities for the MySQL and PostgreSQL database engines.</description></item></channel></rss>