<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona’s HOSS Talks FOSS: The Open Source Database Podcast on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/</link><description>Recent content in Percona’s HOSS Talks FOSS: The Open Source Database Podcast on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/podcasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open source database, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, MariaDB - Part 02 - Percona Podcast Special Edition 50</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/50-percona-opensource-podcast-highlight-of-talks-2021-part02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/50-percona-opensource-podcast-highlight-of-talks-2021-part02/</guid><description>Transcript</description></item><item><title>Open source database, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, MariaDB - Percona Podcast Special Edition 49</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/49-percona-opensource-podcast-highlight-of-talks-2021-part01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/49-percona-opensource-podcast-highlight-of-talks-2021-part01/</guid><description>Transcript</description></item><item><title>OnGres, PostgreSQL, Open Source, Kubernetes, Babelfish w/ Alvaro Hernández - Percona Podcast 48</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/48-ongres-postgresql-open-source-kubernetes-babelfish/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/48-ongres-postgresql-open-source-kubernetes-babelfish/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hi everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m the HOSS, Matt Yonkovit. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Alvaro Hernández. Alvaro, how are you today?
Alvaro Hernández:
I&amp;rsquo;m very good. Thank you for having me today.
Matt Yonkovit:
Yes. And, and quite honestly, based on your wall, I think people will understand what we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about. So, before we go anywhere you have to tell me about the elephant in the room.</description></item><item><title>Talking Open Source, Linux OS, Fedora With David Duncan (Solutions Architect, AWS) - Percona Podcast 47</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/47-aws-opensource-linux-os-fedora-david-duncan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/47-aws-opensource-linux-os-fedora-david-duncan/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m HOSS, Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona. Matt Yonkovit. Today I&amp;rsquo;m here with David Duncan. Hi, David, how are you doing?
David Duncan:
Hi, yeah, Hey Matt, how are you?
Matt Yonkovit:
David, you work for AWS, as a partner architecture Solution Architect, our solution partner architect?
David Duncan:
I am called a Partner Solutions Architect. I spend a lot of my time working with our operating system partners.</description></item><item><title>Positioning Cloud Native Open Source Project - Percona Podcast 46</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/46-emily-omier-positioning-cloud-native-open-source/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/46-emily-omier-positioning-cloud-native-open-source/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m the HOSS Matt Yonkovit. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Emily Omier. Hi, Emily, how are you today?
Emily Omier:
I&amp;rsquo;m doing well. Thank you.
Matt Yonkovit:
No problem. So Emily, you actually have your own consulting company that is focused on positioning open source projects, more specifically,Cloud Native open source projects.
Emily Omier:
Yeah. And actually, to be fair, I generally work with what I call open source startups, or Cloud Native startups.</description></item><item><title>Building a Strong Open Source Community With Corey Hulen (CTO, Mattermost) - Percona Podcast 45</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/45-mattermost-corey-hulen-open-source-ospo-percona/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/45-mattermost-corey-hulen-open-source-ospo-percona/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m the HOSS, Matt Yonkovit. Today I&amp;rsquo;m here with Corey Hulen, who is the CTO of Mattermost. Hi, Corey. How are you?
Corey Hulen Hi! Thanks for having me. Glad to be here.
Matt Yonkovit: So Corey and I worked together briefly a few years ago, and we have kept in touch over open source conferences, and knowing that Mattermost is so dedicated to the open source space, I thought he would be a great resource to come on and talk a little bit about how they&amp;rsquo;re changing some of how people operate DevOps and how people operate their systems and talk a little bit about his experience in the open source space.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB ServerFest and Contribution With Kaj Arnö, CEO at MariaDB Foundation - Percona Podcast 44</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/44-mariadb-serverfest-kaj-arno-ceo-mariadb-foundation-mysql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/44-mariadb-serverfest-kaj-arno-ceo-mariadb-foundation-mysql/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit
Hi, everybody. Welcome to The HOSS talk FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m the HOSS Matt Yonkovit. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Kaj Arnö from the MariaDB Foundation. Hi Kaj, how are you this morning?
Kaj Arnö
Hi Matt! I&amp;rsquo;m fine. How are you?
Matt Yonkovit
Good! Good. So Kaj is the CEO of the MariaDB Foundation. You&amp;rsquo;ve been CEO there for several years now. You just had a new addition to the family?</description></item><item><title>How and Why Quora Moved From HBase to RocksDB via MyRocks - Percona Podcast 43</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/43-how-and-why-quora-moved-from-hbase-to-rocksdb-myrocks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/43-how-and-why-quora-moved-from-hbase-to-rocksdb-myrocks/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here today to talk about MyRocks. And you know, RocksDB with Vamsi from Quora. How are you today, Vamsi?.
Nagavamsi Ponnekanti: Good. Thanks for inviting me.
Matt Yonkovit: Yes, so Vamsi I saw this blog post you did and was very intrigued by it. I know Vadim sent it over to me and said, like, wow, you should really have Vamsi on the podcast to talk about his journey to using RocksDB, because it was so interesting.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Experience, Tips and Tricks for Managing a Team, and Monitoring With PMM - Percona Podcast 42</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/42-engineering-experience-tips-and-tricks-manage-team-and-pmm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/42-engineering-experience-tips-and-tricks-manage-team-and-pmm/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yokovit: Hello, everyone, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS, I am here with Steve Hoffman, VP of Engineering here at Percona. I&amp;rsquo;m also here with potentially the long guys who if you hear lawnmowers outside, it&amp;rsquo;s because they have decided to curse me once again with podcast visitors outside. But hopefully, they will disappear shortly. So how are you, Steve?
Steve Hoffman:
I&amp;rsquo;m doing spectacular, Matt, how are you today?</description></item><item><title>Percona’s 15th Anniversary, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL With Peter Zaitsev and Vadim Tkachenko - Percona Podcast 41</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/41-percona-15th-anniversary-mysql-mongodb-postgresql-peter-zaitsev-and-vadim-tkachenko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/41-percona-15th-anniversary-mysql-mongodb-postgresql-peter-zaitsev-and-vadim-tkachenko/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hey everybody, welcome to an exciting, this is a very exciting episode of the HOSS talks FOSS, because I have with us the founders of Percona, Peter and Vadim, who are here to celebrate our 40th episode of the HOSS talks FOSS. That&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re all here for right? Now, actually, we&amp;rsquo;re here to talk about Percona’s 15 years, 15 years in the open source space. 15 years, we&amp;rsquo;ve been around 15 years, Peter and Vadim have been looking at each other cross eyed and funny for 15 years we&amp;rsquo;ve been here, and we thought it would be good to get together and talk about some of the good old days, some of the reasons why Percona exists, why we were started, and tell you some of the things you might not be aware of.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Community and Why PostgreSQL Continues to Grow in Popularity - Percona Podcast 40</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/40-postgresql-community-adoption-popularity-growth/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/40-postgresql-community-adoption-popularity-growth/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everyone, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. Today I&amp;rsquo;m here with Umair Shahid, from Percona. In the Postgres community, longtime member of the Postgres community. You&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Postgres related companies, since 2003. Maybe tell us a little bit about your background here
Umair Shahid: Well, that’s interesting. By the way, thank you for having me here. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that the start of my Postgres career was, well, not by choice, I was kind of pushed into it.</description></item><item><title>PingCAP, HTAP, NewSQL, and TiDB - Percona Podcast 39</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/39-pingcap-htap-newsql-and-tidb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/39-pingcap-htap-newsql-and-tidb/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another Hoss Talks fosse. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Liquan Pei from PingCAP. How are you today?
Liquan Pei: I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good. And then pretty excited to take this conversation with you.
Matt Yonkovit: Great. Great. And so tell us a little bit about PingCAP and what you do there. For those who might not know about PingCAP or TiDB.
Liquan Pei: Yes, PingCAP is a company founded in 2015.</description></item><item><title>Free Open Source Software Community in Action and Community Efforts Metrics - Percona Podcast 38</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/38-free-open-source-software-community-in-action-and-metrics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/38-free-open-source-software-community-in-action-and-metrics/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS and today I am here with Jono Bacon. Now, as you know, I love open source, and Jono has been a long time person who&amp;rsquo;s been in charge of many different communities: canonical GitHub, XPrize, Open Advantage, all kinds of different things. He&amp;rsquo;s been the author of a couple of books, People Powered and the Art of Community. And I thought, talking about open source, we have to talk about where it all starts, which is with the community.</description></item><item><title>Developer Advocate Background and AWS Open Source Fork OpenSearch - Percona Podcast 37</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/37-developer-advocate-background-and-aws-open-source-fork-opensearch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/37-developer-advocate-background-and-aws-open-source-fork-opensearch/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another episode of The HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS here at Percona. And I&amp;rsquo;m here with Kyle Davis. Kyle, how are you doing today?
Kyle Davis: I am great. Thanks for asking.
Matt Yonkovit: Great. So if you don&amp;rsquo;t know, Kyle works for AWS and his project, his baby is the OpenSearch project, which is the fork of Elastic that just recently came out and recently went GA.</description></item><item><title>Uber Technologies, Inc and Uber’s Custom Built Database DocStore - Percona Podcast 36</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/36-uber-technologies-inc-and-uber-custom-built-database-docstore/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/36-uber-technologies-inc-and-uber-custom-built-database-docstore/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I am here with our famous two engineers from Uber. I&amp;rsquo;ve got Ovais Tariq and Himank Chaudhary. And hi, welcome to the HOSS Talks FOSS. I appreciate you guys stepping by. How are you guys doing today?
Ovais Tariq:
Doing good. Thank you, Matt, for having us here. It&amp;rsquo;s great to chat with you. Normally you would meet up in Percona Live in person, but you know, pandemic doesn&amp;rsquo;t didn&amp;rsquo;t really allow us to do that.</description></item><item><title>Percona Podcast Russian Edition Ep 1 - Andrey Borodin (Yandex)</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/ru_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/ru_1/</guid><description>Transcript Daniil Bazhenov: Hello! My name is Daniel, I&amp;rsquo;m from Percona. I welcome you on the Percona podcast, where we invite engineers, opinion leaders, tech leads and talk about databases, about open source. Andrey Borodin from Yandex is with us today. Hi Andrew! Tell us a little about yourself, what you are doing, what you are doing now, about yourself.
Andrey Borodin: I&amp;rsquo;m fixing Postgres for Yandex, sometimes something doesn&amp;rsquo;t work there or something can be done better.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Database Testing, Tooling, Debugging Code, Using Microservices - Percona Podcast 35</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/35-open-source-database-testing-tooling-debugging-code-using-microservices/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/35-open-source-database-testing-tooling-debugging-code-using-microservices/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Rob Richardson, one of our speakers at Percona.Live. Hi, Rob. How are you doing today?
Rob Richardson: I&amp;rsquo;m doing well. I&amp;rsquo;m great to be on the show. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to be able to talk about all the things. The conference was really fun. And so it&amp;rsquo;s cool to be able to revisit it now.
Matt Yonkovit: Yeah, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you have attended Percona Live in the past?</description></item><item><title>Current Trends in Database Technologies and Postgres 14 With Bruce Momjian - Percona Podcast 34</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/34-current-trends-in-database-technology-and-postgres-14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/34-current-trends-in-database-technology-and-postgres-14/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS, today I&amp;rsquo;m here with Bruce Momjian from EnterpriseDB and from the Postgres community. Now, Bruce, you have been around the database space for a long time, longer than I have. I&amp;rsquo;ve been around for about 25 years in the database space. And you have several years on me. So I read on your website. And recently in one of your blogs, you mentioned 32 years.</description></item><item><title>Variety of MySQL Topics, SE Linux, Database Security, Backups and Recovery - Percona Podcast 33</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/33-mysql-se-linux-database-security-backups-and-recovery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/33-mysql-se-linux-database-security-backups-and-recovery/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another episode of the HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Matthias Crauwels from Pythian, community member who has spoken at many Percona Lives and is a prolific blogger, and has established himself in the MySQL community helping a lot of different people, as he&amp;rsquo;s doing consulting work around MySQL for Pythian. Hello, Matthias, how are you doing?
Matthias Crauwels: Hey, Matt doing well. How are you?</description></item><item><title>Recap From Percona Live and Percona Postgres Operator - Percona Podcast 32</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/32-recap-from-percona-live-and-percona-postgres-operator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/32-recap-from-percona-live-and-percona-postgres-operator/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS here at Percona, Head of Open Source Strategy. I&amp;rsquo;m back with Sergey Pronin. Hey, Sergey, how are you doing today?
Sergey Pronin: Hello, Matt. Fantastic. Thank you.
Matt Yonkovit: You know, you will be happy to know that today in this podcast I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded another one earlier with a different Sergey. So this is a dual Sergey for me.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Database Management, Backup Tools, Migration From Oracle - Percona Podcast 31</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/31-postgresql-database-management-backup-tools-migration-from-oracle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/31-postgresql-database-management-backup-tools-migration-from-oracle/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m Matt Yonkovit, Percona’s HOSS here to talk FOSS with Sergei and Jobin, two of our key support engineers here at Percona, who have been working on all kinds of awesome things in the Postres space. And we wanted to catch up with them and talk to them a little bit about some of the work that they&amp;rsquo;ve been doing and some of the recent conversations they&amp;rsquo;ve had and presentations they&amp;rsquo;ve done.</description></item><item><title>Database Automation, Google Spanner, Ansible, and Kubernetes - Percona Podcast 30</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/30-database-automation-google-spanner-ansible-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/30-database-automation-google-spanner-ansible-kubernetes/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Derek Downey. Hi, Derek, how are you doing?
Derek Downey: Hi, Matt. Doing great. How are you?
Matt Yonkovit: Good. So Derek we&amp;rsquo;re wanting to talk a little bit about what you talked about at Percona Live. But before that there was some exciting news that I saw on the Twitter slash LinkedIn verse. You&amp;rsquo;ve just joined Google.</description></item><item><title>Database Infrastructure at Linkedin, and Challenging Situations - Percona Podcast 29</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/29-database-infrastructure-at-linkedin-and-challenging-situations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/29-database-infrastructure-at-linkedin-and-challenging-situations/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Karthik from LinkedIn. Karthik has presented at several Percona Live conferences about LinkedIn scalability challenges, some of the things that they&amp;rsquo;ve done with MySQL, some of the cool things that they&amp;rsquo;ve learned, and shared with us over the years. Hi, Karthik, how are you doing?
Karthik Appigatla: Yeah. Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m doing good. And you?
Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m great.</description></item><item><title>Serial Micropatcher of Open Source Projects and Patches for MariaDB - Percona Podcast 28</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/28-serial-micropatcher-open-source-projects-and-patches-for-mariadb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/28-serial-micropatcher-open-source-projects-and-patches-for-mariadb/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. Today I&amp;rsquo;m here with Daniel Black from the MariaDB Foundation, the Chief Innovation Officer for the MariaDB Foundation. How are you, Daniel?
Daniel Black: Good. Thanks, man. Working up, got my coffee. Welcome to Canberra winter.
Matt Yonkovit: Yeah, and it&amp;rsquo;s really early there. Right. So what time is it?
Daniel Black: Only 7:30am.
Matt Yonkovit: Okay, so the sun is just picking up?</description></item><item><title>Open Source Databases Performance, Dynamic Tracing, BPftrace - Percona Podcast 27</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/27-open-source-databases-performance-dynamic-tracing-bpftrace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/27-open-source-databases-performance-dynamic-tracing-bpftrace/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS here. We&amp;rsquo;re here with Valerii Kravchuk from MariaDB Corporation. Valerii, how are you today?
Valerii Kravchuk: Nice. Thank you, Matt. Nice to meet you again, online. Not during the conference, but during some personal kind of talk. I&amp;rsquo;m actually proud to be a person of interest for these podcasts.
Matt Yonkovit: Well, Valerii, you&amp;rsquo;ve been in the community for as long as I have.</description></item><item><title>ZettaDB and Kunlun Database Takes the Best of PostgreSQL and MySQL - Percona Podcast 26</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/26-zettadb-kunlun-database-the-best-of-postgresql-and-mysql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/26-zettadb-kunlun-database-the-best-of-postgresql-and-mysql/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody! Matt Yonkovit, Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona, or the HOSS for short. I&amp;rsquo;m here with another podcast “The HOSS Talks FOSS” and today I&amp;rsquo;m here with David Zhao from ZettaDB. Hello, David.
David Zhao: Hi, Matt. Hi, everyone. Glad to meet you.
Matt Yonkovit: I am very glad to have you here. Now, David, can you tell us a little bit about your background?</description></item><item><title>ProvenDB BlockChain Tech to Databases, All Things MongoDB - Percona Podcast 25</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/25-provendb-blockchain-tech-to-databases-all-things-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/25-provendb-blockchain-tech-to-databases-all-things-mongodb/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another “HOSS Talks FOSS”. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Guy Harrison from ProvenDB, who just gave a great talk, 2 great talks, actually, at Percona.Live on MongoDB performance tuning as well as on the changing face of databases and the evolution of databases. Guy has written several books about databases over the years. And he&amp;rsquo;s got two books currently authored and out there. And he&amp;rsquo;s working on a third.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Performance Extensions, Memory Settings, and Hardware - Percona Podcast 24</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/24-postgresql-performance-extensions-memory-settings-and-hardware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/24-postgresql-performance-extensions-memory-settings-and-hardware/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody! Matt Yonkovit, the “HOSS Talks FOSS” is back with another exciting episode today we&amp;rsquo;re here with Ibrar. And I have my Postgres hat on just to talk about Postgres. Ibrar, how are you doing today?
Ibrar Ahmed: Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m fine. What about you?
Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m good as well. I do have an elephant on my head. So it is a little weird. And it is a heavy elephant too, which is kind of&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Highlights From Percona Live Talk 2021: Database Recovery and backups - Percona Podcast 23</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/23-highlights-from-percona-live-talk-2021-database-recovery-backups/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/23-highlights-from-percona-live-talk-2021-database-recovery-backups/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everyone. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Pep Pla, one of our professional service engineers here at Percona. Hi, Pep, how you doing today?
Pep Pla: Hi, fine, fine, really great. And I&amp;rsquo;m in Barcelona, today&amp;rsquo;s a sunny day. So the weather is fine. It&amp;rsquo;s Friday&amp;hellip; So we have to talk about backups. What else?
Matt Yonkovit:
Yes, yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s a nice Friday day here as well.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Open Source, Linux Kernel Patches, and Performance Tuning - Percona Podcast 22</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/22-mysql-open-source-linux-kernel-patches-performance-tuning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/22-mysql-open-source-linux-kernel-patches-performance-tuning/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: All right, everybody, welcome to this special episode. And we&amp;rsquo;re going to change this up. Now typically I have a podcast called the HOSS Talks FOSS. And we&amp;rsquo;re still gonna have that. But with with Marcos here, it requires a little bit more panache, a little bit more jazzing up, because as many of you know who work at Percona, but some of you might not know, Marcos is the Percona official grillmaster and the official BBQ master of all things Percona.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Databases, Debugging, GDB &amp; RR - Record and Replay - Percona Podcast 21</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/21-open-source-database-debugging-gdb-rr-record-and-replay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/21-open-source-database-debugging-gdb-rr-record-and-replay/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hey everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks Foss. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Marcelo Altmann, our Percona’s own super engineer. Marcelo, you&amp;rsquo;ve been at Percona for a few years now, I remember we met in person a couple times at a conference here in there. And also, you came to our headquarters, and, Marcelo, you&amp;rsquo;re down in Brazil. And so what does the American do to the guy who comes from Brazil?</description></item><item><title>Challenges and Issues in Open Source, and the Benefits of MyRocks - Percona Podcast 20</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/20-challenges-and-issues-in-open-source-and-the-benefits-of-myrocks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/20-challenges-and-issues-in-open-source-and-the-benefits-of-myrocks/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m here today with Mike Benshoof, my good friend from many, many years ago and our current technical account manager here at Percona. Mike, how are you doing today?
Mike Benshoof: I am doing great. How are you doing, sir?
Matt Yonkovit: Great. Now, Mike, we&amp;rsquo;ve known each other for what, seven years now? It&amp;rsquo;s been. You&amp;rsquo;ve been here seven, eight years, right?
Mike Benshoof: I actually just had the ninth anniversary like two weeks ago.</description></item><item><title>Overview of MySQL Project, Orchestrator, Ghost, Vitess and PlanetScale - Percona Podcast 19</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/19-overview-of-mysql-project-orchestrator-ghost-vitess-and-planetscale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/19-overview-of-mysql-project-orchestrator-ghost-vitess-and-planetscale/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m here today with a longtime community contributor and a good friend of everyone in the MySQL space. Shlomi, how have things been for you?
Shlomi Noach: Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m fine, everything&amp;rsquo;s fine. Thank you. We&amp;rsquo;re in good health. And that&amp;rsquo;s all we can ask for these days.
Matt Yonkovit: So, yeah, I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s been, it&amp;rsquo;s been tough all over the world, but it looks like you know, with everything going on, hopefully many of us will get vaccinated, hopefully, we&amp;rsquo;ll get back to being in person.</description></item><item><title>KVM Hypervisor Experience, Developing a New OS, and All Things ScyllaDB - Percona Podcast 18</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/18-kvm-hypervisor-experience-developing-a-new-os-and-all-things-scylladb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/18-kvm-hypervisor-experience-developing-a-new-os-and-all-things-scylladb/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: So I&amp;rsquo;m here with Dor Laor, the CEO of ScyllaDB. And we&amp;rsquo;re here to talk about all the fun stuff that they&amp;rsquo;re doing over there. And also talk a little bit about his journey and why he started the company. So, Dor, how are you today?
Dor Laor: I&amp;rsquo;m great. Thanks for having me here. And looking forward for our chat.
Matt Yonkovit: Okay, great. And so I know that your background is very development centric.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Database From Apache Cassandra, HBase to Yugabyte - Percona Podcast 17</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/17-open-source-database-from-apache-cassandra-hbase-to-yugabyte/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/17-open-source-database-from-apache-cassandra-hbase-to-yugabyte/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody, I&amp;rsquo;m here with Karthik Ranganathan, from Yugabite, thank you, Karthik, for being here. You&amp;rsquo;re the founder CTO of Yugabite. So that&amp;rsquo;s an exciting role for you, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?
Karthik Ranganathan: Yes, yes, it is, Matt. Thank you for having me. Yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s been fun at least. Yeah, by way of quick background. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in FB most of the time and yeah, having the blast of my life.</description></item><item><title>OpenUK and the Use of Open Source Software, Hardware, and Databases - Percona Podcast 16</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/16-open-uk-and-the-use-of-open-source-software-hardware-and-database/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/16-open-uk-and-the-use-of-open-source-software-hardware-and-database/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m here with Amanda Brock, the CEO of OpenUK. How&amp;rsquo;re you doing today, Amanda?
Amanda Brock: I&amp;rsquo;m doing great. Thank you. And thanks very much for having me along.
Matt Yonkovit: Ah, we&amp;rsquo;re glad to have you. So welcome to the HOSS Talks FOSS podcast, we like to highlight all of the awesome things happening in open source. And we know that you have a deep background in the open-source space.</description></item><item><title>Data Geekery GmbH and JooQ to Speed Up Open Source Databases - Percona Podcast 15</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/15-data-geekery-gmbh-and-jooq-to-speed-up-open-source-database/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/15-data-geekery-gmbh-and-jooq-to-speed-up-open-source-database/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Everybody, Matt, you&amp;rsquo;re going to head over to our strategy here at Percona with another episode of The HOSS (that&amp;rsquo;s me) Talks FOSS, yes, we&amp;rsquo;re here to give you the best in the open-source space. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ve got an extra special episode. So we love it that you&amp;rsquo;ve tuned in to watch. So I&amp;rsquo;m here with Lucas Eder, the founder and CEO of JooQ. Hi, Lucas, how are you doing today?</description></item><item><title>Get Involved in Databases on Kubernetes (DoK) Community - Percona Podcast 14</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/14-get-involeved-in-databases-on-kubernetes-dok-community/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/14-get-involeved-in-databases-on-kubernetes-dok-community/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, I&amp;rsquo;m here with Bart Farrell, a quote-unquote, community builder for the Data and Kubernetes community. Bart, thanks for joining us today. I really appreciate having you. Now, a lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t know what Docker data on Kubernetes is. Maybe you could just start with that and explain what is this organization?
Bart Farrell: Okay, well, first of all, thanks a lot for me, HOSS. Great to be here.</description></item><item><title>Apache Cassandra, DataStax, Role of SRE/DBRE and DBA's - Percona Podcast 13</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/13-apache-cassandra-datastax-role-of-sre-dbre-and-dba/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/13-apache-cassandra-datastax-role-of-sre-dbre-and-dba/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Database on Kubernetes Operator, PITR Point in Time Recovery - Percona Podcast 12</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/12-database-on-kubernetes-operator-pitr-point-in-time-recovery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/12-database-on-kubernetes-operator-pitr-point-in-time-recovery/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Solution Engineering From Teradata and Oracle to Open Source - Percona Podcast 11</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/11-solution-engineering-from-teradata-and-oracle-to-open-source/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/11-solution-engineering-from-teradata-and-oracle-to-open-source/</guid><description/></item><item><title>All Things Vitess, Planetscale, MySQL, and Sailing Passion - Percona Podcast 10</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/10-all-things-vitess-planetscale-mysql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/10-all-things-vitess-planetscale-mysql/</guid><description/></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Performance on the ARM Processor and All Things Open - Percona Podcast 09</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/9-postgresql-performance-on-arm-processor-and-all-things-open/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/9-postgresql-performance-on-arm-processor-and-all-things-open/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Evolving Open Source Space MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB, and Datastax - Percona Podcast 08</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/8-evolving-open-source-space-mysql-mariadb-mongodb-datastax/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/8-evolving-open-source-space-mysql-mariadb-mongodb-datastax/</guid><description/></item><item><title>All Things Open Source Including Suse, MySQL, and Ceph - Percona Podcast 07</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/7-all-things-open-source-suse-mysql-ceph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/7-all-things-open-source-suse-mysql-ceph/</guid><description/></item><item><title>From PHP and MySQL to Application, Databases, Infrastructures - Percona Podcast 06</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/6-from-php-and-mysql-to-application-databases-infrastructures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/6-from-php-and-mysql-to-application-databases-infrastructures/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB DBA's to DBRE's - Percona Podcast 05</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/5-oracle-mysql-postgresql-and-mongodb-dba-to-dbre/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/5-oracle-mysql-postgresql-and-mongodb-dba-to-dbre/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hi everybody. Matt Yonkovit, The HOSS, Head of Open Source Strategy here at Percona, I welcome you to another Percona Tech Talk, where we&amp;rsquo;re gonna bring you the best in the open-source space and give you the most interesting fun speakers ever. We hope you enjoy the show. So David, how have you been? What have you been up to? I know you&amp;rsquo;ve been busy since the last time I saw you, which was actually in person in Percona Live Amsterdam, like, a year in a few months ago.</description></item><item><title>Database Monitoring Management, Alerting, Contributing MySQL, TiDB, and Waffles - Percona Podcast 04</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/4-database-monitoring-management-alerting-contributing-mysql-tidb-and-waffles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/4-database-monitoring-management-alerting-contributing-mysql-tidb-and-waffles/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Welcome to another episode of The HOSS Talks FOSS. We&amp;rsquo;re here to bring you some of the awesome news in open source. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started. We hope you enjoy the show. Hey, Morgan, glad to see you here. I saw you move back to TiDB. How are things going there? What are you working on? what&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s, what&amp;rsquo;s the scoop?
Morgan Tocker:
What&amp;rsquo;s the scoop? I&amp;rsquo;m working as a developer, which actually, I haven&amp;rsquo;t done, I think for 15 years or so.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Operators and the Latest Trends in the Database Space - Percona Podcast 03</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/3-kubernetes-operators-latest-trends-in%20the-database-space/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/3-kubernetes-operators-latest-trends-in%20the-database-space/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hi everybody. Matt Yonkovit, The HOSS, Head of Open Source Strategy here at Percona, I welcome you to another Percona Tech Talk, where we&amp;rsquo;re gonna bring you the best in the open source space and give you the most interesting and fun speakers ever. We hope you enjoy the show. Hi, Sergey, thanks for joining me for a quick chat here. Sergey, you&amp;rsquo;ve been with Percona for a few months now.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Backups and Database Recovery Best Practices - Percona Podcast 02</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/2-mysql-backups-database-recovery-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/2-mysql-backups-database-recovery-best-practices/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hi everybody. Matt Yonkovit, The HOSS, Head of Percona Strategy at Percona, I welcome you to another Percona Tech Talk, where we&amp;rsquo;re gonna bring you the best in the open source space, and give you the most interesting fun speakers ever. We hope you enjoy the show. Walter, thank you for sitting down and talking with me today. I really appreciate it. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking a little bit about your recent blog MySQL, backup, and recovery best practices.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Database vs. Server Side Public License SSPL With Peter Zaitsev - Percona Podcast 01</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/1-open-source-database-vs-server-side-public-license-sspl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/1-open-source-database-vs-server-side-public-license-sspl/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
I guess the big news of the week for us is that Elastic has decided to kick open to the curb despite saying they&amp;rsquo;ve doubled down on open, which is kind of silly because I have always thought doubling down meant you were going to do more of it, not less of it. But as someone pointed out on Twitter, maybe they&amp;rsquo;re looking at doubling down as two negatives make a positive.</description></item></channel></rss>