<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona’s HOSS Talks FOSS: The Open Source Database Podcast on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/</link><description>Recent content in Percona’s HOSS Talks FOSS: The Open Source Database Podcast on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/podcasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 41 - Peter Zaitsev and Vadim Tkachenko</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/41/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/41/</guid><description>Transcript</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep Ep 40 - Umair Shahid</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/40/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/40/</guid><description>Transcript</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 39 - Liquan Pei, Sr Software Engineer, Database Kernel at PingCAP</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/39/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/39/</guid><description>Transcript</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 38 - Jono Bacon, Community &amp; Collaboration Consultant and Author</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/38/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/38/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS and today I am here with Jono Bacon. Now, as you know, I love open source, and Jono has been a long time person who&amp;rsquo;s been in charge of many different communities: canonical GitHub, XPrize, Open Advantage, all kinds of different things. He&amp;rsquo;s been the author of a couple of books, People Powered and the Art of Community. And I thought, talking about open source, we have to talk about where it all starts, which is with the community.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 37 - Kyle Davis, Senior Developer Advocate AWS</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/37/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another episode of The HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS here at Percona. And I&amp;rsquo;m here with Kyle Davis. Kyle, how are you doing today?
Kyle Davis: I am great. Thanks for asking.
Matt Yonkovit: Great. So if you don&amp;rsquo;t know, Kyle works for AWS and his project, his baby is the OpenSearch project, which is the fork of Elastic that just recently came out and recently went GA.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 36 - Ovais Tariq &amp; Himank Chaudhary</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/36/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/36/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I am here with our famous two engineers from Uber. I&amp;rsquo;ve got Ovais Tariq and Himank Chaudhary. And hi, welcome to the HOSS Talks FOSS. I appreciate you guys stepping by. How are you guys doing today?
Ovais Tariq:
Doing good. Thank you, Matt, for having us here. It&amp;rsquo;s great to chat with you. Normally you would meet up in Percona Live in person, but you know, pandemic doesn&amp;rsquo;t didn&amp;rsquo;t really allow us to do that.</description></item><item><title>Percona Podcast Russian Edition Ep 1 - Andrey Borodin (Yandex)</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/ru_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/ru_1/</guid><description>Transcript Daniil Bazhenov: Hello! My name is Daniel, I&amp;rsquo;m from Percona. I welcome you on the Percona podcast, where we invite engineers, opinion leaders, tech leads and talk about databases, about open source. Andrey Borodin from Yandex is with us today. Hi Andrew! Tell us a little about yourself, what you are doing, what you are doing now, about yourself.
Andrey Borodin: I&amp;rsquo;m fixing Postgres for Yandex, sometimes something doesn&amp;rsquo;t work there or something can be done better.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 35 - Rob Richardson</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/35/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/35/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Rob Richardson, one of our speakers at Percona.Live. Hi, Rob. How are you doing today?
Rob Richardson: I&amp;rsquo;m doing well. I&amp;rsquo;m great to be on the show. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to be able to talk about all the things. The conference was really fun. And so it&amp;rsquo;s cool to be able to revisit it now.
Matt Yonkovit: Yeah, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you have attended Percona Live in the past?</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 34 - Bruce Momjian</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/34/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/34/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS, today I&amp;rsquo;m here with Bruce Momjian from EnterpriseDB and from the Postgres community. Now, Bruce, you have been around the database space for a long time, longer than I have. I&amp;rsquo;ve been around for about 25 years in the database space. And you have several years on me. So I read on your website. And recently in one of your blogs, you mentioned 32 years.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 33 - Matthias Crauwels</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/33/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/33/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another episode of the HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Matthias Crauwels from Pythian, community member who has spoken at many Percona Lives and is a prolific blogger, and has established himself in the MySQL community helping a lot of different people, as he&amp;rsquo;s doing consulting work around MySQL for Pythian. Hello, Matthias, how are you doing?
Matthias Crauwels: Hey, Matt doing well. How are you?</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss Ep 32 - Sergey Pronin</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/32/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/32/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS here at Percona, Head of Open Source Strategy. I&amp;rsquo;m back with Sergey Pronin. Hey, Sergey, how are you doing today?
Sergey Pronin: Hello, Matt. Fantastic. Thank you.
Matt Yonkovit: You know, you will be happy to know that today in this podcast I&amp;rsquo;ve recorded another one earlier with a different Sergey. So this is a dual Sergey for me.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 31 - Sergey Kuzmichev &amp; Jobin Augustine</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/31/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/31/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m Matt Yonkovit, Percona’s HOSS here to talk FOSS with Sergei and Jobin, two of our key support engineers here at Percona, who have been working on all kinds of awesome things in the Postres space. And we wanted to catch up with them and talk to them a little bit about some of the work that they&amp;rsquo;ve been doing and some of the recent conversations they&amp;rsquo;ve had and presentations they&amp;rsquo;ve done.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 30 with Derek Downey, Developer Relations Engineer - Google</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/30/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/30/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Derek Downey. Hi, Derek, how are you doing?
Derek Downey: Hi, Matt. Doing great. How are you?
Matt Yonkovit: Good. So Derek we&amp;rsquo;re wanting to talk a little bit about what you talked about at Percona Live. But before that there was some exciting news that I saw on the Twitter slash LinkedIn verse. You&amp;rsquo;ve just joined Google.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 29 - Karthik Appigatla, Staff Engineer, Linkedin</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/29/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/29/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Karthik from LinkedIn. Karthik has presented at several Percona Live conferences about LinkedIn scalability challenges, some of the things that they&amp;rsquo;ve done with MySQL, some of the cool things that they&amp;rsquo;ve learned, and shared with us over the years. Hi, Karthik, how are you doing?
Karthik Appigatla: Yeah. Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m doing good. And you?
Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m great.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 28 with Daniel Black, Chief Innovation Officer at the MariaDB Foundation</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/28/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. Today I&amp;rsquo;m here with Daniel Black from the MariaDB Foundation, the Chief Innovation Officer for the MariaDB Foundation. How are you, Daniel?
Daniel Black: Good. Thanks, man. Working up, got my coffee. Welcome to Canberra winter.
Matt Yonkovit: Yeah, and it&amp;rsquo;s really early there. Right. So what time is it?
Daniel Black: Only 7:30am.
Matt Yonkovit: Okay, so the sun is just picking up?</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 27 - Valerii Kravchuk, Principal Support Engineer, MariaDB</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/27/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS here. We&amp;rsquo;re here with Valerii Kravchuk from MariaDB Corporation. Valerii, how are you today?
Valerii Kravchuk: Nice. Thank you, Matt. Nice to meet you again, online. Not during the conference, but during some personal kind of talk. I&amp;rsquo;m actually proud to be a person of interest for these podcasts.
Matt Yonkovit: Well, Valerii, you&amp;rsquo;ve been in the community for as long as I have.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep26 - David Zhao, Database Systems Expert, ZettaDB</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/26/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody! Matt Yonkovit, Head of Open Source Strategy at Percona, or the HOSS for short. I&amp;rsquo;m here with another podcast “The HOSS Talks FOSS” and today I&amp;rsquo;m here with David Zhao from ZettaDB. Hello, David.
David Zhao: Hi, Matt. Hi, everyone. Glad to meet you.
Matt Yonkovit: I am very glad to have you here. Now, David, can you tell us a little bit about your background?</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep25 - Guy Harrison, CTO Southbank Software</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/25/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody. Welcome to another “HOSS Talks FOSS”. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Guy Harrison from ProvenDB, who just gave a great talk, 2 great talks, actually, at Percona.Live on MongoDB performance tuning as well as on the changing face of databases and the evolution of databases. Guy has written several books about databases over the years. And he&amp;rsquo;s got two books currently authored and out there. And he&amp;rsquo;s working on a third.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss – Ep 24 with Ibrar Ahmed, Senior Software Engineer , Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/24/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody! Matt Yonkovit, the “HOSS Talks FOSS” is back with another exciting episode today we&amp;rsquo;re here with Ibrar. And I have my Postgres hat on just to talk about Postgres. Ibrar, how are you doing today?
Ibrar Ahmed: Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m fine. What about you?
Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m good as well. I do have an elephant on my head. So it is a little weird. And it is a heavy elephant too, which is kind of&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep23 with Pep Pla, Consultant, Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/23/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everyone. Welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Pep Pla, one of our professional service engineers here at Percona. Hi, Pep, how you doing today?
Pep Pla: Hi, fine, fine, really great. And I&amp;rsquo;m in Barcelona, today&amp;rsquo;s a sunny day. So the weather is fine. It&amp;rsquo;s Friday&amp;hellip; So we have to talk about backups. What else?
Matt Yonkovit:
Yes, yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s a nice Friday day here as well.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 22 with Marcos Albe, Principal Support Engineer at Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/22/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: All right, everybody, welcome to this special episode. And we&amp;rsquo;re going to change this up. Now typically I have a podcast called the HOSS Talks FOSS. And we&amp;rsquo;re still gonna have that. But with with Marcos here, it requires a little bit more panache, a little bit more jazzing up, because as many of you know who work at Percona, but some of you might not know, Marcos is the Percona official grillmaster and the official BBQ master of all things Percona.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 21 with Marcelo Altmann, Software Engineer Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/21/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hey everybody. Welcome to another HOSS Talks Foss. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Marcelo Altmann, our Percona’s own super engineer. Marcelo, you&amp;rsquo;ve been at Percona for a few years now, I remember we met in person a couple times at a conference here in there. And also, you came to our headquarters, and, Marcelo, you&amp;rsquo;re down in Brazil. And so what does the American do to the guy who comes from Brazil?</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 20 with Mike Benshoof, Percona TAM</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/20/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m here today with Mike Benshoof, my good friend from many, many years ago and our current technical account manager here at Percona. Mike, how are you doing today?
Mike Benshoof: I am doing great. How are you doing, sir?
Matt Yonkovit: Great. Now, Mike, we&amp;rsquo;ve known each other for what, seven years now? It&amp;rsquo;s been. You&amp;rsquo;ve been here seven, eight years, right?
Mike Benshoof: I actually just had the ninth anniversary like two weeks ago.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 19 with Shlomi Noach, Software Engineer PlanetScale</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/19/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m here today with a longtime community contributor and a good friend of everyone in the MySQL space. Shlomi, how have things been for you?
Shlomi Noach: Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m fine, everything&amp;rsquo;s fine. Thank you. We&amp;rsquo;re in good health. And that&amp;rsquo;s all we can ask for these days.
Matt Yonkovit: So, yeah, I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s been, it&amp;rsquo;s been tough all over the world, but it looks like you know, with everything going on, hopefully many of us will get vaccinated, hopefully, we&amp;rsquo;ll get back to being in person.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 18 with Dor Laor CEO of ScyllaDB</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/18/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/18/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: So I&amp;rsquo;m here with Dor Laor, the CEO of ScyllaDB. And we&amp;rsquo;re here to talk about all the fun stuff that they&amp;rsquo;re doing over there. And also talk a little bit about his journey and why he started the company. So, Dor, how are you today?
Dor Laor: I&amp;rsquo;m great. Thanks for having me here. And looking forward for our chat.
Matt Yonkovit: Okay, great. And so I know that your background is very development centric.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 17 with Karthik Ranganathan CTO at Yugabyte</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/17/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/17/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 16 with Amanda Brock CEO of OpenUK</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/16/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/16/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 15 with Lukas Eder CEO and Founder of Data Geekery GmbH</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/15/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP14 Databases on Kubernetes: Bart Farrell the Head of the DoK community</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP13 Datastax’s VP of Dev Rel Patrick McFadin Sits Down and Talks Open Source, K8’s, The DBA to SRE Journey, and of Course Cassandra</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/13/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP12 Sergey Pronin returns to talk about Kubernets, Operators, and DBaaS</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/12/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP11 Talking OSS, Linux, Oracle, Big Business and Foss with Brian Walters</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/11/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP10 Alkin Tezuysal talks Vitess, MySQL, Open Source, and Sailing</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/10/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP09 Talking ARM CPU Performance ON EC2 with Jobin Augustine</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/9/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP08 Talking Open Source, Contributions, and Databases with Henrik Ingo DataStax’s VP of Engineering in EMEA</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/8/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP07 Talking Open Source and Development with Lenz Grimmer</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/7/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP06 featuring Gabi Ferrara (Dev Advocate at Google) and talk about Open Source, Databases, PHP, and more</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/6/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP05 featuring David Murphy talking Devops, DBRE, SRE, MongoDB, and Modernizing IT</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/5/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP04 featuring Morgan Tocker talking MySQL, TiDB, Open Source Contributions, and Waffles!</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/4/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP03 talking Databases on Kubernetes, K8 on the edge, Operators and more!</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP02 talking MySQL Backup Best Practices with Walter Garcia</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP01 talking with Percona CEO Peter Zaitsev about SSPL, open source, Elastic, and the cloud.</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/1/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>