<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona’s HOSS Talks FOSS: The Open Source Database Podcast on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/</link><description>Recent content in Percona’s HOSS Talks FOSS: The Open Source Database Podcast on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/podcasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 29 - Karthik Appigatla, Staff Engineer, Linkedin</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/29/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/29/</guid><description>Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hi, everybody, welcome to another HOSS Talks FOSS. I&amp;rsquo;m here with Karthik from LinkedIn. Karthik has presented at several Percona Live conferences about LinkedIn scalability challenges, some of the things that they&amp;rsquo;ve done with MySQL, some of the cool things that they&amp;rsquo;ve learned, and shared with us over the years. Hi, Karthik, how are you doing?
Karthik Appigatla: Yeah. Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m doing good. And you?
Matt Yonkovit: I&amp;rsquo;m great.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 28 with Daniel Black, Chief Innovation Officer at the MariaDB Foundation</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/28/</guid><description>Listen in as the HOSS talks with Daniel Black, Chief Innovation Officer at the MariaDB Foundation. Daniel is a self-professed serial micropatcher of open source projects. He is passionate about all things performance, understanding how things work, and has worked tirelessly on porting coding for POWER Systems. He was formerly a DBA consultant for Open Query where he started writing far too many patches for MariaDB, a tradition which he continues today, and ultimately led him to become the Chief Innovation Officer at the MariaDB foundation.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep 27 - Valerii Kravchuk, Principal Support Engineer, MariaDB</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/27/</guid><description>Join the HOSS Matt Yonkovit and MySQL &amp;amp; MariaDB expert Valerii Kravchuk on the latest episode of the HOSS talks FOSS. Valerii is passionate about all things Performance, Open Source, and Databases. Listen to the Database Performance and Bug guru talk about performance tools and methods like dynamic tracing, flame graphs, BPftrace, and more! Valerii is a Principal Support Engineer at MariaDB Corp with over 20 years of experience in the database field.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep26 - David Zhao, Database Systems Expert, ZettaDB</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/26/</guid><description>David Zhao (ZettaDB) has been working on database kernels for years, developing code and enhancements for Berkeley DB, MySQL, and TDSQL. David is back with a new Hybrid database called Kunlun which aims to take the best of what&amp;rsquo;s in the PostgreSQL and MySQL space both and output a better database. David sits down with Matt Yonkovit (The HOSS) to talk about the Kunlun project, distribution, implementation, scalability, and more. If you are interested in learning more David also delivered a talk at Percona Live 2021 entitled “Performance Comparison of MySQL and PostgreSQL based on Kernel Level Analysis” which is also available now.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS Ep25 - Guy Harrison, CTO Southbank Software</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/25/</guid><description>Guy Harrison, CTO @ ProvenDB (AKA: Southbank Software) is the special guest of Matt Yonkovit in The latest HOSS Talks FOSS Ep25. Guy has authored several books on database technology including MongoDB Performance Tuning, Next Generation Databases, and the Oracle Database Problem Solving and Troubleshooting Handbook. He is currently the CTO of ProvenDB where he is bringing BlockChain tech to databases. In this episode we talk about all things MongoDB, Databases, and the future landscape of technology</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss – Ep 24 with Ibrar Ahmed, Senior Software Engineer , Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/24/</guid><description>The Percona HOSS Matt Yonkovit sits down with Ibrar Ahmed, Senior Software Engineer, at Percona to talk about PostgreSQL Performance! Matt and Ibrar talk about the impact of 3rd party extensions, memory settings, and hardware. Get a bit more detail behind Ibrar’s talk he delivered at Percona Live 2021. The full recording of his Percona Live session entitled: “High-Performance PostgreSQL” is now available.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep23 with Pep Pla, Consultant, Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/23/</guid><description>The Percona HOSS Matt Yonkovit invited Pep Pla, Consultant at Percona to talk about why database recovery trumps database backups every time as well as some highlights from his 2021 Percona Live talk on &amp;ldquo;How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love Backups&amp;rdquo;. Listen to this episode 23 of the HOSS talks FOSS and learn why you should stop worrying so much about backups, and start worrying about recovery</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 22 with Marcos Albe, Principal Support Engineer at Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/22/</guid><description>The HOSS sits down with Marcos Albe Principal Support Engineer at Percona and official BBQ master of Percona. In what will become a recurring feature we “Grill Open Source” talking about BBQ, Open Source, MySQL, and real life fun! Join Marcos and Matt for this fun walk through food, open source, Linux kernel patches, finding difficult bugs in code, performance tuning, and of course all things MySQL</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 21 with Marcelo Altmann, Software Engineer Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/21/</guid><description>The HOSS sit down with the Software Engineer at Percona Marcelo Altmann to talk about all things open source, database, and debugging big projects. In this episode we cover his career, finding and debugging hard to find bugs, GDB &amp;amp; RR - Record and Replay - and talk about ideas for a potential special in-person barbecue &amp;amp; open source event</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 20 with Mike Benshoof, Percona TAM</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/20/</guid><description>The HOSS sits down with Technical Account Manager and long time MySQL DBA Mike Benshoof to talk about the key challenges and issues enterprises are facing today, the benefits of MyRocks, and of course Philadelphia Cheesesteaks!</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 19 with Shlomi Noach, Software Engineer PlanetScale</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/19/</guid><description>Listen in as the HOSS talks with long time MySQL community contributor Shlomi Noach. Shlomi has been developing and enhancing some of the MySQL communities most popular tools for years. You may know his mysql work from projects like Orchestrator, Ghost, and Vitess. He shares his experiences and his motivations behind some of these projects and gives us a preview into what he is up to next!</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 18 with Dor Laor CEO of ScyllaDB</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/18/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/18/</guid><description>The HOSS talks with Dor about his career covering working on the KVM hypervisor, developing a new OS, and also building an Open Source Database. We then go Deep diving into all things ScyllaDB including design decisions, the benefits, and what users are looking for.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 17 with Karthik Ranganathan CTO at Yugabyte</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/17/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/17/</guid><description>Karthik Ranganathan CTO at Yugabyte knows databases inside and out having been on the team that first built Apache Cassandra, helped optimize and scale HBase, and most recently built Yugabyte. What insights does he have from participating in these efforts? He sat down with Percona’s HOSS Matt Yonkovit to talk through what he learned, what he regretted, and how Yugabyte takes those lessons and implements them.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 16 with Amanda Brock CEO of OpenUK</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/16/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/16/</guid><description>Amanda Brock is the CEO of OpenUK an organization that promotes the use of open source software, hardware, and data in the UK. Amanda has a deep background in open source dating back to the time she was the general council for Canonical. The HOSS talks with Amanda about her background, the business of open source, licensing, contributor agreements, FOSS growth in the UK, and more! Join us for the great discussion on all things open source.</description></item><item><title>The Hoss Talks Foss - Ep 15 with Lukas Eder CEO and Founder of Data Geekery GmbH</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/15/</guid><description>Lukas Eder is the CEO and founder of Data Geekery GmbH, the company behind JooQ an open source Java framework that gives you an API that allows you to write SQL statements through natural Java api calls. The HOSS (Matt Yonkovit) sat down with Lukas to discuss ORM’s like Hibernate and how JooQ is different. We also talk about how speed is important and how JooQ can help speed up database applications.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP14 Databases on Kubernetes: Bart Farrell the Head of the DoK community</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/14/</guid><description>Bart Farrell heads up the Data on Kubernetes community ( Dok ). Matt and Bart sit down to talk about what is happening in the community, how people can get involved, and what fun things are coming up next.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP13 Datastax’s VP of Dev Rel Patrick McFadin Sits Down and Talks Open Source, K8’s, The DBA to SRE Journey, and of Course Cassandra</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/13/</guid><description>The two open-source veterans of over 20 years sit down and talk about coming to open source, growing the community, the changes to open source licensing, and of course the new role of SRE/DBRE and how DBA’s are stepping up and turning into awesome contributors in this new role. We will also hear what is new and exciting with Apache Cassandra and what the folks over at Datastax are working on!</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP12 Sergey Pronin returns to talk about Kubernets, Operators, and DBaaS</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/12/</guid><description>Sergey Pronin (Percona Product Owner for Percona&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes operators) visits with the HOSS again talking about the latest releases as Percona adds functionality to Percona&amp;rsquo;s MongoDB and MySQL Operators (Also coming soon a PostgreSQL Operator!).</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP11 Talking OSS, Linux, Oracle, Big Business and Foss with Brian Walters</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/11/</guid><description>Percona’s Hoss (Head of Open Source Strategy) Matt Yonkovit talks to Percona’s SR Director of Solution Engineering on his journey from Teradata and Oracle to Open Source at Percona. Brian explores what he sees as the drivers and obstacles for enterprises moving and adopting more open source.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP10 Alkin Tezuysal talks Vitess, MySQL, Open Source, and Sailing</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/10/</guid><description>Percona’s Hoss (Head of Open Source Strategy) Matt Yonkovit talks to Planetscale’s SR Technical Manager Alkin Tezuysal on his role as a Vitess maintainer, who is using &amp;amp; contributing to Vitess, and where does it make sense for companies. We also dive into Alkin’s passion for sailing and talk about sailing during the global pandemic. You won’t want to miss this week’s episode!</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP09 Talking ARM CPU Performance ON EC2 with Jobin Augustine</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/9/</guid><description>Last year AWS announced ARM-based Graviton2 EC2 instances providing a cheaper more efficient option to classic X86 instances. Jobin and Sergey Kuzmichev wanted to know if the cheaper instances came at a cost in overall performance and set out on a deep dive into benchmarking and testing the different instances. Their hard work culminated in the first of a potential group of blogs highlighting the performance of PostgreSQL on the ARM processor.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP08 Talking Open Source, Contributions, and Databases with Henrik Ingo DataStax’s VP of Engineering in EMEA</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/8/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/8/</guid><description>The HOSS sits down with long time open source engineer, contributor, speaker, and advocate Henrik Ingo. Henrik and Matt talk about his career covering stints at MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB, and currently Datastax. We talk about the evolving open source space and what Datastax is doing to open more code and features up to the community.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP07 Talking Open Source and Development with Lenz Grimmer</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/7/</guid><description>Join the HOSS (Percona’s Head of Open Source Strategy) as he talks all things open-source with long time open source engineer Lenz Grimmer. Lenz has a long history of working on open source projects including Suse, MySQL, Ceph, and others. We talk about how we both got started in the open-source business, how people can contribute, and some of the cool things he has been up to.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP06 featuring Gabi Ferrara (Dev Advocate at Google) and talk about Open Source, Databases, PHP, and more</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/6/</guid><description>Gabi’s role at Google is to help developers get the most out of their applications, their databases, and their infrastructures. She has been a long time community member helping people in the PHP and MySQL community for years. The HOSS sits down with Gabi to talk about her journey from Brazil to the US, how she broke into the tech space, and how she ended up at Google.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP05 featuring David Murphy talking Devops, DBRE, SRE, MongoDB, and Modernizing IT</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/5/</guid><description>Join Percona’s HOSS (Head of Open Source Strategy) Matt Yonkovit as he sits down with David Murphy to talk about his journey and how he is seeing the DBA position evolve into DBRE’s and SRE’s. David has recently been working on helping a major airline modernize its internal database management systems and infrastructure, bringing more of a DevOps and SRE mentality to the company. He will discuss some of the issues and trends he has seen in his role.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP04 featuring Morgan Tocker talking MySQL, TiDB, Open Source Contributions, and Waffles!</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/4/</guid><description>Join the HOSS (Percona’s Head of Open Source Strategy) as he talks with MySQL and open source veteran Morgan Tocker about open source development, how we both got started in the open-source business, how people can contribute, and some of the cool things he has been up to.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP03 talking Databases on Kubernetes, K8 on the edge, Operators and more!</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/3/</guid><description>Sergey Pronin Percona&amp;rsquo;s Product Owner for Percona&amp;rsquo;s Kubernetes operators sat down to talk to us about using Kubernetes to manage databases, running Kubernetes on the edge, and where he sees the technology space headed. We talk to Sergey about his latest blogs covering :
Building A DBaaS with Kubernetes Running Kubernetes on the Edge Draining Kubernetes nodes wisely Don&amp;rsquo;t miss the latest episode of the HOSS talks Foss.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP02 talking MySQL Backup Best Practices with Walter Garcia</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/2/</guid><description>The Hoss talks with Walter Garcia remote dba expert for Percona about how to ensure you are getting good and consistent MySQL backups. We cover details about Walter&amp;rsquo;s latest blog outlining MySQL Backup best practices.</description></item><item><title>The HOSS Talks FOSS: EP01 talking with Percona CEO Peter Zaitsev about SSPL, open source, Elastic, and the cloud.</title><link>https://percona.community/podcasts/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/podcasts/1/</guid><description>On this episode of the HOSS (Head of open Source Strategy) talks FOSS (Free and Open Source Software), we talk with Peter Zaitsev CEO of Percona. We explore the changing landscape of the open source space including recent increases in the use of SSPL licenses by database providers like Elastic. We explore the trends driving the open source business in 2021.
Last week Elastic announced that they were “Doubling Down” on open source by changing their licensing to a non-open license - MongoDB’s Server Side Public License or SSPL.</description></item></channel></rss>