<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/authors/raghavendra_prabhu/</link><description>Recent content on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 02:02:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/authors/raghavendra_prabhu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kubernetes, The Swiss Army Knife For Your ProxySQL Deployments – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/09/kubernetes-the-swiss-army-knife-for-your-proxysql-deployments-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 02:02:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/09/kubernetes-the-swiss-army-knife-for-your-proxysql-deployments-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 10:00 p.m. • London 3:00 a.m. (Wed) • New Delhi 7:30 a.m. (Wed)
Abstract ProxySQL is a high performance proxy from design to implementation. It speaks the MySQL protocol, and can go beyond load balancing. This talk covers various deployment options for ProxySQL in a Kubernetes environment.
Typically ProxySQL is deployed in one of three ways depending on the scale and needs of your environment:</description></item><item><title>Orchestrating Cassandra with Kubernetes Operator and Yelp PaaSTA - Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/06/orchestrating-cassandra-with-kubernetes-operator-and-yelp-paasta-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/06/orchestrating-cassandra-with-kubernetes-operator-and-yelp-paasta-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 3:00 p.m. • London 8:00 p.m. • New Delhi 12:30 a.m. (Wed) Level: Intermediate
Abstract At Yelp, Cassandra, our NoSQL database of choice, has been deployed on AWS compute (EC2) and AutoScaling Groups (ASG), backed by Block Storage (EBS). This deployment model has been quite robust over the years while presenting its own set of challenges. To make our Cassandra deployment more resilient and reduce the engineering toil associated with our constantly growing infrastructure, we are abstracting Cassandra deployments further away from EC2 with Kubernetes and orchestrating with our Cassandra Operator.</description></item></channel></rss>