<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Postgres on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/postgres/</link><description>Recent content in Postgres on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/postgres/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> Community MeetUp - Installation and Configuration of PostgreSQL Operator - March, 2nd</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-02-percona-meetup-postgresql-operator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-03-02-percona-meetup-postgresql-operator/</guid><description>See you at the next Percona Community MeetUp dedicated to PostgreSQL Operator. Matt Yonkovit, The Head of Open Source Strategy (HOSS) at Percona will host this 1-hour live streaming event and Nickolay Ihalainen will take us through the Installation and Configuration of PostgreSQL Operator. Thank you for stopping by and we will answer your questions
Join us for an hour MeetUp for PostgreSQL Operator Day: Wednesday, March, 2nd at 11 am EST (5:00 pm CET / 9:30 pm IST) Live stream on YouTube and Twitch Live chat on Discord Add this event to your Google Calendar We Will Talk About: Installation and Configuration of PostgreSQL Operator with Nickolay Ihalainen and Matt Yonkovit</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item></channel></rss>