<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>recovery on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/recovery/</link><description>Recent content in recovery on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/recovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The lost art of Database Server Initialization.</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/05/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/05/lost-art-of-database-server-initialization/</guid><description>With all the DBaaS, IaaS and PaaS environments, sometimes I think the Art of MySQL initialization is becoming a lost art. Many times we just delete the MySQL Server and order a new one.
Just recently I was talking with a colleague, and this subject came up. We both thought about it and decided we have become spoiled by automation. We were both rusty on this process. This gave me the idea for this post.</description></item><item><title>Are your Database Backups Good Enough?</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</guid><description>In the last few years there have been several examples of major service problems affecting businesses data: outages causing data inconsistencies; unavailability or data loss, and worldwide cyberattacks encrypting your files and asking for a ransom.
Database-related incidents are a very common industry issue- even if the root cause is not the database system itself. No matter if your main relational system is MySQL, MariaDB, PostgresQL or AWS Aurora -there will be a time where you will need to make use of backups to recover to a previous state.</description></item></channel></rss>