<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ProxySQL on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/proxysql/</link><description>Recent content in ProxySQL on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:16:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/proxysql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona on June 4th, 2020!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/29/join-proxysql-tech-talks-with-percona-on-june-4th-2020/</guid><description>Long months of the pandemic lockdown have brought to life many great online events enabling the MySQL community to get together and stay informed about the very recent developments and innovations available to MySQL users. It isn’t over yet! Next Thursday, June 4th, Percona &amp;amp; ProxySQL are co-hosting the ProxySQL Tech Talks with Percona virtual meetup covering ProxySQL, MySQL and Percona XtraDB Cluster.
The attendees are invited to participate in the two-hour deep-dive event with plenty of time for questions and answers (we will have two 40-minute sessions + 20 minutes allocated for Q&amp;amp;A).</description></item><item><title>MySQL Setup at Hostinger Explained</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/11/mysql-setup-hostinger-explained/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 15:27:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/12/11/mysql-setup-hostinger-explained/</guid><description>Ever wondered how hosting companies manage their MySQL database architecture? At Hostinger, we have various MySQL setups starting from the standalone replica-less instances to Percona XtraDB Cluster (later just PXC), ProxySQL routing-based and even absolutely custom and unique solutions which I’m going to describe in this blog post.
We do not have elephant-sized databases for internal services like API, billing, and clients. Thus almost every decision ends up with high availability as a top priority instead of scalability.</description></item><item><title>Production with ProxySQL and Orchestrator</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-alawi-assaggaf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-alawi-assaggaf/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Covering 3 use case scenarios to implement HA utilizing ProxySQL, Orchestrator and Load Balancers in production environments.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/6Cz-ZZodSXM
Transcript</description></item></channel></rss>