<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mayank Sharma on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/mayank-sharma/</link><description>Recent content in Mayank Sharma on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:20:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/mayank-sharma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cassandra Where and How by John Schulz</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/24/cassandra-where-and-how-by-john-schulz/</guid><description>If Percona Live ONLINE had graded its talks by skill level this year, John Schulz’s talk would have been essential viewing in the Beginners track. (You can watch all the event’s presentations now on Percona’s YouTube channel.) This talk was a good overview and meant for anyone who had heard of the Apache Cassandra distributed database but wasn’t sure whether it would be suitable for their project or not.
Database-veteran, John Schulz has been tinkering with Cassandra for about a decade and to help anyone get started he gave a whistle-stop tour of the Cassandra ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Optimize and Troubleshoot MySQL using Percona Monitoring and Management by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 15:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/23/percona-live-online-talk-optimize-and-troubleshoot-mysql-using-percona-monitoring-and-management-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Incorporating a database in an organization is a complicated task that involves a lot of people besides the DBAs. This is something that Peter Zaitsev, co-founder and CEO of Percona, understands very well.
In the build-up to his hands-on presentation with the open source Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) platform, Peter spoke about how inducting a database in an organization is a constant tussle between the developers, the management and the DBAs.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Talk: Enhancing MySQL security at LinkedIn by Karthik Appigatla</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/01/percona-live-online-talk-enhancing-mysql-security-at-linkedin-by-karthik-appigatla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 08:01:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/01/percona-live-online-talk-enhancing-mysql-security-at-linkedin-by-karthik-appigatla/</guid><description>MySQL, arguably the most popular relational database, is used pretty extensively at the popular professional social network LinkedIn. At Percona Live ONLINE 2020, the company’s flagship event held online for the first time due to the Covid-19 pandemic, Karthik Appigatla from LinkedIN’s database SRE team discussed the company’s approach to securing their database deployment without introducing operational hiccups or adversely affecting performance.
Instead of just performing admin duties, Karthik’s team builds automated tools to scale their infrastructure, and he talked about some of these tailored tools in his presentation.</description></item></channel></rss>