<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hacktoberfest on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/hacktoberfest/</link><description>Recent content in hacktoberfest on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/hacktoberfest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recap Monthly Percona Developer Meetup Hacktoberfest</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/05/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/05/recap-monthly-percona-developer-meetup-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>The Monthly Percona Developer Meetup is an opportunity to get a behind-the-scenes view of different projects in Percona and directly interact with the experts to exchange ideas, ask questions, etc.
From now on, Monthly Percona Developer Meetups will take place monthly to have open discussions and in-person (online) communication. You can join our Developer Meetup via Restream, the Percona YouTube channel, and LinkedIn events.
The topic of the first Monthly Percona Developer Meetup was Hacktoberfest.</description></item><item><title>Hacktoberfest with Percona - We Want You! - September 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>October is close, and it is time for Hacktoberfest! Join our stream to talk online about this fantastic challenge at 2:30 UTC on Wednesday, September 28th. And yes, you can be a part of the conversation with experts and jump into the stream to address the audience!
If you love open source as much as we do, Hacktoberfest is created for you. It is a unique opportunity to be a part of a great open source community.</description></item></channel></rss>