<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The MySQL Workshop Book Review</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/03/the-mysql-workshop-book-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/03/the-mysql-workshop-book-review/</guid><description>Good books on MySQL for beginners are rare and excellent ones are even rarer. I often get requests from novices starting with MySQL or intermediates looking to level up on recommendations on books targeted at their level. The MySQL Workshop (Amazon link) by Thomas Pettit and Scott Cosentino is a must buy for those two groups, or those of us who would like a handy reference.
This is a great book and I recommend getting a copy regardless of your MySQL expertise.</description></item><item><title>Liquibase Data is Git for Databases</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/25/liquibase-data-is-git-for-databases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/25/liquibase-data-is-git-for-databases/</guid><description>Author&amp;rsquo;s Note: Robert will be demoing Liquibase Data at Percona Live 2022 on Wednesday, May 18 at 11:50am. Add this presentation to your schedule.
Git is an amazing tool for collaboration — developers can work together to build better software faster. However, the usual Git workflow neglects the database. With Liquibase Data we’re bringing git to the database so you can easily version containerized databases, share changes with team members, store versions in remote locations, and tag versions.</description></item><item><title>A Quick Guide To Austin For Percona Live 2022 Attendees</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/11/percona-live-austin-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/04/11/percona-live-austin-guide/</guid><description>Percona Live returns again to Austin May 16th through the 18th will find the city vibrant, charming, and weird. The semi-official motto for the city is ‘Keep Austin Weird’ and during your visit you will indeed see many of the residents working hard to do just that. Not in a bad way. Austin is at the intersection of so many cultural, artistic, and lifestyle modes that there are a fair amount of many different things happening at the same time to ensure that any dull moments you have will have to be an active choice on your part.</description></item><item><title>How to Publish a Blog Post</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/02/10/how-to-publish-blog-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/02/10/how-to-publish-blog-post/</guid><description>If you write technical content or just want to become an author, this blog is open to you! We accept any technical articles about databases and open source technologies. Also, we have no requirements for the uniqueness of the article. If your post is published on another resource, you can duplicate it here and get more attention.
In this post, I will explain step by step how to publish a post in our Community Blog.</description></item></channel></rss>