<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Presto Community Track on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/</link><description>Recent content in Presto Community Track on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Twitter Runs Presto at Scale in the Cloud</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/7/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/7/</guid><description>Beinan Wang, Ph.D. - Twitter - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto is a widely adopted federated SQL engine for federated querying across multiple data sources. With Presto, you can perform ad hoc querying of data in place.
In this session, Twitter engineer Beinan Wang will share how they use Presto at scale with over 3K Presto workers and 10 million queries and a highly-scalable query predictor service. At Twitter, this service helps improve the performance of Presto clusters and provides expected execution statistics on Business Intelligence dashboards.</description></item><item><title>Presto and Apache Iceberg</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/6/</guid><description>Chunxu Tang - Twitter - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Apache Iceberg is an open table format for huge analytic datasets. At Twitter, engineers are working on the Presto-Iceberg connector, aiming to bring high-performance data analytics on Iceberg to the Presto ecosystem. In this session, Chunxu will share what they have learned during the development and the future work of interactive queries.</description></item><item><title>Running Presto on AWS With Ahana Cloud</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/5/</guid><description>Dipti Borkar (Ahana) and Gary Stafford (AWS) - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto, the fast-growing open source SQL query engine, disaggregates storage and compute and leverages all data within an organization for data-driven decision making. It is driving the rise of Amazon S3-based data lakes and on-demand cloud computing. In this session you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how Ahana Cloud, the only managed service for Presto, simplifies Presto deployment &amp;amp; management on AWS using Kubernetes so data platforms teams of any size can use it.</description></item><item><title>5 Ways Facebook’s Ludicrous Usage Drives Presto Innovation</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/4/</guid><description>Ariel Weisberg - Facebook - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto at Facebook has evolved significantly since its inception in 2012. In this session, Ariel will discuss this evolution including fundamental architectural improvements on scale and efficiency, the business cases that drive improvements like these, how the Presto use cases at Facebook have grown (and what they are), and how this all is balanced with features that the Presto community looks for.</description></item><item><title>PrestoDB Administration Fundamentals – Why, What and How</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/3/</guid><description>Ravi Shankar - PassionBytes - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
The session will discuss how to set up, run, and scale Presto at your organization. You will learn about configuring data sources, memory requirements and monitoring, in addition to how to access the metadata information and get run time information by queries as well as through the admin UI. In case you need to see the live plan, there will be methods shown and explained.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Presto: The SQL Engine for Data Platform Teams</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/2/</guid><description>Dipti Borkar (Ahana) and Tim Meehan (Facebook) - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto is an open source high performance, distributed SQL query engine. Born at Facebook in 2012, Presto was built to run interactive queries on large Hadoop-based clusters. Today it has grown to support many users and use cases including ad hoc query, data lake analytics, and federated querying. In this session, we will give an overview on Presto including architecture and how it works, the problems it solves, and most common use cases.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Operator for Presto</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/presto-room/1/</guid><description>Hemant Bhanawat - Yugabyte - Presto Community Track - Percona Live 2021
Presto Operator for Kubernetes is used to manage Presto clusters which are deployed as custom resources. In short, the task of configuring, creating and managing of Presto cluster(s) in a Kubernetes environment has been made simple, easy and quick with a Presto Operator.
This session will be a walkthrough of provisioning Presto in K8s using Presto Operator. The advanced features of Presto Operator like HTTPS support, additional volumes support, autoscaling and graceful shutdown of workers will also be discussed.</description></item></channel></rss>