<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>backups on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/backups/</link><description>Recent content in backups on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/backups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Standby Cluster With the Percona Operator for PostgreSQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/27/creating-a-standby-cluster-with-the-percona-operator-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/27/creating-a-standby-cluster-with-the-percona-operator-for-postgresql/</guid><description>In this video, Nickolay Ihalainen, a Senior Scaling Specialist at Percona Global Services, explains how to set up replication with standby clusters for Kubernetes databases using Percona&amp;rsquo;s open-source tools, including the Percona Operator for PostgreSQL
A Standby Cluster is a backup version of your main database. It&amp;rsquo;s there to keep your data safe and make sure your database can keep running even if something goes wrong with the main one.</description></item><item><title>Open Door MongoDB Chats</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/26/open-door-mongodb-chats/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/26/open-door-mongodb-chats/</guid><description>Let’s talk about MongoDB! This week, Jan Wieremjewicz, Senior Product Manager, and Michal Nosek, Pre-Sales Enterprise Architect at Percona, made two series of videos covering basic to advanced concepts in MongoDB and backups. Le’s explore them together!
Enterprise Scale Backups for MongoDB with Open Source Software In the first video about enterprise-scale backups for MongoDB using open-source software, Jan and Michal discuss the challenges and solutions associated with backing up large datasets in MongoDB.</description></item><item><title>Are your Database Backups Good Enough?</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</guid><description>In the last few years there have been several examples of major service problems affecting businesses data: outages causing data inconsistencies; unavailability or data loss, and worldwide cyberattacks encrypting your files and asking for a ransom.
Database-related incidents are a very common industry issue- even if the root cause is not the database system itself. No matter if your main relational system is MySQL, MariaDB, PostgresQL or AWS Aurora -there will be a time where you will need to make use of backups to recover to a previous state.</description></item></channel></rss>