<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/authors/wayne/</link><description>Recent content on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/authors/wayne/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lets be inSync!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/22/lets-be-insync/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/22/lets-be-insync/</guid><description>Percona Toolkit + pt-table-checksum + pt-table-sync = Faster Replica Recovery Asynchronous replication with MySQL is a tried and true technology. Add the use of GTID’s and you have a very stable solution.
The fundamental issue with async replication is that writes sent to the Replica are not guaranteed to be written. I have only seen a handful of times when writes did not get applied to the replica. Most of the time this happens is due to network packet drops or a replica crashes before new data is committed.</description></item><item><title>How to Speed Up Re Sync of Dropped Percona Xtradb Cluster Node</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/02/24/how-to-speed-up-re-sync-of-dropped-percona-xtradb-cluster-node/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/02/24/how-to-speed-up-re-sync-of-dropped-percona-xtradb-cluster-node/</guid><description>The Problem HELP, HELP! My Percona XtraDB Cluster version: 5.7.31-31. Single Node is stuck in a joined state.
I recently had the privilege to help a client with a fascinating issue.
NODE-B dropped out of the 3 node PXC cluster. It looked to be DISK IO that caused NODE-B to fall far behind and eventually be removed from the cluster. A restart of NODE-B allowed it to rejoin the cluster. NODE-B looked to have been down for about 4 hours.</description></item><item><title>Disk of Yesteryear Compared to Today’s SSD Drives</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/17/disk-of-yesteryear-compared-to-todays-ssd-drives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/17/disk-of-yesteryear-compared-to-todays-ssd-drives/</guid><description>In my [last blog post](https://www.percona.com/ community-blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/) I showed you how to get the entire Percona “Stack&amp;quot; up and running on a Raspberry Pi. This time around, I would like to show the impact on performance between using an SSD hard disk and a standard hard disk.
Disk performance is a key factor in Percona Server for MySQL (or any RDB platform) performance on a Raspberry Pi 4.
Test set up Each test below was run three times per Hard Disk and I took the best of the three for comparison.</description></item><item><title>How to Build a Percona Server "Stack" on a Raspberry Pi 3+</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 12:50:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</guid><description>The blog post How to Compile Percona Server for MySQL 5.7 in Raspberry Pi 3 by Walter Garcia, inspired me to create an updated install of Percona Server for the Raspberry Pi 3+.
This how-to post covers installing from source and being able to use Percona Server for MySQL in any of your maker projects. I have included everything you need to have a complete Percona Server, ready to store data collection for your weather station, your GPS data, or any other project you can think of that would require data collection in a database.</description></item></channel></rss>