<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PostgreSQL on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/postgresql/</link><description>Recent content in PostgreSQL on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/postgresql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> Comunity MeetUp - The installation of the main part of Percona products - February 9th, 2022 at 10:00 am EST</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-02-09-percona-meetup-for-percona-products/</guid><description>We will meet in The Percona Community MeetUp. Evgeniy will be joining us and talk more about the installation of main part of Percona products . Join us and ask questions and receive an answer right away.
Join us in Community MeetUp for Percona Product Day: February 9th, 2022 at 10:00 am EST (4:00 pm CET or 8:30 pm IST) Live stream on YouTube and Twitch Live chat on Discord Add this event to your Google Calendar Topic The installation of the main part of Percona products with Evgeniy Patlan and Matt Yonkovit</description></item><item><title> MeetUp PostgreSQL - The ins and outs of PostgreSQL Configurations and Tuning - January 27th, 2022 at 10:00 am EST</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-01-27-percona-meetup-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/2022-01-27-percona-meetup-for-postgresql/</guid><description>The Percona Commmunity meetup for PostgreSQL was live on last Thursday, January 27th, 2022 with Charly Batista and Matt Yonkovit. They have talked about the optimal settings to tune a new fresh database. Learn in this recording the different parameters that you should check.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/sQPBqD5zcno
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
And we are starting to stream right now. So welcome, everybody. We&amp;rsquo;re on a few minutes early just to get people warmed up with the opportunity before we start to get on.</description></item><item><title>Percona Supports Community Events - Organize Yours With Us!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/23/community-events-support/</guid><description>One of the things we love doing in Percona is participating in community events and inspiring people to stay connected in the changing world. We have experience in organizing community dinners, meetups, lectures at universities, booths, and even conferences both in-person and virtually. Percona speakers give talks on events all around the globe.
Have you ever thought about organizing a themed meeting for your local open source community? It may harbor many possibilities for you.</description></item><item><title>PMM development and testing with help of minikube</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</guid><description>Why Some time ago I needed to test PG14 with the new pg_stat_monitor version that wasn&amp;rsquo;t released. I decided to log my journey so I would spend less effort next time to replicate it.
I do use podman and run PMM with its help but I also like to hack PMM DBaaS features and think that k8s and minikube are perfect and better scalable solutions for the different development environments and especially for the number of clusters and DBs.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PostgreSQL - Optimization of PostgreSQL instances - Dec 15th, 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/postgresql-december-2021-optimisation-rds-ec2-instances/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/postgresql-december-2021-optimisation-rds-ec2-instances/</guid><description>We have talked about what&amp;rsquo;s been going on support side with Jobin Augustine, Senior Support Engineer at Percona, before starting to stump the expert with RDS and EC2 live tuning. This Community MeetUp for PostgreSQL is 1-hour live streaming hosted by Matt Yonkovit, The HOSS at Percona, to talk more about Optimization of PostgreSQL instances.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/BZNw5HHXnW0
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hello, everyone out there in internet land! How are you today?</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PostgreSQL November 2021 - Autovacuum</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-november-2021-autovacuum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-november-2021-autovacuum/</guid><description>Listen to the full recording of The MeetUp for PostgreSQL of November 17th. We have talked about autovacuum in PostgreSQL with Percona Senior Support Engineer Sergey Kuzmichev. Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS at Percona, asked Sergey to resolve a database issue live.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/PtWQFkTt1Bo
Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hello, everybody, sorry, we double clicked on the video clip there. Look at how are you, Sergey? Welcome, Sergey, welcome, everyone, to another Percona meetup on our regular live stream Sergey, how are you doing?</description></item><item><title>Balalaika Meetup With Local Community in Ulyanovsk</title><link>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</guid><description>On November 15th, Percona organized a meetup with the local community in Ulyanovsk (Russia). From Percona, there were Peter Zaitsev (CEO), Maria Azizova (Staff Executive), and Aleksandra Abramova (Community Specialist). They had a chance to meet engineers from different IT companies who live nearby.
The event took place in an interesting location. It was a private Balalaika&amp;rsquo;s Museum. It is a Russian national musical instrument. If you wonder how it sounds like, there are some examples on YouTube like this one.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PostgreSQL October 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-october-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-october-2021/</guid><description>Community MeetUp for PostgreSQL was live stream on Oct 13th at 11:00am EDT to talk about how to improve your database performance with appropriated tools for monitoring and optimization. Here are the full recording and transcript :
Video Link: https://youtu.be/rAuz1usu9Z4
Transcript Matt Yonkovit Oh, the abrupt start, I started the soundtrack a little, a little later than normal so we didn&amp;rsquo;t get the full five minutes of awesome retro 80s soundtrack in.</description></item><item><title>Percona MeetUp for PostgreSQL Sept 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-september-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-meetups/percona-meetup-for-postgresql-september-2021/</guid><description>Full video recording of the live-streamed Community MeetUp for postgreSQL we held on September 15th, 2021. Matt Yonkovit, the HOSS, sat down with Jobin Augustine, PostgreSQL Escalation Specialist in Support at Percona, and Ibrar Ahmed, Senior Software Architect at Percona to talk about “PostgreSQL Data and Database Security” and &amp;ldquo;Driving factors for increased PostgreSQL adoptions&amp;rdquo;.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/B_U3rYue0iQ
Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hey everybody, welcome to another Percona live stream. We are here with Ibrar and Jobin today.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Highly Available PostgreSQL With GKE</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live/google-room/4/</guid><description>Christoph Bussler and Shashank Agarwal - Google - Percona Live 2021
When you have an application running in Google Kubernetes Engine, there are multiple options and considerations for how to deploy a database. In this session, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn some of the architectural considerations for choosing a database deployment option in GKE. We will demonstrate one of these options, as you learn how to configure PostgreSQL as a container in GKE based on regional persistent disks and PersistentVolumeClaims.</description></item><item><title>Fixing Common PostgreSQL Performance Bottlenecks</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/04/fixing-common-postgresql-performance-bottlenecks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 20:26:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/12/04/fixing-common-postgresql-performance-bottlenecks/</guid><description>Overview In this article, I look at how poorly designed sharding systems and replication systems in PostgreSQL affect query performance in high volume situations, and how to ensure data consistency across many servers. I also discuss how excessive vacuuming generates I/O traffic, and how connection pooling is used to improve transaction throughput by caching connections from clients. I also cover how insufficient memory could affect PostgreSQL performance. These are key problems I have encountered as a database consultant, and how I&amp;rsquo;ve overcome them.</description></item><item><title>What If We Could Use Machine Learning Models as Tables – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/12/what-if-we-could-use-machine-learning-models-as-tables-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 17:56:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/12/what-if-we-could-use-machine-learning-models-as-tables-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 1:30 p.m. • London 6:30 p.m. • New Delhi 11:00 p.m. • Singapore 1:30 a.m. (next day)
Abstract In most machine learning tasks, one has to first organize data in some form and then turn it into information about the problem that needs to be solved. One could say that the requirement to train many machine learning algorithms is information, not just data.</description></item><item><title>Analytical Queries in MySQL – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 17:05:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 6:00 p.m. • London 11:00 p.m. • New Delhi 3:30 a.m. • Singapore 6:00 a.m.
Abstract MySQL&amp;rsquo;s sweet spot is known to be online transaction processing (OLTP), and it can support a very high load of short transactions. Many users will also want to run analytical queries (OLAP) on their MySQL data. Often they achieve this by exporting their data to another database system that is tailored for analytical queries.</description></item><item><title>Kunlun Distributed DB Cluster Intro – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 22:25:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 9:30 p.m. • London 02:30 a.m. (next day) • New Delhi 7:00 a.m. • Singapore 09:30 a.m.
Abstract Kunlun Distributed Database Cluster is a distributed DBMS that aims to combine the best of both MySQL and PostgreSQL for a highly performant, highly available, highly scalable and fault-tolerant, easy to use and manage database system that requires minimal human maintenance. It enables users to define table sharding rules so that it automatically distributes tables properly to available storage shards; implements the two-phase commit protocol to do distributed transaction commit; uses MySQL group replication for high availability in storage shards; fixes a series of MySQL XA bugs to make distributed transactions highly reliable, among many other enhancements.</description></item><item><title>Database Schema Management Via Liquibase</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 22:30:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/database-schema-management-via-liquibase/</guid><description>Creating the database for an application is simple and easy. However, database script management gets complicated in a hurry when you need to support multiple versions, work with multiple teams, and apply the same changes to multiple types of databases. One open-source tool that helps teams track, version, and deploy database schema changes is Liquibase. It executes database scripts sequentially, allows for the automatic creation and execution of rollback scripts for failed updates, and provides an easy way to use the same scripts and apply them to different types of databases.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE: Anti-cheating tools for massive multiplayer games using Amazon Aurora and Amazon ML services</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/11/percona-live-online-anti-cheating-tools-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 14:21:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/11/percona-live-online-anti-cheating-tools-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services/</guid><description>Would you play a multiplayer game if you discovered other people are cheating? According to a survey by Irdeto, 60% of online games were negatively impacted by cheaters, and 77% of players said they would stop playing a multiplayer game if they think opponents are cheating. Player churn grows as cheating grows.
Stopping this is therefore essential if you want to build and develop your community, which is essential to success for today’s gaming companies.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.4 and the Competition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 23:10:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/07/mariadb-10-4-and-the-competition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 19 May • New York 12:30 p.m. • London 5:30 p.m. • New Delhi 10:00 p.m.
Abstract There are many good databases out there. Picking the right database for your project is never easy. There are technical criteria, business criteria, perhaps even ethical criteria. In this keynote, MariaDB Foundation CEO Kaj Arno will present his - obviously completely impartial - view of the process. Should you pick a database in the cloud or on premise?</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Gonymizer, A Tool to Anonymize Sensitive PostgreSQL Data Tables for Use in QA and Testing</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/17/percona-live-gonymizer-tool-anonymize-sensitive-postgresql-data-testing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 11:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/17/percona-live-gonymizer-tool-anonymize-sensitive-postgresql-data-testing/</guid><description>SmithRX is a next generation pharmacy benefit platform that is using the latest technology to radically reshape the prescription benefit management industry. To move quickly, we require the ability to iterate and test new versions of our software using production like data without violating Health Information Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) regulations.
At Percona Live 2019, we are introducing a project we open sourced to anonymize our sensitive production data for use in rapid QA and testing of our software.</description></item><item><title>London Open Source Database Community Meetup</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 09:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/03/15/london-open-source-database-community-meetup/</guid><description>I strongly believe in the community.
Communities are the real strength of open source. Not just the theoretical ability to study, modify and share code – but the fact that other people out there are doing these things. Creating a base of knowledge and a network of relations.These can become work relationships, valuable discussions, open source tools, or even friendships.
That is why, when I heard that several people from the Percona support team will soon be in London, I badly wanted to organise an event.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Europe Presents: pg_chameleon MySQL to PostgreSQL Replica Made Easy</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 14:42:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/10/26/percona-live-europe-presents-pg_chameleon-mysql-postgresql-replica-made-easy/</guid><description>What excites me is the possibility that this tool is giving to other people. Also, the challenges I’ve faced and the new ideas for the future releases are always source of interest that keep me focused on the project. So I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to sharing this with the conference delegates.
pg_chameleon can achieve two tasks in a very simple way. It can setup a permanent replica between MySQL and PostgreSQL, giving the freedom of choice for the right tool for the right job, or can migrate multiple schemas to a PostgreSQL database.</description></item></channel></rss>