<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Information on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/information/</link><description>Recent content in Information on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 17:23:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/information/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Write Your Index in Tarantool</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 17:23:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/09/28/how-to-write-your-index-in-tarantool/</guid><description>Tarantool is an application server and a database. The server part is written in C, and the user is provided with a Lua interface to use it. Then, Tarantool is an open-source product with its source code in open access, and anyone can develop and distribute Tarantool-based software freely.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you about an attempt to write my own data structure for the search (the Z-order curve) and build it into the Tarantool ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Making a Tarantool-Based Investment Business Core for Alfa-Bank</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/19/making-a-tarantool-based-investment-business-core-for-alfa-bank/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 13:23:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/19/making-a-tarantool-based-investment-business-core-for-alfa-bank/</guid><description>A still from &amp;ldquo;Our Secret Universe: The Hidden Life of the Cell&amp;rdquo;
Investment business is one of the most complex domains in the banking world. It&amp;rsquo;s about not just credits, loans, and deposits — there are also securities, currencies, commodities, derivatives, and all kinds of complex stuff like structured products.
Recently, people have become increasingly aware of their finances. More and more get involved in securities trading. Individual investment accounts have emerged not so long ago.</description></item><item><title>Percona Projects for Google Summer of Code - 2020</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:38:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/04/percona-projects-for-google-summer-of-code-2020/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that Percona was selected as a participating organization for the Google Summer of Code (GSoC) 2020 program, this is our second year as a participating org with the GSoC program.
GSoC is a great program to involve young student developers in open source projects. We participated in the program in 2019 for the first time and we were really happy and satisfied with the results.</description></item><item><title>How to contribute Dashboards to PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 14:54:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/05/04/how-to-contribute-dashboards-to-pmm/</guid><description>Have you already contributed to Percona’s open-source products or perhaps you wanted to try doing so?
I will tell you how to become a contributor to the popular open-source product from Percona in just a few hours. You don&amp;rsquo;t need any serious developer skills.
We earlier explained how to contribute to PMM documentation in our last post. Now we will contribute to PMM itself, namely to Dashboards. Dashboards are an important part of PMM, they are seen and used by thousands of users, so your contribution may be of benefit to many others.</description></item><item><title>Our Offer to Online Meetups and Community Leaders</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/07/our-offer-to-online-meetups-and-community-leaders/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 10:52:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/04/07/our-offer-to-online-meetups-and-community-leaders/</guid><description>Percona’s Community team organizes our speakers at in-person events around the world, such as Percona Live, Percona University, and events sponsored by other organizations. However, like everyone else around the world, all our plans are on hold due to the Coronavirus pandemic.
Perhaps you, like many others, are organizing online events, such as virtual meetups on Meetup.com. We can help you by making Percona’s team of experienced and well-known speakers available for your event.</description></item></channel></rss>