<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Live 2019 on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/percona-live-2019/</link><description>Recent content in Percona Live 2019 on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/percona-live-2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Are your Database Backups Good Enough?</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/09/20/are-your-database-backups-good-enough/</guid><description>In the last few years there have been several examples of major service problems affecting businesses data: outages causing data inconsistencies; unavailability or data loss, and worldwide cyberattacks encrypting your files and asking for a ransom.
Database-related incidents are a very common industry issue- even if the root cause is not the database system itself. No matter if your main relational system is MySQL, MariaDB, PostgresQL or AWS Aurora -there will be a time where you will need to make use of backups to recover to a previous state.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Globalizing Player Accounts with MySQL at Riot Games</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/28/percona-live-presents-globalizing-player-accounts-mysql-riot-games/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:48:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/28/percona-live-presents-globalizing-player-accounts-mysql-riot-games/</guid><description>During my presentation at Percona Live 2019, I’ll be talking about how Riot Games, the company behind League of Legends, migrated hundreds of millions of player accounts to unlock opportunities for us to delight players. This meant moving ten geographically distributed databases into a single global database replicated into four AWS regions. I’ll talk about some of the technical decisions we made, the expected vs actual outcomes, and lessons we learned along the way.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: An Open-Source, Cloud Native Database</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/14/percona-live-presents-open-source-cloud-native-database/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 17:38:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/14/percona-live-presents-open-source-cloud-native-database/</guid><description>During our presentation at Percona Live 2019 Intel and its software partners will introduce the audience to the work we’re doing to enable an open-source framework, we call Cloud Native Database. This is a collaborative effort between Intel, Rockset, PlanetScale, MariaDB and Percona.
Through the presentation the audience will be introduced to a set of principles and architectural elements that define what we mean by Cloud Native Database. We will discuss Rockset’s RocksDB-Cloud library and how it works with Facebook’s MyRocks storage engine.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The State of Databases in 2019</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/09/percona-live-presents-state-databases-2019/</guid><description>At this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live I am talking about The State of Databases in 2019. As a Software Engineer in the thick of the Database landscape, there are two problems that I see repeatedly.
Due to the massive explosion of database solutions, it has become very difficult to evaluate what database solution will serve the best for one’s use case, and
The constant tug of war between database operators and users.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The First Ever TiDB Track</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 20:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</guid><description>The PingCAP team has always been a strong supporter of Percona and the wider open source database community. As the people who work day in and day out on TiDB, an open source NewSQL database with MySQL compatibility, open source database is what gets us in the morning, and there’s no better place to share that passion than Percona Live.
At this year’s Percona Live Open Source Database Conference in Austin, Texas, we are particularly excited to bring you a full track of talks and demo on the latest development in TiDB during Day 1 of the conference.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The MySQL Query Optimizer Explained Through Optimizer Trace</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/24/mysql-query-optimizer-explained-optimizer-trace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 16:16:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/24/mysql-query-optimizer-explained-optimizer-trace/</guid><description>During my presentation at Percona Live 2019 I will show how using Optimizer Trace can give insight into the inner workings of the MySQL Query Optimizer. Through the presentation, the audience will both be introduced to optimizer trace, learn more about the decisions the query optimizer makes, and learn about the query execution strategies the query optimizer has at its disposal. I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the main phases of the MySQL optimizer and its optimization strategies, including query transformations, data access strategies, the range optimizer, the join optimizer, and subquery optimization.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live Presents: Vitess – Running Sharded MySQL on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/18/percona-live-presents-vitess-running-sharded-mysql-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 17:19:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/04/18/percona-live-presents-vitess-running-sharded-mysql-kubernetes/</guid><description>The topic I&amp;rsquo;m presenting addresses a growing and unfulfilled need: the ability to run stateful workloads in Kubernetes. Running stateless applications is now considered a solved problem. However, it&amp;rsquo;s currently not practical to put databases like MySQL in containers, give them to Kubernetes, and expect it to manage their life cycles.
Sugu Sougoumarane, CTO of Planetscale and creator of Vitess.
Vitess addresses this need by providing all the necessary orchestration and safety, and it has multiple years of mileage to show for it.</description></item></channel></rss>