<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>contributions on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/contributions/</link><description>Recent content in contributions on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/contributions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nurturing, Motivating and Recognizing Non-Code Contributions</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/08/nurturing-motivating-and-recognizing-non-code-contributions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/08/nurturing-motivating-and-recognizing-non-code-contributions/</guid><description>When discussing contributions, we still see a lot of emphasis on the code contributions into project repositories. But the open source world is extensive and diverse, and everyone can find their place there. Your project will benefit from various experiences that non-coders can bring to the table. Isn’t that cool when you receive an issue with an interesting bug from the community, read about a user case in a blog or a review, or someone makes a video guide for your product?</description></item><item><title>How To Contribute to PMM Documentation</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 16:43:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/28/how-to-contribute-to-pmm-documentation/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;d love to see more contributions towards the development and improvement of Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM), one of Percona&amp;rsquo;s most valued projects. Like all of Percona&amp;rsquo;s software, PMM is free and open-source. An area where we&amp;rsquo;d dearly love to see some community provided enhancement is in its documentation. In future blog posts, we&amp;rsquo;ll provide some insight on how to contribute to our software but&amp;hellip; the beauty of documentation is that it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward to maintain, and you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to be a programmer to be able to provide valuable corrections and enhancements.</description></item></channel></rss>