<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>minikube on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/minikube/</link><description>Recent content in minikube on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/minikube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Binding your application to the database in the Kubernetes cluster</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</guid><description>dbaas-operator is Yet Another DBaaS Kubernetes Operator (need to suggest yadbko as a name) that tries to simplify and unify Database Cluster deployments by building a higher abstraction layer on top of Percona Kubernetes Operators.
So it becomes much easier to deploy the DB cluster with dbaas-operator and PMM DBaaS on top of it.
But another part of the picture is applications and their workloads to connect to the deployed DB Clusters.</description></item><item><title>How and Why Contribute to Communities</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/30/csi-minikube-multinode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/05/30/csi-minikube-multinode/</guid><description>Why Lets start with a simple question &amp;ldquo;Why to contribute?&amp;rdquo;.
In our day to day development&amp;rsquo;s and user&amp;rsquo;s life we use tons of OSS (open source) software. Ppl develop that software together to have ability to use them in more standard and open way, so they spend less time negotiating on interfaces and tools (and that is not the main reason, one of the reasons for OSS).
As any sustainable process, OSS development also needs not only users but contributors to be able to move project forward as well as to sustain bugs, time and new tech trends.</description></item><item><title>PMM development and testing with help of minikube</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/12/20/pmm-minikube-postgres/</guid><description>Why Some time ago I needed to test PG14 with the new pg_stat_monitor version that wasn&amp;rsquo;t released. I decided to log my journey so I would spend less effort next time to replicate it.
I do use podman and run PMM with its help but I also like to hack PMM DBaaS features and think that k8s and minikube are perfect and better scalable solutions for the different development environments and especially for the number of clusters and DBs.</description></item></channel></rss>