<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Labs on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/labs/</link><description>Recent content in Labs on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying MySQL Group Replication With Terraform</title><link>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2023-02-15-deploying-mysql-group-replication-terraform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2023-02-15-deploying-mysql-group-replication-terraform/</guid><description>Previously, I wrote about our Terraform provider to deploy Percona Server for MySQL (Percona Server for MySQL: Automatic Cloud Deployment With Terraform) and Percona Monitoring and Management (Deploying Percona Monitoring and Management (PMM) With Terraform). Now we also added the capability to deploy Group Replication configuration with Percona Server for MySQL, and assuming we have PMM installed (see previous post), we also can automatically add Group Replication nodes to PMM monitoring.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Percona Monitoring and Management With Terraform</title><link>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2023-02-14-deploying-pmm-terraform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2023-02-14-deploying-pmm-terraform/</guid><description>Recently, we released Percona Monitoring and Management 2.34 (PMM) which includes upgrades for backup and Database as a Service (DBaaS) features, and we are seeking ways to simplify PMM deployment.
Previously I wrote about our Terraform provider to deploy Percona Server for MySQL — Percona Server for MySQL: Automatic Cloud Deployment with Terraform — and now we added capabilities to deploy PMM with Terraform.
You need the provider version 0.9.10 and PMM can be deployed as:</description></item><item><title>Binding your application to the database in the Kubernetes cluster</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</guid><description>dbaas-operator is Yet Another DBaaS Kubernetes Operator (need to suggest yadbko as a name) that tries to simplify and unify Database Cluster deployments by building a higher abstraction layer on top of Percona Kubernetes Operators.
So it becomes much easier to deploy the DB cluster with dbaas-operator and PMM DBaaS on top of it.
But another part of the picture is applications and their workloads to connect to the deployed DB Clusters.</description></item><item><title>Percona Server for MySQL – Automatic Cloud Deployment with Terraform</title><link>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2022-10-20-terraform-percona-server-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/labs/posts/2022-10-20-terraform-percona-server-for-mysql/</guid><description>We are looking to provide simplified ways to deploy Percona software in cloud environments, especially for more advanced scenarios like replication and multi-node cluster (in the case of Percona XtraDB Cluster).
For this I propose trying out our new Terraform provider, with the capabilities:
Deploy in AWS or GCP Cloud. The provider will automatically create instances and deploy Percona Server for MySQL Deploy either Percona Server for MySQL or Percona XtraDB Cluster Choose instance size Choose storage volume size, type, and IOPs Multi-node async replication or multi-node Percona XtraDB Cluster Customize MySQL configuration file Capability to deploy MyRocks Engine To get more understanding let’s review some examples, but before that, where you can obtain modules:</description></item><item><title>Enabling KMS encryption for a running Amazon RDS instance</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/08/enabling-kms-encryption-running-amazon-rds-instance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 11:40:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/08/enabling-kms-encryption-running-amazon-rds-instance/</guid><description>Since summer 2017, Amazon RDS supports encryption at rest using AWS Key Management Service (KMS) for db.t2.small and db.t2.medium database instances, making the feature now available to virtually every instance class and type.
Unless you are running Previous Generation DB Instances or you can only afford to run a db.t2.micro, every other instance class now supports native encryption at rest using KMS. As for the Amazon documentation:
Encryption on smaller T2 database instances is useful for development and test use cases, where you want the environment to have identical security characteristics as the planned production environment.</description></item><item><title>Percona Terraform Provider</title><link>https://percona.community/labs/terraform-provider/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/labs/terraform-provider/</guid><description>Percona offers Terraform provider for easy installation of Percona Server for MySQL and PMM in AWS and Google Cloud.
Terraform offers the following benefits:
Automation: Terraform automates the process of creating, updating, and managing infrastructure, reducing the risk of errors and increasing efficiency. Versioning: Terraform allows you to version control your infrastructure, making it easier to track changes and collaborate with others. Scalability: Terraform makes it easy to scale infrastructure up or down, so you can quickly adapt to changing needs.</description></item></channel></rss>