<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stream on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/stream/</link><description>Recent content in Stream on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/stream/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Observing &amp; Tuning Your MySQL Workload Using PMM - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - April, 15th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-15-observing-tuning-your-mysql-workload-using-pmm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-15-observing-tuning-your-mysql-workload-using-pmm/</guid><description>Join the next Community Live Stream for MySQL and learn how to increase the performance of your database with our experts. Matt and Marcos will show how to optimize and tune the workload of your database using Percona Monitoring and Management. Hang out and ask questions to get answers straightforward!
Join us Live &amp;amp; Ask Questions Friday, April 15th at 9:00 AM EDT / 03:00 PM CEST/ 06:30 PM IST Matt and Marcos will get across Observing &amp;amp; Tuning Your MySQL Workload Using PMM</description></item><item><title>Setting Up and Scheduling Regular PostgreSQL Backups - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - April, 8th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-08-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-08-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups/</guid><description>Join the next Community Live stream for PostgresSQL and learn about the best setting to protect and restore your data in our next. Matt and Charly will talk about database backup settings, frequency, and different types of backups. Come up with your questions and our experts will answer live.
Topic Friday, April 8th at 2:00 pm EDT / 07:00 PM CEST Setting up and scheduling regular PostgreSQL backups with Matt and Charly</description></item><item><title>Installing MySQL and Setting Up a Default Configuration - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - April, 1st</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-01-install-mysql-setting-up-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-01-install-mysql-setting-up-configuration/</guid><description>Watch out this recording from Percona Community live stream of April 1st. Learn how to install MySQL and Setting Up a Default Configuration with Matt Yonkovit and Marcos Albe. This is a series of live stream to discuss MySQL tricks with experts.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/AMGNklpAjJ8
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
We might even be live right now. Marcos, we might be live oh we are live oh we see now we&amp;rsquo;re live there we popped in.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for PostgreSQL - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - March 25th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-25-setting-up-alert-and-basic-automation-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-25-setting-up-alert-and-basic-automation-for-postgresql/</guid><description>Percona Community organized live stream to talk more about Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for PostgreSQL. This recording is from the live event of March 25th with Matt Yonkovit, Charly Batista and Agustin Gallego. This is a part of the Percona Community bi-weekly Live Stream series to discuss Postgres-related topics and deep talks with technology secrets.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/f1NklbrVvYY
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hello, hello, everyone, Welcome to another Friday edition of the Postgres Percona database meetup.</description></item><item><title>Observing &amp; Tuning Your PostgreSQL Workload Using PMM - Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - March 11th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-11-observing-and-tuning-your-postgresql-workload-using-pmm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-11-observing-and-tuning-your-postgresql-workload-using-pmm/</guid><description>Organize and access easily to your database data by observing and tuning your PostgreSQL workload using PMM. Our experts Matt Yonkovit and Charly Batista present use cases in a bi-weekly live stream about Postgres-related topics.
Video Part 01 Link: https://youtu.be/H2uNDbQ8lCk
Video Part 02 Link: https://youtu.be/SxQyC2RdBCg
Transcript Part 01 Matt Yonkovit:
Here we go! We&amp;rsquo;re live! Hello everyone! Welcome to a specially exciting Friday live stream. Hopefully everyone is getting to the weekend.</description></item><item><title>Installing PG and Setting Up a Default Configuration - Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Jan 27th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-01-27-installing-pg-and-setting-up-default-configuration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-01-27-installing-pg-and-setting-up-default-configuration/</guid><description>Listen out to this full recording of the 1st Live Stream dedicated to PostgreSQL hosted by The Head Of Open Source Strategy at Percona, Matt Yonkovit with Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona. They took us through the installation of Postgres and the setting up of the default configuration. This is a part of the bi-weekly Live Streaming series to discuss Postgres-related topics and go deep into technology secrets and tricks.</description></item></channel></rss>