<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stream on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/stream/</link><description>Recent content in Stream on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/stream/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using PG and Redis to Boost Performance - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - November 17th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-11-17-using-redis-for-performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-11-17-using-redis-for-performance/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for PostgreSQL will focus on using PG and Redis. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
WHEN Thursday, November 17th at 10:00 AM EST / 04:00 PM CET / 08:30 PM IST.
Add this event to your Google Calendar.
WHERE Watch it live on:</description></item><item><title>How to Secure MySQL Database - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Nov 11th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-11-11-how-to-secure-mysql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-11-11-how-to-secure-mysql/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for MySQL will focus on securing MySQL. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/Bei-AhP52vc
TRANSCRIPT Mario Garcia:
Hello, everyone! Welcome to our stream this week. I am Mario Garcia, Technical Evangelist at Percona. Today we have Marcos Albe, Principal Support Engineer, who will talk about how to secure MySQL.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up a PostgreSQL Connection Pool - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Oct, 20th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-10-20-setting-up-postgresql-connection-pool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-10-20-setting-up-postgresql-connection-pool/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for PostgreSQL focused on setting up a PostgreSQL connection pool. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/fZ84jx6kvpU
TRANSCRIPT Mario Garcia: Hello, everyone. Welcome to our stream. I am Mario Garcia. I&amp;rsquo;m a Technical Evangelist at Percona. And today we have Charly Batista, who will talk about setting up Postgres connection pool.</description></item><item><title>How Do We Develop Code? Live Coding Session Into Our DBaaS Controller- October 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-10-27-develop-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-10-27-develop-code/</guid><description>Have you always wanted to know what and how a developer is working? What do they do, how do they start looking into issues and how do they finally turn that into code? It’s your time to get a behind the scenes view into the daily life of a developer from Percona!
In this session, Andrew is going to implement the db engine configuration support for the PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management) API and will implement that into the DBaaS controller.</description></item><item><title>How to Benchmark Your MySQL Database - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Oct 14th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-10-28-how-to-benchmark-your-mysql-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-10-28-how-to-benchmark-your-mysql-database/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for MySQL will focus on benchmarking a MySQL database. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/OOp8vy1Wxko
SLIDES Check out Marcos' slides HERE.
TRANSCRIPT Mario Garcia:
Hello, everyone. Thank you for joining us today. I am Mario Garcia, I&amp;rsquo;m a Technical Evangelist at Percona.</description></item><item><title>How to Secure PostgreSQL - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Oct, 6th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-10-06-how-to-secure-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-10-06-how-to-secure-postgresql/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for PostgreSQL will focus on How to Secure PostgreSQL. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/ZBD3HaoBTPs
TRANSCRIPT Dave Stokes: Welcome back. This is Percona, this little biweekly Postgres talk. We&amp;rsquo;re part of this Percona Community Postgres live stream. Now the official title, my name is Dave Stokes, I&amp;rsquo;m a Technology Evangelist, and with me is Charly Batista.</description></item><item><title>Finding Poorly Designed Schema's and How to Fix Them - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Sept 30th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-09-30-finding-poorly-designed-schema/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-09-30-finding-poorly-designed-schema/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for MySQL will focus on Finding Poorly Designed Schema&amp;rsquo;s and How to Fix Them. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions. Add this event to your Google Calendar.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/PDYWBDGLBE0
TRANSCRIPT Dave Stokes: This is a podcast or stream cast we&amp;rsquo;re doing on finding poorly designed schemas, featuring Marcos Albe, who is our resident expert.</description></item><item><title>Hacktoberfest with Percona - We Want You! - September 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-monthly-dev/2022-09-26-hacktoberfest/</guid><description>October is close, and it is time for Hacktoberfest! Join our stream to talk online about this fantastic challenge at 2:30 UTC on Wednesday, September 28th. And yes, you can be a part of the conversation with experts and jump into the stream to address the audience!
If you love open source as much as we do, Hacktoberfest is created for you. It is a unique opportunity to be a part of a great open source community.</description></item><item><title>How to Benchmark Your PostgreSQL Database - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Sept, 22nd</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-09-22-how-to-benchmark-your-postgresql-database/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-09-22-how-to-benchmark-your-postgresql-database/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for PostgreSQL will focus on How to Benchmark Your PostgreSQL Database. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/RYHPWjzZF2Q
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Hello, folks, let me bring Charly again, and hopefully, we can hear him unfortunately, it was fighting this data for a little bit.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Designing a Schema - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Sept, 8th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-09-08-postgresql-designing-a-schema/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-09-08-postgresql-designing-a-schema/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for PostgreSQL focused on Designing a Schema. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/3-hntRj6J4I
Transcript Dave Stokes: Good morning, good evening. Good everything to everybody. I&amp;rsquo;m Dave Stokes. I&amp;rsquo;m a Technology Evangelist at Percona. And with me is Charly Batista, one of our gurus on Postgres. And today, we&amp;rsquo;re talking about designing a schema.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Designing a Schema - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Sept 2nd</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-09-02-designing-a-schema/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-09-02-designing-a-schema/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for MySQL will focus on Designing a Schema. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/PEa3cBKwAI4
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Good Morning, good evening, good afternoon, good whatever it is, wherever you are. I&amp;rsquo;m Dave Stokes from Percona and with me is Marcos Albe.</description></item><item><title>Exploring the scalability limits of PostgreSQL on Kubernetes - Percona Community Live Stream August 25th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-08-25-exploring-the-scalability-limits-of-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-08-25-exploring-the-scalability-limits-of-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Join us at Percona Community Live Stream, and we will explore the scalability limits of PostgreSQL on Kubernetes with Dave Stokes and Charly Batista. Come up with all your questions and get an answer right away.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/Ij5TLLv6xuo
Transcript Dave Stokes
It should be starting up. Let me see if it started on Twitch. There we go. Okay, folks, originally, we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to talk about the scalability and limits of Postgres on Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Installing and Setting Up MySQL on Kubernetes - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - August 19th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-08-19-installing-and-setting-up-mysql-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-08-19-installing-and-setting-up-mysql-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Start running MySQL on Kubernetes with the lead of Percona Experts. Dave and Marcos were at the Community Live stream to share some tips and tricks.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/VflG2XicCCE
TRANSCRIPT Marcos Albe:
Good morning, Dave. Good morning.
Dave Stokes: So today we&amp;rsquo;re talking about installing and setting up MySQL on Kubernetes. And yes, I am fumbling around the basics of Kubernetes. And you&amp;rsquo;re going to enlighten us and make us all experts.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL running on Kubernetes operations - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Aug, 11th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-08-11-postgresql-running-on-kubernetes-operations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-08-11-postgresql-running-on-kubernetes-operations/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream will share a demo and some best practices on running Postgres on Kubernetes Operations. This is a part of a bi-weekly regular meetup to share experience and improve database opensource skills with Dave and Charly. Come up and ask questions.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/rQJTgm3O5WQ
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Good morning, good afternoon. Good evening. Good wherever you are. I&amp;rsquo;m Dave Stokes. And with me today is Charly Batista.</description></item><item><title>Migrating MySQL to a New Server - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - August 5th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-08-05-migrating-mysql-to-a-new-server/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-08-05-migrating-mysql-to-a-new-server/</guid><description>Our experts run a demo and took us through all steps to migrate MySQL database to a new server. Get more tips to improve your database skill with Dave Stokes and Marcos Albe.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/QQJMGONBwWw
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Amazing right that&amp;rsquo;s so cool. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Good morning, good afternoon. Good evening, depending where you are. I&amp;rsquo;m Dave Stokes. I&amp;rsquo;m a Technology Evangelist with Percona. And I have Marcos Albe with me.</description></item><item><title>Installing and Setting Up PostgreSQL on Kubernetes - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - July, 28th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-07-28-installing-and-setting-up-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-07-28-installing-and-setting-up-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Learn more about Installing and Setting Up PostgreSQL on Kubernetes with experts. This is a part of Percona Community&amp;rsquo;s bi-weekly Live Stream. Dave and Charly shared their experience with a demo session.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/vO5pHTRONJQ
Transcript Dave Stokes well, I&amp;rsquo;m going to drop off quickly and get handed over to the Postgres person the week last week, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get him online, that thing, and I will drop him off.</description></item><item><title>Installing and Setting Up PostgreSQL on Kubernetes - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-07-14-installing-and-setting-up-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-07-14-installing-and-setting-up-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Hello,
Thank you for your visit! This event is postponed Follow us on Twitter and get informed of the new date Thank You
Percona Community Team
![Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp;amp; Chat - July 14th](events/streams-pg/pg-stream-cover-week-10-july-14.jpg) Learn more about Installing and Setting Up PostgreSQL on Kubernetes with experts. This is a part of Percona Community&amp;#39;s bi-weekly Live Stream. Dave and Charly will share their experience and run a demo session. Come up with all your questions and get an answer right away.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Failover via a Replica for MySQL - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - July 8th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-07-08-setting-up-failover-via-a-replica-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-07-08-setting-up-failover-via-a-replica-for-mysql/</guid><description>This Community Live Stream is talking about Failover and Replica for MySQL. Our experts Dave Stokes and Marcos Albe took us through the setting to make it easier.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/c5tj-0THNLI
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Oh, one. And there we are.
Marcos Albe:
Hey there. Hello, Mr. Stokes.
Dave Stokes:
Hello, Mr. Albe. Good evening, good morning, good afternoon, good, whatever, wherever you are. This is, a live stream on setting up failover via a replica for MySQL, I see we&amp;rsquo;re live on Twitch, not sure what&amp;rsquo;s going with YouTube, but we&amp;rsquo;re gonna go as we are, and we&amp;rsquo;ll post the recording later.</description></item><item><title>Migrating PostgreSQL to a New Server - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - June, 30th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-30-migrating-postgresql-to-a-new-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-30-migrating-postgresql-to-a-new-server/</guid><description>Listen out to this Percona Community Live Stream if you ever had a problem migrating PostgreSQL to a New server. Charly and Dave, gave some tips to take you through the process without any problems.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/ML_wWD-KCcM
Transcript Dave Stokes
Good morning good afternoon, good evening, good whatever you are, welcome back to Another dream for the ricotta community live stream. I am Dave Stokes; I am in Texas.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up and Using Patroni to Automate Failover in PostgreSQL - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-16-setting-up-and-using-patroni-to-automate-failover-in-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-16-setting-up-and-using-patroni-to-automate-failover-in-postgresql/</guid><description>This is a part of bi-weekly Percona Community Live Stream. Our experts, Charly and Matt has talked about setting up and using Patroni to automate failover in Postgres.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/dkp-3S3l8tY
Transcript Charly Batista
And my frozen looks like you
Matt Yonkovit
You are frozen though I don&amp;rsquo;t know why Charly&amp;rsquo;s frozen he just we just went live and Charly is frozen so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what that means for us hopefully nothing is Too bad, right?</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Backups and Scheduling Regular MySQL Backups - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - June 10th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-06-10-setting-up-backups-and-scheduling-regular-mysql-backups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-06-10-setting-up-backups-and-scheduling-regular-mysql-backups/</guid><description>Learn more about Backup best practices to ensure the availability of your database. This is a part of the bi-weekly live-streamed meetup dedicated to MySQL.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/6Ai149MDjFo
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Yes, Miss Foreign minister that was singled out scintillating conversation ever had because I forgot to hit the wrong button for those who are expecting Matt Yonkovit, but he&amp;rsquo;s on his way to the Southeast Linux Fest today.</description></item><item><title>Setting up failover via a replica for PostgreSQL - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - June, 3rd</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-03-setting-up-failover-via-a-replica-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-03-setting-up-failover-via-a-replica-for-postgresql/</guid><description>This is part of our bi-weekly Percona Community Live Stream. Our experts, Charly and Matt talk more about database failure and setting up a failover on PostgreSQL.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/DhLg4tMvHuI
Transcript Matt Yonkovit
Hello Hello everyone how are you doing today? Welcome to another exciting episode of Percona&amp;rsquo;s bi-weekly Postgres live stream. I am Matt Yonkovit, the head of open source strategy here at Percona. With Charly, our esteemed Postgres Tech Lead, Charly, how are you today?</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for MySQL - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - May, 27th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-05-27-setting-up-alerts-and-basic-automation-for-mysql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-05-27-setting-up-alerts-and-basic-automation-for-mysql/</guid><description>Percona Community live stream for MySQL is back. Matt Yonkovit and Marcos Albe talked about Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for MySQL during the session of May 27th. Check full recording and transcript! Follow us on Twitter and stay tuned to all upcoming Percona events.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/0fhiioT0Tbg
Transcript Matt Yonkovit: Hello, everybody. We had a little bit of a delay there. We&amp;rsquo;ve been fighting with some new equipment because guess what happened?</description></item><item><title>Setting Up and Installing Backups With pgBackRest - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - May, 6th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-05-06-setting-up-and-installing-backups-with-pgbackrest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-05-06-setting-up-and-installing-backups-with-pgbackrest/</guid><description>Listen out to this full recording of the live stream dedicated to PostgreSQL hosted by the Head Of Open Source Strategy at Percona, Matt Yonkovit, with Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona. They took us through the setting up and installing backups with pgBackRest This is a part of the bi-weekly Live Streaming series to discuss Postgres-related topics and go deep into technology secrets and tricks.</description></item><item><title>Observing &amp; Tuning Your MySQL Workload Using PMM - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - April, 29th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-15-observing-tuning-your-mysql-workload-using-pmm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-15-observing-tuning-your-mysql-workload-using-pmm/</guid><description>Percona Community live stream for MySQL is a biweekly events with Matt Yonkovit and Marcos Albe. This is the recording for the session of April, 29th. We have talked about Observing &amp;amp; Tuning Your MySQL Workload Using PMM (Percona Monitoring and Management). Follow us on Twitter and stay tuned to all upcoming Percona events.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/4ccEZZtjqWg
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
We&amp;rsquo;re live and you&amp;rsquo;re singing… Marcos was here, you know, singing the song of folks on the PT stock song.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up and Scheduling Regular PostgreSQL Backups (Part 2) - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - April, 21st</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-21-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-21-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups-2/</guid><description>Join the next Community Live stream for PostgresSQL and learn about the best setting to protect and restore your data. This is the second part of the previous stream. Matt and Charly will continue to talk about database backup settings, frequency, and different types of backups. Come up with your questions and our experts will answer them live.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/7ZdQ4xjX464
TRANSCRIPT Matt Yonkovit: Hello, everyone, welcome to another Live Stream.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up and Scheduling Regular PostgreSQL Backups - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream - April, 8th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-08-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-08-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups/</guid><description>Learn about the best setting to protect and restore your data with Matt and Charly. They are talking about database backup settings, frequency, and different types of backups. Follow us on Twitter and get informed of all upcoming meetups
Listen to the recording here Link: https://youtu.be/3OeX-gsdwFc
Transcript Matt Yonkovit
Hello everyone out in live stream land. I am, Matt. And do you know who is not here? Charlie? I am in Jose.</description></item><item><title>Installing MySQL and Setting Up a Default Configuration - Percona Community MySQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - April, 1st</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-01-install-mysql-setting-up-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-mysql/2022-04-01-install-mysql-setting-up-configuration/</guid><description>Watch out this recording from Percona Community live stream of April 1st. Learn how to install MySQL and Setting Up a Default Configuration with Matt Yonkovit and Marcos Albe. This is a series of live stream to discuss MySQL tricks with experts.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/AMGNklpAjJ8
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
We might even be live right now. Marcos, we might be live oh we are live oh we see now we&amp;rsquo;re live there we popped in.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for PostgreSQL - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - March 25th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-25-setting-up-alert-and-basic-automation-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-25-setting-up-alert-and-basic-automation-for-postgresql/</guid><description>Percona Community organized live stream to talk more about Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for PostgreSQL. This recording is from the live event of March 25th with Matt Yonkovit, Charly Batista and Agustin Gallego. This is a part of the Percona Community bi-weekly Live Stream series to discuss Postgres-related topics and deep talks with technology secrets.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/f1NklbrVvYY
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hello, hello, everyone, Welcome to another Friday edition of the Postgres Percona database meetup.</description></item><item><title>Observing &amp; Tuning Your PostgreSQL Workload Using PMM - Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - March 11th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-11-observing-and-tuning-your-postgresql-workload-using-pmm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-11-observing-and-tuning-your-postgresql-workload-using-pmm/</guid><description>Organize and access easily to your database data by observing and tuning your PostgreSQL workload using PMM. Our experts Matt Yonkovit and Charly Batista present use cases in a bi-weekly live stream about Postgres-related topics.
Video Part 01 Link: https://youtu.be/H2uNDbQ8lCk
Video Part 02 Link: https://youtu.be/SxQyC2RdBCg
Transcript Part 01 Matt Yonkovit:
Here we go! We&amp;rsquo;re live! Hello everyone! Welcome to a specially exciting Friday live stream. Hopefully everyone is getting to the weekend.</description></item><item><title>Installing PG and Setting Up a Default Configuration - Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Jan 27th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-01-27-installing-pg-and-setting-up-default-configuration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-01-27-installing-pg-and-setting-up-default-configuration/</guid><description>Listen out to this full recording of the 1st Live Stream dedicated to PostgreSQL hosted by The Head Of Open Source Strategy at Percona, Matt Yonkovit with Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona. They took us through the installation of Postgres and the setting up of the default configuration. This is a part of the bi-weekly Live Streaming series to discuss Postgres-related topics and go deep into technology secrets and tricks.</description></item><item><title>Common Possible Preventative Measures to Avoid Locking Issue in PostgreSQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-naveed-shaikh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-naveed-shaikh/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss about the preventive measures to avoid the locking issue in PostgreSQL. Here are the main thumb rules, golden rules for processing police
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/opdZbJ3X_y8
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Database Reliability Engineering for MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-matthias-crauwels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-matthias-crauwels/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
A common request that we get from our clients is to make MySQL highly available or to enhance existing architecture. We have standardized our approach by combining a proxy layer, for traffic redirection, a topology management tool, for master failover/switchover, and some additional tools to glue together both layers.</description></item><item><title>Let's Talk About MySQL Query Tuning</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-gabriel-ciciliani/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-gabriel-ciciliani/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Regardless of development frameworks, despite linters, besides countless sessions with the DBA, slow queries always end up making it to production. Proactive and reactive slow query tuning is still critical to ensure poorly written queries aren&amp;rsquo;t undermining server performance and wasting valuable compute resources. Cloud-based database managed services are not the exception: slow query root cause analysis requires human intervention.</description></item><item><title>Optimization Techniques in MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-yunus-shaikh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-yunus-shaikh/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Optimization of mysql with indexing, server tuning and OS tuning to make performance better
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/oFTFch9_wSM
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Overview of Different ALTER Algorithms and Its Locking Scenarios in MySQL (DEMO)</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sri-sakthivel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sri-sakthivel/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
I would like to show the demo session on describing the different MySQL ALTER Algorithms ( COPY / INPLACE / INSTANT ) and how they are performing with different locking methods ( Exclusive / Shared / None ).
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/MqWQH-WWFBE
Transcript</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL and Artificial intelligence</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-ibrar-ahmed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-ibrar-ahmed/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Artificial intelligence, machine learning, and deep learning are intertwined capabilities that attempt to solve problems that defy traditional computational solutions &amp;mdash; problems including fraud detection, voice recognition, and search result recommendations. While they elude simple computation, they are computationally expensive, involving the calculation of perhaps millions of probabilities and weights.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Replication Conflicts: Avoiding Pitfalls</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-hamid-akhtar2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-3-hamid-akhtar2/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Experiencing replication conflicts is not too unfamiliar a sight. Whether one experiences replication lag, slots, locks, snapshots, tablespace issues, or other conflicts, establishing a set of best practices along with using proper observability tools will help avoid potential issues. This talk focuses on what to do and what not to in order to avoid database conflicts in streaming replication setups by providing deep insight into how issues are PostgreSQL internals.</description></item><item><title>Production with ProxySQL and Orchestrator</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-alawi-assaggaf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-alawi-assaggaf/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Covering 3 use case scenarios to implement HA utilizing ProxySQL, Orchestrator and Load Balancers in production environments.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/6Cz-ZZodSXM
Transcript</description></item><item><title>The Future of MyDumper</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-david-ducos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-david-ducos/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
MyDumper has changed a lot in the last year. We are going to high-level review the features added, new use cases and enhancements that are going to be added in future release and how they are going to impact in performance.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/JnPuIdLh16U
Transcript</description></item><item><title>The Journey to Achieve 1000x TPS for a Real-World Core Banking Application on TiDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sidney-chen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sidney-chen/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Performance tuning is complicated, especially with a distributed database like TiDB. It becomes even more challenging when the whole system is running on arm64-based servers.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/jSrK0x1MmYk
Transcript</description></item><item><title>The Low Hanging Fruits of MySQL</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-kedar-vaijanapurkar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-kedar-vaijanapurkar/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
MySQL is one of the top used database system and with highly active community. Though without proper configuration you may not squeeze the most out of it.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/y8-ecVLcaaY
Transcript</description></item><item><title>Using PMM Alerting in Production</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-francisco-bordenave/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-francisco-bordenave/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Now that you&amp;rsquo;re using PMM to identify slow queries and chart your database activity, what PMM can do for you to avoid problems? PMM is getting more and more popular for monitoring databases while features are increasing and allowing us to do more with less effort. In this talk we will show you how PMM can help you on your day to day operational tasks to prevent issues by setting up alerts.</description></item><item><title>Walking Through Identifying and Drilling Into a Slow Down in MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-divyanshu-soni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-divyanshu-soni/</guid><description>This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Divyanshu Soni, MongoDB DBA II in Managed Services at Percona, is talking about walking through identifying and drilling into a slowdown in MongoDB. Dive into the different reasons behind that and how you can overcome all issues that you might face in your database. This video is going through the best practices:</description></item></channel></rss>