<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Promo on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/promo/</link><description>Recent content in Promo on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/promo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona University Istanbul 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2024/</guid><description>Percona University is an ongoing series of community-driven database meetups, bringing together open-source enthusiasts from around the world. On September 7th, we landed in Istanbul, the vibrant cultural and economic hub of Türkiye, for a day of learning, networking, and meaningful connections.
The day began with clear skies and high energy as we gathered early on Istanbul&amp;rsquo;s Asian side, at a co-working space.
The event kicked off at 9:30 with coffee, networking, and a chance to register, followed by the opening talk by Percona’s founder, Peter Zaitsev.</description></item><item><title>preFOSDEM MySQL Days 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/prefosdem-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/prefosdem-2023/</guid><description>Two days before the main FOSDEM event, MySQL enthusiasts all over the world gather together for learning and networking at preFOSDEM MySQL Days in Brussels. This time the event took place at the same building where it was interrupted by COVID - ICAB Incubator. The event was free but required registration due to limited capacity. A couple of weeks before the event, all available tickets were sold out.
The room was almost full.</description></item></channel></rss>