<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pg_jan on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/pg_jan/</link><description>Recent content in pg_jan on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/pg_jan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Progress report on pg_tde - GA extension is nearer every day!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/05/08/progress-report-on-pg_tde-ga-extension-is-nearer-every-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/05/08/progress-report-on-pg_tde-ga-extension-is-nearer-every-day/</guid><description>Another week, another blogpost about the state of open source Transparent Data Encryption (TDE) for PostgreSQL.
First off, thank you for all the feedback shared so far!
Whether it&amp;rsquo;s reports about deployment issues with pg_tde, integration with KMS, missing features or gaps in our documentation, we truly appreciate it! Your input helps us build a better, more complete solution and to properly prioritize what&amp;rsquo;s next.
What’s the word? We know many of you are eagerly waiting for a production-ready release of pg_tde, and today we’ve got some good news!</description></item><item><title>Learn PostgreSQL and SQL Quickly and Free</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/20/learn-postgresql-and-sql-quickly-and-free/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/20/learn-postgresql-and-sql-quickly-and-free/</guid><description>Learn PostgreSQL and SQL Quickly and Free
Want to learn PostgreSQL? What if you could learn PostgreSQL without having to install the database, load data, find sample data, and it was free? PGExamples.com is what you are looking for.
First, let me state that I have no connection to the website or its author. I discovered PgExercises.com by accident and was impressed by its quality and completeness. I am so impressed that I am exploring a video series on it.</description></item></channel></rss>