<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/categories/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/categories/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Bug Report: April 2025</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/05/19/percona-bug-report-april-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/05/19/percona-bug-report-april-2025/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Percona Operator for MongoDB 1.19: Remote Backups, Auto-Generated Passwords, and More!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/31/percona-operator-for-mongodb-1.19-remote-backups-auto-generated-passwords-and-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2025/01/31/percona-operator-for-mongodb-1.19-remote-backups-auto-generated-passwords-and-more/</guid><description>The latest release of the Percona Operator for MongoDB, version 1.19, is here. It brings a suite of enhancements designed to streamline your MongoDB deployments on Kubernetes. This release introduces a technical preview of remote file server backups, simplifies user management with auto-generated passwords, supports Percona Server for MongoDB 8.0, and includes numerous other improvements and bug fixes. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the details of what 1.19 has to offer.
Remote Backups with Network File System (Technical Preview) Backing up your MongoDB data is crucial, and Percona Operator for MongoDB 1.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: October 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/11/25/percona-bug-report-october-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Timeline for Database on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>The Evolution Since its inception in June 2014, Kubernetes has dramatically transformed container orchestration, revolutionizing the management and scaling of applications. To mark its tenth anniversary, the Data on Kubernetes Community (DoKC) released an infographic showcasing key milestones and community contributions to the evolution of operators for managing stateful applications. This project was made possible by the collaboration of DoKC members Edith Puclla, Sergey Pronin, Robert Hodges, Gabriele Bartolini, Chris Malarky, Mark Kember, Paul Au, and Luciano Stabel.</description></item><item><title>Let's take a look at Percona Everest 1.0.0 RC</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/14/lets-take-a-look-at-percona-everest-1.0.0-rc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/14/lets-take-a-look-at-percona-everest-1.0.0-rc/</guid><description>Hi, the Percona Everest 1.0.0-rc1 release was published on GitHub.
Percona Everest is the first open source cloud-native platform for provisioning and managing PostgreSQL, MongoDB and MySQL database clusters.
I want to tell you how to install it so you can try it out.
RC builds aren&amp;rsquo;t meant for the general public; we don&amp;rsquo;t support upgrading from RC to stable versions. This means that this is only for testing and familiarizing yourself with the features.</description></item><item><title>How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes with Percona Everest Summary</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</guid><description>Kubernetes continues evolving, and the complexity of deploying and managing databases within the ecosystem is a topic of considerable discussion and importance these days. This article summarizes a detailed discussion between Piotr Szczepaniak and Diogo Recharte, who offer insights and live demonstrations to simplify database operations on Kubernetes with a new technology for cloud-native applications: Percona Everest. If you want to watch the full video, check out How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes Webinar.</description></item><item><title>Percona Bug Report: April 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/29/percona-bug-report-april-2024/</guid><description>At Percona, we operate on the premise that full transparency makes a product better. We strive to build the best open-source database products, but also to help you manage any issues that arise in any of the databases that we support. And, in true open-source form, report back on any issues or bugs you might encounter along the way.
We constantly update our bug reports and monitor other boards to ensure we have the latest information, but we wanted to make it a little easier for you to keep track of the most critical ones.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Percona Everest on GCP with Kubectl for Windows 11 Users</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/19/deploying-percona-everest-on-gcp-with-kubectl-for-windows-11-users/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/19/deploying-percona-everest-on-gcp-with-kubectl-for-windows-11-users/</guid><description>Welcome to this blog post! Today, our primary goal is to guide you through deploying Percona Everest on GCP using Kubectl, specifically for users on Windows 11. It&amp;rsquo;s been some time since I last used Windows, so this will be an excellent opportunity to do it from scratch.
Let me tell you a little bit about Percona Everest. You may have already heard it recently. It is the new open source tool launched by Percona and is already well-received by Kubernetes database users.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Standby Cluster With the Percona Operator for PostgreSQL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/27/creating-a-standby-cluster-with-the-percona-operator-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/27/creating-a-standby-cluster-with-the-percona-operator-for-postgresql/</guid><description>In this video, Nickolay Ihalainen, a Senior Scaling Specialist at Percona Global Services, explains how to set up replication with standby clusters for Kubernetes databases using Percona&amp;rsquo;s open-source tools, including the Percona Operator for PostgreSQL
A Standby Cluster is a backup version of your main database. It&amp;rsquo;s there to keep your data safe and make sure your database can keep running even if something goes wrong with the main one.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Your Environment for Kubernetes Operators Using Docker, kubectl, and k3d</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/04/setting-up-your-environment-for-kubernetes-operators-using-docker-kubectl-and-k3d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/03/04/setting-up-your-environment-for-kubernetes-operators-using-docker-kubectl-and-k3d/</guid><description>If you are just starting out in the world of Kubernetes operators, like me, preparing the environment for their installation should be something we do with not much difficulty. This blog will quickly guide you in setting the minimal environment.
Kubernetes operators are invaluable for automating complex database operations, tasks that Kubernetes does not handle directly. Operators make it easy for us – they take care of essential tasks like backups and restores, which are crucial in database management.</description></item><item><title>Our Top Picks from the Kubernetes 1.29 Release</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/12/our-top-picks-from-the-kubernetes-release/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/12/our-top-picks-from-the-kubernetes-release/</guid><description>The latest Kubernetes version, 1.29, was released on December 13th 2023. Inspired by the Mandala and symbolizing universal perfection, it concludes the 2023 release calendar. This version comes with various exciting improvements, many of which will be helpful for users who run databases on Kubernetes.
Figure 1 - Mandala created in Excalidraw, not perfectly symmetrical.
Here, we highlight this latest release&amp;rsquo;s four key features and improvements. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at them together.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Anti-Affinity in Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/30/anti-affinity-in-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/30/anti-affinity-in-kubernetes/</guid><description>Last week, I embarked on the task of deploying our Percona Operator for MongoDB in Kubernetes. After completing the deployment process, I noticed that the status of the Custom Resource Definition for Percona Server for MongoDB was still displaying as &amp;lsquo;initializing&amp;rsquo; and two of our Pods remained in a Pending state.
edithpuclla@Ediths-MBP % kubectl get perconaservermongodbs.psmdb.percona.com -n mongodb NAME ENDPOINT STATUS AGE my-db-psmdb-db my-db-psmdb-db-mongos.mongodb.svc.cluster.local initializing 4m58s edithpuclla@Ediths-MBP % kubectl get pods -n mongodb NAME READY STATUS RESTARTS AGE my-db-psmdb-db-cfg-0 2/2 Running 0 109m my-db-psmdb-db-cfg-1 2/2 Running 0 108m my-db-psmdb-db-cfg-2 0/2 Pending 0 107m my-db-psmdb-db-mongos-0 1/1 Running 0 106m my-db-psmdb-db-mongos-1 1/1 Running 0 106m my-db-psmdb-db-rs0-0 2/2 Running 0 109m my-db-psmdb-db-rs0-1 2/2 Running 0 108m my-db-psmdb-db-rs0-2 0/2 Pending 0 107m my-op-psmdb-operator-77b75bbc7c-qd9ls 1/1 Running 0 118m Upon further inspection of the pod in pending status, I discovered a clear indicator of the error:</description></item><item><title>Day 02: The Kubernetes Application Lifecycle</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/20/day-02-the-kubernetes-application-lifecycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/20/day-02-the-kubernetes-application-lifecycle/</guid><description>If you are in the world of application development, you know that every application has a lifecycle. An application lifecycle refers to the stages that our application goes through from initial planning, building, deployment, monitoring, and maintenance in different environments where our application can be executed.
On the other hand, the Kubernetes Application Lifecycle refers exclusively to applications deployed and managed in Kubernetes clusters. This differs from the normal application lifecycle because Kubernetes introduces new principles, practices, and tools for managing applications on containers.</description></item><item><title>Data On Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/10/data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/10/data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve attended one of the Kubecon talks or related events, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely encountered the phrase Data on Kubernetes. To understand what this means, let&amp;rsquo;s explore some fundamental concepts related to Kubernetes, workload, stateless, and stateful applications.
Kubernetes, workload, stateless and stateful applications Kubernetes is a container orchestration tool that has already become an industry standard. When we talk about &amp;ldquo;container orchestration&amp;rdquo;, we are referring to the automated management and coordination of containers using Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Kubernetes Operators</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/03/kubernetes-operators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/03/kubernetes-operators/</guid><description>The concept of Kubernetes Operators was introduced around 2016 by the CoreOS Linuxdevelopment team. They were in search of a solution to improve automated container management within Kubernetes, primarily with the goal of incorporating operational expertise directly into the software.
According to the Cloud Native Computing Foundation, “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components”.
Kubernetes is designed for automation, offering essential automation features. It can automatically deploy and manage workloads.</description></item><item><title>Building and Running Percona Everest From Source Code</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/10/30/building-and-running-percona-everest-from-source-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/10/30/building-and-running-percona-everest-from-source-code/</guid><description>Digging deeper into the architecture of an open source product
Recently, Percona team announced the public alpha version of a new open source product – Percona Everest. It allows you to create database clusters on Kubernetes cluster.
I have installed Percona Everest several times and tried its features. Standard installation is very simple and takes a few minutes.
But, to understand the product deeper, I came up with the idea to explore repositories, build and run Percona Everest from source.</description></item><item><title>DoKC Operator SIG Update</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/14/dokc-operator-sig-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/14/dokc-operator-sig-update/</guid><description>Before our meeting, we started with a question to begin the morning: What board game or tabletop game have you played that you would recommend to others?
Itamar Marom suggests that Catan as a good board game, which takes a lot of time, super annoying when you lose, but generally a lot of fun. So highly suggested!
Other members like Hugh Lashbrooke and Robert Hodges prefer Monopoly, where you must reach a higher level of monopoly awareness to enjoy it fully.</description></item><item><title>Data on Kubernetes Meetup May 23</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Percona has started to participate in Data on Kubernetes (DoK) meetings about Kubernetes Operators. These meetings are an initiative of DoK meetups that spotlight DoK case studies. In this blog post series, I will summarize the topics covered in each meeting.
On May 23, very interesting topics were discussed on the agenda. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin to summarize it.
We start with a new project proposal, which is called: Distributed Systems Operator Interface (DSOI).</description></item><item><title>​What experts said at Kubecon about Data on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Melissa Logan, managing director of Data on Kubernetes (DoK), led one of the best panels I’ve been to at a conference at Kubecon EU in Amsterdam about challenges with and the state of the art of running databases on Kubernetes.
This panel united the Data on Kubernetes Community Operator SIG and Kubernetes Storage SIG to discuss key features of Kubernetes database operators. Xing Yang from VMware, Sergey Pronin from Percona, and Álvaro Hernández from OnGres came together to discuss what works, what doesn’t, and where the industry is going.</description></item><item><title>​My Experience at Kubecon Europe in Amsterdam</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/11/experience-at-kubecon-europe-in-amsterdam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/11/experience-at-kubecon-europe-in-amsterdam/</guid><description>Kubecon is the most significant event focused on the Kubernetes ecosystem. It takes place once a year in North America, Europe, and Asia. It is a perfect opportunity to learn from experts, meet friends, grow your network, and attend talks at a varied technical level and meetings focused on CNCF communities. This time I attended Kubecon in Amsterdam. The theme for this version of Kubecon was: community-in-bloom because we are still healing from COVID, and people are getting back to feeling comfortable participating in events.</description></item><item><title>Nurturing, Motivating and Recognizing Non-Code Contributions</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/08/nurturing-motivating-and-recognizing-non-code-contributions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/08/nurturing-motivating-and-recognizing-non-code-contributions/</guid><description>When discussing contributions, we still see a lot of emphasis on the code contributions into project repositories. But the open source world is extensive and diverse, and everyone can find their place there. Your project will benefit from various experiences that non-coders can bring to the table. Isn’t that cool when you receive an issue with an interesting bug from the community, read about a user case in a blog or a review, or someone makes a video guide for your product?</description></item><item><title>Node metrics available inside of a container</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/06/node-metrics-container/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/02/06/node-metrics-container/</guid><description>Several people asked me this question: Could we get Node metrics inside of a container?
Usually, this comes from the fact that PMM or standalone people run node_exporter inside a container. PMM does it as a sidecar along with many other exporters to monitor DBs, and node_exporter comes out of the box as a default one. So people could see accurate data on dashboards, like Memory and CPU, that node_exporter reads inside the container.</description></item><item><title>Binding your application to the database in the Kubernetes cluster</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</guid><description>dbaas-operator is Yet Another DBaaS Kubernetes Operator (need to suggest yadbko as a name) that tries to simplify and unify Database Cluster deployments by building a higher abstraction layer on top of Percona Kubernetes Operators.
So it becomes much easier to deploy the DB cluster with dbaas-operator and PMM DBaaS on top of it.
But another part of the picture is applications and their workloads to connect to the deployed DB Clusters.</description></item><item><title>How to Automate Minor Version Upgrades for MySQL on RDS</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/07/10/automate-minor-version-upgrades-mysql-rds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:19:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/07/10/automate-minor-version-upgrades-mysql-rds/</guid><description>Amazon RDS for MySQL offers the option to automate minor version upgrades using the minor version upgrade policy, a property that lets you decide if Amazon is allowed to perform the upgrades on your behalf. Usually the goal is not to upgrade automatically every RDS instance but to keep up to date automatically non-production deployments. This helps you address engine issues as soon as possible and improve the automation of the deployment process.</description></item><item><title>Enabling KMS encryption for a running Amazon RDS instance</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/08/enabling-kms-encryption-running-amazon-rds-instance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 11:40:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/08/enabling-kms-encryption-running-amazon-rds-instance/</guid><description>Since summer 2017, Amazon RDS supports encryption at rest using AWS Key Management Service (KMS) for db.t2.small and db.t2.medium database instances, making the feature now available to virtually every instance class and type.
Unless you are running Previous Generation DB Instances or you can only afford to run a db.t2.micro, every other instance class now supports native encryption at rest using KMS. As for the Amazon documentation:
Encryption on smaller T2 database instances is useful for development and test use cases, where you want the environment to have identical security characteristics as the planned production environment.</description></item></channel></rss>