<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TiDB on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/tidb/</link><description>Recent content in TiDB on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 13:41:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/tidb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TiSpark: More Data Insights, No More ETL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/18/tispark-data-insights-no-etl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 13:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/18/tispark-data-insights-no-etl/</guid><description>When we released TiDB 2.0 in April, part of that announcement also included the release of TiSpark 1.0&amp;ndash;an integral part of the TiDB platform that makes complex analytics on “fresh” transactional data possible. Since then, many people in the TiDB community have been asking for more information about TiSpark. In this post, I will explain the motivation, inner workings, and future roadmap of this project.
Motivation The motivation behind building TiSpark was to enable real-time analytics on TiDB without the delay and challenges of ETL.</description></item><item><title>The Journey to Achieve 1000x TPS for a Real-World Core Banking Application on TiDB</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sidney-chen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-2-sidney-chen/</guid><description> This session was presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Performance tuning is complicated, especially with a distributed database like TiDB. It becomes even more challenging when the whole system is running on arm64-based servers.
Watch Video Here Link: https://youtu.be/jSrK0x1MmYk
Transcript</description></item></channel></rss>