<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Exporter on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/exporter/</link><description>Recent content in Exporter on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/exporter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Going back to the original node_exporter in PMM</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/10/21/going-back-to-original-pmm-node-exporter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/10/21/going-back-to-original-pmm-node-exporter/</guid><description>Going back to the original node_exporter in PMM This is my first (I hope) post about something no so usual in our regular posts about technology. Usually we discuss new features, talk about how to do something but even for me, a Percona developer, sometimes it is hard to know where and what to touch in PMM. There are many components, many abstractions, parts that send messages to remote APIs or agents, the PMM agent, the PMM API (pmm-managed), the command line client (pmm-admin) and all the external exporters.</description></item><item><title>Create your own Exporter in Go!</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/21/create-your-own-exporter-in-go/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/07/21/create-your-own-exporter-in-go/</guid><description>Overview Hi, it’s too hot summer in Korea. Today I want to talk about an interesting and exciting topic. Try to making your own exporter in Go language.
If you register a specific query, it is a simple program that shows the result of this query as an exporter result metrics. Some of you may still be unfamiliar with what Expoter is.
I will explain about Exporter step by step in today’s post.</description></item><item><title>Exporters Roadmap</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/11/exporters-roadmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2021/06/11/exporters-roadmap/</guid><description>Exporters Roadmap Goals Prometheus exports as a part of PMM are a big and valuable component.
According to the goal to involve open source contributors to contribute to PMM and Percona to contribute to open source. As the main focus, it was decided to start from the exporter.
For now PMM use the next exporters:
https://github.com/percona/node_exporter https://github.com/percona/mysqld_exporter https://github.com/percona/mongodb_exporter https://github.com/percona/postgres_exporter https://github.com/Percona-Lab/clickhouse_exporter https://github.com/percona/proxysql_exporter https://github.com/percona/rds_exporter https://github.com/percona/azure_metrics_exporter Groups We can split them into three groups.</description></item></channel></rss>