<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>russia on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/russia/</link><description>Recent content in russia on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/russia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Balalaika Meetup With Local Community in Ulyanovsk</title><link>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/balalaika-meetup-ulyanovsk-2021/</guid><description>On November 15th, Percona organized a meetup with the local community in Ulyanovsk (Russia). From Percona, there were Peter Zaitsev (CEO), Maria Azizova (Staff Executive), and Aleksandra Abramova (Community Specialist). They had a chance to meet engineers from different IT companies who live nearby.
The event took place in an interesting location. It was a private Balalaika&amp;rsquo;s Museum. It is a Russian national musical instrument. If you wonder how it sounds like, there are some examples on YouTube like this one.</description></item><item><title>Merge Conf 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/mergeconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/mergeconf-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team members visited Merge Conf 2021 in Innopolis, Russia, on November 13-14.
Percona speakers gave 2 talks on the Open Source track.
Technologies and Trends in the World of Open Source Databases in 2021 by Peter Zaitsev (CEO, Percona). Peter talked about all the main open source databases and their versatility, considered specific solutions for different situations and provided information on the changes in open source licenses and what can be expected next year.</description></item></channel></rss>