<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona University Istanbul 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2024/</guid><description>Percona University is an ongoing series of community-driven database meetups, bringing together open-source enthusiasts from around the world. On September 7th, we landed in Istanbul, the vibrant cultural and economic hub of Türkiye, for a day of learning, networking, and meaningful connections.
The day began with clear skies and high energy as we gathered early on Istanbul&amp;rsquo;s Asian side, at a co-working space.
The event kicked off at 9:30 with coffee, networking, and a chance to register, followed by the opening talk by Percona’s founder, Peter Zaitsev.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Limassol 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-limassol-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-limassol-2024/</guid><description>On April 20th, 2024, people who love working with databases came together in Cyprus for something special - the Percona University Limassol. Percona put on this event to help folks dive deep into the latest database tech.
The meetup was all about sharing knowledge. Percona brought in international and local experts in a database space. These experts talked about the newest trends, best ways to manage databases, and cool new solutions.</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/fosdem-2023/</guid><description>FOSDEM is very special: people from all over the world come to Brussels to participate in the biggest open source event in Europe. How many people? FOSDEM attracts more than 5000 attendees to the ULB Solbosch campus.
Many open source projects have stands at the event that are provided to them free of charge by the organizers. It is a perfect opportunity not only to collect some swag with the logo of your favorite project, but also to chat with its representatives and maybe even core developers and ask your questions in person.</description></item><item><title>preFOSDEM MySQL Days 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/prefosdem-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/prefosdem-2023/</guid><description>Two days before the main FOSDEM event, MySQL enthusiasts all over the world gather together for learning and networking at preFOSDEM MySQL Days in Brussels. This time the event took place at the same building where it was interrupted by COVID - ICAB Incubator. The event was free but required registration due to limited capacity. A couple of weeks before the event, all available tickets were sold out.
The room was almost full.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Istanbul 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2022/</guid><description>Percona University is a series of database meetups that we organize worldwide in different locations. November 5th we came to Istanbul, economical, cultural and historical heart of Turkiye. HostedPMM and FerretDB supported us during this meetup and sponsored it.
It was a wonderful sunny day in Istanbul. We gathered together early in the morning at Kolektif House. It is an awesome coworking place with wonderful inhabitants and all the necessary equipment to hold an event.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-live-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-live-2022/</guid><description>Links Percona Live 2022 was an amazing 3-day event of keynotes, educational sessions, hands-on activities, and more. It took place in Austin, TX on May 16th-18th. Attendees could hear the biggest names in the industry, discuss their experience, dive deep into software, and offer actionable advice. They also learned about how open source database technology can power applications, improve websites, secure data, and solve critical database issues. On this page, you can find the list of presentations from Percona Live 2022.</description></item></channel></rss>