<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dok on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/dok/</link><description>Recent content in dok on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/dok/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Timeline for Database on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>The Evolution Since its inception in June 2014, Kubernetes has dramatically transformed container orchestration, revolutionizing the management and scaling of applications. To mark its tenth anniversary, the Data on Kubernetes Community (DoKC) released an infographic showcasing key milestones and community contributions to the evolution of operators for managing stateful applications. This project was made possible by the collaboration of DoKC members Edith Puclla, Sergey Pronin, Robert Hodges, Gabriele Bartolini, Chris Malarky, Mark Kember, Paul Au, and Luciano Stabel.</description></item><item><title>Data on Kubernetes Community initiatives: Automated storage scaling</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/data-on-kubernetes-community-initiatives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/data-on-kubernetes-community-initiatives/</guid><description>In the world of Kubernetes, where everything evolves quickly. Automated storage scaling stands out as a critical challenge. Members of the Data on Kubernetes Community have proposed a solution to address this issue for Kubernetes operators.
If, like me, this is your first time hearing about Automated storage scaling, this will help you understand it better:
Storage scaling in Kubernetes Operators refers to the ability of an application running on Kubernetes to adjust its storage capacity automatically based on demand.</description></item><item><title>Volunteering as a Program Committee Member for Data on Kubernetes Day Europe 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/volunteering-program-committee-data-kubernetes-europe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/volunteering-program-committee-data-kubernetes-europe/</guid><description>The Data on Kubernetes Day Europe 2024 Program Committee is a group of professionals and experts responsible for organizing the Data on Kubernetes Day Europe 2024 content for the upcoming co-located events at Kubecon in Paris on 19 March.
As Data on Kubernetes community members, Sergey Pronin (Group Product Manager at @Percona) and I (Tech Evangelist) volunteered to evaluate proposal topics submitted for the event through the Sessionize platform. Not only us but also many other members of the Data on Kubernetes community participated as volunteers.</description></item><item><title>Data On Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/10/data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/10/data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve attended one of the Kubecon talks or related events, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely encountered the phrase Data on Kubernetes. To understand what this means, let&amp;rsquo;s explore some fundamental concepts related to Kubernetes, workload, stateless, and stateful applications.
Kubernetes, workload, stateless and stateful applications Kubernetes is a container orchestration tool that has already become an industry standard. When we talk about &amp;ldquo;container orchestration&amp;rdquo;, we are referring to the automated management and coordination of containers using Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>DoKC Operator SIG Update</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/14/dokc-operator-sig-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/14/dokc-operator-sig-update/</guid><description>Before our meeting, we started with a question to begin the morning: What board game or tabletop game have you played that you would recommend to others?
Itamar Marom suggests that Catan as a good board game, which takes a lot of time, super annoying when you lose, but generally a lot of fun. So highly suggested!
Other members like Hugh Lashbrooke and Robert Hodges prefer Monopoly, where you must reach a higher level of monopoly awareness to enjoy it fully.</description></item><item><title>Data on Kubernetes Meetup May 23</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Percona has started to participate in Data on Kubernetes (DoK) meetings about Kubernetes Operators. These meetings are an initiative of DoK meetups that spotlight DoK case studies. In this blog post series, I will summarize the topics covered in each meeting.
On May 23, very interesting topics were discussed on the agenda. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin to summarize it.
We start with a new project proposal, which is called: Distributed Systems Operator Interface (DSOI).</description></item><item><title>​What experts said at Kubecon about Data on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Melissa Logan, managing director of Data on Kubernetes (DoK), led one of the best panels I’ve been to at a conference at Kubecon EU in Amsterdam about challenges with and the state of the art of running databases on Kubernetes.
This panel united the Data on Kubernetes Community Operator SIG and Kubernetes Storage SIG to discuss key features of Kubernetes database operators. Xing Yang from VMware, Sergey Pronin from Percona, and Álvaro Hernández from OnGres came together to discuss what works, what doesn’t, and where the industry is going.</description></item></channel></rss>