<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/</link><description>Recent content in Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting Up a PostgreSQL Connection Pool - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Oct, 20th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-10-20-setting-up-postgresql-connection-pool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-10-20-setting-up-postgresql-connection-pool/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for PostgreSQL focused on setting up a PostgreSQL connection pool. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/fZ84jx6kvpU
TRANSCRIPT Follow us on Twitter and get informed of all upcoming meetups.
Live chat with Percona community is always available on Discord.</description></item><item><title>How to Secure PostgreSQL - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Oct, 6th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-10-06-how-to-secure-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-10-06-how-to-secure-postgresql/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for PostgreSQL will focus on How to Secure PostgreSQL. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/ZBD3HaoBTPs
TRANSCRIPT Dave Stokes: Welcome back. This is Percona, this little biweekly Postgres talk. We&amp;rsquo;re part of this Percona Community Postgres live stream. Now the official title, my name is Dave Stokes, I&amp;rsquo;m a Technology Evangelist, and with me is Charly Batista.</description></item><item><title>How to Benchmark Your PostgreSQL Database - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Sept, 22nd</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-09-22-how-to-benchmark-your-postgresql-database/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-09-22-how-to-benchmark-your-postgresql-database/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for PostgreSQL will focus on How to Benchmark Your PostgreSQL Database. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills. Come up with your questions and get an answer straight forward to all your questions.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/RYHPWjzZF2Q
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Hello, folks, let me bring Charly again, and hopefully, we can hear him unfortunately, it was fighting this data for a little bit.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL Designing a Schema - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Sept, 8th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-09-08-postgresql-designing-a-schema/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-09-08-postgresql-designing-a-schema/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream for PostgreSQL focused on Designing a Schema. This is a part of our bi-weekly meetup to develop open-source database skills.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/3-hntRj6J4I
Transcript Dave Stokes: Good morning, good evening. Good everything to everybody. I&amp;rsquo;m Dave Stokes. I&amp;rsquo;m a Technology Evangelist at Percona. And with me is Charly Batista, one of our gurus on Postgres. And today, we&amp;rsquo;re talking about designing a schema.</description></item><item><title>Exploring the scalability limits of PostgreSQL on Kubernetes - Percona Community Live Stream August 25th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-08-25-exploring-the-scalability-limits-of-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-08-25-exploring-the-scalability-limits-of-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Join us at Percona Community Live Stream, and we will explore the scalability limits of PostgreSQL on Kubernetes with Dave Stokes and Charly Batista. Come up with all your questions and get an answer right away.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/Ij5TLLv6xuo
Transcript Dave Stokes
It should be starting up. Let me see if it started on Twitch. There we go. Okay, folks, originally, we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to talk about the scalability and limits of Postgres on Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>PostgreSQL running on Kubernetes operations - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Aug, 11th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-08-11-postgresql-running-on-kubernetes-operations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-08-11-postgresql-running-on-kubernetes-operations/</guid><description>Percona Community Live Stream will share a demo and some best practices on running Postgres on Kubernetes Operations. This is a part of a bi-weekly regular meetup to share experience and improve database opensource skills with Dave and Charly. Come up and ask questions.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/rQJTgm3O5WQ
Transcript Dave Stokes:
Good morning, good afternoon. Good evening. Good wherever you are. I&amp;rsquo;m Dave Stokes. And with me today is Charly Batista.</description></item><item><title>Installing and Setting Up PostgreSQL on Kubernetes - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - July, 28th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-07-28-installing-and-setting-up-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-07-28-installing-and-setting-up-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Learn more about Installing and Setting Up PostgreSQL on Kubernetes with experts. This is a part of Percona Community&amp;rsquo;s bi-weekly Live Stream. Dave and Charly shared their experience with a demo session.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/vO5pHTRONJQ
Transcript Dave Stokes well, I&amp;rsquo;m going to drop off quickly and get handed over to the Postgres person the week last week, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t get him online, that thing, and I will drop him off.</description></item><item><title>Installing and Setting Up PostgreSQL on Kubernetes - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-07-14-installing-and-setting-up-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-07-14-installing-and-setting-up-postgresql-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Hello,
Thank you for your visit! This event is postponed Follow us on Twitter and get informed of the new date Thank You
Percona Community Team
![Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp;amp; Chat - July 14th](events/streams-pg/pg-stream-cover-week-10-july-14.jpg) Learn more about Installing and Setting Up PostgreSQL on Kubernetes with experts. This is a part of Percona Community&amp;#39;s bi-weekly Live Stream. Dave and Charly will share their experience and run a demo session. Come up with all your questions and get an answer right away.</description></item><item><title>Migrating PostgreSQL to a New Server - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - June, 30th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-30-migrating-postgresql-to-a-new-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-30-migrating-postgresql-to-a-new-server/</guid><description>Listen out to this Percona Community Live Stream if you ever had a problem migrating PostgreSQL to a New server. Charly and Dave, gave some tips to take you through the process without any problems.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/ML_wWD-KCcM
Transcript Dave Stokes
Good morning good afternoon, good evening, good whatever you are, welcome back to Another dream for the ricotta community live stream. I am Dave Stokes; I am in Texas.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up and Using Patroni to Automate Failover in PostgreSQL - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-16-setting-up-and-using-patroni-to-automate-failover-in-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-16-setting-up-and-using-patroni-to-automate-failover-in-postgresql/</guid><description>This is a part of bi-weekly Percona Community Live Stream. Our experts, Charly and Matt has talked about setting up and using Patroni to automate failover in Postgres.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/dkp-3S3l8tY
Transcript Charly Batista
And my frozen looks like you
Matt Yonkovit
You are frozen though I don&amp;rsquo;t know why Charly&amp;rsquo;s frozen he just we just went live and Charly is frozen so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what that means for us hopefully nothing is Too bad, right?</description></item><item><title>Setting up failover via a replica for PostgreSQL - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - June, 3rd</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-03-setting-up-failover-via-a-replica-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-06-03-setting-up-failover-via-a-replica-for-postgresql/</guid><description>This is part of our bi-weekly Percona Community Live Stream. Our experts, Charly and Matt talk more about database failure and setting up a failover on PostgreSQL.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/DhLg4tMvHuI
Transcript Matt Yonkovit
Hello Hello everyone how are you doing today? Welcome to another exciting episode of Percona&amp;rsquo;s bi-weekly Postgres live stream. I am Matt Yonkovit, the head of open source strategy here at Percona. With Charly, our esteemed Postgres Tech Lead, Charly, how are you today?</description></item><item><title>Setting Up and Installing Backups With pgBackRest - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - May, 6th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-05-06-setting-up-and-installing-backups-with-pgbackrest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-05-06-setting-up-and-installing-backups-with-pgbackrest/</guid><description>Listen out to this full recording of the live stream dedicated to PostgreSQL hosted by the Head Of Open Source Strategy at Percona, Matt Yonkovit, with Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona. They took us through the setting up and installing backups with pgBackRest This is a part of the bi-weekly Live Streaming series to discuss Postgres-related topics and go deep into technology secrets and tricks.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up and Scheduling Regular PostgreSQL Backups (Part 2) - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - April, 21st</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-21-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-21-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups-2/</guid><description>Join the next Community Live stream for PostgresSQL and learn about the best setting to protect and restore your data. This is the second part of the previous stream. Matt and Charly will continue to talk about database backup settings, frequency, and different types of backups. Come up with your questions and our experts will answer them live.
VIDEO Link: https://youtu.be/7ZdQ4xjX464
TRANSCRIPT Matt Yonkovit: Hello, everyone, welcome to another Live Stream.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up and Scheduling Regular PostgreSQL Backups - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream - April, 8th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-08-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-04-08-setting-up-and-scheduling-regular-postgresql-backups/</guid><description>Learn about the best setting to protect and restore your data with Matt and Charly. They are talking about database backup settings, frequency, and different types of backups. Follow us on Twitter and get informed of all upcoming meetups
Listen to the recording here Link: https://youtu.be/3OeX-gsdwFc
Transcript Matt Yonkovit
Hello everyone out in live stream land. I am, Matt. And do you know who is not here? Charlie? I am in Jose.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for PostgreSQL - Percona Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - March 25th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-25-setting-up-alert-and-basic-automation-for-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-25-setting-up-alert-and-basic-automation-for-postgresql/</guid><description>Percona Community organized live stream to talk more about Setting Up Alerts and Basic Automation for PostgreSQL. This recording is from the live event of March 25th with Matt Yonkovit, Charly Batista and Agustin Gallego. This is a part of the Percona Community bi-weekly Live Stream series to discuss Postgres-related topics and deep talks with technology secrets.
Video Link: https://youtu.be/f1NklbrVvYY
Transcript Matt Yonkovit:
Hello, hello, everyone, Welcome to another Friday edition of the Postgres Percona database meetup.</description></item><item><title>Observing &amp; Tuning Your PostgreSQL Workload Using PMM - Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - March 11th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-11-observing-and-tuning-your-postgresql-workload-using-pmm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-03-11-observing-and-tuning-your-postgresql-workload-using-pmm/</guid><description>Organize and access easily to your database data by observing and tuning your PostgreSQL workload using PMM. Our experts Matt Yonkovit and Charly Batista present use cases in a bi-weekly live stream about Postgres-related topics.
Video Part 01 Link: https://youtu.be/H2uNDbQ8lCk
Video Part 02 Link: https://youtu.be/SxQyC2RdBCg
Transcript Part 01 Matt Yonkovit:
Here we go! We&amp;rsquo;re live! Hello everyone! Welcome to a specially exciting Friday live stream. Hopefully everyone is getting to the weekend.</description></item><item><title>Installing PG and Setting Up a Default Configuration - Community PostgreSQL Live Stream &amp; Chat - Jan 27th</title><link>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-01-27-installing-pg-and-setting-up-default-configuration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/streams-pg/2022-01-27-installing-pg-and-setting-up-default-configuration/</guid><description>Listen out to this full recording of the 1st Live Stream dedicated to PostgreSQL hosted by The Head Of Open Source Strategy at Percona, Matt Yonkovit with Charly Batista, PostgreSQL Tech Lead at Percona. They took us through the installation of Postgres and the setting up of the default configuration. This is a part of the bi-weekly Live Streaming series to discuss Postgres-related topics and go deep into technology secrets and tricks.</description></item></channel></rss>