<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>operators on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/operators/</link><description>Recent content in operators on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/operators/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data on Kubernetes Community initiatives: Automated storage scaling</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/data-on-kubernetes-community-initiatives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/01/10/data-on-kubernetes-community-initiatives/</guid><description>In the world of Kubernetes, where everything evolves quickly. Automated storage scaling stands out as a critical challenge. Members of the Data on Kubernetes Community have proposed a solution to address this issue for Kubernetes operators.
If, like me, this is your first time hearing about Automated storage scaling, this will help you understand it better:
Storage scaling in Kubernetes Operators refers to the ability of an application running on Kubernetes to adjust its storage capacity automatically based on demand.</description></item><item><title>Day 02: The Kubernetes Application Lifecycle</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/20/day-02-the-kubernetes-application-lifecycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/20/day-02-the-kubernetes-application-lifecycle/</guid><description>If you are in the world of application development, you know that every application has a lifecycle. An application lifecycle refers to the stages that our application goes through from initial planning, building, deployment, monitoring, and maintenance in different environments where our application can be executed.
On the other hand, the Kubernetes Application Lifecycle refers exclusively to applications deployed and managed in Kubernetes clusters. This differs from the normal application lifecycle because Kubernetes introduces new principles, practices, and tools for managing applications on containers.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Kubernetes Operators</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/03/kubernetes-operators/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/11/03/kubernetes-operators/</guid><description>The concept of Kubernetes Operators was introduced around 2016 by the CoreOS Linuxdevelopment team. They were in search of a solution to improve automated container management within Kubernetes, primarily with the goal of incorporating operational expertise directly into the software.
According to the Cloud Native Computing Foundation, “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components”.
Kubernetes is designed for automation, offering essential automation features. It can automatically deploy and manage workloads.</description></item><item><title>DoKC Operator SIG Update</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/14/dokc-operator-sig-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/08/14/dokc-operator-sig-update/</guid><description>Before our meeting, we started with a question to begin the morning: What board game or tabletop game have you played that you would recommend to others?
Itamar Marom suggests that Catan as a good board game, which takes a lot of time, super annoying when you lose, but generally a lot of fun. So highly suggested!
Other members like Hugh Lashbrooke and Robert Hodges prefer Monopoly, where you must reach a higher level of monopoly awareness to enjoy it fully.</description></item><item><title>Percona University in Peru 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/20/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Peru is a country in South America home to a section of the Amazon rainforest and Machu Picchu ⛰️, an ancient Incan city high in the Andes mountains. Percona decided to hold the first event of Percona University 2023 in Lima, the capital of Peru, on June 10.
Percona University is a series of free technical events organized by Percona in various cities around the world since 2013. Percona uses these events to share its unbiased expertise on open source databases with the community, users, and organizations.</description></item><item><title>Data on Kubernetes Meetup May 23</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/06/01/percona-and-data-on-kubernetes-meetup/</guid><description>Percona has started to participate in Data on Kubernetes (DoK) meetings about Kubernetes Operators. These meetings are an initiative of DoK meetups that spotlight DoK case studies. In this blog post series, I will summarize the topics covered in each meeting.
On May 23, very interesting topics were discussed on the agenda. Let&amp;rsquo;s begin to summarize it.
We start with a new project proposal, which is called: Distributed Systems Operator Interface (DSOI).</description></item><item><title>​What experts said at Kubecon about Data on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Melissa Logan, managing director of Data on Kubernetes (DoK), led one of the best panels I’ve been to at a conference at Kubecon EU in Amsterdam about challenges with and the state of the art of running databases on Kubernetes.
This panel united the Data on Kubernetes Community Operator SIG and Kubernetes Storage SIG to discuss key features of Kubernetes database operators. Xing Yang from VMware, Sergey Pronin from Percona, and Álvaro Hernández from OnGres came together to discuss what works, what doesn’t, and where the industry is going.</description></item><item><title>Binding your application to the database in the Kubernetes cluster</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</guid><description>dbaas-operator is Yet Another DBaaS Kubernetes Operator (need to suggest yadbko as a name) that tries to simplify and unify Database Cluster deployments by building a higher abstraction layer on top of Percona Kubernetes Operators.
So it becomes much easier to deploy the DB cluster with dbaas-operator and PMM DBaaS on top of it.
But another part of the picture is applications and their workloads to connect to the deployed DB Clusters.</description></item><item><title>Learning Kubernetes Operators with Percona Operator for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</guid><description>One of the topics that have resonated a lot for me since the first KubeCon I attended in 2018 is Kubernetes Operators.
The concept of Operators was introduced much earlier in 2016 by the CoreOS Linux development team. They were looking for a way to improve automated container management in Kubernetes.
What do we mean by a Kubernetes Operator? We use the definition of CNCF. The Kubernetes project defines “Operator” simply: “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components“.</description></item></channel></rss>