<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>operators on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/operators/</link><description>Recent content in operators on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/operators/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>​What experts said at Kubecon about Data on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/05/31/what-experts-said-at-kubecon-about-data-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Melissa Logan, managing director of Data on Kubernetes (DoK), led one of the best panels I’ve been to at a conference at Kubecon EU in Amsterdam about challenges with and the state of the art of running databases on Kubernetes.
This panel united the Data on Kubernetes Community Operator SIG and Kubernetes Storage SIG to discuss key features of Kubernetes database operators. Xing Yang from VMware, Sergey Pronin from Percona, and Álvaro Hernández from OnGres came together to discuss what works, what doesn’t, and where the industry is going.</description></item><item><title>Binding your application to the database in the Kubernetes cluster</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/01/24/k8s-app-db-binding/</guid><description>dbaas-operator is Yet Another DBaaS Kubernetes Operator (need to suggest yadbko as a name) that tries to simplify and unify Database Cluster deployments by building a higher abstraction layer on top of Percona Kubernetes Operators.
So it becomes much easier to deploy the DB cluster with dbaas-operator and PMM DBaaS on top of it.
But another part of the picture is applications and their workloads to connect to the deployed DB Clusters.</description></item><item><title>Learning Kubernetes Operators with Percona Operator for MongoDB</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2022/10/13/learning-kubernetes-operators-with-percona-operator-for-mongodb/</guid><description>One of the topics that have resonated a lot for me since the first KubeCon I attended in 2018 is Kubernetes Operators.
The concept of Operators was introduced much earlier in 2016 by the CoreOS Linux development team. They were looking for a way to improve automated container management in Kubernetes.
What do we mean by a Kubernetes Operator? We use the definition of CNCF. The Kubernetes project defines “Operator” simply: “Operators are software extensions that use custom resources to manage applications and their components“.</description></item></channel></rss>