<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sponsorship on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/sponsorship/</link><description>Recent content in sponsorship on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/sponsorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FTD Data 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</guid><description>A big part of the Percona Brazilian team gathered together in Florianópolis to participate in a special edition of the Floripa Tech Day (FTD), focused on DATA. The agenda included talks on various technologies: MongoDB, MS-SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, and PostgreSQL.
It was a 1-day event with 13 talks from early morining till late evening. Three of them were deliverd by Percona speakers:
Online Backup in MySQL with XtraBackup by Marcelo Altmann (Software Engineer).</description></item><item><title>PGConf Brazil 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconfbrazil-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconfbrazil-2022/</guid><description>Percona supports events all over the globe. We were so happy to participate in a big (maybe even the largest!) Postgres event in Brazil - PGConf Brazil 2022. It is a world-class conference, which builds on the efforts of professionals and enthusiasts to expand the community of PostgreSQL, enabling participants to develop new knowledge through lectures and training.
Since the pandemic has slowed down a bit and allowed all of us to gather together safely again, we take part in offline events again and this is super exciting.</description></item><item><title>SCaLE 19X 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/scale19x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/scale19x/</guid><description>This July, Percona Team met in Los Angeles. We participated in the Scale 19x from July 28th to 31st. SCaLE is the largest community-run open-source and free software conference in North America. It is held annually in the greater Los Angeles area. It was a big event with many sponsors this year.
Percona sponsored the event on the Silver level and had a huge presence there. 5 experienced Percona experts gave several talks:</description></item><item><title>Postgres Conference Silicon Valley 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2022/</guid><description>This time Percona Team flew to San Jose to participate in the Postgres Conference Silicon Valley from April 7th to 8th. This is a significant event for the Postgres Community on the West Coast.
Percona sponsored the event on the Gold level and had a huge presence there. 4 recognized database experts gave 5 stunning talks:
PostgreSQL Replication Conflicts: Avoiding Pitfalls by Hamid Akhtar (Technical Product Manager for PostgreSQL); Tune PostgreSQL for Read/Write Scalability and A Deep Dive into PostgreSQL Indexing by Ibrar Ahmed (Senior Software Architect); How Users Will Dictate and Change the Next 20 Years of PostgreSQL by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy); PL/Java - Extend the Power of Your Database by Charly Batista (PostgreSQL Tech Lead).</description></item><item><title>PGConf NYC 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</guid><description>On December 2th-3th, Percona Team was in New York on an important event in the PostgreSQL world - PGConf NYC. It is a non–profit, community-run conference, focused on business users, database professionals, and developers of PostgreSQL. Percona was thrilled to participate in it as a Platinum sponsor this year.
Speakers from Percona gave several amazing talks at the conference:
Postgres and Json - How to get the best of them?</description></item><item><title>All Things Open 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in ATO (All Things Open) in Raleigh Convention Center on October 17th - 19th.
Percona speakers gave 4 talks during the conference:
The PostgreSQL Twin Bill: The 7 Deadly PostgreSQL Mistakes &amp;amp; Review of what&amp;rsquo;s new in PostgreSQL 14 by Matt Yonkovit (HOSS) and Barrett Chambers (Sr. Manager, Solutions Engineering). Distributed Storage in the Cloud by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Deploying MongoDB sharded clusters easily with Terraform and Ansible by Ivan Groenewold (Architect).</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit Seattle 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in the OSS event organized by Linux Foundation in Seattle in Hyatt Regency Hotel on September 27-30. It was really exciting for all of us to start meeting in person with customers, community members, and teammates as well!
Percona speakers gave 3 talks during the conference: From a database in container to DBaaS on Kubernetes by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Default to Open - Steps and Traps by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy).</description></item><item><title>OSDN Conf Kyiv 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</guid><description>Percona sponsored the OSDN Conf Kyiv which was held in person in the Nivki-hal on September 18th. It was a one-day non-commercial, volunteer-organized event centered on free and open-source software. Mykola Marzhan (Director of Server Engineering, Percona) and Evgeniy Patlan (Manager of Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering, Percona) are the main organizers of the conference.
During the event, 400 attendees had the opportunity to visit presentations by the open-source community leaders, meet each other and chat during lunch and coffee breaks, discuss the latest trends with representatives on booths.</description></item><item><title>HighLoad++ Spring 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</guid><description>Percona team participated in the HighLoad ++ Spring conference in Moscow on May 17-18, 2021. It is the most famous IT conference in Russia for developers of highload projects. This year it brought together 2000 participants offline and 2000 online running 8 parallel tracks and having 20+ company stands for networking.
On the conference, Percona speakers presented 4 talks:
MySQL 8 Observability and Query Analysis with PMM by Peter Zaitsev (CEO) Comparison of Kubernetes Operators for MySQL by Sergey Pronin (Product Owner) Migrations between schemas and updates in MySQL: mechanisms, locks, loads by Nikolay Ihalainen (Senior Support Engineer) Anatomy of a Kubernetes Operator for a database by Peter Zaitsev and Sergey Pronin.</description></item></channel></rss>