<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sponsorship on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/sponsorship/</link><description>Recent content in sponsorship on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/sponsorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona University Delhi 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-delhi-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-delhi-2024/</guid><description>Percona Universities are was designed to help attendees dive deep into the latest advancements in database technology. On June 21st, 2024, database enthusiasts gathered in Gurgaon to talk all things databases.
The event took place at The Circle Work Huda City Center co-working space. The location was perfect eith easy access from the metro station.
Throughout the day, various talks and sessions allowed participants to gain new insights and exchange ideas.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Limassol 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-limassol-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-limassol-2024/</guid><description>On April 20th, 2024, people who love working with databases came together in Cyprus for something special - the Percona University Limassol. Percona put on this event to help folks dive deep into the latest database tech.
The meetup was all about sharing knowledge. Percona brought in international and local experts in a database space. These experts talked about the newest trends, best ways to manage databases, and cool new solutions.</description></item><item><title>Postgres Conference 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2024/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2024/</guid><description>In April 2024, the Percona Team journeyed to San Jose for the Postgres Conference in San Jose, CA, taking place from April 17th to 19th.
This conference holds great importance for the thriving Postgres Community on the West Coast.
Percona proudly sponsored the event at the Partner level. Percona experts also gave many talks at the conference:
Reducing Costs and Improving Performance With Data Modeling in Postgres by Charly Batista. Monitoring PostgreSQL: Navigating the Landscape of Metrics, OS and Hardware Relationships, and Toolsets by Charly Batista.</description></item><item><title>PGConf India 2024</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-india-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-india-2024/</guid><description>PGConf India 2024 took place in Bengaluru at February 28 - March 01, 2024. With about 400 conference attendees, it is the biggest Postgres event in India. This conference is part of efforts to grow the PostgreSQL community by increasing awareness and providing the appropriate training and resources to further PostgreSQL adoption in India.
Participants from 61 different cities and 10 countries gathered together in Radisson Blu Bengaluru Outer Ring Road Hotel for a 3 day event.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Athens 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-athens-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-athens-2023/</guid><description>Percona University Athens took place on November 7th. The event in Athens was organised with the help and sponsorship of FerretDB.
Attendees of the event had a chance to interact with recognised database experts and each other.
Speakers from different countries and companies participated in this event. Click on the links below to view the slides:
Cloud of Serfdom vs Cloud of Freedom: Why Open Source Will Win in the Cloud Age by Peter Zaitsev (Founder, Percona)</description></item><item><title>Percona University Buenos Aires 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-buenos-aires-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-buenos-aires-2023/</guid><description>Percona University came to Buenos Aires on October 20th. Percona University is a series of database meetups that we organize worldwide in different locations.
It is a wonderful opportunity to discover more about open source software, databases, and services, and speak to recognised experts and featured speakers. Build your knowledge and get up to speed on hot database topics.
Agenda included talks both in English and Spanish. Click on the talk&amp;rsquo;s titles to look through slides.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Montevideo 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-montevideo-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-montevideo-2023/</guid><description>We bring international speakers and invite local ones to help you to build your knowledge and get up to speed on hot database topics.
Percona University came to in Montevideo at October 24th. Percona University is a free database meetup open to everyone in the community.
This time agenda included talks both in English and Spanish:
Cloud of Serfdom vs Cloud of Freedom: Why Open Source Will Win in the Cloud Age by Peter Zaitsev (Founder, Percona)</description></item><item><title>HighLoad++ Serbia 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2023/</guid><description>This summer Percona Team traveled to Belgrade in Serbia to participate in 2 events - Highload++ Serbia 2023 and Percona University Belgrade.
The journey started with team building for those who arrived early. They went to a segway tour around the city and visited Belgrade Fortress with Kalemegdan park with an amazing guide who told them a lot about Serbia history. They also ride segways in the city center to get acquainted with the main tourist attractions.</description></item><item><title>PGConf Germany 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-germany-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-germany-2023/</guid><description>The PGConf Germany 2023 took place in the Haus der Technik in Essen, Germany, on June 27, 2023. It had a record-breaking registration with above 250 people.
The sessions weren’t recorded but many speakers added their slide decks to their talks, so check out the schedule if you’re interested to learn more about a specific talk.
Kai Wagner and Dimitri Vanoverbeke from Percona participated in the event and worked on Percona booth.</description></item><item><title>PGConf India 2023</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-india-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-india-2023/</guid><description>PGConf India 2023 started on a fresh note after 2 years of gap due to the pandemic. With 400+ conference attendees and 150+ attendees for the training program, it was a great event.
There were three parallel tracks for the presentations. Jobin Augustine, PostgreSQL Escalation Specialist from Percona, gave 2 talks during the event:
Reducing PostgreSQL Costs in the Cloud In the face of economic uncertainty and a possible recession, many companies are trimming expenses, freezing hiring, and, in some cases, laying off staff.</description></item><item><title>Percona University Istanbul 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-university-istanbul-2022/</guid><description>Percona University is a series of database meetups that we organize worldwide in different locations. November 5th we came to Istanbul, economical, cultural and historical heart of Turkiye. HostedPMM and FerretDB supported us during this meetup and sponsored it.
It was a wonderful sunny day in Istanbul. We gathered together early in the morning at Kolektif House. It is an awesome coworking place with wonderful inhabitants and all the necessary equipment to hold an event.</description></item><item><title>FTD Data 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ftd-data-2022/</guid><description>A big part of the Percona Brazilian team gathered together in Florianópolis to participate in a special edition of the Floripa Tech Day (FTD), focused on DATA. The agenda included talks on various technologies: MongoDB, MS-SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, and PostgreSQL.
It was a 1-day event with 13 talks from early morining till late evening. Three of them were deliverd by Percona speakers:
Online Backup in MySQL with XtraBackup by Marcelo Altmann (Software Engineer).</description></item><item><title>PGConf NYC 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pfcong-nyc-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pfcong-nyc-2022/</guid><description>The PostgreSQL NYC is a PostgreSQL community conference that was held in the last week of September 2022. It is a non–profit, community-run conference. About 140+ attendees participated in the event. Percona supported the conference on a Broze level and also provided additional support, for example, sponsoring speaker/stuff dinner.
Two speakers from Percona gave amazing talks:
A Deep Dive Into PostgreSQL Indexing by Ibrar Ahmed. Abstract: Indexes are a fundamental feature of relational databases, and PostgreSQL offers developers and designers a rich collection of options.</description></item><item><title>PGConf Brazil 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconfbrazil-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconfbrazil-2022/</guid><description>Percona supports events all over the globe. We were so happy to participate in a big (maybe even the largest!) Postgres event in Brazil - PGConf Brazil 2022. It is a world-class conference, which builds on the efforts of professionals and enthusiasts to expand the community of PostgreSQL, enabling participants to develop new knowledge through lectures and training.
Since the pandemic has slowed down a bit and allowed all of us to gather together safely again, we take part in offline events again and this is super exciting.</description></item><item><title>SCaLE 19X 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/scale19x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/scale19x/</guid><description>This July, Percona Team met in Los Angeles. We participated in the Scale 19x from July 28th to 31st. SCaLE is the largest community-run open-source and free software conference in North America. It is held annually in the greater Los Angeles area. It was a big event with many sponsors this year.
Percona sponsored the event on the Silver level and had a huge presence there. 5 experienced Percona experts gave several talks:</description></item><item><title>Postgres Conference Silicon Valley 2022</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgsv-2022/</guid><description>This time Percona Team flew to San Jose to participate in the Postgres Conference Silicon Valley from April 7th to 8th. This is a significant event for the Postgres Community on the West Coast.
Percona sponsored the event on the Gold level and had a huge presence there. 4 recognized database experts gave 5 stunning talks:
PostgreSQL Replication Conflicts: Avoiding Pitfalls by Hamid Akhtar (Technical Product Manager for PostgreSQL); Tune PostgreSQL for Read/Write Scalability and A Deep Dive into PostgreSQL Indexing by Ibrar Ahmed (Senior Software Architect); How Users Will Dictate and Change the Next 20 Years of PostgreSQL by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy); PL/Java - Extend the Power of Your Database by Charly Batista (PostgreSQL Tech Lead).</description></item><item><title>PGConf NYC 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/pgconf-2021/</guid><description>On December 2th-3th, Percona Team was in New York on an important event in the PostgreSQL world - PGConf NYC. It is a non–profit, community-run conference, focused on business users, database professionals, and developers of PostgreSQL. Percona was thrilled to participate in it as a Platinum sponsor this year.
Speakers from Percona gave several amazing talks at the conference:
Postgres and Json - How to get the best of them? by Charly Batista (PostgreSQL Tech Lead).</description></item><item><title>All Things Open 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/ato-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in ATO (All Things Open) in Raleigh Convention Center on October 17th - 19th.
Percona speakers gave 4 talks during the conference:
The PostgreSQL Twin Bill: The 7 Deadly PostgreSQL Mistakes &amp;amp; Review of what&amp;rsquo;s new in PostgreSQL 14 by Matt Yonkovit (HOSS) and Barrett Chambers (Sr. Manager, Solutions Engineering). Distributed Storage in the Cloud by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Deploying MongoDB sharded clusters easily with Terraform and Ansible by Ivan Groenewold (Architect).</description></item><item><title>Open Source Summit Seattle 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/open-source-summit-seattle-2021/</guid><description>Percona Team participated in the OSS event organized by Linux Foundation in Seattle in Hyatt Regency Hotel on September 27-30. It was really exciting for all of us to start meeting in person with customers, community members, and teammates as well!
Percona speakers gave 3 talks during the conference: From a database in container to DBaaS on Kubernetes by Peter Zaitsev (CEO). Default to Open - Steps and Traps by Matt Yonkovit (Head of Open Source Strategy).</description></item><item><title>OSDN Conf Kyiv 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/osdn-conf-2021/</guid><description>Percona sponsored the OSDN Conf Kyiv which was held in person in the Nivki-hal on September 18th. It was a one-day non-commercial, volunteer-organized event centered on free and open-source software. Mykola Marzhan (Director of Server Engineering, Percona) and Evgeniy Patlan (Manager of Build &amp;amp; Release Engineering, Percona) are the main organizers of the conference.
During the event, 400 attendees had the opportunity to visit presentations by the open-source community leaders, meet each other and chat during lunch and coffee breaks, discuss the latest trends with representatives on booths.</description></item><item><title>HighLoad++ Spring 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/highload-2021/</guid><description>Percona team participated in the HighLoad ++ Spring conference in Moscow on May 17-18, 2021. It is the most famous IT conference in Russia for developers of highload projects. This year it brought together 2000 participants offline and 2000 online running 8 parallel tracks and having 20+ company stands for networking.
On the conference, Percona speakers presented 4 talks:
MySQL 8 Observability and Query Analysis with PMM by Peter Zaitsev (CEO) Comparison of Kubernetes Operators for MySQL by Sergey Pronin (Product Owner) Migrations between schemas and updates in MySQL: mechanisms, locks, loads by Nikolay Ihalainen (Senior Support Engineer) Anatomy of a Kubernetes Operator for a database by Peter Zaitsev and Sergey Pronin.</description></item></channel></rss>