<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>author_wayne on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/author_wayne/</link><description>Recent content in author_wayne on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 16:48:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/author_wayne/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Disk of Yesteryear Compared to Today’s SSD Drives</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/17/disk-of-yesteryear-compared-to-todays-ssd-drives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 16:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/01/17/disk-of-yesteryear-compared-to-todays-ssd-drives/</guid><description>In my [last blog post](https://www.percona.com/ community-blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/) I showed you how to get the entire Percona “Stack&amp;quot; up and running on a Raspberry Pi. This time around, I would like to show the impact on performance between using an SSD hard disk and a standard hard disk.
Disk performance is a key factor in Percona Server for MySQL (or any RDB platform) performance on a Raspberry Pi 4.
Test set up Each test below was run three times per Hard Disk and I took the best of the three for comparison.</description></item><item><title>How to Build a Percona Server "Stack" on a Raspberry Pi 3+</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 12:50:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/08/01/how-to-build-a-percona-server-stack-on-a-raspberry-pi-3/</guid><description>The blog post How to Compile Percona Server for MySQL 5.7 in Raspberry Pi 3 by Walter Garcia, inspired me to create an updated install of Percona Server for the Raspberry Pi 3+.
This how-to post covers installing from source and being able to use Percona Server for MySQL in any of your maker projects. I have included everything you need to have a complete Percona Server, ready to store data collection for your weather station, your GPS data, or any other project you can think of that would require data collection in a database.</description></item></channel></rss>