<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PLO-2020-10 on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/plo-2020-10/</link><description>Recent content in PLO-2020-10 on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 14:01:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/plo-2020-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MySQL 8.0 Document Store, Discovery of a New World – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/19/mysql-8-0-document-store-discovery-of-a-new-world-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 14:01:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/19/mysql-8-0-document-store-discovery-of-a-new-world-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 5:00 a.m. • London 10:00 a.m. • New Delhi 2:30 p.m. • Singapore 5:00 p.m.
Abstract MySQL Document Store enables us to work with SQL relational tables and schema-less JSON collections. So instead of having a mixed bag of databases, you can just rely on MySQL, where the JSON documents can be stored in collections and managed with CRUD operations.</description></item><item><title>The State of ProxySQL, 2020 Edition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/16/the-state-of-proxysql-2020-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 20:08:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/16/the-state-of-proxysql-2020-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 7:30 a.m. • London 12:30 p.m. • New Delhi 5:00 p.m. • Singapore 7:30 p.m.
Abstract ProxySQL is a high performance, high available, protocol aware proxy for MySQL. 2.0 has been GA for some time now, and there have been a lot of changes that come in point releases as well, such that you can benefit from them. Listen to René, the founder of ProxySQL, take you through some of the new features in 2.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Data Reliably Using SLO Theory – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/16/engineering-data-reliably-using-slo-theory-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 02:43:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/16/engineering-data-reliably-using-slo-theory-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 12:30 p.m. • London 5:30 p.m. • New Delhi 10:00 p.m. • Singapore 12:30 a.m. (next day)
Abstract Not so long ago, operations specialists worked much like today&amp;rsquo;s data engineers do: with specialized skills, they were the people who kept sites running, who responded to emergencies, and who—unfortunately—spent much of their time dealing with incidents and other &amp;ldquo;fires.&amp;rdquo; When the DevOps revolution came, this began to change.</description></item><item><title>DBdeployer, the Community Edition – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/14/dbdeployer-the-community-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 18:44:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/14/dbdeployer-the-community-edition-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 3:30 a.m. • London 8:30 a.m. • New Delhi 1:00 p.m. • Singapore 3:30 p.m.
Abstract DBdeployer, an open source tool that allows easy deployment of many MySQL/Percona servers in the same host, has passed two years of development. Its latest additions have aimed at improving ease of use for both beginners and experts. This talk will show how to start with dbdeployer with an empty box, and quickly populate it with recent and less recent server versions, all at the command line.</description></item><item><title>Sharding: DIY or Out of the Box Solution? – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/14/sharding-diy-or-out-of-the-box-solution-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 03:04:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/14/sharding-diy-or-out-of-the-box-solution-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 7:00 a.m. • London 12:00 noon • New Delhi 4:30 p.m. • Singapore 7:00 p.m.
Why is your talk exciting? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if my talk is exciting, but I&amp;rsquo;m quite positive the subject is! Vitess has been gaining a lot of traction over the past few years and I must admit that I&amp;rsquo;ve been keen to get hands-on experience with it for years.</description></item><item><title>What If We Could Use Machine Learning Models as Tables – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/12/what-if-we-could-use-machine-learning-models-as-tables-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 17:56:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/12/what-if-we-could-use-machine-learning-models-as-tables-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 1:30 p.m. • London 6:30 p.m. • New Delhi 11:00 p.m. • Singapore 1:30 a.m. (next day)
Abstract In most machine learning tasks, one has to first organize data in some form and then turn it into information about the problem that needs to be solved. One could say that the requirement to train many machine learning algorithms is information, not just data.</description></item><item><title>Vitess Online Schema Migration Automation – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/10/vitess-online-schema-migration-automation-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:28:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/10/vitess-online-schema-migration-automation-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 2:30 a.m. • London 7:30 a.m. • New Delhi 12:00 noon • Singapore 2:30 p.m.
Abstract For many, running an online schema migration operation is still a manual job: from building the correct command, through identifying where the migration should run and which servers are to be affected, to auditing progress and completing the migration. Sharded environment poses an additional burden, as any logical migration must be applied multiple times, once for each shard.</description></item><item><title>Analytical Queries in MySQL – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 17:05:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/09/analytical-queries-in-mysql-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 6:00 p.m. • London 11:00 p.m. • New Delhi 3:30 a.m. • Singapore 6:00 a.m.
Abstract MySQL&amp;rsquo;s sweet spot is known to be online transaction processing (OLTP), and it can support a very high load of short transactions. Many users will also want to run analytical queries (OLAP) on their MySQL data. Often they achieve this by exporting their data to another database system that is tailored for analytical queries.</description></item><item><title>Serverless Databases: The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/08/serverless-databases-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 20:58:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/08/serverless-databases-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Oct • New York 4:30 a.m. • London 9:30 a.m • New Delhi 2:00 p.m. • Singapore 4:30 p.m.
Abstract Starting with AWS, the major cloud providers offer different options to run a MySQL or a MySQL-compatible database on the cloud. A new approach is to rely on so-called serverless (relational) databases like Aurora Serverless that offer both traditional TCP connections and HTTP API access.</description></item><item><title>MySQL Ecosystem on ARM – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/08/mysql-ecosystem-on-arm-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 02:28:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/08/mysql-ecosystem-on-arm-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 8:00 p.m. • London 1:00 a.m (next day) • New Delhi 5:30 a.m. • Singapore 8:00 a.m.
Abstract? The ARM ecosystem is quickly evolving as a cost-effective alternative to run High-Performance Computing (HPC) software. It continues to grow with some major cloud players hosting ARM-based cloud servers. MySQL too joined the ecosystem with 8.x. MariaDB already has made its presence.</description></item><item><title>NoSQL Endgame – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/06/nosql-endgame-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 01:08:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/06/nosql-endgame-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 3:00 p.m. • London 8:00 p.m. • New Delhi 12:30 a.m. (next day) • Singapore 3:00 a.m.
Abstract The amount of data collected by applications nowadays is growing at a scary pace. Many of them need to handle billions of users generating and consuming data at an incredible speed. Maybe you are wondering how to create an application like this?</description></item><item><title>Kunlun Distributed DB Cluster Intro – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 22:25:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/02/kunlun-distributed-db-cluster-intro-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Tue 20 Oct • New York 9:30 p.m. • London 02:30 a.m. (next day) • New Delhi 7:00 a.m. • Singapore 09:30 a.m.
Abstract Kunlun Distributed Database Cluster is a distributed DBMS that aims to combine the best of both MySQL and PostgreSQL for a highly performant, highly available, highly scalable and fault-tolerant, easy to use and manage database system that requires minimal human maintenance. It enables users to define table sharding rules so that it automatically distributes tables properly to available storage shards; implements the two-phase commit protocol to do distributed transaction commit; uses MySQL group replication for high availability in storage shards; fixes a series of MySQL XA bugs to make distributed transactions highly reliable, among many other enhancements.</description></item><item><title>MariaDB 10.5 New Features for Troubleshooting – Percona Live ONLINE Talk Preview</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/mariadb-10-5-new-features-for-troubleshooting-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/01/mariadb-10-5-new-features-for-troubleshooting-percona-live-online-talk-preview/</guid><description>Percona Live Online Agenda Slot: Wed 21 Aug • New York 12:00 midnight • London 05:00 a.m. • New Delhi 9:30 a.m. • Singapore 12:00 noon
Abstract I want to help DBAs and Support engineers find out what&amp;rsquo;s really going on when some problem strikes. My goal is to show new ways to diagnose problems now available in MariaDB 10.5. See the full abstract for more.
Why Is Your Talk Exciting?</description></item></channel></rss>