<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Percona Everest on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/percona-everest/</link><description>Recent content in Percona Everest on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/percona-everest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Timeline for Database on Kubernetes</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/07/16/timeline-for-database-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>The Evolution Since its inception in June 2014, Kubernetes has dramatically transformed container orchestration, revolutionizing the management and scaling of applications. To mark its tenth anniversary, the Data on Kubernetes Community (DoKC) released an infographic showcasing key milestones and community contributions to the evolution of operators for managing stateful applications. This project was made possible by the collaboration of DoKC members Edith Puclla, Sergey Pronin, Robert Hodges, Gabriele Bartolini, Chris Malarky, Mark Kember, Paul Au, and Luciano Stabel.</description></item><item><title>Percona Joins Community Over Code 2024 in Bratislava, Slovakia</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/21/percona-joins-community-over-code-2024-in-bratislava-slovakia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/21/percona-joins-community-over-code-2024-in-bratislava-slovakia/</guid><description>Last week, I participated as a speaker for the first time at Community Over Code 2024.
Community Over Code Community Over Code is a key principle at Apache, highlighting the importance of having a solid and collaborative community rather than just focusing on the code. While good code is essential, the community&amp;rsquo;s strength and resilience keep a project going and growing. I love how this is expressed in the &amp;ldquo;Apache Way.</description></item><item><title>Let's take a look at Percona Everest 1.0.0 RC</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/14/lets-take-a-look-at-percona-everest-1.0.0-rc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/06/14/lets-take-a-look-at-percona-everest-1.0.0-rc/</guid><description>Hi, the Percona Everest 1.0.0-rc1 release was published on GitHub.
Percona Everest is the first open source cloud-native platform for provisioning and managing PostgreSQL, MongoDB and MySQL database clusters.
I want to tell you how to install it so you can try it out.
RC builds aren&amp;rsquo;t meant for the general public; we don&amp;rsquo;t support upgrading from RC to stable versions. This means that this is only for testing and familiarizing yourself with the features.</description></item><item><title>How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes with Percona Everest Summary</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/05/02/how-to-provision-a-mongodb-cluster-in-kubernetes-with-percona-everest-summary/</guid><description>Kubernetes continues evolving, and the complexity of deploying and managing databases within the ecosystem is a topic of considerable discussion and importance these days. This article summarizes a detailed discussion between Piotr Szczepaniak and Diogo Recharte, who offer insights and live demonstrations to simplify database operations on Kubernetes with a new technology for cloud-native applications: Percona Everest. If you want to watch the full video, check out How to Provision a MongoDB Cluster in Kubernetes Webinar.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Percona Everest on GCP with Kubectl for Windows 11 Users</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/19/deploying-percona-everest-on-gcp-with-kubectl-for-windows-11-users/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2024/04/19/deploying-percona-everest-on-gcp-with-kubectl-for-windows-11-users/</guid><description>Welcome to this blog post! Today, our primary goal is to guide you through deploying Percona Everest on GCP using Kubectl, specifically for users on Windows 11. It&amp;rsquo;s been some time since I last used Windows, so this will be an excellent opportunity to do it from scratch.
Let me tell you a little bit about Percona Everest. You may have already heard it recently. It is the new open source tool launched by Percona and is already well-received by Kubernetes database users.</description></item><item><title>Building and Running Percona Everest From Source Code</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2023/10/30/building-and-running-percona-everest-from-source-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2023/10/30/building-and-running-percona-everest-from-source-code/</guid><description>Digging deeper into the architecture of an open source product
Recently, Percona team announced the public alpha version of a new open source product – Percona Everest. It allows you to create database clusters on Kubernetes cluster.
I have installed Percona Everest several times and tried its features. Standard installation is very simple and takes a few minutes.
But, to understand the product deeper, I came up with the idea to explore repositories, build and run Percona Everest from source.</description></item></channel></rss>