<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Liquibase on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/liquibase/</link><description>Recent content in Liquibase on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 14:14:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/liquibase/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zero downtime schema change with Liquibase &amp; Percona</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/26/zero-downtime-schema-change-with-liquibase-percona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 14:14:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/10/26/zero-downtime-schema-change-with-liquibase-percona/</guid><description>I am always surprised to learn something new whenever I talk to a member of the open-source community. No matter how much I think I have heard of every use case there is for Liquibase (and database change management in general), I always hear something that makes this space still feel new. There’s always something left to discover.
Today, that new something is the problem of how to perform large batches of changes with SQL ALTER TABLE statements.</description></item><item><title>Liquibase Data: Version Control and Collaboration for the Database</title><link>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/events/percona-community-live-2022/day-1-robert-reeves/</guid><description>This session is presented on Percona Community Live Online June 21-23, 2022. Check out the full schedule here.
Watch This Talk Here The talk will be live-streamed on several platforms. No registration is required. Feel free to ask your questions in chat. Follow the links now and subscribe to notifications not to miss anything!
YouTube LinkedIn Twitter @PerconaBytes Twitch PerconaCommunity Liquibase is the defacto standard for versioning your database schema.</description></item></channel></rss>