<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>author_lawrence on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/author_lawrence/</link><description>Recent content in author_lawrence on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/author_lawrence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE Opening Keynote: State of Open Source Databases by Peter Zaitsev</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 15:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/15/percona-live-online-opening-keynote-state-of-open-source-databases-by-peter-zaitsev/</guid><description>Peter Zaitsev is CEO and co-founder of Percona. He opened Percona Live ONLINE with a keynote which took a look at the historical foundations of open source software and how they have shaped the field today.
The history of open source software In the early days of computing, software and hardware were bundled together. While the term open source wasn&amp;rsquo;t coined, software was open by default. According to Peter: &amp;ldquo;One of the big reasons for that was copyrights on software was not a thing, because the software was not really a thing before that.</description></item><item><title>Matt Yonkovit: It's a crazy world, and these trends are disrupting and breaking your database infrastructure</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/12/matt-yonkovit-its-a-crazy-world-and-these-trends-are-disrupting-and-breaking-your-database-infrastructure/</guid><description>Matt Yonkovit, Chief Experience Officer at Percona, presented a session at this year&amp;rsquo;s Percona Live ONLINE, sharing initial insights from the Open Source Data Management Survey 2020. The survey provides a critical insight first-hand into how enterprises of all sizes are using, developing, and troubleshooting open source database software. The full data will be released later this year with a detailed analysis.
He who controls the application controls the stack Matt started with discussing the challenge that developers face: &amp;ldquo;Those building it are not the ones managing it.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE: Anti-cheating tools for massive multiplayer games using Amazon Aurora and Amazon ML services</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/11/percona-live-online-anti-cheating-tools-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 14:21:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/11/percona-live-online-anti-cheating-tools-for-massive-multiplayer-games-using-amazon-aurora-and-amazon-ml-services/</guid><description>Would you play a multiplayer game if you discovered other people are cheating? According to a survey by Irdeto, 60% of online games were negatively impacted by cheaters, and 77% of players said they would stop playing a multiplayer game if they think opponents are cheating. Player churn grows as cheating grows.
Stopping this is therefore essential if you want to build and develop your community, which is essential to success for today’s gaming companies.</description></item><item><title>Percona Live ONLINE: MySQL on Google Cloud: War and Peace! by Akshay Suryawanshi &amp; Jeremy Cole</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:12:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2020/06/02/percona-live-online-mysql-on-google-cloud-war-and-peace-by-akshay-suryawanshi-jeremy-cole/</guid><description>This session at Percona Live ONLINE was presented by Akshay Suryawanshi, Senior Production Engineer at Shopify, and Jeremy Cole, Senior Staff Production Engineer - Datastores at Shopify. Shopify is an online and on-premise commerce platform, founded in 2006.
Shopify is used by more than a million merchants, and hundreds of billions of dollars of sales have happened on the platform since its inception. The company is a large user of MySQL, and the Black Friday and Cyber Monday weekends are their peak dates during the year, handling hundreds of billions of queries with MySQL.</description></item></channel></rss>