<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>author_pingcap on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/tags/author_pingcap/</link><description>Recent content in author_pingcap on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 20:45:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://percona.community/tags/author_pingcap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Percona Live Presents: The First Ever TiDB Track</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 20:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2019/05/06/percona-live-presents-first-ever-tidb-track/</guid><description>The PingCAP team has always been a strong supporter of Percona and the wider open source database community. As the people who work day in and day out on TiDB, an open source NewSQL database with MySQL compatibility, open source database is what gets us in the morning, and there’s no better place to share that passion than Percona Live.
At this year’s Percona Live Open Source Database Conference in Austin, Texas, we are particularly excited to bring you a full track of talks and demo on the latest development in TiDB during Day 1 of the conference.</description></item><item><title>TiSpark: More Data Insights, No More ETL</title><link>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/18/tispark-data-insights-no-etl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 13:41:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/blog/2018/06/18/tispark-data-insights-no-etl/</guid><description>When we released TiDB 2.0 in April, part of that announcement also included the release of TiSpark 1.0&amp;ndash;an integral part of the TiDB platform that makes complex analytics on “fresh” transactional data possible. Since then, many people in the TiDB community have been asking for more information about TiSpark. In this post, I will explain the motivation, inner workings, and future roadmap of this project.
Motivation The motivation behind building TiSpark was to enable real-time analytics on TiDB without the delay and challenges of ETL.</description></item></channel></rss>