<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engineering Monthly Meeting on Percona Community</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/</link><description>Recent content in Engineering Monthly Meeting on Percona Community</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Percona Community. MySQL, InnoDB, MariaDB and MongoDB are trademarks of their respective owners.</copyright><atom:link href="https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Engineering Meeting August 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/2021-08-31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/2021-08-31/</guid><description>Location: Discord voice channel Date: Tuesday, August 31, 2021 Agenda Reverting Percona&amp;rsquo;s node_exporter to Prometheus'
We&amp;rsquo;re share how to revert back PMM&amp;rsquo;s node_exporter to the Prometheus original&amp;hellip;and why we want to.
Carlos will be going deep inside the code, rummaging through the innards of the Golang code, seeing how the exporter works, making changes, and giving step-by-step commentary.
He&amp;rsquo;ll be working in these repos:
https://github.com/percona/node_exporter https://github.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Meeting July 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/2021-07-27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/2021-07-27/</guid><description>Location: Discord Date: Tuesday, July 27, 2021 (Google Calendar event) What? We&amp;rsquo;re talking about Prometheus exporters:
How they work Who uses them and why Where they&amp;rsquo;re used What you can and can&amp;rsquo;t do with them So, basically anything to do with Prometheus exporters.
Who? Come along if you&amp;rsquo;re a:
User of Prometheus exporters (standalone or within PMM) Student of Prometheus exporters (and want to learn how to code/tweak them) Potential user of Prometheus exporters (what can they do) DBA thinking about Prometheus exporters (getting metrics data out of databases) DBA dreaming about Prometheus exporters (thinking about the same) &amp;hellip; you get the idea Who else?</description></item><item><title>Engineering Meeting June 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/2021-06-29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/2021-06-29/</guid><description>Location: Discord Day: 2021, June 29 (Google Calendar event) Agenda Introduction Meet your community, short intros Percona Exporters and PMM Exporters Roadmap. Project Board Review. Open PRs: review and questions. All exporter repositories now use GitHub Actions. Linter issues. Issues with forks. Usage and contribution in grafana-dashboards. Additional labels of targets in Prometheus. How to contribute Dashboards to PMM. Release schedules and artefacts.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Meeting May 2021</title><link>https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/2021-05-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://percona.community/contribute/engineeringmeetings/2021-05-25/</guid><description>Location: Discord Day: 2021, May 25 (Google Calendar event) Agenda Introduction Meet your community, short intros Percona Exporters Strategy and plans Open PRs How to make contribution easy Docs Building and testing Revising Build/Test and contribution docs Release strategies PMM Is there an interest to contribute to PMM? Issues with build and testing What areas to contribute? Feedback and Q&amp;amp;A How can we improve?</description></item></channel></rss>